hello my name is Eric and I'm going to
teach you about Pokemon and stuff so
every Pokemon has a weakness every
distance and um some has immunity so I
I'm gonna take ice type because it's a
good time to start from and
it's
Venus to rock fire
[Music]
deal
fighting
weather
squeaky pen yeah
okay and and it's super effective
against Grass
flying
um
oh yeah ground
and dragon
a super effective means it so so
it's the grass one of grass's weaknesses
is ice so I will do double the amount of
damage to these types and and and and
these would do double amount of damage
to that
I mean Pokemon Pokemon has has some
has made sense to color real likes like
rock you can chuck a rock out of Earth
and it will break fire you can melt ice
with fire it turns to water Still Still
um let's say uh a steel got so nice if I
think you can punch a nice annual break
grass you can
freeze freeze freeze freeze dragon is in
real life so
um
so
so you have Pokemon has types and
and ice and they're single type and do
type single type is single type is only
has one type and and dual types it has
two types
so I if let's say what Pokemon
let's say um
uh Pikachu Pikachu is uh
is a a single type because these are
only electric type
and it has nothing else really and that
single type and do types for two types
um
it has more than two has three times
Pokemon's maximum entices two and
minimum entirely as one and
so
let's say
let's say Charizard is
is
a fire
and and flying
that's a dual type because it has more
than one type
and
for
and for eyes
and and do toys can change your
weaknesses and can change the
effective Effect one of the super
effective stuff kind of thing so
um
that I should be using Rock fire still
fighting and
let's take let's let's take ice
and flying
item flying is in okay
current combination and flying is
resistant to fighting because a bird can
can
um pick a person
so super weaknesses
so awesome flying is not weakness in
fighting and
steel fire
Rock flying is Venus to rock because
because Birds hate it when you Chuck
rocks at them I'm not sure about that
but Pokemon that does it and and steal
fire rock and flying flying is also
weakness to Electric
it also means to rock so so that's times
two so rock does four times the amount
of damage to death so it's kind of over
weak uh weakness Point
um so an electric and
and there's also flying it's also Venus
to ice but as ice is resistant to us
because ice ice
um if you
Chuck and Ice a knife um it's not very
effective so so there's no weakness to
Iceberg so these are the weakness so
yeah
ending part uh so what have you learned
today
okay and then the ice
okay that's very interesting thank you
thank you for that thank you