hello my name is Erica this is the
second day and I I'm gonna teach you
about
ghosts uh go upstairs to go this is kind
of a spirit of a dead person in real
life and it's I I think it's mostly a
myth I'm gonna say about immunity
because ghost has the most immunity I'm
gonna talk about immunities because I
know you're gonna say what's that huh
it's like immune and said okay ghost is
it's immune
I mean to oh yeah two
two
normal and fighting
and guys for me in mutant Pokemon it
means for example it does zero damage to
to the type so so no matter like if it
if it does 10 damage
the zero there's there's a hundred
damage still the zero so for example
fighting the like you can't punch a
ghost like you can't punch a ghost
because yeah you can't yeah zero damage
two girls so it doesn't matter how hard
you punch a ghost
um because it still does no damage
and Ghost types are weakness to
and oh wait this is
good
this is a very confusing type as it's
weakness to him itself so
so it does super effective damage
against ghosts and also his Venus it
goes so ghost does super effective
against damage to ghost I don't expect
you to understand that but not so dark
yeah and oh and and also I'm talking
about res resistance
resistance means it it kind of resist
resist it means it doesn't actually do
zero damage it means it's kind of like
you it does half damage
for example
uh if it goes through resistant as a bug
and poison
for example so it means like blood does
half amount of damage to ghosts and
poison because like bug you if you bug
doesn't goes and you can't really poison
the goat so it doesn't make any sense
and so it's kind of resistant
and
and what else
weakness resistance
okay so which one is uh Stronger like
the ghost type or ice ice type we talked
about last week oh good size okay
so always stronger
is it always stronger against times
types in Pokemon if you
guys talk
best cut as it is and it also has the
most immunities I see okay good what
does it look like can you try it
the Ghost type oh it's a kind of drawing
this type of sign is this
ah
it does look like a ghost I guess it
doesn't have red nose and ears and hairs
what does it look like
I think it's kind of like a snowflake uh
it's basically a snowflake
yeah I'm not very good
I don't know
anyway Pokemon isn't just throwing
snowflakes okay yeah okay okay I got it
so oh yeah the super effective we're
super
effect
Ive
means it does ghost does double amount
of damage ghost obviously and psychic
okay psychic is basically like light in
Pokemon it does super effective damage
and so
so you know like I talked to you about
[Music]
a pair of eyes and ghosts like for
example a nice and Ghost type is like
for example is
um is it like that what's less it is I
think Ghost type Pokemon and so
so if
so
um it's ice isn't resistant to ice so
you put that there
ice ice is not clean as you bug and
poison so it does normal damage so you
keep that there for super effective ice
and you put on grass
um
dragon
and round
you can't really see that but
[Music]
and so
and its Venus is ISA is leanness to
Rock
okay Steel
fire
and that says immune to fighting so as I
said no matter how much damage it does
there's still zero so it's immunity
fighting and normal so you don't put
fire in there and yeah okay
oh I will have you been today okay so I
learned this uh Ghost type yeah so it
looked like a ghost and it's a meal to
fighting normal
what's normal normal fighting no one is
oh
no one ties is kind of like oh I see
okay so he said not like a Pokemon thing
right yes okay no it's another type okay
and also ghost also has no has no effect
on no one I don't know because no one
guess it's kind of like
I see okay
okay
good thank you bye-bye