hello my name is Eric I'm going to teach
you about psychic type but if I can't
type is an okay time it's kind of made a
leak I don't know because and it's
sweetness is um let's see oh yes bug
okay
and dark
okay the sidekick is something like
light or something it's like basically
mind controlling and light so kind of
like that I like fagot
um so it's super effective
but
psychic is like a person who is uh crazy
crazy person the person like can mind
control like for example in in the book
Matilda Roald Dahl it I think she has
like psychic powers oh I see okay
and fighting
oh okay fighting like a psychic I think
you can mind control and like and
you also have no effect
okay effect on dark
uh yeah because this weakness to dark
okay I didn't imagine this yeah because
my mind control like with like Darkness
or kind of thing so oh yeah resistance
resistance is a
is psychic
and fighting you can't really it doesn't
do much if if you like
psychic one another that that's
resistance like it's it's not very
effective against each other both types
both ways that's normally what what most
majority of types are I see come here
and the
and were not very effective on not
effective
not very
they're less types today than the
previous one I remember in the previous
video you well you put out something in
different types yeah you know
[Music]
it it said to be like the best type it
has load of defenses the difference is
it kind of
it's kind of neutral it doesn't deem so
it normally doesn't do much damage
against
one two three four five six seven eight
ah yeah
and we have ten types of neutral I see
because Steel
and psychic
steel and psychic type is something like
Metagross Metagross is like on coding on
coding last time we talked about the
table and one of them was Metagross oh
okay you'll remember okay
it's really good type combination
so still
Okay so
so it's not lean is too dark anymore
in a neutral section okay
because steel is resistancy dog so so
like if you even out it makes it a bug
okay okay
uh
good steel is also weenies to fire oh
look around so we add that on since
psychic isn't resistance to firing
ground so if you put them at but it's
also weenies to fighting but since it's
resistance we wrote that off and then
put it in so you can combine the
different Pokemon types and then we put
a load on here okay I
so so we put
dragon
Rock
Steel
grass
you don't put bug Virgo duck so we have
what else is there oh yeah very
and um
like I think it's okay there's a load of
different defenses from steel and it's
not very effective against
steel is
so too effective left foot Rock
and ice
oh okay so we also have this four times
resistance
which means it's resisted by four times
so when that happens it's like this not
very so that so resistance is to psychic
so I give a Stealers both of them are
resistant to say to remove that out and
put it there and it's not not very
effective on
steel is not very effective against
also another effect is gonna steal so if
that's already there so you did so can
you draw a psychic type
okay it's I yeah I see okay good
that's great okay
okay so the psychic is like a person
looking to this mind reading right yeah
okay thank you okay so what's the next
one next week
I think it's gonna be
um normal okay okay thank you thank you
very much thank you bye