hello my name is Eric and I'm going to
teach about water types and water is is
water yeah
it's like Pokemon
seed like turtles starfish uh I don't
know accidentals
um okay so it's just like a thing like
leaving water not not this water
stuff like that um so the weakness
grass
electric yeah grass and electric because
if you if you don't like science and
stuff like water conducts electricity
very well that's right yes
so that's why I'm doing it another
plants drink water so yeah that makes
sense
and
and it's super effective
and obviously tired that doesn't need
explaining that's right yes look
um
grounds
Rock ground I don't know if
what uh cleans a rock I don't know maybe
lift into the ground or maybe
flows Rock didn't I but that is how it
is and not very effective
not very effective it's not very
effective against
water like you know water doesn't do
much against water grass because because
grass is a stirring kit
dragon
yeah I think that's it for Dragon I
guess like was it
like dragons yeah and nowhere effects
against Dragon it does it doesn't have a
name with you or anything or not no
effect it's kind of it's kind of just
like that
um
the thing is like
so this is kind of like a real Pokemon
so this is kind of like oh this is like
a Pokemon and it has like a weakness
point and but this is kind of like a
move like the move and you do this and
sorry
okay so this could be a regular 35 like
this could be a this could be used like
any type can be used to get weakness
points and that this is what this is for
and five these are all the types that
has a weakness point of water and these
this has not very effective so this is
like kind of however however Pokemon
attacks because and it and it doesn't do
much against these
makes sense okay okay
what works well against water yeah uh
water they say water and
Steel
kind of like that so water and steel
types
it's
not Venus to
grass anymore between fighting
the greenness to ground as well
not very effective so still oh yeah
resistance
forgot to add that it has a
like last time still has a long
resistance so it's gonna be
loads of space there so it's gonna be
like steel Rock a load of that that one
is kind of like they're doing water now
so
so we've got a bunch of like that and
what the steam toe is kind of like
Empoleon and and water stiff water is a
kind of it's really like
different and and is and it's a really
good type as not very excited I mean it
was mostly a lot of water types has a
lot of ice type moves so it can get rid
of that and mainly with electric so yeah
and in real estate I think it's I think
it's like Seventh Place
what does it look like
yeah
a drop a water drop yep
it looks
[Music]
like
Peach
okay
so what's next
um I think
I think about
I think
fuck okay good thank you bye bye