hello my name is Eric and I'm gonna
teach you about bug patch so bug type is
kind of like bug and and work and it's
actually what's actually known as the
weakest type in the game
because it's so small right yeah I know
yeah yeah is that clean so that's
probably why so
it's um
[Music]
fighting
around
and grass
it because for example for fighting you
can punch you can punch it if you can
punch your bag or maybe a mosquito or or
you can punch your wasp with but it'll
be really inconvenient because they can
fly and ground so you doesn't do much
against bugs grass bugs eat grass and
that's good
this is what they do against psychic
dark
broth well psychic I don't know why
because maybe me but I don't know maybe
and dog I think it's because like how
how some books have my videos and dog
doesn't do much against them and graph
they eat grass
okay this is the same thing that
resistance and the effective super
effective no for bug resistance
and see like the Pokemon like taking the
damage from from the apartment and
either will read spots and super
effective is this is how the Pokemon
attacks and that how the actual Pokemon
taken taking taking the damage and this
weakness
fire fire kills everything
[Music]
and
not very effective
so the bug is not buggy is
effective
on it's not very effective against
against fire
as as but can't do much against like a
flame and fighting
as as Bots can do much against the big
fist oof how about ice type
you know freeze it
it's not it's not in here okay okay
it's not very effective against poison
yeah because I think it's because
um I can't do much things we can flying
because
because it's a bird
it's a bird okay
and it's not very effective against
ghosts because
it can
really do much and
still and fairy you can't do it much
against the steel and
and fairy is just like the things in
fairy tales and it can't and I prefer
itself and about funding me
so this is it so so as you can see it's
it's not it's not like is is known as a
uh weakest guys you can probably see why
it's not very effective against
like seven times
and so it's probably best for a daughter
so looking at the bug type Pokemon
they're like stuff like bugs like
butterflies like beetles
beetles bees
wasps
mosquitoes mantis stuff like that so
let's say one of my best for bug is bug
and steel the worst type
with the best type basically because
steel is the best type and bug is the
worst type the bug toe is known as the
worst time and Steel type is known as
the best type I didn't have loads of
resistance you're like this this thing
is steel this has been here for like a
year or so and nothing and haven't had a
dent in it can you draw a bug type
no
is it like that um
is it like that
and so so let's see for bug and steel is
not really enough to Flying anymore so
that's neutral and bug bug resistant
it's not resistance to fighting as steel
is clean as if I think and it has a
whole body like dark
it has and its steel is also a
resistance across so
two kind of resistance as it resisted to
buy twice so so it does
so it does four times less
well for number resistance it is two
times less but but scaling bug um are
both so they go to graphs grass goes
here
and and it has a hole and Weiner so far
steel is also meaning supplier so it
makes up to
oh
okay so would move times four times and
the normal
quickness is times two but but this is
times four so it has a mean weakness bug
resistance is not mean it's not
resistancy graph ground anymore because
because it still is really super brand
and it has a whole one very
it's not really listening to rock
because like if green is a rock I am
Rock if there's it and so and see let's
do this and so yeah ice
it goes here because yeah
um
I
and it fairy eyes grass
Electric
not very effective against electric
I feel that it's not
it's too effective against fairy
so this is what basically it looks like
for a bargain stereotype it
it has four times Venus is fire which
which is basically like a mainly with
weakness for like weaknesses for Pokemon
the damage
Times by two twice and but for the main
limit as it has to be a dual type and
and both of them have to be penis to a
certain point and and it has a day and
it's weak making this is fine
so what have you learned today okay okay
the box and the weakest it's not your
favorite type right yeah okay your
favorite type is uh
okay okay thank you bye
foreign