hello my name is Eric and I'm going to
teach about electric type and so
electric code is kind of if you look
over Electric Touch they're probably
stuff to do with like electric like you
usually like Thunderbolts and stuff so
it's weaknesses
his weakness is ground
and that's really it and it's a ground I
don't know why but I think it's like
earthquakes are maybe rattle a socket I
don't know so it's resistance
foreign
type is resistant to itself because it's
the same type not always not always okay
can you give me an example why this is
not the case
you know you know in the center like
water is it resistant to water yes
so one of them is ghost ghost is super
effective against each other and also if
I think that neutral damage to yourself
okay okay thank you electric fly and and
steel
so electric yeah it kind of like I'm
flying like a bird I don't know
electrified
steel because like you know how steel
how it comes you can definitely that
just say yes yes so yeah so and it's
super effective
against water and climb yeah if you know
like five and sounds like the water for
like water conducts electricity well and
so like because we're made we have water
inside so that's why we get electric
shocks yes
flying I don't know what's good birds
and electricity but that's how it just
works
and it's not very effective
they're effective
okay
not very effective against electric
obviously
graph
and dragon
so
so this has been going on as as so this
is like the actual Pokemon like the
actual
the actual Pokemon
okay
and and and there's a appointment
wait a minute and but this is the
appointment
this is a permit
attacking the Pokemon
opponent attacking the Pokemon so this
is this is this is the Pokemon's
resistance and the Pokemon's weaknesses
would you call it kind of yes so so the
weakness and resistance and you notice
they might have the same thing so this
is where my attacking the Pokemon and
this is a Pokemon's weakness and
Pokemon's resistance and what with this
one
the Pokemon attacking the appointment so
this is what this Pokemon is super
effective and this is what is not very
effective against uh let's see
so super thank you not very effective
and water and we're listening electric
is like a very a pretty good type it's
unless if the third referred best
what's the top best
deal what's the second dragon
what does it look like in a job
ah yeah okay okay looks like a chicken
neck
but oh you can or you can do uh if we
like this better
yeah
yeah okay okay I see okay
okay so what have you learned today yeah
electric type what's next
I think I'm gonna do
today I see now we cover the top three
best all right yeah thank you thank you