hello my name is Erica and I'm going to
teach you about Dragon time so dragon's
weakness is Dragon Eyes
so dragon is also one of these types
that is Venus and super effective
against himself so it's Dragon I swear
resistance is electric
fire
water
grass
first of all can you draw what it looks
like
okay so one thing I'm a little bit
confused is that these 18 Pokemon types
so for each type how many Pokemons are
there oh it's a lot it's a
little okay so because the yeah there's
a certain amount for each different type
so I'm not sure how much dragon has I'm
100 sure that ice has the least amount
of a Pokemon really the least amount of
Pokemon are ice types
is super effective dragon
that's it so
um
not very
paper against steel so this is what
dragons look like it's the second best
type rank the first type is still right
yep Steel Dragon electric
fairy ground go guys water fire
dark psychic poison I see yeah because
the most popular ones are those stronger
ones right so for example like last time
this is like
this is like a dragon type Pokemon yeah
and this is a
payment
so this is the dragon type Venus and
resistance
so so this is well you know if the
appointment these two other permanent
attacking the Pokemon the Dragon type
Pokemon and these are the weakness
weaknesses so if you use a dragon ice
fairy will be too effective and if you
use electric fire water grass they'll be
not very effective against the pure
dragon type
and this is a dragon type of Pokemon
attacking the Poland
so this is what this is super effective
against and this is what is not very
effective than this not very effective
thing
is what this can't do much against and
if I can do a law against you get yeah
okay good so poor Dragon we can pair up
dragon against a load of other types so
so one of the best
kind of combinations with dragon is
dragon and fairy a dragon and fairy is
like it's like make it out Mega Target
is a dragon effect so if if you look at
most of the dragon types the dragon
types are kind of Fizz and
face and stuff can kind of like a snake
photo kind of like
stuff that flies well well not all of
them flies so a dragon and fairy type
it'll be super effective against very
very significant against
fighting
oh yeah also I meant we've got to
imagine that dragon has no effect
no effect
against fairy
so no effect it's kind of like it does
zero damage too so no matter how much
power if it has a hundred part base
power it still does a zero and if it's a
200 base power it has zero ten by power
zero it is always zero so it does
nothing against fairy
dragon fighting dark
dark and dragon
so and his weakness is no longer witness
to Ferry
an immune and the mean
it goes
goes down there and vanilla effect goes
up here because oh no birming goes here
and then nobody goes there
so the immunity is for resistance it
resist weakness weakness point is actual
dragon type body kind of taking the hit
or dying
foreign
type is immunity dragon
as fairy is immune to dragon
it doesn't matter what is paired paired
up with it at least at the fairy tale is
still immune to dragon
so
if not ween is the dragon anymore
poison
resistance irresistance to fighting
dark and it's not and fairy is not also
not very effective against Steel
not very effective against poison
so what have you learned today okay so
the best type of dragon yeah it's the
second best time okay so I can still
okay so uh how many Pokemons are in
dragon type
no I think it's like I don't know I
think okay maybe you'll tell me the next
lesson okay so each Pokemon type can you
name a few because all I have been
learning uh in the last 10 lessons
including this one is the the type
actual types so can you name a you know
a concrete Pokemon or the specific
a Pacific Pokemon oh yeah yeah
a dragon
oh or any other types it doesn't matter
any other time
so for a bit I'm gonna do dragon so
there's a Pokemon first dragons
including legendary Pokemon and mythical
Pokemon oh okay so there's there's
pseudo legendary Pokemon there's
mythical Pokemon they're the legendary
Pokemon Legendary Pokemon is a type of
Pokemon which is kind of legendary you
can guess by the name a mythical Pokemon
is kind of myth myth kind of thing and
pseudo legendary Pokemon are just normal
Pokemon but they're as strong as
legendary Pokemon and there's at least
one pseudo legendary for every different
region okay so each Pokemon is different
right I mean it has different skills
different okay it has different skills
abilities
and he has to obey in that group in a
type right because for example like if
it's a Pokemon is in the dragon type and
he has to obey all these Blues right all
these effective weaknesses yeah because
I see and if it's
improves of a very tight and for example
let's see um let's say four wheelers as
a dragon's minions to fairy but fairies
resistance to theory in the fairies one
and dragons and dragon's Venus to fairy
so so when they paired up uh
a weakness and a weakness and resistance
makes it neutral so it does neutral
damage okay and can two programs in the
same Pokemon type pair with each other
like two you know two Pokemons of the
same type pair each other tear up with
each other
so dragon and dragon yay or something
this is called
ah I see so this pair up is to waste uh
two times coconut type it's not actually
Pokemons no so a single type is a
Pokemon with only one type and a door
type Pokemon is a Pokemon that has two
types
okay
okay thank you thank you and what's next
okay okay see you next week bye bye
thank you