hello I'm Eric and I'm gonna talk talk
about um doctor so like the dark is kind
of like if you look at the dark time
Pokemon there's like dark yeah how do
you draw it what does it look like uh it
looks like
okay
I don't know so um
his weaknesses is a very
fighting and bug
so the fairy is kind of like the fairy
tales and stuff but it's very fighting
and bug I don't know why is that but
that's about it so those are the types
that the dark are Avail of a weakness so
how do you interpret it so for
weaknesses is so we have a dark type
Pokemon just pretend that's the dark
type Pokemon yeah and so today's
Witnesses is this this
these type moves and and if that and if
there's the Dark type weakness yeah it's
kind of like Venus so this does more
damage to them
okay got it so
and it's resistant resistance kind of
like almost like opposite of weakness
it it kind of resists it
um
there is the resistance is well dark
and
ghost
s
I think that's that's it yeah
and so it's
it's not very effective
it's not very effective against dark
uh
don't worry about your kids fighting
not very fucking around the fairy
so um
and it's
and they're super effective
who's effective against
well ghost
and psychic
and also it has immune system and an
immunity
psychic
foreign
because
I feel like like last time
this is an appointment packing so this
is kind of like the body of a dark type
like it's resistance and its venuses and
it's also
and there's also needed immunities so
this is how it how its weaknesses
resistance how it how it damages the
dark type Pokemon how it like takes a
move and
here is
like like we don't have like I'm
attacking with everyone so this is this
is kind of like it it's defenses it's
Witnesses and this is kind of like his
attack how like how it damages uh other
Pokemon like us you can see the effect
against like it and it's not very
effective against stuff fighting fairy
our last time that appeared in here like
you know water
it does kind of like new tooth damage as
I see as it does like normal damage you
have the super stick it's moving forward
venuses for very fighting a buggy for
Pure for a few adult type
um if it does two times the amount of
damage
okay usually you say that there's a two
type you pair with other type yeah so
what's the type like it compared to it
[Music]
and so some do type Pokemon
combinations like I don't know rock
gossip I haven't there's no Pokemon
which is like a specific like double
Thai so for for a dark side let's say uh
let's say I'm an adult dragon
for adult Dragon it has a
uh so I wear that on your hair
and four times
Before Time filming this so it does four
times a month because dark hand Dragon
are both wieners to fairy so
so
much
right so if fighting bug
um
very
dragon
eyes
yes so and resistance to Electric
fire
bras
oh
is is it mean to psychic and dragon is
not my own effect against Steel
I see so basically in the Dual tab it
just combines the poster types yeah
okay so can you name a few Pokemons of
the dark type
or maybe it's one or two like combined
[Music]
legendary and
High Dragon which is a Duncan dragon
type there's also a big shop
this up which is a dark and Steel type
there's also um
worth is that
Malamar which is a dark and psychic type
and earthy food which is a dog and
fighting dive
okay and there's also Umbreon which is
just a single type dog okay good okay
so what have you learned today okay the
dark type interesting okay so what's
next
if I remember correctly so there are
seven to go
it's now being covered so far
no okay poison is a good point okay
thank you thank you bye