hello my name is Eric and today I'm
going to teach you about poison type so
poison types of neatness
what does it look like
so
okay looks like a ring
I don't know what's that the poison type
Venus is uh ground a psychics grand
grand psychic are just super effective
and I don't really know about poison
like science kind of thing so and it's
resistance
if resistance is
thrust but I think
poison
um bug and fairy
so it has quite a few resistance it's
grass fighting poison bug Berry poison
is kind of like that type which is
and not very effective against each
other but I guess most of them are like
that and
fighting fighting doesn't do much
against poisons
grass yeah bug blood's not very
effective very
I don't know fairy and it's super
super effective against
awesome fairy
so there's only two poison soup
effective but
is
grass and fairy and it's neutral to all
of us and
for
um it's not very effective
it's not very significant
um
poison
as is the ground
Rock
ghost
and it also has a no effect so it's no
there's no effect on Steel
so
this is kind of like the
the poison poison like me
there's last time you mentioned how much
was there for each type for for this one
it's there's 92 poison types
obviously it's gonna change you as
there's gonna be added more Pokemon as
a month a month about a month ago this
new paldia region
and it was in Pokemon Skyline Vada and
and there was a new region so me more
Pokemon was added and created and so and
in their new region there was eight more
poison types so so that's added on to
90. and so that makes it 92 obviously is
Gonna Change
throughout so poison types is a good
single time and daughter well I guess
the best combination with poison is dark
poison and dark and
today we talk about that last week right
yeah
so
what does it mean so it's a very uh
effectively feels poison in the dark
okay a poison and a dark type so like
Game Freak
how they design for dual types is is
most of like so if you look at all of
the Pokemon of that kind like poison
like for for example if you look at
normal
but for normal most of them are like
kind of white so and for the Ghost type
and in ghost eyes they're normally black
purple stuff like that so if they want
to make a normal and good stuff they
kind of merge them together
so
the poison and dark type I'm not very
good at drawing so
there's drapion and scum tank
so
and I'm just giving you an idea what it
looks like
is it like that no no no
I think it has some of this I see things
and it has a long well it's kind of like
that so it's like a poison and a dark
type so that's me trying to draw a
drapion the Whiteboard fan so poisonous
I guess is in my I think is the most
best one so for for poison so it's
really nice too it's not Venus too
anymore as you remember
dark
so immune
and it changes to me
so they kind of pair up together and
resistance
there's no resistance to ferret anymore
because because dark is Venus to it so
it's going to neutral section so
so it kind of does was ordinarily power
is and all of these stuff this thing
it changes kind of like it like super
effective times two times divided by two
times four divided by four stuff like
that so that's going neutral and it is
no resistance to fighting anymore
or bug
as dark as weakness to those
and dark is resistance to dark so you
put slot that in
and dark is
and so it's super very inside here
two and ghost
s not very effective it's not very
effective against
dark can hit goes like that
so
basically so all you really need to know
is kind of like the two task what what
kind of like you do types really like do
so so they're kind of like oh if if oh
this type like if this title is going to
stick that to one toe and and and the
other pad if resistant to that then you
then you'll go to neutral
I see okay okay
so kind of like poison so right now I'm
just teaching about types but for poison
there's a loads of goods and moves like
for like for like let's say toxic so
toxic is a poison type move that kind of
like toxic really and and then it will
poison guitar a Target which and the
wind went and they hit they get hit by a
poison but they get hurt by poison and
and every and and then the poison damage
does more
the small more every poison damage it
doesn't more and there's also abilities
for poison like
like
I think it's
corrosion something like that is allow
it to poison steel tights even though
it's not has no effect and also it can
poison types okay so in Pokemon
world there is a how many kind of damage
like poison damage and I guess there's a
physical damage the foot side so there's
stats so
stats
there's six I think there's six
different type of categories of stats
like there's
Health points also short H is also HP is
short for help points
defense
special defense
attack
special attack
speed
yeah and that's it so speed speed
obviously is how fast it is so in like
in the games
the faster the Pokemon so if like one
pug like like this is a Pokemon this is
a Pokemon this Pokemon is faster than
that Pokemon then this Pokemon gets to
start first
okay and
the special attack the special defense
and special
so
let's say attack attack is kind of like
physical moves like a like fire punch
drain punch wake up slap it's kind of
like moves that makes contact like a pot
like
500 from the punch um
uh kind of kind of ones that make
contact like like touches the
appointment
kind of need and
for life and special attack is different
it's kind of you it's kind of like a
range attack like
like if like I'm not sure if humans can
do range attacks I the only one I know
is a spit like meow I was like like
water gun
it is a long range attack it's from afar
it's kind of like opposite
so yeah so what's a defense and special
difference so
it's kind of like special defense is
blocking the far a range attacks and
defense is blocking the physical attacks
okay so you mentioned the physical
attack so physical attacks as opposed to
Ranger attacks
so there's no something like a magic uh
you know damage like when a castle space
you thought how you can cut cut the
stairs
for casting spells I guess I guess it's
there's three I think there's three
different type of attacks there's
there's special attack
physical attack and State
status attacks it's kind of stages is
kind of makes put a kind of condition on
the other Pokemon like you can use you
can use sleep powder to make them asleep
or you can use baby doll eyes which
which lowers their attack that's kind of
like
status it's kind of like poisoning them
like you fund a wave you it's kind of
like blowing lowering their stats or or
put them in a condition like poison
poison paralyze
burned
sleep
um
yeah okay okay so what have you learned
today okay they've poisoned type and so
how many poison the type here Pokemons
right now it is 92. oh yeah you
mentioned that yeah yeah okay yeah there
are 92 of poison type okay and then I
also then these uh different steps okay
uh so what's uh next have we done
fire no okay we're gonna do five okay
thank you yeah we talk about water so
surely we need to talk about five okay
thank you bye-bye bye