hello I'm Eric and I'm going to teach
about fire time fire type is like fire
so I think the majority of them are red
uh orange kind of like that so it's
super effective
what does it look like just like a fire
yeah well a friend the Orange is red and
the inner bit is like Kind of Blue
yeah the inner bit the bottom part of
the flame It's Kind of Blue a little bit
tiny bit it's still effective against
Grass you can turn the glass yeah I
think it's super effective against steel
I guess ice and
fire they are just super effective to
each other right because eyes can put
out fire
yeah I
I think that's wrong
[Music]
fire melts eyes and then I and then the
eyes will melt into water and then the
water will fill out a fire yeah I think
that's where you get it from but the
thing is the real Pokemon is is
and it's kind of like you kind of knock
knock a Pokemon out if
I think it's
sort of
and that I don't think that's actually
so a fire super effectively against ice
but I say super effective against
ice is not very effective against fire
but on the water water is super
effective against fire okay it makes
sense yes
so I and I also I don't really think a
Pokemon will melt
okay
and it's not very effective against
it's not very effective against
fire
obviously a flame is not very faced
against another Flame
water
Rock
and dragon
Through Fire like I said I think if even
I I think most of it is not very
effective against each other
water
that doesn't need explaining rock kind
of I think
it can really burn I don't know I think
it's something to do with like it can't
really spread fire stuff like that
Dragon
[Music]
so it's Venus is Venus it is a weakness
against
water
Rock
round
I think it's kind of like if you Chuck
sand or dirt on fire I'm not sure but
maybe it's
resistance
the resistance to
fire
grass ice
bug
fairy
uh oh yeah and steel
and a vlog has a kind of big chunk of
resistance
I think it doesn't have any no effects
or immunities
I say I mean there's only two types of
fire type as well I think that they
um covered most of the Dual types like
even though they're like over a thousand
Pokemon they still haven't covered all
of the door type like normal and
no more and Bug there isn't a normal bug
type in Pokemon like 18 times right if
you pick two awesome 80 so how many
possibilities see 18 times pick two two
as a due time all right so this equals
18 times 17 divided by two so that's uh
9 times 17 so that's uh what 17 times
nine I think it's a 157
so it's 170 minus
70 right 753 yeah 153 153 okay so 153 at
least one Pokemon for each two type
right so it means 153. I think
show you example of like fire and Bug
yeah an idea of fire Embark is one of
the Pokemon Legends in the fire and Bug
there is one which is which is a volcano
so I think I'm not very good at drawing
so
you like a flower
it's like
it's something like that butterfly
it's it's supposed to be move Moss okay
okay so these wings are ready so I think
it's kind of or whatever
um representation yeah of a sun so and
with me to find bug type so there's no
real Instagram anymore because bug is
resistant to ground so which makes
ground in a neutral second because a
minus one and a plus one makes a zero so
it's a neutral okay
do you get that
yes kind of yes
bug is weakness to flying
so you pop that in
we we were flying in as far as no
resistance to Flying hole or immune and
bug is also Venus to rocks and rock is
already dead so I think it's a rock
count too because so normally normally
venuses is times two if so times two of
a not neutral amount of damage and but
if it's twice a chord weakness
it can only happen for dual ties because
dual ties have two ties and if those two
dice have one of the same weaknesses
it's a chord weakness so if I embark is
Rock
2v times four and next bug is also
winners to fire but fires resistance to
fire
which puts it into the neutral section
and also bug is also resistant to Grass
which makes it which makes it resistance
by four times so that's kind of
obviously a recording this so I chose
this tote in particularly because it has
a quad weakness and it also has a
resistance so this grass is resisted
twice because fire is resistant to grass
and bug is also resistance to Grass
which is resisted by twice sidekick
grass
grass is already there yet
and dark
[Music]
yeah so what have you learned today okay
the fire type it seems the fire type is
very strong right
because fire depends everything so who
beats the fire
uh
um water Rock and ground okay so I would
look for the uh which were not very
effective right so if this is what fire
is not very effective
but in Samsung that means that those
type speed site can I understand that
that way
so
so like water in there right so Japan is
not very effective against water so it
means water is very effective to fire oh
it's not always it's not always so are
we done fighting
no okay that's good so today is the 13th
right so we have five more people yeah
okay thank you bye-bye