hello my name is Eric and I'm going to
teach about fighting type so fighting
type is kind of like the Pokemon which
are like very good at fighting uh you
can look at them and then you can say oh
that's a karate guy so and this fighting
type weakness
what does it look like oh it looks like
it kind of looks like that
kind of like that
like that I think yeah it's supposed to
be stopping weakness is
is psychic
fairy
I'm not actually sure why is fighting
being a psychic fairy and falling okay
so this weakness these Pokemons beat
fighting it means it kind of has an
advantage it doesn't mean 100 beat okay
and it means like if it uses like a
flying time if it does double the damage
neutral damage is what it normally does
um flying so if it's super effective it
does it it doubles it and it says if
it's a chord weakness then what weakness
is for dual type because if both of the
types are winning still in a particular
time and then it'll do four times as
much okay
so the fighting is
um resistance
to
its resistance to bug I think because
bugs are small bugs can't do much
same like rock
and dark
Rock
so fighting is resistant to rock and
dark dark I think I don't know I think
they can see me dark or something rock
is uh they can punch a rock
it's it's super effective against normal
Rock
ice
dark
deal
so fighting is a a pretty okay time it's
not as as is the only time which is
super effective against normal as normal
as when he has a one witness
no more it can punch
rock you can punch a rock but I think a
punch your eyes dog he can punch dark
steel can kind of Steel I think these
fighting type Pokemon are really strong
fists because they can point to steal
all right
effective let me guess fire
a poison
uh okay yeah we have
um flying
very
psychic
and bug
is resistance and nowhere effective so
bug and fighting can't do much against
each other I don't know why it's not
very effective against Bug for poison it
it can't really karate people are not
scientists so what's karate I mean what
does it mean it seems like
pancake stuff like that like it's kind
of like a gym for
fighting
karate card is very
k-a-r-a-t-e
k-a-r-a-t-e okay I don't know what he
means flying I think flying flying I
like birth I don't know why birth why
birth can do so much against a guy with
Fists
yeah but I'm seeing why the birds can do
so much damage to the fighting guy fairy
I don't think like fairy is a kind of
Pokemon which ones too right but I think
I don't know why it's that there and
sake is kind of like mind controlling
and also has a no effect
can I remember it from um
what no effect
yeah I talked about the time which
fighting has no effect on and I love
that video it I put immune to fighting I
know
water no no attack
oh okay
because you can't punch your ghost I see
I mean okay so you never says then
not many types come from girls because
it's just like uh non-existent a ghost
type Pokemon and no more and fighting
type moves
so it's an effect because you can't
really touch it or punch it but it does
it's also different moves like Thunder
Punch Thunder Punch is electric I mean
and there's also Fire Punch which is a
fire type move I used to punch which is
the ice type move and there's also
Shadow punch which is a ghost type move
okay and they're also there are 91
fighting type Pokemon the fighting type
Pokemon have the most average attack
stat the average of a fighting type
Pokemon stat is the highest I'm not
saying like it's on the limit I'm saying
it's higher than the rest yeah okay you
mentioned that yeah because it's
fighting yeah yeah for the fighting I
think they did all of the fighting type
of doctors I I'm just gonna do fire and
fighting so fire
if I am fighting fire in the fighting is
kind of like
um
Inferno Inferno is kind of to to get the
image of a fine fighting type Pokemon
Inferno is a
punching ape or monkey with with fire on
his head and it's red
well not really red not like not like a
tomato I think you already know how this
works fire is this is nasty fairy so he
popped out in the neutral section
so it does no more damage like minus one
plus one make zero
it's weakness to five weakness to water
so you pop that in
fighting is not resistance to water
so we pop that in if it was resistant to
water we've rubbed water from here and
we've popped our neutral section we
don't put Rock in because fighting is
resistance to rock and the fire's
weakness of rocks so minus one plus one
zero
whoops
is also weighing us to ground as
fighting is no resistance to ground and
as you see as you've seen forever broken
that would happen if fighting was that
so he popped that in there the fire is
really listen to fire
through this into grass
fires also a resistance to bars
since fighting and fire are both with
the social bug so it does four times
less instead of two times for normal
resistance the damage divided by two if
both of them are resisted by five so
this these two are both resist bug so it
does four times less so let's say we
have a bug time move and there's 80
damage then it will turn to 20. okay on
a final connecting type
so for time to do this
is also resistance to ice
also resistance to steel
and I think that's it fires also
resistance to
um grass
uh eyes oh your eyes is already there
do you leave us there
is anger I already figured them
oh yeah bug
three for for fighting fighting is a
good count for steel and steel is I I
think is one of the I think it has the
highest average defense
so fighting is a good counter for steel
it can super effect all of these I'm not
sure if there's a word so
so for dual type
for super effect super Effectiveness and
and not very effect is is a different
thing to weakness and resistance because
a Venus resistance is uh kind of like
like I said the body of a Pokemon or
Pokemon
being hit by the move this is
it's using the move
using the moon yeah
so to make this clear it says super
effective and not very effective is to
do with the move like what how the
Pokemon attacks so if I Pokemon attacks
or an ice type it will be super
effective and when it attacks aov not
very effectively gone fair so for dual
type it's hard to put that because one
time I'd be super effective one time
might be not very effective so it's
basically your choice of what move do
you use okay I thought you become
neutral if there is one type for
Humanity yeah yeah that's that's what
this doesn't
because that's a body you can't change
your body
ah okay yeah but but this you can choose
which attack do you use
this is kind of Defending you on you if
you use a fighting or fire or or
whatever so
you can choose one at a time right yeah
so and and the Pokemon can at most
Remember full moves if it says it wants
to learn a new move if you want it you
can replace the move by by the Pokemon
forgetting one move and learning a new
move okay so move is a skill
it's like casting a sphere
what kind of movie what can you give me
example what movie is that there's a lot
of the news like let's say let's say um
psychic earthquake oh yeah okay okay
so the move the different Pokemons have
different moves right yeah sometimes
they have the same move if it depends on
what they can learn but
not all of the Pokemon can learn all of
the moves
that each Hero has a four or five skills
and you can learn the heroes can learn
the skills customers there there's a
physical damage there's a magical damage
the impact on the special special and
physical physical is making contact and
and a special is is like arranged I saw
you at the other day the sniper the
Delta with the oh it's a gun yeah and
then it's a range attack right similar
okay okay good that's interesting yeah I
should play the Pokemon some other day
because it really seems really
interesting to me
how hard it is to learn how to play this
it kind of depends on how quick you
learn it since the um lots lots of types
and lots of parts to it so I'm not sure
how long I think it will be
pretty long how many a thousand eight
and eight wow that's a lot yeah that's
really a lot I can't even memorize that
much do you feel like I can't remember
all of them but but when you mentioned
it and then I remember it all of them
are in my head so if you say it so if
you kind of say oh I'll name some
psychic and fairy type pokemon I'll name
some but I can't remember all of all of
them okay so they are a thousand and
eight Pokemon but they are only 18
Pokemon types
yeah and they are two types that they
can you can mix too okay a thousand and
eight Pokemons there are some are due
type right yeah and some are singles I
see okay stuff like yes fire just
fighting I see I see okay okay so that's
good okay so what have you learned today
okay so ladies are fighting and you say
they are 91 Pokemon which are fighting
right yeah and then it seems a pretty
okay in terms of ranking where it fits
in a ranking paper it's the last time
the most strongest type is still is it
still yeah okay
so roughly which place number
I think it's 12. okay so it's just in
the winter it's kind of like yeah it's
kind of like
a two-thirds so what's next so we have
14 tests no we haven't talked about rock
right maybe next week we can talk about
rock
um
yeah I think we haven't talked about it
I have to check like this but the locker
is definitely you know to go one one of
the type so we need to mention okay
that's great thank you thank you very
much
oh yeah yeah frying okay thank you thank
you bye-bye