hello my name is Erica mango let's teach
you about rock type so rock type rocks
or Pokemon's make our rocks rocks
they're also fossil Pokemon The Rock
so rock types are weakness
to grass
water the rock is like a stone right
what does it look like
uh it I think it kind of looks like
weaknesses is like that rock type has a
very good defenses and and the stats
have a high defense so it has quite a
few weaknesses so it's kind of easy to
take them down but they still have high
defenses it has a second highest defense
average
start at the highest and we're first
place to steal and rock is the second
place for the highest defense yeah it
still is harder than the rock I guess
and then it's resistance
it's really listen to normal
poison
it's also resistance to Fire and flying
is resistance to normal because like a
normal thing can't really a rock
poison poison doesn't damage a rock fire
I don't think fire travels and rock well
I don't know applying come pick a rock
yeah Fire doesn't burn a rock right yeah
okay
it's super effective
against fire I think you can just Chuck
rocks on fire and then you'll cool down
um via ice
you can
crack a knife from rocks bug
s flying
I think we're flying I think you just
Chuck rocks and it's not very effective
it's not very effective against
fighting
another very quickly against ground
and it's also not very effective against
Steel I think it's for steel
I think steel is Venus is super
effective against rock and
rock is not very effective against Steel
so against Steel
I have a lot of high defenses so for
rock
um
we can pair up rock with
bug if you can't imagine a rock and bug
type it's basically a bug with some kind
of rock like let's say uh one bottom
rock type is shackle and shackle is
basically
it's basically what kind of shackle
looks like a a bug with a shell as a
rocket it's not a perfect drawing but
that's what kind of it looks like and I
think fossil Pokemon so if also Pokemon
is is Pokemon okay that came from
fossils and in Pokemon there's also
fossils and then you can put in the
machine that will turn them to a life
and and a lot of rock and I think all of
them are rock tops
so rocking bug type
is so that's a rock and back yeah that
guy
looks weird and this is also a rocking
bug type Russell
looks like the turtle then but you know
it has got a very long neck
this is awesome
available carrying a big rock it's about
a rock type called crossover I think
these are the crusts
bug is resistance to grow so it's not
Crossing beneath to a second so it
doesn't know the damage Rockets
resistance to ground
the ground there
Mark is resistance you fight in
fighting room is the star
Buck is in resistant to water steel so
we didn't put any of them there the bug
is Venus with fire rock is resistant to
fire so we put that there
bug is also means to Flying but rock is
resistance to fly plus one minus one
zero that's kind of how it works and
also the last type bug is Venus 2 is
Rock but Rock is in resistant to rock as
you can see
so you put that there
so these are all kind of it looks like
for bugging rock types
like I said it's kind of like the body
but for this one super effective you can
use full move so it's he so you can't
really like determine like like oh like
super effective you have full moves and
like the player can easily remove
your Pokemon wants to do so let's say
you can choose a type of move you have
like on the last one you have four moves
I think it's called the move set so you
have four different type of moves and
then you can choose evil for moves to
find the other Pokemon but like I said
it's your choice so you can't really do
this it's super effective because
because it is your choice it's your
choice of move so I can't really do this
rock is the slowest
of all of the types
because they're so heavy it moves so
slow yeah and it has a lowest average
and all of the rock type
stats rock type Pokemon stats average
speed is lowest is the lowest
so what have you learned today the rock
the second is that the second high is
the defense Pokemon type after speed
right yeah it's a good story still
moving Pokemon
what's next
flying have you done that let me check
have we done that
yeah we haven't done fighting we haven't
done
okay
here this is the 15th so we have three
to go so we have some grass we have done
some frying
what what's the one missing
have we done uh wait have we done have
we done Ghosts no yeah we can go see the
first one I know in a second
so let's see um yeah a few tell me if if
okay the steel yes Dragon yes Electric
yes fairy yes ground
good one
no we have none okay so it's a clowns
grass and flying and flying ground cross
and flying good morning for you okay
okay that's that's great thank you
bye bye