hello my name is Eric and I'm gonna
teach uh flying types flying types are
like birds and basically
things that are wings I think all of the
entire Pokemon can fly you can't have
wings I mean and not necessarily fly
like like a penguin
so I thought okay it's a penguins
there's no fries so it's not a fried
there's like ostriches and they're
flying type where they can't fly so it's
[Music]
two Electric
eyes
Rock
this and that's it
so for electric I think it paralyzes the
eyes that can freeze it
lock
you can throw the lock to it yeah it's
resistant to grass
bug
I'm fighting
I've been Grass Grows something like a
bug if I couldn't do much and fighting
fighting is on the ground
and also has immunity
to ground
as ground can do anything to find
because it flies in the air like for
example groundhog you because the
earthquake and earthquake doesn't look
like pets flying types it's super
effective
against the grass bug
I think it's the same as resistance it's
super effective
basically the same it's not like it's
strange or anything
because this is like my Pokemon
like the Pokemon
and this is the appointment
and then this is this is all you need to
know
if the payment is attacking you this is
all you really need to know oh and that
too but this is the opposite this is
like the user attacking the
Pokemon but you've got choices because
you got more than one move so you can
choose your move that's kind of how you
win
I see
not very effective
Electric
Steel
and Rock
it can't do damage to Rock still
and electric and there's
132 friends have Pokemon right now so
there's a lot
how many in the Pokemon you like
[Music]
they only total 46 right in Pokemon
United they're all together is it yeah I
think so okay
and and also trying to
highest
speed
yeah yeah of course it's right yeah
so I do type I'm gonna do is flying in
the seal but if you in case you can't
imagine the flying on Steel type Pokemon
uh I'll go live through a fun type I'm
still tired is covering there's
um there's a Quebec night
okay sounds like coffee that 19th
okay
and they're both dealer see
Ryan's theater is this camera I'm just a
little girl's coming is the kind of like
a bird
okay a steel book yeah it's basically
still bad
okay so it doesn't matter so
look at this
so is weakness to electric ice rock I'll
just put it right back there
still it really listens to ice and rock
so we get rid of that okay by the way
still frying is the same as frying still
right it's just different way of telling
it yeah okay
and we put that there so it does normal
damage and steel is resistance to normal
so you put that there oh no yeah
hey
out of the resistance
steel is weakness to fighting and flying
is resistance so like minus one plus one
it's in neutral
we put that
with the right
yes oh yeah fighting I remember
you've got me I forgot
and we also put
four times with this resistance as as
four times resistance only works on
those types if they're like both
resistance to that time and they're both
resistance to grass and bug
but it is also a steel is resistance to
psychic
resistance today is also resistance to a
dragon
the distance the flying
is really sense to steal
is assistant too fairy the steel is
Venus to ground but is immune to ground
so and also if
weakness to fire so but flying is not
resistance immune so all means so
let me put that there
and and also steel is immune to poison
so let me put that there
for like this one
I can do this but for this part I can't
really do it because because it's kind
of like your choice like I can't
determine this move for like a daughter
you can just move or a different move so
it's kind of your choice
um which moves you use so and I can't
really determine what move you use so I
can't really do this
but I can't do that because that that's
kind of like my Pokemon that's the
Pokemon that's the Pokemon that's like
the Pokemon's 40. you can't really
change your body it makes sense or
choose your body
[Music]
so yeah
what have you learned today ah okay so
that I'm flying type the fat is the
moving Pokemon
and we also take a look at this the
flying sphere so usually you combine the
two Pokemons which has different
strengths and weakness
yeah
one can only have one type
okay so we have two more to go which is
the grass and grounds yeah
okay okay
thank you
bye