hello my name is Eric and I'm gonna
teach you about grass type so grass type
is grass like plants like Pokemon with
maybe with like leaves what does it look
like
I think it looks a bit I think it's kind
of like a leaf
greenness
is fire
eyes
flying there is poison
bug
not necessarily the best type because it
has five weaknesses is fire I find
poison fire burn ice
freezes flying birds poison
Ing and bugs like to eat grass like
caterpillars
I think there's like the Cycles like for
like fire water grass but and I just I
just talk about that
resistance
it resistance to water
electric electric
grass which is itself
around
water water
the grass
absorbs it
Electric
yeah there's nothing here yeah and
growth doesn't doesn't do it much
against
[Music]
so it says resistance to ground grass is
resistance to water electric Crossing
ground yeah then how about the opposite
like water is water resistant to grass
water is not very effective
resistance and not very effective are
the opposite so water will be not very
effective against Grass Electric will be
very effective against Grass Grass will
be not very effective against Grass and
ground would be not very effective
against okay and you're basically even
seeing the same thing as saying grasses
resistance to water grasses resistance
to Electric grasses resistant to grass
and grasses resistant to ground okay so
the opposite is not very effective okay
it makes sense
super effective
is super effective on water
ground
and Rock
it absorbs water I think
and Brass because the roots I think
and rock I don't know why I don't know
why it's super effective against Rock
but it just is
so the rock is not very effective on
grass as well
but I don't see in resistance so
grass is super effective against like
like these yeah is not always grassy
resistance to those I don't I don't know
why
you know if you're super effective to
something and that is something that you
resisted to right
oh that's a special case oh yeah I'm
trying to understand why Robbie seems
they're super effective but not in
resistance I think Pokemon
how one did it is is that the types they
kind of related to real life so like I
think grass is super effective against
Rock but rock is not like not very
effect not very effective I think it's
just effective because I don't think
grass like plants resist like a big
boulder or something
it's not very effective
not very effective against Steel
dragon
cross
others dead since we just do a coffee
fire
there's a bug
poison fly it's not very effective
against
seven so it's not really good for like
attacking I think it has a little
weaknesses no very like it's not like
the best type I was saying in the
beginning like five like there's this
chain
it's kind of like a chain
like this imagine this arrows like this
is super effective against that and
that's super effective against that and
that's super effective against that so
fire
is super effective against Grass
but you see infected against water
and water soon infected against fire oh
yeah that's uh that's how you make a
game interesting because you want to
balance the different Pokemon types
well that's good yeah it's like a
daughter yeah
and normally only you're in in when you
when you plug no like Pokemon you know
it's like for
live Adventure like most of it like
Adventures like becoming the Pokemon
champion and your status are a fire type
of grass type and a water type and I'm
gonna
um so I'm supposed to
show a dual type of breath I think grass
is like hard to like pair up because
grass has a lot of weaknesses here so so
if you get a bad combination it kind of
makes it worse so grass and The Rock
I think there's two girls and rocks uh
grass and one grass and rock is cradley
which is a I think if the fossil plant a
barnacle and I'm going to try to draw
here is like I think it's supposed to be
a barnacle
it's the animal plus flower animal with
a flower head
this means it does
um of a normal effectness and rock is
moved us into fighting
as grass it's not resistance grass is
not resistance to fighting so and then
it just comes a Venus if a grass was
resistant to fighting fighting will be
here we rub that out and then put it
there
do you understand
yeah kind of yes
so for the flying
[Music]
yeah yeah that's what kind of it is if
Rock wasn't resistant to Flying then
then we'll just stay there like rock is
resistant to poison
well
I may put it here
broke his resistance
Rook oh yeah this is a
thing that I was explaining so rock so
rock is my weeners to water water this
is n't a grass is resistant to water we
we rub the water out now so and now if
we put in the neutral
it as well as explaining before yeah
plus one minus on YouTube yeah
rock is also weakness to ground but
ground but grass is resistance to ground
so it becomes neutral
if it wasn't neutral
if if Rock wasn't we miss it'll stay
there like electric and rock is also
meanest to um Steel
grass has no resistance to skills so we
put that in
rock is also is this weakness to grass
and cross the resistancy grass so you
put that here
and rock is
resistance to normal
and we put that in
and like other ways this um
you can't really do that this because
this this we can do because and and for
one time we can we can do we can show
you what's super effective against but
when there's two
um when there's two times I we can't we
can't we can't do it because you can
choose what you're moving we can't like
determine what what you're gonna do oh
no that's how that's how you win and and
can you just pick two at the same time
you know two moves one move and one
Pokemon one move for another problem
that you just you just you know choose
two at the same time
although it doesn't look that way it
doesn't work okay you can only choose
one more at the time
that one weakness and resistant it's
just you can combine yeah you can do it
because you have your Pokemon
that's right yes
and your winner stays the same so yeah
we can do it
okay what have you learned today yeah
second last type of grass since it has
lots of this weakness and then nothing
left over there okay okay thank you so
the next one which is the last one which
is the ground type right yes okay thank
you thank you bye