[Music]
oh yeah yeah
so it's Salinas what does it look like
it's like
water and ice
I think grass because like you can plant
plant it at Water you can moisture and
ice freeze
okay last week we talked about grass
across the weakness is it is it weakness
I see okay okay that's super effective
and weakness
you can pay us right yeah like like I
say like grass is super effective
against the ground it's the same same
ground as weakness to grasp if
resistance is a rock
and poison
Rook I think it can carry Rock and I
don't know why poisoned because maybe
you can pop with them and it doesn't
and it's immune to Electric I think
electric because you can't really uh
electric can't do any damage to a ground
so this is ground it's not a lot here
and it's super effective
milk
deal poison
[Music]
Electric
foreign
weakness
and it is not very effective
they're not very effective against the
grass
and bug
and as an effect
and flying
and I don't think I'm flying because it
flies that doesn't really need
explanation and like always
every Pokemon has a weakness there's no
light if a Pokemon is weakness to a
specific type then it's bad because
every Pokemon has weaknesses and
resistance like this you can see it's
very powerful and these two types are
one of the most weakest types and ground
is not very effective against them
the steel is a
strongest type in the game with DC
Harbor most weakest type in the game and
the ground is nowhere effective and the
super effective against that
see sometimes my arm needs one of those
toys because like ground is number 50
videos like every type has a wenis and
grass is a good one for ground
is in first place for most highest
defense average and the 89 Grand Pokemon
ringer
I'm gonna show you a steel and ground
once you ground the Pokemon is Steelix
Steelix uh is basically a kind of
snake made out of rocks which is made
out of steel
okay and
so
um
Steel
if
that's my hard drive don't worry about
it
so both of those
go there like if it's one that's
weakness one type is resisted then it
becomes neutral
steel is weakness to um fire but ground
it doesn't resist fire so we put it here
if ground was resisted by fire it will
be here and we will rub that off and and
then we put it there
let's see steel is also been up to
fighting the ground both of those tires
are not resisted by ground so you put
put them both there
they're feeling ground type is is one
instagram ground is one of those types
that is not resisted by each other so if
you see a steel and ground type of his
wieners stick around
and if steel is resistant to normal
we put that there
is this in to flying
Steelers resistors
psychic
also releases it
um bug
fairy
dragon
and a steel
that's what I listen to still has a lot
of resistances so that makes it a good
dual type to pair up with which can
cover a lot of uh weaknesses and also
still is immune to poison so we put that
there
so this is what steering ground looks
like so there's also a disability
levitate of levitate there's also in
Pokemon there's abilities which can
which you like for example the levitate
ability
makes it immune to ground
so if the Pokemon had levitate then it
will be immune to ground immune can get
you forgotten immune means you're you're
you're able to like avoid the attacker
like right resist the damage and it
always become zero damage if I said oh
I'm immune to you if you attack me then
it will do zero damage no matter no
matter what you did it will do zero
damage like let's say earthquake to move
with the Pokemon with levitating it'll
do zero damage so desserts have a
concept of the Pokemon dying and respond
thing if it takes too much damage
Pokemon died
Pokemon at the time no like many at once
the maximum you can carry is six Pokemon
in your party it's called party party
which is the basically your Pokemon team
your Pokemon team is called your party
and if a Pokemon has fainted you can
send out another Pokemon
you could send out another Pokemon and
also there's different things you can do
in a battle you can fight you can switch
out to another Pokemon you can heal a
Pokemon by using an item from your bag
and that's basically it sometimes you
can run away from a battle for like a
wild Pokemon you just run away and from
your back you have potions potions which
he will like
a specific amount like a person I think
it does 20 super Pokemon 60 and Hyper
potion 120 and there's also antidote
which can heal poisoning
there's a ice heel which can heal
freezing like if you're Frozen you if
one of your Pokemon is Frozen then you
can use an IP landed and then you'll
fall out
and also there's this item revive which
you can put on the Pokemon and a fainted
Pokemon and then your respawn but it
wouldn't go too Max Health it'll be like
half and there's also Max revive like
you can put them on the Pokemon and then
they will restore to full health there's
also this move in I think it's
introduced in year 9 which is a new gen
uh which I think is like there's this
Pokemon called Hound Stone which is the
ghost dog and it has um it didn't move
which is called last respect and it does
the amount of damage depending on how
much Pokemon
of your party has died
hasn't been fated so let's say zero
Pokemon have been fated then you'll do
50 damage and if all five Pokemon the
maximum is five Pokemon has been fainted
because the maximum is six and
houndstone can't be fainted to use the
move so the maximum is five and which
will do uh and if all of your Pokemon
has been painted a step on a hamster
then you use last respects then you'll
do 300 damage
so what have you learned today the
ground type the last type so we cover
all the types so what's next okay so
we're going to talk about the Mega
Evolutions
what's it about it's about every
into another Pokemon and then you can
evolve again and then sometimes there's
a Pokemon which can't evolve and
sometimes they put one with any two
evolutions and sometimes it was free and
sometimes we have a different Choice
like depending like let's say Evie has
eight different
eight different Evolutions he can evolve
to any of them and you and to evolve to
evolve it you can you have to do a
specific thing like level up to like
let's say 40 I don't know use a use a
stone and maybe level up level bar
30 night time maybe trade maybe Stones
evolutionary stones
okay good okay so looking forward to it
I saw you meant that the biology
Evolution will come from monkeys okay
okay thank you bye-bye bye