hello everyone I'm Derek and I'm going
to teach about Pokemon Mega Evolution
so
so normally in Pokemon there's there's
Evolution country is like how we evolved
from monkeys
do we yeah okay yeah monkeys evolved
into humans
so like evolution is permanent like we
can't turn back to monkeys
in only for evolution you have to to
evolve you have to come like mostly it's
mostly you have to to evolve yeah I have
to do like something like like it's
mostly a level like if you're this
certain level you will evolve but you
always can stop the evolution you also
can stop the evolution from happening by
pressing the B button from the remote
control or not anyway I'm not telling
you how to play a video game I'm just
telling you how it really works
and you also can let a person a voice
every two people normally do you
evolveware Pokemon it gets stronger and
then it has the higher stats and and
then you can learn more moves and then
it comes more powerful but you also can
put some like high friendship you also
can involve but also you have to evolve
Pokemon by high friendship you don't
have to evolve a Pokemon with birthday
but and four Pokemon like Eevee Evie can
evolve into a to different forms so far
it can evolve to Flareon Jolteon
Vaporeon Leafeon Glaceon espion
Umbreon and Sylveon each have a
different type
it only can evolve into one of them or
you can not let it evolve
so like I said you don't have to evolve
with Pokemon let's see in the generation
like let's say this this Pokemon like
Onyx and and Onyx was uh had no
Evolution you also can get Pokemon which
doesn't evolve and doesn't have any
evolution
so it just stays as it is and in
generation one it didn't have any
Evolution and in Gen 2 they added
Steelix which was a
Steelix which was onyx's evolution is
like it when I was talking about ground
type I was using the example Steelix if
you remember I'm not sure if you
remember that but now you do yeah and
also you can have a Pokemon there's this
item called evolite you can put it on a
Pokemon which can evolve which can
evolve which hasn't evolved
to its final stage
and you're comfortable another problem
with no Evolution and and then you read
the special defense of a defense of a
Pokemon which can still evolve
okay
so so for media Evolution Mega Evolution
is temporary so the first formica
Evolution you need a keystone and the
mega evolution stone with it so one
thing is this is a trainer
and this is a Pokemon
how do I make it more like a yes a
trainer
hat with a Pokeball
and a backpack
the key thing is they're Pokeball right
whoever gets their book cover become a
trainer if
and as a Pokemon Pokemon is actually not
like that so this trainer
has to have a keystone
it kind of looks like this
is an item you have to have it like in
its back any Pokemon can have a can hold
only one item
Pokemon only can hold one item or zero
items for Pokemon to mega evolved the
trainer needs a keystone and and the
Pokemon needs a mega evolutionary stuff
stand you have to hold the diamond get
evolutionary stone that Pokemon must
hold uh hold a stone which is kind of
like this
it doesn't really look any different but
this one this one has color and that one
doesn't well it supposedly has color
well the color thing
for coffee this is kind of like a marble
well it's not actually a marble so this
Stone this Stone there's other Stones
there's different stones and this
Pokemon has to have its own Stone you
can't give it another Pokemon's Mega
evolutionary Stone and because it
wouldn't work so let's say this Pokemon
was um let's see
what's easy to draw
a b Grill
V drill is basically a bee
like that
if antennas
filling point is this has a stone kind
of like as a stone with like kind of
purpley outside
this part is purple and this has like
black
and this line in the middle is yellow is
for that
is for that Pokemon is a bibra
and let's see let's take another Pokemon
um we can take a Gengar
foreign
like that I'm not talking about like the
drawing I'm talking about the Mega
Evolution so this guy have
uh also has a standard like purpley
outside I think it's more blue and this
guy also has a
right inside ever had they had red
inside instead of yellow you can't give
this Gengar has to hold this to to Mega
Evolve and this has to hold this to Mega
Evolve this Pokemon has to hold this hit
this and this trainer has a whole disc
but you can't give a Beedrill a Gengar
up Ginger right and you can't give a
Gengar a big relied
that's what the mega evolutionary stones
are called it is normally called with an
eye
so this is a bigger light and that's a
Gengar right so you have to hold this
when the mega evolves you only can make
it evolve one Pokemon in the battle you
can't evolve two Pokemon
Mega Evolve two Pokemon because I think
it's because of this Keystone
and when you make a Volvo if that's
increased which makes it very which it
makes it even more powerful and it has
and it's mostly have different abilities
I think they only have one ability for
Pokemon sometimes they they can have
more than one ability and it has to have
one ability it's like a chance to have
disability and turns it has disability
so Mega Evolve problems have different
abilities and mega evolved Pokemon has
like one one like Gengar make a Gengar
have Shadow tag which prevents the
problem from switching or which is like
fleeing
and this mega b Grill has
um adaptability which makes the moves
moves of its same type powerful if you
don't understand like this video is a
bug and poison type so it will boost the
bug and poison type moves in the battle
you also can return your mega evolution
and send it out and it will still be
mega evolved and like some other things
like down next Pokemon when you return
Dino Pokemon and then you send the
number and then eventually you send it
out again and then it won't have uh it
won't be dominant ax when you make a
bowl of Pokemon it's always going to get
involved in the battle but after the
battle a good one goes back to its
original form
so it is temporary
so
if you have any questions okay so that
Visa evolution is that it's permanent so
in the game Pokemon I mean is it also
prominent no for the Mega Evolution is
temporary uh okay so what is spoken
other Evolution like like this is
when they put on the balls it needs to
like go up to this level evolutionary
Stone high friendship or have to use
just moves at certain times
and that's kind of like any other stuff
it needs to have a nervous
Weedle
looks like a caterpillar yeah yeah it is
a caterpillar okay
and and then because this is the B and
this and this is a cocoon
and it's called cocoon Weedle Kakuna and
region
if this is supposed to be a cooking I
think it's like level five elbow
I think and this is level 10.
perfect
so it also can stop it
you can let a Pokemon evolve and you can
and you can stop an evolution you don't
have to evolve a Pokemon if you want to
so you can stop it
it's not like you have to have to evolve
a Pokemon when it's on the evolution
let's go it says oh
okay your what is like what when your
Pokemon is evolving whatever Pokemon is
evolving and and then this says
something like congratulations deal
your Pokemon evolves into a wild Pokemon
is it like the level up thing yes it's
not always
and then it's
so there's something is like level 25.
25 I think and this is you have to trade
foreign
between you there's two people playing
playing the game or like console to play
a Pokemon game and then you trade and
then you'll have to try to do a Haunter
and then wherever Haunter has been
traded the other person who has been
trading with you for haunted will evolve
there's also evolutionary stones
so like Evie
this Evie I'm just going to draw his
face finally so it can evolve into eight
different forms for
each stove
there's a firestone uh Thunderstone and
a water stone
is for the First Republic
for Firestone Evie is a normal type and
full Varian is gonna be a fire type
is a fire type Pokemon
a fire type and then fire time which is
called Flareon water type from a water
stone uh electric type of electric from
the forgotion for um Leafeon you need to
level up near a Morsi Rock I think I
bought a Glaceon you need you need to
level up near uh icy Rock
for espion you need to have high
friendship in the daytime which is a
psychic type refill in the grass type
and Glacier only the eyesight and what
I'm really need is a dark type and you
need to have high friendship in the
night
for uh Sylveon you have to have high
friendship while knowing a fairy timing
fairytale means that Evie can learn is
like baby doll eyes
I feel like charm I think I'm not sure
if I can learn playgraph so if you want
to like to Umbreon your Eevee mustn't
have a fairy time moves always it will
automatically go to seal field instead
of Umbreon
and if you want to roll to Espeon
you need to have high friendship without
a fairy time with always it goes through
Silverado instead of svl ambiance
so what we learned today Mega Evolutions
this is something new so all Pokemons
can make a Evolution right this is
temporary
I mean like some Pokemon can ever evolve
and you need uh this another thing yeah
obviously and who can initiate these
process
the trainers all the Pokemons can do
make a evil yeah the trainer has to have
a keystone and just have to have their
own like this means this beef will need
to visualize to forget this mirror again
it's called The Beatles
okay they have to have both like if this
beedro didn't have a beetro light then
then it wouldn't work
then it wouldn't make a wall and you
have to find it didn't have a keystone
then it wouldn't work okay so in the
process of Mega Evolution can it be
interrupted or cannot be abandoned in a
in a meter weight
no no I want to say it's initialized it
has to finish
and can it reverse I mean
no it can't it can't reverse you
it goes back to its original form after
the battle
when you mega evolving Pokemon in a
battle it's always Megan evolved in the
battle
and and after the battle it'll go back
to his original I see that's why it's
temporary okay
okay thank you thank you bye-bye