hello my name is Eric and I'm going to
teach you about Diamond neck thing
so from that thing is the thing in
generation eight and in sword and shield
so if you don't know if you need this
time next brand and uh this we can stop
what's Timex I mean how do you spell it
like that
okay this is new it basically
like Malaga Pokemon have at most full
moves it could have three two one and it
removes change so it depends on what
type it is
and and you're changing to a certain
move so obviously they're gonna be some
tumors which become the same time next
move
so the first is Max strike
any normal type attacking move so this
is normal
let's just put it as a table
and this is going to be the additional
facts so
foreign
strike is it
lowers but
lose the speed
all the other opponents
so the next one is
I don't think we have to pay for like 18
so
is Max there
is there any fire time we will turn to
max player it will summon
in harsh sunlight five housemates are
raised by 50 and water timers are
decreased by 50 percent and in rain it's
basically we always say water Titan is
increased by 50 Cents still type
yeah so two times still have to choose a
move and all the moves have a certain
type
of water
is Max geyser
some someone's rain
next
Electric
is Max lightning
which summons the electric green looks
like it's like the art in Dota is it the
ultimate skills it's not really Earth
and I'm just going to tell you like all
of this because we'll be here forever
the grass one
is a Max overgrowth
we summoned but
grassy Terrain
poison
Max is
what to lose
eyes Max hailstorm
fighting
next knuckle
I don't think we have a space on the
Whiteboard to squeeze those 18 types
one two three four five six seven eight
nine halfway there yeah yeah we can
squeeze it like this okay yeah maybe we
can some more space on the right okay so
you haven't answered me what's messed
what does it mean
is a move
okay this is the name of the move yeah
okay it's quite abstract
a Max what's the one under the max
imum
this one
of them how about those additional
effects you haven't put any on the last
five this one is grassy Terrain
this one is really special attack
this one always attack
special defense hail storm okay
I'm not gonna write that down because
that would take for like yeah okay and
also you have some more space because
more
stuff well that's what I think yeah
we're flying
is Max ice cream
so for psychic
is Max mind Stone
oh
bug
is Max Flutterbye
I'll just squeeze you on one
Rock
mix
rock or
this one is dragon
Max
[Music]
Darkness
Steel
Spike
and finally fairy which is
next
Le they're only 17 there is one more
missions I think
oh yeah ghost oh
thank you Max
Anderson
some
and also for every stated movie status
means are like protect like sources and
sleep powder and all of those become Max
guards
so
so basically when you dominate the
Pokemon becomes bigger and and then the
Diamondbacks is only for three turns and
then he'll become its original size
is there a cooldown for that
you only can use it once in a battle if
the original Pokemon uses protect or
detect it takes a little bit of damage
you're not fully protected by the
Diamondback moves but for Max card it
protects it from everything even the
dominant and download the last for three
times
and unless it's already died it just
becomes original and and if you return a
dark next Pokemon and you send it out
you'll it'll be not done mixed
um what have you learned today okay so
this the time Max is the kind of like
level up in the battle and can be only
used once so it becomes stronger right
yeah yeah it sounds bigger figures means
stronger
okay that means that in every Pokemon in
the battle should do this time maximum
well you don't have to down next
very interesting it just last for three
turns and then it's only once per
beta Okay so
is there a counter to that well
for like a counter I think it's more
like a typing not really like what's
accounted to a diamond X it depends on
what the time next Pokemon is because
the Pokemon which is dime next is
basically uh that Pokemon but strong is
and the type of that Pokemon is still
the same so you can just use like
but you can go like down next Pokemon
against another next Pokemon
okay okay thank you great thank you very
much bye
foreign