hello America I'm gonna teach you about
math sliding so interactivating is a
thing in let's put on skull and water
that like you can like you only can like
die relaxing
and Mega Evolution you only can
you can trust them at once
okay so time vaccines make it bigger so
what's this it's making like tarately
it's like basically like Chris Crystal
kind of like
it's like it's hard to explain it's like
kind of like Crystal make it Crystal
yeah make a crystal and they also have
this like head key and and which hints
about who is it's Terror type when you
trust a lot of it but they they also
gain a terror type and it's only one
territory it can't be dual type and it
only can be one type so you can get into
what one time let's see like
like a meowskarada is one of the
starters is a grassland dog type it's
mostly going to be is a grass I have a
grass territory and and that is primary
is grass type is grass and the evolution
before are just pure grass types like
grass and also you don't need to have a
there's such thing as a character having
a Pokemon having a terror attack which
is not noticed and time like like a
Pikachu could have a flying territory
when there's no flying type a Pikachu is
just electric it doesn't offline
also it will gain Boost from that from
its Terror type so let's say it's Terror
type is I don't like poison and then you
can get a boost for Poison type moves
okay
and and for different territory it has
different like taxes and and and it's
like and then you can know what what's
this character
at the same time
they're not in the same game so I get no
what do you mean not in the same because
die next thing is is in sword and shield
and trializing in
in Scotland violet
and it's kind of violet there isn't done
nothing and then sword and shield there
is into asphalizing
I see okay okay and then both of them
there is a Mega Evolution so before you
ask okay yeah we also talk about make a
little Evolution okay so I see so the
Pokemon is like different games and you
can't mix
the skills set but you don't need to die
an actual trash size or
Omega rub or whatever because you also
have a
problem you don't need to do that till
like win there's this like Terror race
in sword and shield there there were
dinosaurs and down next race you battle
with three other people and then against
a down next Pokemon and then you and
then you fight yeah and then and then
you have the Killer and then and then
you can catch it or you don't have to
catch it you don't have to catch it so
but you can catch if you want and in
draculating you can go to this Terror
race which are basically like a bunch of
crystals so
and then you can battle a
terrestrialized Pokemon and I think with
terrestrialized Pokemon is uh now I'm
not with Terror type is random so so you
can get a Pokemon with a completely
different Terror type two which is usual
sometimes you can get Pokemon with
Terror attacks with with Terror types of
which they don't have a move for it like
let's say uh you have a cloth Style with
a terror type flying it doesn't have a
flying type mode so it won't get boosted
so that's why uh they I think that's why
they made a move called Terra Blast so
if I were to to rasterize a class higher
into flying type and then use Terra
Blast Terror blast will become a flying
time move and then that will become
boosted it doesn't change his music and
it still is basically still the same but
just like if the appearance is different
and one move is boosted and I'm not
saying my king is type
changes type what do you mean so it
could be from water to park okay yeah
you can get them from like terrorists
but sometimes they're the same I see
okay interesting okay and in case you in
case you want to learn like what it what
like what I hate you look like
um
I'm gonna draw example like ghosts okay
so so it had a hair give like this
it was that and then
something like that no okay okay
and then I just have that on his head
and the negative
it also has a mouth
better yeah
nice okay and if I type we have like a
chandelier when it says uh water type
will have like a water spout a graph
style will have uh flowers on his head
and and about type will have
will have antennas a Steel type will
have an ax on its head uh a dragon tie
will have a dragon's head on it electric
type will have a lightning bulb on it uh
a Fairy Type will have a heart on it a
ground type will have
a I think a ground type will have like
oh yeah we'll have like like half of
like with Earth and then clocked on its
head
okay okay interesting okay
so what have you learned today okay
I can't pronounce this word okay but it
seems interesting okay so what's next
[Music]
good okay thank you thank you bye-bye
bye