hello my name is Eric and I'm going to
talk about Evie so EV stands for effort
values and in in Pokemon so Evie's is
basically what you get from like
battling a Pokemon uh every every
Pokemon drops like different Eevee
different EVS don't drop like the same
EVS I think the maximum EV they can drop
is free so you can get HP EVS attack EVs
and all of the stats EVS
I'll be added to you a Pokemon's stats
so depending on what Pokemon you like
the velocity if a maximum amount of EVS
you're a Pokemon can get is
510 EVS it takes quite a long time to
like even train them a lot they only can
get 255 maximum in one of that
by the time your Pokemon
reaches level 100 every four EVS will be
one point added two you start
but I definitely until a little 100 it
when you start like low level you don't
see it like added to your stats right
away
so since there's only four EVS as it
makes one stats
one point I mean is
255 isn't divided by divisible by four
so it's only useful to get 252 EVS EVS
which will be 63 points and the last
three if you get them will be wasted
okay and then there's also like vitamins
for TV
EVS which are 10 10 points no 10 EVS to
to depending on What vitamin is it so HP
up as 10 EVS to the HP stats
uh protein I had 10 attack EVS
and I went as 10 defense EVS
and calcium as
10 special attack EVS zinc as
special defense EVs and
something called carbos at
10 EVS to speed
since there's only you only can get 510
EVS in one Pokemon there's these like
berries
team which is
can refuse for
um EV so you can get like maximum on
others thank you bye-bye bye bye