hello my name is Eric and I'm gonna
teach you about family time and fairy
types are kind of like like in English
like fairies like you have like fairy
tales so it's
super effective
[Music]
it's super effective against
dragon
dark
I do
for Dragon normally in fairy tales I
guess I guess that's kind of a dragon
pair somewhere I don't know and not
normally because I don't I don't know
what happens in fairy tales but very
very Tales like kind of
it it's a based on fairy and very super
effective Dragon Dark fire
so I just we know
his weakness is
for steel
and
I I think it's kind of like steel is
kind of like a night in fairy tale night
and I don't know what's with poison very
can be poisoned yeah
how about a ghost type
yeah so dancing
okay
so it's resistance
is resistance to
Very Yes resistance here yes
like oh oh it doesn't do much really I
have really sensory bug fighting
foreign
[Music]
defeat the Dragon
and okay so why the dragon appears in
new emu and Super 8 defective how do we
interpret this
things and
these are kind of like these are kind of
like defensive like like the type itself
and and how it how it's um
how it
um takes the attack and this is how the
how it attacks
wow they can open doors perfect
[Music]
yeah so that basically yeah because
sometimes kind of like is defensive like
fighting dog fighting so like like you
said you ghost and
and the fairy
it's one one of his stuff is mimikyu
I think I think that
I think that's like we only got some
fairy type there is like a non-existent
type combinations like fire and grass
and and rock and ghosts and so
so it goes down very the way we do it is
writing
it's no longer
it's not as dark because ghost with me
but then like neutral systems
and so effective
um ghost is super effective against
ghosts
like it
[Music]
and resistance and oh it means you know
more
[Music]
and dark ghosts
ghost is resistance truth
oh yeah
so yeah
okay can you draw a fairy thing
a flower
something like that okay
what's that fairy
okay
a fairy so what's uh next
[Music]
water yeah okay just like normal water
okay thank you
bye