hello and I'm gonna teach you about a
Steel type and a few times has a lot of
this is has a great defense it's more
like a Defender than attacker if yeah it
defends a lot of other types and and
there's more defense and if it
resistance
for resistance is
resistance to normal
still
sidekick
cross okay bug
ice
okay
that's good
[Music]
lion Rock I see okay these are not all
of the times
these are only one two three four five
six seven eight nine okay one two three
four five six seven eight nine yeah yeah
nine okay so normal is like a person can
like a person can't do much uh to a
steel boarding like that ah and still
doesn't do much that it's still sidekick
like it doesn't do much thing
Grass Grass you can't really make a dent
bug bug also can't make a dent dark
darkness doesn't do much I can't really
freeze it like
too hard for beak and rock if you can't
make it then okay and there's weaknesses
I guess Ghost type is fire ah oh yeah it
makes sense yes fire up and make it like
soft yeah yeah it doesn't really need
that cleaning but I think
okay
around
well we advertised which are not in here
I definitely need food damage it means
no damage and and none of these none of
resistance agreements affected and also
now I
oh
I mean
still also has a mean which is
poison
ous is fire yet obviously but I think I
don't know why but if I think I don't
know break punch it really hard
and ground to an earthquake chatted to
pieces
how about Ghost type
neutral okay we need to one two three
four five six seven eight nine ten
eleven two thirteen and the oven the
neutral neutral it means it does no more
damage and these don't really affect it
it does what is supposed to be but but
neutral is um a good good
Seattle water
oh oh yeah I forgot a dragon okay so how
many times are there like look like 15
right three four
here all together they are 15 so
there's 18 types okay so that's so
you're missing on there yeah
[Music]
10 11 12 13 14.
goes in
water they are 16. right yeah and also
also steel steel is super effective if
it doesn't have much super effective
as because it's not a Defender like I
said because it has a loads of
resistance super effect
Ive
him
Rock
ice fairy okay but you I see the rock
you put it on the resistance as well so
look uh yeah yeah it's also super
effective and also it's still the super
effective is like remove like steel like
a Steel type move is super effective
against these it's not like
yeah so
I guess
yeah one two three four five six then
eight nine ten eleven three
fifty sixteen and and 17 18. so
basically a little touch that on the
board right now uh but I see the rocket
appears twice yeah it does
another ice
so but why is it the same type or it's
not the same time it is the same time
okay but you count it twice yeah but
because this is the move and this is the
actual Pokemon
ah okay
this is
the moon actual Pokemon
hmm
okay
okay a little bit confused about that I
think I I got it yeah okay
I see I see okay so what does it look
like the Steel type I mean
can you draw I mean every week that you
draw something yeah
it looks like let me think
is this
I don't know
if
we actually don't know what's this you
look okay I know I know what we are with
for fire is oh yeah okay fighting is
just
the fifth
ah yeah oh this is the Fist and ground
is
uh looks kind of here okay okay I see
oh poison it
and these are the neutrals so if for
example if I want to pair still up with
ghost
deal
huh which is a steel on Ghost type is
like eager slash if you can slash is a
stealing this time also also red Pokemon
on on Ryan's and Ryan's cake last
birthday uh okay yeah I'm still still
good so
so fighting as steal his Venus to
finding is a meaning to fighting
because of ghosts and and we've crossed
that out
and
and let's see no more
it's it
no one has no effect
and psychic
grass
bug
dark dark
now that need to
neutral damage because ghost is weakness
to dark so we put that to Nature that so
it kind of evens it out okay good good
and it's too effective against
sidekick
and
and guess as low because because that's
all for good stuff
okay nice
yeah
and where have you learned today okay so
it's very interesting so what about next
week what are you going to teach daddy
about next week what time
I think I'm gonna talk about psychic I
see psychic okay so that the words
itself is it's just like uh what it
means yeah for example like still it's
the steel glass is the grass ice is the
guys love is a rock yeah and there's
different Pokemon of that type and also
it can turn into two types so it's kind
of mixed
okay okay good good okay thank you thank
you very much thank you bye
bye