hello my name is Ryan and today I'm
going to talk about this
is not perfect so cool
so on the circle
like that
there's a diameter which goes through
that part with that line is called a
diameter
the whole circle here
is called the surf ruins I don't really
have to pronounce it it doesn't really
matter
which is how long it is
half of the diameter
is called a radius
and part of the circle like this part is
the ark
to calculate how how long is someone do
you need to use
pie
I'm
um and Pi is the the letter P in the
Greek alphabet
foreign
like 3.142
and it is
3.14159 and T six five three five eight
nine
um we're taking well that's the disaster
for part of it okay it's good enough yes
yeah
and
and you can just use
3.142 which is special so basically you
just imagine the diameter so you could
just do PI
D or two pi r which is basically twice
the radius with because the radius are
the radius equal in the diameter because
it's basically half of it
and so if it was 10 centimeters you'll
just be
3.142 times 10
which equals
31.42 so it's like roughly
that centimeters of that part if it was
10 feet
and
um
also a semicircle is half of a circle
and you know we did pretty easy
this is the diameter of a circle and
a quarter of it is called a quadrant
cool slice of pizza yeah
like pizza
that part
okay
and
the radius the plural of it could array
the eye
just spell like this and the radii of a
quadrant is always a right angle
like that part okay
and
and or Circle
if you put a line across it not a
diameter it's called a cord and the and
the smaller part of it is called a minor
a minor
segment
and uh
the bigger part is called a major
segment
and also
um I need more space yeah
you'll use this okay yeah and remember
to wash your hands before you touch your
food okay okay also for the circle
two pie eyes the
parameters right
yeah yeah I know how big is this core
area yeah yeah is it covered in a book
okay okay let's try we talk about it
right it's pi times R times R right
remember High r squared notice I read in
just the first
100 did it and it says
um yeah it says three point one four one
five nine two six five three five eight
nine seven nine three two three eight
four six two six four three yeah okay
yeah and also I saw this tab which I was
looking at and it showed a million
digits of pie if I didn't want to write
all of them down yeah obviously it never
ends the pie for the important thing
about this place it's not a fix right so
they are Unlimited
the digits go forever and never repeats
right okay and and for the Greek
alphabet
um
the pie the uppercase that one is like
that okay but but the lowercase one
the lowercase one is it says it was this
which is normally what you use for pie
and you also degree also because it's
not the first one is called Alpha you
say
you said and it's written like that
simple yeah and the next one is better
yeah the last one is like Omega and it's
written like that the capital
and the lowercase was like this yeah and
the next one the old G which is like
gamma
something like that yeah okay
okay
so we talk about the circle okay and uh
what's the center of the circle it's
just called center right yeah the radio
is the distance between Center to the to
the edge of the circle and double it is
the is called the diameter diameter
diameter which one is diameter diameter
is twice of the radius yes okay the
radius is like that yeah diameter is
twice okay yes
better diamond
so and it also has infinite light of
symmetry
um
well I'm just showing the Angles and
that's a cute girl or two single reflex
and glue and right angle with it like
that
acute article is
which is smaller than a right angle and
an obtuse angle is bigger than the right
angle that's smaller than
180 degrees which is a line and the
reflex angle is greater than and it's
greater down there
80 880 degrees okay good that's good
okay so what's next
um yeah just give us a little preview of
what are you going to talk in next
lessons I
should always see you okay okay thank
you bye-bye