hello my name is Ryan and today I'm
going to teach you about being healthy
so keeping your body healthy is a matter
of staying active eating the right food
fighting illness and staying away from
stops and substance like that have like
ice cream
which is bad for you so you shouldn't
really eat
much of
lots of it but foods like fruits and
vegetables you can eat a lot because
they are healthy for you and normally
fruits have fiber so they could bring
along the food without them getting to
stop like a banana
and also you don't you really eat cake
much because they have a lot of sugar
and also no a lot of sweets
and also these are some foods that you
shouldn't really you should eat but
they're not a lot like eggs
chicken
and also they're like milks some milk
and um yogurt
and also I'm gonna talk about drugs
so annoying
drugs are basically
but it changed the way how our body
works so
Tom's indica's wearing some in a bad way
like medicines medicines
and also it's like addiction
when something is addictive it feels
like you're gonna need it even if it's
very harmful going without a mix might
make you sick and physically ill and
many drugs are addictive
like alcohol
because the fact which you might not
think are good but
yeah uh it can make you feel relaxed and
humbly
and also it can also it can make you
feel part of a group
but the bad effect it can make you feel
sad and or angry can make you do silly
or dangerously can badly damage your
liver brain and harder and can be
addictive
also Nick to tine
the good effect they can make you feel
relaxed
and can also make you feel energetic
but the bad effects that it can cause
headaches and dizziness
it's smoking
tabaco and badly damaged your mouth for
it Longs and heart and can be addictive
as well
also to be healthy you need exercise
but exercise means moving around doing a
particular set of actions to keep your
boat the flexible build up your muscles
strengthen your hearts and knock them
control or lose weight
and also using your muscles
using muscles
can
built a new muscle tissue tissues are
basically the stuff between your bones I
don't know why they're called tissue to
help with the work here making your body
do
so and also
working your joint strength with them
and helps them to move free more freely
and like when exercising you breathe
more deeply to take in real action
oxygen this strengthens your lungs which
are for breathing
and your heart gets stronger during
exercise as it beat faster to pump your
blood also exercise sends oxygen to the
fat stores in your body it breaks down
the
fast to release energy
so data like at what exercise is for is
that basically you could just say it
helps your body parts move forward
also you can have a balanced diet it's
not just eating too much of one thing
even if it's healthy because eating too
much of one thing it can make you sick
as well having a balanced diet means
eating the variety of foods in the rhyme
for all the foods people with balanced
diets take in all the nutrients they
need to stay healthy and don't eat too
much you think that might make them up
and help you such as fats and sugars
and also food pyramid is just this part
you don't eat right lenders but you
really and this is basically moderately
so you can't you don't need ice cream
sweets or cake
and all lollipops stuff like that people
don't like unhealthy
eat more literally eggs nuts yogurt meat
cheese and fish and milk
and eat moat you need to eat a lot of
fruits rice pasta beans and bread
well the little fruits are in vegetables
like orange
pear I don't know how to grow well
and like and also like there's cucumbers
for vegetables which are yummy in my
opinion
also watermelon is a fruit and vegetable
also pineapple
Queen 33 degrees you can use the
watermelon and some bananas on top
but not really
um so yeah
okay so how much is too much
how like a hundred
and what
sweets okay that's too much to be honest
okay okay so to sum up yeah uh eat the
healthy fruit
do exercise yeah
okay and avoid drugs
well not all drugs since drugs some
drugs are good for you like medicine
okay unless you have to like you have to
take the medicine medicine it's not and
you could only take them if they're
prescribed to you you're a doctor yeah
and don't share them or something like
if somebody took somebody else's
antibiotics it won't make them feel good
okay
okay good good thank you thank you very
much thank you bye
bye-bye