hi my name is Ryan and today I'm going
to teach you about the air and
atmosphere so here is a pie chart that
shows what are the gases in the air so
78 of the world are is nitrogen
21 of the world is oxygen and one
percent is other gases
oxygen is a guy that has no color or
smell so you can see nothing
as in here but you can't really see
anything and it doesn't smell anything
when animals breathe in uh they use
oxygen and breathe out
and then breathe it out and it comes in
like a different into carbon dioxide
what what do we put now carbon dioxide
okay so it's CO2 basically right
yes okay or you could just say other
gases since carbon dioxide is just other
and that's only one percent of the world
when people are climbing mountains to
high paths don't really usually have
much air so they bring tanks to get
oxygen
so they didn't really just like and also
simple when you're under water you need
a tank to go scuba diving
carbon dioxide and
is basically is basically just
it is waste from its way from the humans
but plants like trees and flowers
[Music]
so trees breathing carbon dioxide and
their wasted oxygen
when humans breathe the carbon dioxide
goes and the tree socks here and gets
oxygen out of it the tree is also need
the sunshine to do this right yeah
okay carbon dioxide is also used to make
bubbles in fizzy drinks
so
um and then when if you take it the
bubbles will go up and try to escape by
the constantly but when you open it or
go camping
and explode
and the bubbles go up
to go up
and they try to get out of
the place
is also used for some fire in English
extinguishes
that you used to get out fire
is most flames and it's safe when
burning electrical equipment like
like the found one
and nitrogen is also a gas that doesn't
smell of anything and you can't see him
living there 78 pack yes definitely
yeah and turn with the food and it turns
it bad
like Chris
potatoes meat
yeah
filling packs it
or food with nitrogen gas health and
keep them 50 Foods fresh for longer the
other gases are found in smoother Mouse
than oxygen nitrogen and carbon dioxide
some using
store oh documents in case they're full
of organ gas it stops them from decaying
like it's not dark you can guess for
disappearing
so they did kept this bit okay neon is
colorless but it's close with an orange
red one that when electricity power
through it it's a used to make bright
glowing street signs so
so if you like see a sign and if you
just yeah it glows
so you can see online and methane Burns
easily and it's sometimes used as a fuel
in power stations
so if you get a power station
and did the chimneys
like those
and I'm also going to talk about the air
pollution which is like about the
congestion chart that's happening so air
pollution is built up of Gases such as
carbon dioxide methane there's smoking
there and atmosphere small amounts of
these gases occur naturally but
factories cars offices and have produced
a large amount that the plan they can
cope with
and the these places it is like in an
open area
away from the cities
from the smoke
no the air pollination can damage well
like rivers and building like those
breathing difficulties for people so
they have to have like the medicine for
it
the atmosphere is a blanket of gas is
that surround the planet it is made up
of
layers of different mixtures of gases
the atmosphere Shields that the planet
from the harmful ultraviolet rays
of the sun it also attracts you from the
Sun Ray close to the surface
this keeps the planet warm enough to
support life
and there's all it's also in protected
by the ocean and the reason why
Australia is like a desert is because a
meteor hit there before and now there's
a hole in it so the sun just goes right
through
oh really okay
I see well that's new okay and
this is the Earth and this is the song I
have to say
here's the ozone layer
and this is the Earth's atmosphere here
is where the song goes in and then it
makes it warm and over here this part
which is it just the right amount of
heat being trapped there so it doesn't
feel very hot
this part is food
greenhouse gases the greenhouse gases
such as carbon dioxide so the myth or
gases that help to trap some of the sun
seed neither in a similar way of grass
trapping heat inside the greenhouse
greenhouses are basically just like
glass with plants
a build up or
greenhouse gases trap too much she's
closing the general eyes in the World's
temperature known as the global warning
here and the ozone layer of the
atmosphere contains a gas called ozone
the nail absorbs harmful Rays from the
Sun by damaged by air pollution in
winter and spring a whole form in the
ozone layer at the south pole down
harmful right through
so so basically in the North
um I made the South Pole
here and then this is north
South
east and west
the South Pole in winter and spring
which is currently right now spring
the ozone layer will make a gap for the
sun to
make harmful Rays allow go through there
okay so the black cap is that original
flare or is it is caused by the air
pollutions
it's basically in Winter Spring it just
Falls in New England
I see so the Gap is it good or bad
well I don't really know
it says it lets home already three but
I'm not sure okay so it's humbles it's
not good
I think so thank you so we talked about
the air air pollution the atmosphere the
next I'm gonna talk about gravity whoa
that's interesting I'd like to hear more
about gravity okay I'll fix this yes
I think I learned some but I forget
almost everything okay thank you thank
you very much thank you bye bye bye bye
foreign