hello my name is Roy and today I'm going
to talk about gravity so gravity is a
force that pulls things together this
pull is because object has mass the
biggest amounts only bigger the pool
only gravity is really bad object and it
is noticeable
so gravity
so if you don't know what I mean by
gravity gravity is basically
pulls everything down like
there's a tree and then an Apple full
sounded because of gravity
yeah yeah the Newton right the apples
Falls and hit the head of Newton yeah
the scientists
okay and mass is basically
oh heavy right yeah okay it measures in
kilograms the more muscle we can do
bigger photographs so if it is like
let's say
um a thousand
kilograms
or at least a million meters
which
don't really use
it will be more that it will feel more
quickly because of the gravity
the Earth's gravity is the force that
pulls everything towards the ground like
the apples and also this pen
yeah
when you drop something it will because
the Earth has a huge mass so the effect
of gravity is noticeable notable means
you can see it it's like you notice it
quite easily it's
and this is the Sun
and this is the Earth and the Moon
the Earth
I understand both have lots of Master
they pull of gravity is Big without this
pool if I move float away into space
so basically they're together the moon
circles are because of the poor gravity
between the mass of the Moon and the
mass of the Earth the mass of the Moon
is here and
so it floats around
here the Earth Cycles around the sun
because of the full of gravity in
between the mass of the Earth and Sun
like the moon and uh because the map of
the Earth and the Sun they're both big
so it's so cool all right
so this song and in case you didn't know
which probably you know if the earth
goes around it's have been a year and
I'm also going to talk about the weight
if it's up here
say weight is pulled downwards on an
object because of gravity it's a full
statue depending on where the object is
and how much mass it is on the Moon Moon
the pool of gravity is less than is in
the Earth because the moon had left Mass
extend it up
just so the gravity the gravity is less
since and the Earth has more since
there's more
this is more heavier than that let's say
I think that's nothing okay
if you're on the moon you would weigh
one sixth of will you weigh now you
wouldn't be anything so your mouth will
stay the same in space astronauts get
used to feed a night when they return to
Earth they feel heavier and they have
difficulty moving normally so this is an
astronaut
okay that's like one question
things the mass of the earth is bigger
than the moon why we don't pull the moon
towards you know why the moon doesn't
fall to the Earth because it
is a balloon
okay I don't know I mean any possible
reasons it's in the space and since the
Earth is pulling
and maybe the sun is also pulling the
Moon
no worries we can find it out later okay
the air Finders on both have lots of
maths so they would pull of gravity is
Big with Deadpool the Earth and Moon
would float away into space okay so it
will fly because of the
I see
a force meter okay
um
that's the fourth meter it's also known
as a Newton meter is a piece of
equipment you could use to measure force
it the strength of force is murdered
units is called Newton it's a named
after the English scientist so I don't
need to
yeah you've discovered gravity so it is
measured in Newtons yeah so it's n right
so the units and Newton yeah
and the force of gravity acting an apple
mass is pulling the scale down
so if you wear an apple
down here
it will full it will make this fool down
and the meter showed how the Apple
weighs in Newtons okay the gravity
gravitation new Fields is an objects
gravitational field is an area where
it's forced of gravity can be found
everything in our solar system
serpenterizing as it is with the solar
gravitational field
the sun currency Fields the planet
circle around it so because of its field
none of them could just leave like
none of them leave they all stay and
circle around the Sun
and the center of gravity is an object's
center of gravity it's the point on it
where all right same time it doesn't
mean that if you push an object up
supporting it directly underneath the
center of gravity it won't fall over so
if you're putting like a sewer lid
if you hold it here it will fall that
way so it doesn't but if you hold in the
middle
the middle of it is the center of
gravity and if you put object up around
the center of gravity is easier to keep
it balanced so let's say that build a
crane
is building and I hold it
if it holds in the middle it becomes
more balanced but if it holds it like
this it's not that balanced like for
spinning object to be spinning
balance it needs to be spinning around a
center of gravity so your plate spin is
a skill that involves it's been in place
around the center of gravity which is
very hard
so if you want to spin something if you
hold it here it won't spin well but if
you're holding them until it will Spin
and keep on spinning because it's
holding the industrial gravity
okay good
thank you so what's next
I'm not sure okay we'll worry about that
later thank you thank you bye-bye