okay
yep so today
come on eric uh i'm going to talk about
recursion
so tell me what's the question
i-c-u-r-s-i-o-n
recursion tell me what does it mean
i don't know you don't know what's what
does that mean
what does this word mean in english
i don't know okay that's right
simplicity properly please
recursion so
it's like something that calls itself
repeatedly
so
so for example if i define the function
yeah if i define the function
like let's say factorial yeah
you know factorial yeah like n factorial
equals n times n minus 1
times n minus 2 times until 1 right
yeah three factorial equals three times
two times one all right
so do you see this what's this what's
this bit
that's two factorial yeah and what's
this
that's one factorial i hope about four
factorial
equals four times three times two times
one right
yeah what's this
three factors yeah
do you understand so this problem can be
solved by solving a smaller problem
right
yeah okay so we call it
we can call this like let's call it f
function okay f
n okay so it's the
base case if it's one if
n is one
return one one factorial is what
one one then as we don't need to
write the errors but it's good to write
the errors
because you can say okay return if n is
one return one a has to return
and right this is n yeah
times
what's this f and -1
yeah look this is minus one we're
calling excel so this is called
recursion
look at it because now we are solving
this problem
by solving a smaller problem yeah
okay and now it comes itself okay
so so let's let's do this example f3
okay
so what do we have f3
f3 okay we come here n
is three it's not equals one so as yeah
what does it return so f3 it will return
three times f3 minus one f2 right
all right yes okay f2
calling itself if n is one no
right your f2 will become two
times f1 right yes
f1 if only was one then what we return
one
okay so we can going backwards two times
two two times three six so s3 equals six
yes any questions so far
no yeah no no it's easier is it
is it easy
okay so look what this recursion
look recursion anyway where is the
location happen can you tell me
[Music]
that yeah look this is the function we
defined here
yeah look it's calling itself with
another parameter which is a smaller
one right because we are solving the
problem with n
and now we're calling excel because the
recording is with n
minus one yeah so n n minus 1
and minus 2 until we reach n n equals 1
which we know how to solve it
yeah because when n is 1 we return 1
and when n is 2 it will return 2 times
f1
yeah which is 1. so we're calling itself
okay
yes okay do you want to input this in
the computer okay i'm going to turn this
off for a while