hello everything ryan hello
hello okay so today
we are going to talk about an
interesting mathematics problem
we call it inverse
factorial yeah
so can you tell me what is bacteria eric
i think you understand
factor yeah okay so okay do you want to
tell everybody no
[Music]
i think about factors
not exactly factorial look remember this
exclamation mark
yeah we extend hmr equals
equal 120 times 3 we're down okay
so now this is answer six yes yeah okay
four factorial
equals three factorial times four equals
24 all right yes okay so now today we're
going to define a function
def called the inverse
inv factorial okay i'm very hot i want
to drink
okay you can get a drink fatalia and
we're given a number n
okay and if the number given is 24
i need you to return four
okay if the number given is six i need
you to return three
okay do you understand so so let's let's
let's do it f just f f function okay
define
f f n so what i want this f
24 i need you to return
four f six i need you to return three
f f what f two
which is one f2 which is what
point two right yeah
okay and f one one f zero
zero nothing right because there's
nothing
minus one if it's not if it's not uh
like f7
even less no such number
factorial is seven then with the ten
minus one
is that clear yeah so any any sorts
how do we do seven yeah no no factorial
equals to seven right
all right
there is no factorial equals 7 because
you can't find any factorial
that would be equals to 7 right
now because because look 3 factorial is
4 bacteria right so there's nothing
between right
all right okay so any thoughts any
thoughts how do we do that
we can try right
what i mean is we can try and here
we can try this number until
we can try time it yes until this number
is bigger than the n
then we can't find it if it's all if
it's equals to n
we find it right that's the easier way
right
yeah okay so i'm going to do it let's do
this
that okay f
f n right
yes we we need to check at the end
if if n
is equals to one
do we do we return one right
yeah if n
is smaller than
one small equal zero or smaller than one
with return minus one because there's no
such number
factorial the factorial of this is
is smaller than one am right yeah
negative numbers they don't the factor
is always positive
right okay so now we can try
we can try from the two because we know
once actually we have handled it
so now we we try from two i
and then s will be equals to what
to 1 at the beginning yeah so what what
do we know
why this the factorial
is smaller length
smaller than n what do we do
s times s equals
s times i right and then we need to i
plus equals 1. you get it
do you get it look s equals 1 and then s
smaller than
this number if it is 24 okay if it's n
is 24
and s is 1 and i is 2 s is 1
x equals s times i equals that will
become 2
right s is 1 i equals 2 s will become 2
i will become now
what i will become 3 3 right
all right is 2 smaller than 24
yeah okay then 2 times
3 will become 6 right yeah
and i plus 1 will become 4
is six smaller than twenty-four
then times four equals twenty-four is
twenty-four smaller than twenty-four
now then what then we can do this
return because now the i will be 5 right
plus 5 will be 5 i will be now b5
so but the answer is 4 so we return
i minus 1 if
if s we can put it this way if s equals
n right
s will return minus one
as minus one so this is the same as
if s equals n return i number i minus
one
as return minus one am right anyway
yes okay that's one way of doing it so
do we get it
yeah that's a lot but it's but it's okay
i mean this is just
checking checking and then the
the man is here the men's
so to get it yeah or we can do the other
way
i i read right here this is the same and
then i write it in different color
different colors
maybe blue maybe blue is
no black
so look we can say this look this is
still let's have i equals two okay
this power would be the same okay this
part will be same and y
if n we divide it equals one bigger than
one
what do we do now we're going to try if
if n modulus
i can be divided by i if it's not equal
zero
remember not equal to zero then we
return minus one because
we found out is not a fraction uh
it's not a factorial then otherwise we
can divide it
and divide it by i we divided b
and then i plus one
and then f return minus then here return
minus l return i minus one okay
so how we can check here look we can
check here
we can check we can check uh
24 again we're using the 24
24 is it bigger than one
yeah if 24 can be divided by 2
yes yes so i don't execute this
and 24 divided by 2 now become
12 12 and i will become
3 all right 2 plus one
okay is is twelve bigger than one
twelve divided by three
can be divided okay so i don't return
five minus one
twelve divided by three equals four
right
and i will become four right all right
is four bigger than one yeah it's four
can be divided by four
yes four divided by four one and four
minus one
five okay so four
one bigger than one
what's what's the value of four i five
right so the answer is five minus one
four so four it means four factorial
equals
24. you see you get it now
yeah so which way do you like
which which what do you think which way
is better
which agreement is better ryan left the
right
right one which which which measure is
better
the one with black this one is better
yeah
yeah how about you because it hasn't
been good a lot
yeah it's shorter right it's shorter
yeah yeah are you sure
are you sure this is easier to
understand right because if i
24 if i given the number 24
i divide it by two and then i again
divide it by three
and then again i divided four by four
until it reaches one
right this is easy right like six how do
you know if
six is a factorial number divided by
two and divided by three and then it's
one right
how do you know seven is no number
because you can't divide by two
that's right oh maybe i look a is a
factor no because a can divided by two
but now it's four
right yeah but four o'clock divided by
three right yeah
okay so you get it right yes so which
way do you like best
the black one the black one is easier
yeah but this way this this one is also
okay it's
very opposite do you understand this is
opposite this is
you divide it but this one is times a
you i have to try
okay for this one for this example okay
how do we know if a is not a factorial
number one times two
two two times three smaller six smaller
than a
and times four twelve is bigger than a
so it's not a
fracture okay you get it
okay how about 25 is this the second
number
1 times 2 2 2 times 3 6
6 times four 24 24 times five
or 120 right if one is bigger than this
number it can't be a factor
right it can only be equal right all
right
okay okay good job so pick one and put
it on
your computer and the last thing you
know what to do say goodbye to
people say good bye
you need to say see you next time
that's it