go hello hello hello hello mr ryan how
are you today
so today we talk about an interesting
problem which you may seem
familiar you know later which is called
climbing the stairs
we climb
okay so look how many stairs are there
can you count
how many steps one two three four seven
six
six okay one
climbing stairs so listen carefully
okay so now you're here
[Music]
so every time you can climb one step or
two step
so you can first all nearly bigger
yeah that's okay you can jump here this
is one way and you can jump to two
here yeah okay got it
so you can jump here or jump here that's
it no more jump three if you want the
jumpsuit you have the jump here and jump
two or jump two and jump one
so basically you can jump maximum two
step at a time
okay so the question is to get to these
how many ways can you do it so for
example look here
uh maybe if six is a bit more let's do
it like uh
four okay if it's coming at these four
okay
so look you can do this one one
so it's one two three four okay
one two three four each time at the time
all you can do is one what what what
you can do one no you can do two
and four okay or you can do two three
four or you can do one three
four okay so how many ways
oh you can do i think four
one two
four okay one two four yeah that's it
yeah one two four one two three four two
four two three four
right one three four okay so there are
five
so any idea how can we achieve this kind
of problem
remember yesterday we talked about what
what
what's that what did we talk about
yesterday dynamic programming to count
the number of ways to work in the grid
from the left top left corner to the
right bottom corner yeah
in order to reach the right bottom
column
corner and where could could it come
from is similar
where could it come from look in imagine
in a grid
this is the target this is a destination
so before the destination well how many
possibilities
the of these previous locations how many
uh if it's three by three yeah yeah
for example you are starting here
starting at this point you can only walk
south
walk east and work south and to reach
this destination what's what
possible location can it be
before reaching this destination
um yes we're down
two okay so look this is the way to
think backwards
you see think backwards so in order to
reach this position you
you can reach here or here right so the
solution would be
the sum of these and these right
that's why we will roll a dynamic
programming equation
f and m equals f m minus
1 m plus f and m minus one
got it yeah so for this one i'm at stair
n
so where possibly the previous location
the one before or t button we're done
okay so suppose this is f n
so it could be coming from f n minus 1
or
f n minus 2 right and what's this
i what how many answers would be would
this be
so is it simply equals these plus this
all right yeah and what's this
uh what's this we we talked about this
before the one star
is f what's that fibonacci number
yes fibonacci number okay so look in
order to get here
you need to get here oh get here right
yeah
and then what's the terminal condition
which is f1
equals one right because in order to
reach one
only one way right yes f2
equals one uh
[Music]
before all the beginning yeah so how
many ways to come come here
you can jump two or you can jump one one
so it's two right yeah
okay so that's it f1 equals fn minus one
plus f of minus two which is dynamic
programming
got it yeah yeah correct because we are
we we save this value we need to save
the value by implementation okay
so to get it right right to get it yeah
look in order to reach jump to this
point
you have to jump here or jump here yeah
because here is one step and here is two
steps
all right you think it backwards yes yes
and then look at n equals f n minus one
plus f of minus
what's that fibonacci number got it okay
so now we
we we can just implement it very easily
look one thing
be fine but but the starting point will
be a little bit different
because fibonacci number the first one
is zero one and then here
first one is one two okay so a little
bit shifting but it's basically the same
okay
f n what's missing
okay then look if n equals
one return what
what one okay if n equals
two between two
otherwise return what
[Music]
okay so this is basically the fibonacci
number is that this
uh values are slightly different okay
this is recursion remember we talked
about recursion
this is in in efficient the
time complexity of this one is what
look remember we talked about this and
the tree each one has two possibilities
how many possibilities will that be
yeah and
why is that why is that not yet not yet
look
i haven't finished with it yet okay okay
f3 equals f2 again
f1 okay f2 equals
f1 plus f0 okay
look look f1 calculate multiple times
again and again
remember this three yeah yes
and a one square no no no because two
each
is it each end each n
chord spawns two so it's all to the
power of n
this is very in a very in
efficient but we can all we can put
something
to speed up to make it a win yeah what's
that
because we we want it must be slow
yeah so how can we speed it up
using a notebook yeah using notebook
remember we talked about this many times
no book yeah
no book okay and i now look up
if if end in notebook yeah
return notebook n right
otherwise value equals left and the
notebook
n equals and put the value into the
notebook and then return what
and look we don't need to please
implement this notebook
manually we can just erase it yeah look
we can just erase it
and remember the magic keyword remember
yield at are you cash yeah
cash cash this is the cash but from from
tyson 3.9
you can you can you can remember this
shorter one
add cache that's it
simple simple right so if you please
if you please in front of the function
and it tells the computer to memorize to
automatically use a notebook
to memorize these values given or n
right
so for example if you calculate f5
and the next time you're asking for f5
you will automatically retrieve it from
the cache
yeah yeah instead of calculating and
again
again right yeah okay so this complexity
is what
i just said it before oh and yeah
because for
if you want to calculate fnd
that's right if you want to calculate fn
and then
how many values you just need to
calculate f and f n minus one f of n
minus one each
f each n value each value each value
from zero
from one to n you only calculate once
right
yes so that's why that's how we make it
fm this is called top-down
dynamic programming yeah because we want
to calculate fn
so we calculate fn minus 1 and f n
minus 2. in order to calculate f of n
minus 1 i calculate f
minus 2 and f of n minus 3 okay
but f n minus 2 i have calculated so
this one i don't need to calculate it
again right
top down how about butter up yeah we
talked about that
as well
so in order to calculate
calculator fn right so i i i can
calculate f1
and then f2 and then i calculate f3
and here i get the fn right yes
yeah this is called what
what's the opposite of top down bottle
up yeah because look
you're circulating from the bottom f1
okay so how can we do this look
a b equals one one okay
for i in or you don't need the i for
in range one
n and then what what do we do here
a b what's the new a what's the new a
what's this is a b and i want to shift
it here
become a b what's the new a what b
b and what's the b c
no no what's the b what's in here sorry
b what what's here a b and what's next c
what's c b
f n equals f n minus one plus f m n
minus two so what's c
f n equals n
so what's what's c what's here what's
your output here
f and fb this is a this is b so what's
next
fb no this is a this is b so what's this
this is a this is b so what's this c
there's no c this is a this is b what's
this
n what come on
this is this is a this is b look this is
two this is three this is one four
fibonacci number nine
five yes yeah so what's this
this is a this is b what's this
hey uh yes i'm looking for this party
wait why why is it so hard
okay and then return return one return p
yeah that's it so which one you think is
better
this is butter up butter out
and remember we talked about uh
cash okay i'm i'm implementing again
okay define
fn and i show you okay
if n equals one return
one if n equals two return one
three two and return one
f1 and
okay so this is top down this is butter
up okay so this one in order to
calculate f
and i calculate backwards f minus one
plus f and minus two
this one in order to calculate n i
calculated from f
f one f two f three f five this is photo
out okay
so which one you think is better uh uh
it depends on how you like yeah it's the
same base the both complex pieces oh and
why
okay so
any questions so far interesting
okay you can say see you tomorrow bye
bye bye
bye bye bye bye