go hello hello hello
mr ryan hello how are you today it's
good
okay so remember yesterday we talked
about dynamic programming yeah we have
been talking about dynamic programming
for a few days
and yesterday we talked about using
dynamic programming to climb the stairs
all right okay so now today another
interesting problem
okay so suppose there's a street yeah a
street
a street i'm in a car no and there's a
house
one house two hours smooth
how house it could be on the street the
cars would just smash into it
they have to have yeah okay that's
that's fine that's fine
so suppose
suppose there are six houses and
for each house there are some money in
there
okay you know some goods yeah and we use
the number integer
for example to to represent how
uh how much money he has yeah for
example
five three two one ten
six okay
yeah yes and suppose
suppose a rock a rock rubber you know
the rubber
yeah rubber which is a bad guy yeah
robert
yeah and one one night very quiet
tonight he decides he or she
decides to uh drop
those values the goods in this street
in the house on this street yeah but the
thing is that if
he robbed this house he take this money
yeah and if he or she take this money
then the police will be notified because
then if there are two
to neighbor neighboring house yeah
if you took the if you if you take the
goods from two neighboring house
the alarm will be will fire off yeah
we'll be off
yeah yeah and then a police will come so
so you shouldn't take the goods from the
into neighborings
okay but you can't i could have done
that because i didn't have the key
yeah that's okay that's why the robot
broke into the houses
okay so the thing is that the robot
could to take at least five
but look you could take five yeah
and then two yeah and then ten so hold
together how much to get
so let's so basically you are you want
to pick
the the values the numbers yeah
the numbers but not picking the
neighboring so if you pick five you
shouldn't pick seven but if you pick
five you can pick
two or not pick two pick one yeah so
this is
17. can we have a better one
look we can pick seven yeah you can pick
six seven and one and six
seven plus ten plus six which is
what oh wait uh 33 yeah so this
is obviously better oh no no no
seven plus one plus six plus one plus
six
so that's how many 14. okay fourteen so
it's not better okay
yeah yeah okay my mistake okay and how
about
are there any better ones
wait no i think this is the
optimal one this is the optima yeah
okay how about seven and ten
seven and ten but again the another
solution will be seven and ten
which is seven but that's okay you can
skip two
okay so any ideas how are we doing this
any ideas any thoughts
using the dynamic programming since we
are on this subject use the biggest one
biggest one the biggest one
or the biggest one ten you pick you'll
pick the biggest one and then
uh the second biggest if it's
the biggest neighbor yeah then you do
this
so first third biggest third biggest
and then so your strategy is
how do you pick them so for this one
yeah how do you pick it up yeah
what's your strategy what's your status
is to kick it
you pick the largest one yeah and then
you start from the largest one and then
to pick to jump at
you you only pick these two or not
or you're gonna pick five yeah what are
you gonna pick
suppose look if if
if this is a all right leave it this is
right so you turn
and then put the second lattice which is
18 yeah
yeah and how about if i have at least
another 10 here
maybe no maybe i put this 15 here
then 15. 10
so you always pick the second second
largest i know if this is 19 here
i'll pick 19 15 then i'll pick
six 1956
okay so your strategy might work but
there are some cases it might not work
okay and i need to come up with some
some uh so you pick always pick the
largest one yeah
you always pick the largest one so let's
say 18 here
glasses one and then you pick uh
uh and then i put uh
what you get
you pick you'll pick at 19 yeah yeah
and then 19. what what's that
sorry no i'm i'm thinking of yeah i'm 20
okay maybe 20 here so you pick 20
and 19 yes then six
and six it might work yeah
it might work 20
you pick 20
oh well it's 19 years well
okay and then you pick 19.
you pick 18 as well no you if once you
pick 19 you complete 18 because they are
neighbors well how about if you pick
uh oh yeah no yeah yeah
so it doesn't mean that you could pick
19 and six
you can pick 19 and six yeah
okay so i'm trying to think about the
negative examples
yes what's negative i mean the one that
your strategy
doesn't work so look
so i'm thinking of you always pick a
knight the biggest one
yeah a biggest one and how about if they
have duplicate numbers
so which one you pick yeah
so you need three of them yeah i know so
which which one
are the largest there's no largest wall
there's 20 okay maybe that looks
19 here so what what do you pick
i'll pick definitely one of the nine
teams
yeah but now you might need to pull the
proof of search right
for example or 19 so what happened
can you pick four yeah you can only pick
three
so that's how many number two three yeah
because every other one yeah
yeah so every other one
okay so so it seems that
if it in this case you you just pick
every other one so do you have a do you
come up with some
genetic uh i mean general approach to
approach that
uh yeah you can
also search from here you can search
from this side you pick this one or not
pick
this one yeah once you pick this one
you're not picking this one and you go
to the next
yeah yeah so you you
start from the search definite search we
can do a deathless search right
yeah all right do you remember that
bfs or bfs also work as well so
basically the tree i start from the
first house
first half right i pick
this one is pick yeah and the next one
is not pink
i i'm constructing a tree so but you can
search it with different search or
preferences right
it doesn't matter when i pick
the one and the next one i will pick
pick number three but i cannot pick
number two right i pick a number three
yeah yes
pick one pick three
pick sweet yeah
pick one not pick one not pick one
and then i i what should i do with the
not pick one
not pick don't pick two
yes but so maybe we can refine this tree
to to not to just like if i only have
one and
pick one okay pick one so the next one
will be three yeah yeah
oh oh
you can do five oh
yeah yeah as long as it so so as you can
see when i pick one
when i pick one i can travel
to when i pick one i can travel to
three yeah pick one to three and when i
start from three
i can start from five okay all right
so but for this one so look because it
has a lot of
possibilities pick one and then i can
pick three i can also pick four here
right
yeah yeah and i also can pick five pick
six p you see this is very complex
all right there's no seven i know i know
i'm just giving an example so do you get
it
so look this is very time consuming
because for each node
you could you could the next note you
could be
any from uh if you pick the no i
so the next note when you are i know
yeah so that next note could be from i
plus 2
to n right yeah all right
so what's the complexity of this one
[Music]
so there are duplication here oh it's
it's very
exponential you know it's exponential a
and something
how many nodes are there the n and and
unknowns yeah normally
into that to the power of n yeah
yeah so look actually this is a bit
complex
look if you pick this yeah you can pick
this
yeah i'll pick this yeah
if you pick this look if i pick one pick
this one and pick this one only
this is not optimum yeah because i can
i can also pick this one why not pick it
all right yeah
so look at the tree has duplication so
somehow
we are searching some branch which is
not optimal we know
right because look if i pick this one
and the next one i skip three and i pick
this one this is not optimum because i
can i know i can always pick
this middle one which is more value
am right if these values are all
positive do you get it
okay so this is not optimum so the
tfs or bfs may work if they are the
number of the
houses are small maybe like five five
houses
ten houses the computer is fast yeah if
five houses five to the power five
it's very small number yeah look but if
it's 100 to the power of 100
this is a huge number yeah yeah i'm
right a hundred that would be a hundred
zero after after a hundred yeah maybe
maybe how many zeros i don't know
twenty four hundred zeros yeah yeah okay
so that's all that's a huge number the
computer wouldn't
be able to compute it you know
for for in the short time amount of time
okay so this search blue for search
we call it brief research does not is no
idea
so i give you a hint that dynamic
programming so
suppose i'm here at the last house
yeah yeah so
so does it uh
if i'm at this last house and then i can
collect it
yeah if i collect it
i can't collect this one yeah i can pick
this one
so so i i will compare to
if i pick this one if i pick this house
i will pick
pick i will pick
the previous location would be this one
right
yeah or i don't pick this one
i don't pick this one and the previous
location could be this one
do you see it yes
so look if i use fn to
to represent the number of the number of
values i can collect
the numbers i can collect at house n
yeah am i mm-hmm
so let's see f1 equals one
if i'm at if i i walk from the left to
the right
okay so f1 is representing the number of
values that i can collect from house one
to house n
you know between this range f1 equals
one
f1 equals
the house one yeah yeah because they
look if there's only half one house and
then i can pick it i either pick it yeah
yeah because if i don't pick it i go
nothing i pick it
yeah also will be house one okay
okay f2 equals one
so there are two houses so
which way the biggest yes we'll begin so
there will be max
of house one and house two right
yeah yeah because there are two houses i
can pick pick one or two it doesn't
matter
so look if fn houses so how horse you
will write it
okay i i look up
fn so if i pick it what's
what's the value if i pick it
and then house n so if i pick it what's
the value
f pick it that will be house n right
house n yeah i pick it yeah
yeah and plus
which value plus we usually
this bit what's this bit
uh so i picked the house end
and i i can't take this house n minus
one but i can
i can pick i can i can check those
values so which
this is the sub problem of which what
f as what look fn
i pick this one i can't pick this one so
what's this this bit
this problem f and and y and minus
two yeah we're gonna be confident look
yes okay
so i i pick this half and i can pick
this n minus one
but i can pick this bit yeah which which
is the problem
f minus two yeah and
maximum of least if i don't
if i don't pick this one so what should
i
what's the value if i'm not picking this
one
and what's this bit
if i don't pick this one then i i could
possibly pick this one and what's this
problem
what's the biggest problem
fn the house end there's two choice i
pick it
i pick it then the problem will be the
house n plus
f minus two yeah i don't know what
happened here but i saw i know this is
the problem like
the answer for n minus two yeah or if i
don't pick it
if i don't pick it then the problem is f
and minus one yeah because
i don't care what happened here but if i
don't pick this one
then the the maximum value i can get is
from this
this bit yeah what's this
dynamic programming equation so we can
just solve it we think this look this is
the terminal condition f1 f2
you know you know how to solve the base
condition small the smallest problem f1
f2 right
and then now we have n and the f
n can be divided into a smaller problem
yeah you see look in order to calculate
f n
we we we want to calculate f minus to an
s
n minus one so this seems uh
looks similar to a fibonacci number yeah
instead of this slightly different we
need to add the value the value the
value of the house are known
yeah okay does it make sense
what's the complexity if we're using the
notebook thing yeah do you get it we are
talking about the mooc
minimization what's the complexity
oh yeah when because they are
why is online
and then each for each house fn is only
calculated
how many times
uh how many times
we're using the notebook why are we
using the notebook
we are going to remember it yeah yeah so
for each house
this only calculate how many times
what yes yes that's why we use a number
okay let's try this
so it's simple okay
okay i'm going to write it okay look
define
let's say f4 function and then we have
the
house value okay house value yeah
house value and then
okay let's maybe just do the uh
value okay valuable right value
comma okay so the length n will be lens
all right yeah
yeah the lens how many houses okay
this is a list of numbers yeah v will be
like one two three
zero five seven yeah you'll be like that
yeah
okay and then n dance n will be one two
three four five so what's n here
what's the value and
what's the value of n equals length v
what's the value i went
blank how many elements left five
so lowest n five yeah it's easy okay now
we need to create a array okay let's say
uh dynamic programming array okay
dynamic problem
already equals zero initially for each
value is zero locally syntax
bracket zero but times we use that star
times n so what it means is that n is
five and after this
we're creating an array of five so we
which will be zero
zero zero zero zero got it
yeah so after this dp is this yeah yeah
is it simple yeah times n yeah
a bracket a bucket with number zero
times five equals this
okay yeah okay okay now
let's look
if n equals zero
okay we return zero okay if there's no
houses we return zero
okay yes
actually this should go here okay it
doesn't matter
if n equals one what should we return
if there is only one house it's once we
return
so which is v 0 yeah
v 0 is the first house if n
equals 2 return
so how do we write it return next
v0 and v1
one one okay now at least
this is okay and then what return
yeah the thing i want to pick the
maximum
of one of these two if i pick that
actually we are missing the parameter
here
we are missing a parameter uh actually i
only pick
pic k okay now it's k
so look this will be uh
because because it's not n so n is
how can we write this better
so look uh if n equals uh
[Music]
so actually this value should be put
outside
okay so so look if n
uh
[Music]
if k equals zero
uh k equals zero returns zero if k
equals one return
v one if k equals two return v to
return okay i'll fix the data again
return maxima if i want to pick k
i'm currently okay so the house value
will be vk
plus f v
k minus 2 right or if i don't pick it
so it will be f v k minus 1
right yeah yes
come on come on yeah okay so now
so we can call this is fv
then length v minus one because we are
getting that so we don't need that dp
value yeah because look it will
be going it will be the space condition
here yeah
so what's missing here if i implement
this what's the complexity
what's the complexity
because this is recursion we don't need
to let dp array but i can show you later
why we
we need it in the top bottom of dynamic
programming this is top down remember
top down because in order to calculate f
n we need to calculate
f n minus 1 and f y minus 2 yeah and
this is the equation yeah
okay what's missing what's missing here
we need to catch it easily
cache yeah
[Music]
actually you can just do cash yeah this
cash string is equals to
f a i u cash
now okay this is the same thing needs to
this is your
cache oh we can we can do this using the
notebook yeah remember
yeah yeah no book
yes no book and if
notebook equal uh if okay actually
if we move this v outside we don't need
to pass
v it's not changing this no one right
away the house
value is known so we k
this is just fk yeah got it
so if this value is is outside if you
want to reference it
we need to use the global keyword global
v okay so look using the notebook then
we can we can do this if k in notebook
we do turn notebook k
and then before returning the value we
save this into a value
and then notebook k equals value return
value all right i'm going to write it
it's quite similar
than yesterday okay so i'm talking about
uh
the okay um look i talked a little bit
about the python here look eric
define this is a function f yeah with
nothing
and if i want to print
uh array here yeah i don't care
m is defined outside this function area
equals
eight okay yeah yeah
and this confusing number look
yeah okay look this is not going to work
why is that
because this function is in the scope
in the stone different than this
but in order to use eric here i need to
i need to add a keyword global
globa eric that means i
i want to use eric and then print area
will be eight
if i don't at least how does if i don't
at least
this will print these will be
a reference it will be none okay you you
because if
this area only lives here yeah
it doesn't mean outside and then then if
you want to use outside you have to tell
computer okay i want to use the area
from outside which is i need to add a
globe
it's in a global scope okay yeah
okay this is one thing
on eight because you're assigning here
arabic
equals hey i mean you can also do this
look define
f you can put a value here n yeah look
come on and then you can print all right
okay if i do this look yeah
yeah now that's okay because this area
is this area and then in order to call
this you have to call this
f eric yeah right and then you will take
this arrow
value pass it into the function
then you put the array which is a do you
get it
yeah okay this is passing these
parameters
okay so previously this is that was top
down
top down yeah top down the left corner
if we want to calculate fn we calculate
f1 minus one and five minus
and the the other the other way of
calculating it which is called
the other direction of dynamic power
button
yeah so in in order to
do it the house is here i can just
start here start here and then i can
calculate from the left to the right
from the f1 f2 to fn right
yes yeah okay so
that one will be we love the recursion
yeah okay so let's do this define
i have and we have the houses and we
have houses okay so now again
we now we need to do this length equal v
yeah okay and then now dp this is the
value of dp db equals zero
times n so we have an array a way to
keep those values
all right yeah to keep a reverse value
and then
and again i'm not going to write it if n
equal
if n equals one okay okay let's write if
n equals
one return at return what
v zero yeah yeah
this should be put in the power
uh before that if n equals zero what's
your return
return here if n
equals two return
return max
yeah okay now this is interesting
and then we can loop it yeah for
i in range
start from one start from one
b zero starts from number two we
start from
uh start from two yeah two and then end
look we just return it yeah but actually
actually we also need to do this if n
and and here
here i need to do this d p zero
equals d p zero equals v zero
and d p one equals max
v zero v1 right
yeah so that array that array
remember this tp array yeah beginning
with the values i need to
update the first two values yeah this
first this
first value would be v 0 yeah because
the
if i pick the the first house i can only
pick one right
the second house that's the same value
would be max
of v0 and v1 right yeah
and then start from two start from two
start from two look this is the magic
dp i dpi
equals max can you can you say
it's almost finished dpi equals max 1
3 v i
plus 1 v sorry
i pick this house and what's the value i
need to
get i v
i plus dp1
i pick the half and then dp what's the
smaller problem i need to add
even better i pick this house and then i
need to
it's the the total value i can have up
to this point is
this house picking this part and the
preview is what
[Music]
yes and then or i pick i don't pick this
house and
which is dp1 and then i can dpi
one yeah okay so let now return
determine which value return this this
is the dp array i i calculated
along the way which value is in return
dp1 the last value yeah
because i the in-house i want the last
value will be the
maximum value i can get for this end
house so dp
db1 the last value what should i put
here
what that was the last value the first
one is minus one
we're done yes good job yes
so look this is bottom up
both of our dynamic programming we buy
we feel english already remember the
fibonacci number yeah
zero one two and we feel we start from
zero feeling that way
the previous recursion which the
notebook thing is the top down
starting from the the last one and going
backward this is going
starting from the beginning going
forward and then we use the gonna write
dp equals zero times
n yeah this is this checking and we feel
these the first two values dbz
was the first house yes because we can
pick it
yeah it's better we pick it if we don't
pick it we get nothing the first one
the tp1 for the first two houses we just
pick the maximum
yeah and and then going through the
third house
two third house yeah because in computer
it's not from zero
two is the third house and dpi equals if
i pick this house
then i can also collect the maximum
previous i minus two halves this is a
sub problem
or if i don't pick this house i can pick
the sub uh previous i minus one houses
right
yeah and then i return the last value
which is the
maximum value i can collect from the
visiting and houses
okay so any questions
any questions so far no okay
see you tomorrow no see you tomorrow bye