oh hello hello mr mr marlin how are you
today good good
good good so today we'll talk about
one problem which is called the longest
pending drum subsequences
long piece
[Music]
okay so what's the subsequence that is
another parameter what's substance
is in the sequence that can be
divided from another sequence by
deleting
some unknown yeah that's what they're
using changing the order of
the remaining elements whatever okay so
a b
c d is a substance you can delete any of
them so it could be a
c e yeah you can delete b and d or you
can do it
b c d then you become a basically you
can delete now
when you divide now is a b c d or you
did it
one or more yeah you can do one of them
it will be a c d e or a a
d yeah do you get it but the others do
not change
yes so basically you can erase
any characters okay yeah
okay so the longest subject is a
subsequence for example like
b b b a b b
b so
you can delete the a then it becomes the
longest subsequent which is bbb
and then you should give me the answer
for because you can find the longest
paragraph of subsequent is four and
another one c b b a
b b b yes well done so it's two right
you can do this c
and a yes yeah
so how to how do we achieve this problem
like for example like
a b b a c d d
e okay so forgiveness
how do we what's the approach to find
the longest subsequence
any idea you
yeah and any other one because you can't
have
eu right because there's no uh reality
so you need the
two e's dd yeah c
d d b v c d d
b b c d d
c d d where down yeah that's five we're
done we're done
that's good so five so when when you
have no
do you have any other approach
if you don't you can always start with
one approach
which is what blue force you know
first brute force
so what's blue force blue force is try
natively try naively as many pos
try try as all the possibilities
and then check each one yeah take a long
time yeah yeah let's
prove us brute force blue force approach
is very
intuitive right you can think of any you
can
the first approach to solve any problem
should be
performance then we analyze how complex
will be so
basically we can prove first we can find
or if if we know how to find all the
subsequence
yeah if we can find all the subsequence
and then we check if each subsequence is
a pending term right
all right so checking this pendulum
what's the complexity
checking a string if it's a calendar
what's the capacity
if i give you a string bb a i want to
to find gimme hop if it's a paragraph
do you still remember how we're checking
it yeah
this is really easy yeah so given a
string how do we tell if it's a
parenting job
eric you spread it backwards
spare backwards or use the two points
okay look
if a equals a yes b equals b
yes when i meet then it's a temperature
and how about this a b
c d a a equals a yes
b not equals t then we know it's not
planned on
simple yeah so we have two pointers
moving towards each other when i meet in
the middle
then it's a pairing zone okay so let's
complexity of this how many db
how many complexity what's the
complexity of this approach
o n right and
b b c d d is no yeah yeah i'm finding
the subsequent generating all the
subsequence
if i given a string i want to generate
all the subsequence
what's the complexity
so it basically you'll be the same as
given the end characters i want to find
all right so what's the given the n
parameter and encoders
remember i want to find i
i want to find these c and one yeah
picking one picking one out of n
plus picking 2 out of 10 out of n
right plus picking 3 out of n right
i'm picking n out of m right
and possibly you can pick an n out of
zero yeah which is
empty yeah picking zero out of m is
empty
so when you add remember this
combination
yeah do you remember three apples out of
five i want to pick
three apples out of five apples how many
how many ways i can do it
how many might be easier picking two
apples out of three
how many ways i can do it picking two
levels out of three
three three picking two levels out of
three
is equal picking three picking one
apples out of three right
and picking one apples out of three how
many ways three easy
okay so picking three out of five is
five times
is same as picking 2 apples out of 5.
so picking 2 apples out of 5 is 5 times
4 divided by 2
which is 10. okay so look
when you added all these together i
this is this is equations to two to the
power n
okay so the complexity o to the power n
times n so two to the power
and exponential is we generated
subsequence right
and n is the complexity of checking
if the subsequence is the planing jump
right
so all together the complexity will be
o2 to the power
n times n this is huge
yeah it's not feasible yeah it's too
slow
yeah all right so we don't need to do
this
we can use dynamic programming okay we
talk about that
so can you tell me what's dynamic
programming remembering
yeah the key word is remembering we're
done memorize
minimization yeah minimization memorize
so if i give you a function dp
array dp if i tell you
dv a b this is an array okay two
dimensional
stops if this stops the number of
the the length of the longest
subsequence between
index a and index b
okay don't get it okay so look d
p n any number n
n what does the angle
dv and n what is equal if the same dt
and n
equals one i need that the longest
sub uh parallelism subsequence longest
parenthesis substituting between
index a the left a and the left
the right a so it's a single character
so what's this equal
one we're done yes that's what i'm
looking for yeah
yeah yeah because it's only one
character yeah it's the longest the
index index is a single character is a
pendulum right yes okay how about
dt is a
b if a bigger than b
okay if a bigger than b this is invalid
right
this is left this is a big right if left
is bigger than right this doesn't make
sense
when we make it zero right if
a bigger than b i'm right yeah so this
a is the left so basically look at
a1a is zero and b is two
so zero one two maybe zero three yeah
zero one two three okay so a is zero
b is three here so what's this
what what's tp what's tv03 in this case
how many how what's the what's what's
the longest
subsequence depending on subsequence
here four
yeah four yeah you've got the one yeah
okay so this is interesting okay so
look if i don't know anything about this
yeah i don't know anything about this
yeah
suppose i don't know anything about this
and i have this
so i know a equals a yeah the index s
the s string s i equals sj here
right so so it means that so look
dp a b
what's the what's the relation between
dp ap and dp
a plus 1 b minus 1
which is this back if if
s a if s a equals s b
if these two characters are equal what's
the
relation between dp a b and dp a plus
one b minus one
if these two characters are equal
what's the relation between dp least
boundary
and then the one just just
moving each other just get rid of these
two what's the
relation uh
what what how how big is this what's the
balance of yeah two
but we don't know if it's two right
this is dt a plus one
b minus one right and this is
d p a b so what's the relation between
these and this
there's how many difference
how many different it's right there
sorry y is
zero these two what
come on this equal this if this is the
pending term
if i put a two same thing at both sides
it will be also apparent all right
what's the difference less difference
minus one what's the length different
two yes of course i
added two then it will be 2 right so
if sa equals sb dpa b
equals dpa plus 1 b minus 1 plus 2
got it you see
and if it's not equal what happened
yeah if it's equal we know it if it's
not equal
what's the problem look if it's not
equal
look if this is uh
okay i'm just dragging here okay dp
this is very important okay let that be
when it's equal
okay then if s a
not equals sp okay
look like this a b b
c okay if these two are not equal
so what does it equal what does the
equal
[Music]
because these two are not equal is it
equals the maximum of
least bit or maximum of this bit
yeah there are only two possibilities
yeah
does it make sense if these two are not
equal
then the length of dpij ab is equal to
the maximum of bp
a minus one and dp a plus one b
all right okay
so look if it's not equal d p
a b this is a bit difficult to
understand yeah equals what
maximum dp
a plus one b and one
bp what a and one what's that
b b y b a b
equals if if they are not equal if a
equal not equal c equals uh it will be
ep a a plus one b
yeah or a what's this
b minus 1
1 1 yes so basically look
look one more time look if this is not
equal yeah
then it should be the value of this
and this you see look at it
sifting one yeah
okay so this is not equal and that's it
we know how to solve it
look if we know we want to solve dpa b
yeah all right so we need to solve
db a plus one b minus one if s a equals
s b this is known right
or if it's no n not known we can solve
db a plus one b
and db a b minus one which is we've got
a maximum
right yes so if we solve this
db db a and b a's from
zero to n yeah
exclusive n yeah and b
from zero to n exclusive so what's the
complexity
time complexity if we solve this
equation
o and
what let to a and b
i want to solve this cpa b two
dimensional array so what's the
complexity
a is from zero to n b is from d l to n
[Music]
a a is from zero to m b is from zero to
n so what
if we add it together how much
complexity
a are they
and an end if they are n
a a from n to 0 to n
b from 0 to n what's the combination
what's the combination
what is f y is around l why not multiply
uh zero t n square
o n squared come on look for the first
for a is there are n possibilities and
for each n
i have b which is impossibility so it's
a
a times b not a b to get it
it's like a row remember you have when
we go from a to here we have two
possibilities
remember we talked about that tesco yeah
let's go and then
there are three ways coming home how
many ways all together
there are two here six is two times
three it's not two f3 okay
yeah got it because these two are
quite independent they are quite
independent you
multiply them together yeah okay
if that if they are the same you add it
together
if it here is the same you add it
together but when these when you combine
two things
you need to multiply the same here okay
okay
okay so now let's write the program
dynamic programming how many ways of
dynamic programming
how many talented performing we can
write three
two two what are those two
one is me by violation
recursion with minimization which is
called top
are you tell me what what is it okay i
need to put a
uh s here this is a string and then
uh from let's say a and b
what's missing okay
yeah let look e
if a equals b written one
yeah if the boundary is the same it's a
single character between one
one one yes okay if
s a equals sp
return y
remember the boundaries are the same and
we move it to each other
returns s what
return what dp we want to call this
problem
a plus one and what wait what's here b
b y hmm
what's that what's the least between s a
and b remember we talked about
if these how many more characters can it
what's this should i do something here
if a equals b even the string here a b
or b
and then it must be the longer than the
a plus one b
minus one by how many generators two
two yes plus two okay all right
yes okay then otherwise we can return
what
return pp the maximum okay
in terms of maximum vps
a plus one
i plus one dp dps a plus one
b and
[Music]
minus one come on a plus one b minus one
okay okay
okay that's it what's missing here
no no no not me there's one thing
missing
remember this is cash yeah without the
cash
this is exponential yeah we need to cash
the value yeah
just put the add cash and that's
recursion
with minimization which is top down
dynamic programming got it yeah okay now
we write the opposite
bottom up what's the complexity by the
way
we talk about it why is the way i'm not
thinking oh what
i want oh what
[Music]
squared again n times n okay yeah
because look a and b a the possibility
from 0 to n
right b from the possibility from 0 to n
so
you are actually calculating n
square values okay roughly in a sk
in a in a scale n square okay because
when a bigger than b we just return zero
we don't care okay
okay now let's do the opposite
define d
p s we don't need a b here right
so and we calculate the length yeah
if n equals zero if it's empty we return
what
return what if the zero string if it's
empty
z yeah if n equals one will return one
one yeah because we want only one
character okay now we need to create a
dp array
all right vp equals look 0
times n for
in n range n okay
so what does it mean it means that dt is
a two-dimensional array okay
two-dimensional right
it's a it's a way there are n
columns and n-rows yeah it's an array
two-dimensional array
magic this is a magic yeah all right
now i need to feel mean right for
a in
for a in range because we are starting
from
uh we can start it from n minus one
tier minus one to the tier zero and
minus uh
and from a from n minus one to zero
and now we need to fill here d p a a
equals one
a single character dba equals one
a single character
a single character the parent of a
single character
which is what dba one yes and then we
need to follow
b in range we starting
because a is defined in that boundary
and then right boundary should be
from the next of the left boundary
until n right all right so
range what should i put here
a plus one right
yeah trn
okay and here now we can say if
s a look equals sp right
now what should i write d p
this is quite similar than previous one
if s a equals sp
if these two characters are the same dp
a b equals one
come on
these two characters are the same what
happened
it's it's more than dpn
and what's the two these two relations
what's what's this so this is how many
bigger than this
come on i just show you two minutes ago
two yeah at two come on
okay i asked look as if it's not equal
then dp
a b equals one maximum of what
maximum or what if this a s
a not equals sp so dpa b equals maximum
what
bp y
a b
minus one minus one where yes okay so a
plus one b
or a minus one b yeah yeah okay and then
we turn which one
i calculate these two these are least
two dimensional right and right return
t p y zero
because i want to get it from the
beginning to the end right
what's the end what's the n
and a you can do n minus one over
minus one minus one right down okay so
this is the bottom off so now look
compared to recursion with my
minimization this is a bit
uh you need to write a for loop by
yourself right
yeah yeah but for the recursion with
minimization you don't need to right
because the computer will just call
itself to find those values for you but
now
you are you are actively actively
called uh computing
the values by yourself and then you
store it in this array
yeah what's the what's the space
complexity
we are creating this yeah and what's
this
our our n1
and square because look we're creating a
two dimensional array based on this
number n why
okay yeah okay so
any questions so far
okay you can say bye bye to people and
see you tomorrow okay
bye bye
[Music]
how are we solving it which agreement
are we solving it
dynamic programming and how many ways of
dynamic programming
two and what are those top down and
bottom
yeah we're done okay