in each integer in the binary right for
example 15 in binary what's that
1 1 1 1
1 1 1 yeah yeah how about
8 in binary
yes so so basically we count one one
there will be four and there will be one
yeah
yeah okay do you still remember how
come here
define count 1
10 yeah do you still remember how to
recall
it one one one easiest way would be use
the
uh python function called bin bin
yeah bin is short for binary not for the
rubbish bin okay binary yeah so what it
takes it takes the number
15 number yeah then you will give
this will give a string look it has two
two extra bits zero zero binary and then
one one one one so basically you
have prefix the actual binaries with
zero bit okay so and then we can count b
how can we do this we can first of all
convert this n yeah yeah but we don't
want this
number two yeah these two yeah
yeah we can just do this
two then you'll get rid of this oh
we don't need to get rid of it and then
we after that we do what
count one okay
that's it yeah this is the remember yeah
okay the last thing is knowledge that
looks pretty short
yeah pretty soft so leave this
converting
numbers to binary yeah converting by
numbers to binary is log n right
yes and then call again
counting usually is o n but n
is is the number of bits but when you
when you count it
convert it to binary the n is actually
login
so actually because number of
one is log n times log n
you're going to get it oh don't get it
because this
counting one in the number in the string
is o n right it's a n but this n
is the number of the bit number of the
bits
which is o n o log n in this case
yeah so actually it's all locked and
again okay
so so this is not the first time
yes yes okay so now we can do another
one remember
define let's let's do another version
count two okay
look one one one one so every time
we turn two yeah look at every time we
can
every right every time we can
count we can look at the last digit
yeah and if it's one i add it if it's
zero i add a zero
and then i get rid of it and then it
becomes three digit and then i look at
the last digit
least significant
bite okay fit so it's last digit and i
look at it
i take away i look at it i think away so
we can do this
look answer equals yellow
wire and bigger than zero
answer plus equals and the last bit
the last bit is n and
one what's the last bit
n1 in the last bit one yeah
do you still remember and then i want to
i want to remove the last bit how can we
do it we can do this
shift shift to equals one yeah
or you can do this divided by two yeah
divided by two divided
equals two okay it's the same thing yeah
this divided by two the integer part
is same as in the binary you
shift it as one one bit okay so look
what's this mean
all right one zero one zero one
when you do this n is this one when you
do this and
shift the shift equals one shift to the
right one position
where is that you shift to one to the
right what happened
the rightmost one gone then it becomes
that and you shift one more the last
zero okay yeah and if it is
the the opposite way yeah it shifts to
the left
what does it become you put a zero at
the end and do it one more time
shift equals two what what does it
become
e6 you take away two zeros
easy yeah so this means i take away
one digit at the end when i add it if
it's one then it's one if
zero is nothing and return one
reason why can you guess answer
okay so this is one way of doing the
other way is what
defined let's do a country
complexity good answer is log n yeah is
it logan
look because if n is 15 then log n
is four it only has four bits four
iterations yeah
because every time i take a bit in the
binary i
cut it out and how many times i need to
cut for 15
four times i'm right yeah yeah so look
at okay how about this
country instead of i just can't count
four counts no no no look look one
zero zero zero two look this is
area okay yeah do you need to
take away one zero zero zero
we don't right because we know it's zero
it doesn't matter right
how about we just take away the last the
right most one
yeah if we take the right most one we
add one to get it
yeah okay so then look how do we take
away the right most one remember
the opposite no no no look look one zero
zero one how do we take away the one
all right remember we talked about this
before right look how do we take
the number one if we minus one that will
become
zero zero zero one one one yeah
if we minus one from this this minus one
you become right yeah all right in
binary
yeah and then we end we do this
n logic n
0 0 0 0 0 0
1 3 so basically if n
you want to take away lemons and you you
will become
n and n minus one right so in short you
will you write
n equals n minus one it's the same thing
okay
so every time we take away the rainbows
one until it's zero
so it's quicker right it's just look at
this one first
it doesn't look under each digit it skip
the digits am right
yeah so look this is useful
you want if we want to check the power
of 2 if number
is the power of 2 remember we talked
about this before 8
yeah hey look if it's the power of 2
2 to the power 3 yeah one it only has
one yeah
it only has one right it has only has a
single one in the binary
so it will be n n minus one that will
become zero right
you get it if it's one followed by four
zeros
the same thing right i will look at this
this is two to the power four one two
three four it's 16 in binary right
yeah so what n minus one what's n minus
one
n minus one zero
one one one what's n
what's n what what what is
zero it's zero yeah only one is n
it means the both if both number is one
it's one otherwise it's all zero
okay zero sorry
for zero it's yellow so only it's only
one
when both sides are one okay
all right three three cases zero okay
but for the o it's different it's one at
ol one of nine is one then it's one it's
one zero or
zero one or one one is one for all yeah
always orion yeah one of them
is true is true right eric and ryan
both of you needs to be true then
d2 okay it's something this is logic
okay
okay so this is also o log n right
yeah okay now suppose we have these
functions already okay
so now given okay given a number
n okay now listen carefully given the
number n
and i want you to find out
i want you to print out a list of
integers containing the number
of bits for the num all numbers between
zero
bigger than so x okay bigger than zero
and smaller equals n
so this is given for example this is
when n
is is three okay so now i want you to
find all the numbers between
uh less than three or equals three
bigger than zero so you'll be zero
one two three yeah yeah yeah
and then i want you to give me an array
containing
the number of ones in each digit so zero
will be zero one will be only one right
two how many
ones in two two how many ones in two z
one is zero
it's one yeah how many ones in three
zero
one what's three in binary
look zero let's binary one one zero
what's next
one zero one one one look you always
increment the last thing and what's next
and what's next one
zero come on you adding one and then you
carry over you'll be one and this
becomes zero and what's next
one one one okay and what's next
one two one two one
there's not two one five thousand zero
where the
i know what's next
what's next one
[Music]
what's next one one okay let's see
zero one two three four five six seven
eight
nine ten eleven twelve thirteen fourteen
fifteen
yeah you see
that yes yeah
[Music]
it's basically the same as like
9 what's next 10 yeah 99 what's next 100
yeah
and you make mistakes on this
one zero one plus one one zero one plus
one you say it's one
one it's not true look one plus one
equals zero carry over one
so it's one one zero okay got it
okay so look
given the number n and then you find all
the number of bits between the numbers 0
to n right
how can we do this eric all right
you can just write the number your
answer is look answer equals zero and
then
look for four
i in range
range one tier n plus one yeah
and then i can just say answer don't
append
ready yeah count yeah
count i that's it when we can answer
what's the complexity
[Laughter]
if it is count no no no yeah
we if we using the first first count
what's the complexity oh and logan why
is it
again can you tell me a and
log n can you tell me why okay
[Music]
look this one is oh you need to
understand
not reading
at least there's a loop end here yeah
that's
all that's talking about so oh and yeah
yeah how we can can we do better
one hint
do you know dynamic programming dynamics
programming dynamic what's dynamic
programming can you tell me
what's dynamic programming is
remembering
remembering yeah so do we need to count
look
we are counting all the bits from the
what number zero to number n
right yeah listen listen
we are counting the numbers uh number of
bits from number zeros to
number n do we need to count every
number
yeah no no we don't have every time
look if if we know look if you know
yeah look what's this in binary that
is well in decimal is a plus 4
is 12 yeah this is a this is four yeah
this is two this is one right
this is 12. so and what what's this you
find uh
what's this in
what's this in binary okay yeah
finally let's take okay so eight
plus one okay and twelve
last one equals thirteen so if i tell
you
if i tell you okay if i tell you
eight if i tell you eight has only one
one single one okay how many one
yeah it is yeah you don't need to
calculate i already give you that
f8 is one
and then you know 12
12 is one single bit after
one single bit more than eight yeah
so f12 is one t
two and this will be s a plus one right
yeah do you see the problem dynamic
programming
do you get it yeah so the basically is
like
how do we get the right uh how do we can
write normal speed
right most speed look f n
equals f
and if we can read the right one more
speed that would be
this yeah we talk about that yeah look
look what's this
one one zero zero minus one
one zero one one yeah yeah what's the
answer
beyonce is zero zero sorry
okay so look fn i can't read the right
mouse bit
and then i'll be what should i do here
what should i do here
what's the answer this is f is the
number of bits in
for the number of integer n and then if
i get rid of right most bit
i get rid of one bit and what
what should i do here
[Music]
i have f 12 equals
f 12 12 minus this is 12
and n and one minus one is this is
eleven
this is eleven yeah yeah and that would
be
this will be a yeah yeah f a one
so every time we want to calculate fn we
get
get rid of the one in binary
just erase it becomes zero right and
this
these f and and n minus one we already
calculated before
right and then what's the difference
what's the answer difference
there'll be only one difference yeah
because i i can't read the one
and i need to plus one yeah you get it
okay so now we can we can write this
look
uh define uh let's do this uh
f okay n and then i do this answer
equals
because the first row is zero okay then
i can do this for
i in range
n plus one yeah alright look look look
answer i equals what
i equal answer what
remember what should we do here and here
there's something here there's something
here and i can return
answer here
[Music]
this is i there's no n here this is i i
watch
what should i do when i yeah i know i
strong
from actually this is from one to m plus
one so if
i will be from one to
n right okay so i
please so i i want to get rid of the
right monster one
you don't have this yeah i i want to get
rid of right most one what should i do
i what
i minus one what's what's that i
minus i not equal
i talk about like all the time 12
becomes
12 becomes a what's what 12 how how
how does claire become 8.
one bit okay so how do we take one bit
and and what
come on look 12 is one one zero zero i
take away one bit
i minus one what's what's square minus
one is eleven right
in final would be one zero one one yeah
and then if i do this
n it'll become one zero zero zero okay
so that's how we do to the one big yeah
[Music]
i
uh minus one yeah come on it's here
what you're looking at what's the
complexity
um what's the complexity and
no there's
[Music]
answer we can also do this look
there's only one there's another way
yeah
look look this is taking the one bit
yeah taking the one bit they'll become
one one zero zero one zero right you
take over
the right most one bit yeah how about i
can do this
how about if i take away the right most
bit
you become one one zero okay this is the
same so
answer i equals i
how can i take away the normal speed
and no i remember we're shifting
yeah c y y one yeah
yeah do you need equal no because this
is just the
evaluation i take away the rainbow
street i shift it to the right yeah
but how do you know if it's the
rightmost speed you need to add one or
no
if it's zero we don't care if it's one
we need to add one right
so plus what's only plus here
we know plus one because it might be
zero so how can we check if we need to
check i
the last bit of the if the integer
integer n what's the rightmost speed how
can we get it
and and what i
n and what the
last bit look you could release and how
can i
get the last bit i can do this
yeah look at me what's this number
that's one one look if it's one the last
bit is one
then it's it's one if it's zero
if it's yellow then it's yellow right if
it's one it's one yeah
all other bits are zero because i have
zero here yeah
i don't it doesn't matter if it's one or
zero because
if anything n zero is zero yeah
okay so and and one right yes
all right so look this one will be n
and one why does it doesn't make sense
i want to calculate the number of bits
in i
yeah i then i can calculate because i
already calculated this number is
smaller than
i right because i i take away the last
bit this number is always smaller than i
am right yes if i take away
one digit the last digit of eight what
will it become
in binary four yes we are done
the four i already calculated and then
but the answer the one i need to take
away i don't know if it's
take away zero or one and then and i can
do this and one right
yeah how about five look five is
one one zero one right
five yeah i take away one bit
no b that will be one zero that will be
two right but the last bit is
five five and one is one right
and i need to add one instead of zero
and one yeah
but what's the complexity for this one
as well
[Music]
yeah you're not thinking when you talk
about the
login okay when we
the first one is because of the car yeah
okay okay that was correct
we're done okay because we're using the
count function which is login right
yeah if we're using the counter
the first one remember the pin function
then the complexity will be on login
login am i yes so what's this algorithm
dynamics
you can do it butter up at least this
problem is
it's better to be solved using top down
because the butter up
you need to start from zero one and then
and then you'll be
you'll be less i mean less intuitive as
top down because look we want to
calculate
i then we can solve it you we can click
we can update the value we can calculate
the value based on the smaller problem
because we already know
i i
shifted one or i take away the last and
the rightmost one i already know a
smaller the answer for a smaller problem
so more smaller integer right yeah and i
already know that so this part i don't
need to calculate it again right this is
the magic
this bit i already know it i memorize it
i don't need to calculate it again and
then the new answer is just plus one or
yeah do you see how hard it works
yeah okay good job today okay good job
good job good job do you have anything
to say to the people
over the world okay you say bye
ryan you want to say something
okay okay then see you tomorrow okay bye
bye
goodbye bye