oh hey hello miss terry hello mr ryan
how are you today
good good okay so today we talk about
something very interesting which is
called
the arrangement can you guess what these
mean
the rendering
putting things in order derangement is
not in order okay so but this is uh
has a special meaning which is group uh
look if there are three numbers yes
what arrangement in order you'll be one
two three right yes
let's ignore the that's because the
first number it's
in the first place the second number
is in the second place the third number
is in the third place okay
yes so the arrangement means that
the one cannot be in its position
so it can be here or here two cannot be
in
second place because it's not you know i
just
want it to be in other places three one
two
yeah one two okay so let's do right one
that's the the
arrangement for example like three one
two this is what one of the degreement
sequence permutation yeah so
how many look just remind me how many
total solutions if there are n numbers
and how many permutations
remember we talked about is
communication yeah
what's permutation one two three
is that if you're using three numbers
how many permutations you can get
remember how many plays how many
possible
numbers can the first number be
three how many for the second number two
how many for the third number one so
what's the total
six yeah three times two times one so
that permutation for n numbers
is n factorial am right
yes okay so now
obviously yes obviously
the total number of derangement is less
than the
n factorial right because that's the
possible total number of possible
permutation right
which includes the derangement right yes
yeah and so
the question is how given the number n
given number and every y we want to find
out how many different
arrangements per mutation it can be
they are okay so for example given
number
one okay for for example given what
number how many different arrangement
sequence is just one number
one no zero because look
one is in its place so it can't be
it's not true so it's different
there's none arrangement okay how about
two
two numbers how many one two how many
one yeah because it can only be two one
right it cannot be
one two okay so look so that's easy yeah
you call the concept let's say f is the
function we are going to
look at f zero um obviously there's no
zero so let's do f1
equals zero right f2
equals one right
equals one yeah because they can only be
two one right
two numbers you can only place into one
that means the requirement which is each
number is not in its original
position got it
okay so now how can we calculate fn
the question is how can we calculate fn
okay
yeah okay so now look
all right look this is the interesting
part yeah yeah look
look this is interesting right so they
are
n minus n numbers here yeah
yeah and i want to put the n number n
here
these are from number one to n minus one
right
and i want to put number n here right
so i want to put the number n so how how
i cannot put it here right because this
is not
n will be original position will be here
right
yes so how many positions i can put
in there's no fight i mean how many
positions
six no i'm not talking about the number
i'm talking about this is
n and n minus one yes
so look i put n i can only put in n
minus one position yeah
yes okay good job
okay now if i put it in this number k
for example any number okay yeah
yes and the k can be put here right
let's see four people yeah yeah
all right yeah because because the
the n this position belongs to
n right all right the last partition
belongs to n
if i don't take if n is placed in the
first n minus y so any number i swap it
can be directly put in the last
number right yes yeah because
because this this ndk can just put it in
a
in the last position because this this
[ __ ]
is not does not belongs to this n
minus one any of these n minus one right
yes
so there are if i put it here if i can
put it here
so how many positions how many numbers
can
how many solutions are these kind of
solutions
how many so look if i put an n here and
i
put a k here so they are m minus two
possibility am right yes
f n minus two
right yeah look can you imagine if i put
the k
at the last yeah and put an n
so basically i picked one of the n minus
one number
yeah the first and then and i swapped it
with n
yeah i swap it so the rest will be n
minus two right
yeah so i can just times it a minus two
yeah times it
yeah this is and how about if i don't
put enough
put the k in the last if i don't put ok
in the last
it means that it means what
sorry if
if i don't put a number k
in the last position then how many
positions
can i put
how many positions can i put is
okay so lazy will be because of this n
plus one i need to put it outside yeah
because
those together will be n minus one uh i
choose n
minus one positivities so that would be
plus
f what can you guess
okay no no there's no cages n
n minus one if i put it if i put the
number
if i i want to put that number n in the
first n minus one there's
n minus one i pick a number k and then k
can be put and the last
k can be put in the last and if okay put
it in the last that will be f
and minus two positions
yeah and then if i
if i don't put it in the k minus uh in
the last position that would be
something minus one n minus one i why is
it a minus one
why is it a minus one so look if i don't
put it in
so if i don't put it in uh
well if i don't i don't put the k here
so how many positions can we put
so it means that it means it means there
are n
minus one numbers can permute permutate
right do you get it
do you get it yep let's see let's see
if this is true okay f n minus 1 f minus
f n minus one okay so this is a bit
tricky to understand
so if i don't put i don't put the last
pull of k in the last number
if i don't put the number k in the last
number
so i have m minus 1
this is the the solution of n minus 1
right yeah is the solution of n
minus 1.
okay so let's try let's see this let's
see this is
if it works okay so f
3 let's see f n equals
n minus 1 times
f n minus 2 plus f minus 1 right
so let's see s3 equals 1
equals 2 times 3 minus one two
two times f one
plus f two f one is zero f two is one
so that would be one so f will be two
so that is equal to way
two one no two three
one right okay this is one solution
how about three one two yeah
all right okay so that's the only two
solutions
yes can we look uh if i want to put the
so look if i want to put the number
n the three so i can put it in if i want
to put a number three so i can put it
here and put it here that will be
two position yeah two every right look
it will be two
right when i put it here and then i can
swap it with two number two
so that would be f
f one right that would be f one because
there's only one and then
if if i uh
three i put it if i put it in a
k and k don't swap it with the last
position
don't swap it with the last position and
it will be
you'll be f what it'll be only one
positive
positivity right if f3 uh
this is the original place will be
number two
number two is here number two is here
and then if i
i'll put it here and then two can go
from if you go from the last one you'll
be here
right right if you go from
not the last one it will be it will be
in the f these two numbers
that would be two one right so that
would be a minus one
right will be n minus one you see
memorization because look if i if these
two doesn't go into the last position
look i pick a three here right
three i'm going to put this three i
choose any number of the first n i
for example i choose the number two
right so if i two
goes from the last one right goes from
the last one
then we don't have a solution because
look 3 2 and then the first one is 1
so that would be if it swapped with the
then the first the the solution would be
f three minus two would be f one right
f one would be zero right yes look
you see three i put a three i swap it
with two right
yeah and 2 can go to the last yeah slope
will be 3 yeah
yeah if i solve with 2
then the last the solution will be f 1
right you'll be only this one number f
one is zero because i can't put a one
here
in the first place all right if it
doesn't work with the number one then
they will be n minus two
because they are n minus two numbers or
n minus one numbers
for the n right yeah got it
look why why this is a minus one i just
look you understand this part yeah it's
a minus two yeah
yeah and what's this n minus one look
if i pick the number three put it in
here and two
doesn't go into the last then they are n
minus one right look
they are minus one which is two numbers
yeah
all right got it yeah okay so this is
what we call this is what do we call
dynamic programming transition function
or transition equation what's transition
from a state to another state because i
want to calculate f
n then i can calculate f of minimizer
look what's the difference between this
and fibonacci number
uh what's the difference
what's fibonacci number it's without
speed yeah
all right the difference between this
equation and a fibonacci number is
this bit correct
okay so look if we we don't know this
equation if we want to compute
if you want to try to find out how many
what's your proof of search remember
first try every possibility
right yeah and what's the how many
possibilities are they
and what what's the complexity of the
proof force if i want to
try every possibilities and then check
and check if each one is a diff uh
derangement
how many possibilities if the elements
the permutation third permutation
n minus
three numbers how many permutations
what's the possibility of the first
number
what's the possibility of second number
yeah so what's that
three times two times one what's that
three what three factors
yeah yeah so how many ends are totally
yes so n factorial
for blue forcing all permutation right
and how to check if this one's
permutation is uh
different the arrangement or not
well you need to go through this
permutation once
to see if the original value is in the
original place right
if if it's a then it's not a valid
arrangement right
so what's the complexity of that
[Music]
over all complexities all n factorial
times n this is huge this is too complex
it's not feasible for n equals 10 that
would be a lot
i mean right it's not feasible all right
so we can do this using dynamic
programming we just
prove an equation and we can just do
this can you tell me okay f
n column yeah if n equals 1
return y 0 yeah if
n equals 2
yeah this is quite similar yeah we tend
n minus one yeah times
f n minus one plus f one
x minus two well done that's it and
what's missing here
it's not column okay what's amazing from
a cash
cash because if you know using the cash
what happened
if at least intermediate numbers like
fibonacci number
will be calculated over and over again
and the time complexity because a
at each round is is exposed to
paths right the complexity will be o to
the power n right
this is still huge right yeah so we want
to add the cache
or the notebook yeah remember the
notebook without least
we with this the compiler the commuter
knows
if a computer calculates f 10 for
example
yeah the next time you can you are
asking for f10
you will return the value without
calculating it right
yes so without the look with the
notebook
how do you do this a notebook yeah
and then you can just do this here yeah
uh you can just edit if and
in notebook yeah return
return what notebook end right and then
before you return you store this number
in a value all right in a value and then
you put it in the notebook yeah okay
and then return what reason what
i came to the value i put it in level
everything
no value yes okay
let's see minimization okay and how
about
how about we're doing uh this is called
top-down dynamic programming how about
we're doing this bottom-up
mini programming okay all right look
it's been quick okay look 18 minutes
yeah yeah that's okay that's the same
yeah look let's do the same
return yellow e and equals to
return one okay
otherwise look otherwise look we have a
value dp value all right remember
this ddb alright look dt equals let's
say
zero times n minus n plus one okay
okay 19 minutes okay look look
look all right and then i need to set
the dp
two equals one okay and then i can do
this for
i let's say for i in
when start from the number three to end
my n plus one right
after n plus one then i can do this dp
i equals i minus one times
fbp i minus one
plus dp i minus two right yeah
this is basically we start from the tt
the number two
and calculate number three number four
number five until number n yeah
and then return the last value which is
tp1
db1 the last value of the array
minus one minus one last value always
okay
so look what's the time complexity
our n yeah because each value will only
calculate what's the space
n o n right because we're using the
right can we
do it without a array
like fibonacci number we are not using
array right we can use the way but we're
not using array
all right look we can because look every
time we're calculating dpi
we only need how many values do we need
to calculate for
if we want to carry the value i
how many values do we need to calculate
i minus b p i minus one and d p my i
minus two so that's a value like the one
lasting number you can't give like a
fibonacci number like
uh the first two item is uh for example
there are two fibonacci numbers three
and four and what's in the next value
what's the next value what's the
negative huh
what's the fibonacci number if the first
two item is three and four
the next two items next one item
seven yes you only need the three and
four you don't need you don't need to
take consideration of the previous yeah
up a preview to three yeah
yeah okay so for this is simple look
yeah so let's say a b equals
zero one right because we know the the
first item is zero the second number is
item is one and now we just need to do
this look
i three to n and a b
what's what's a what's the new a what's
the new a
you'll be the b right yeah exact simple
number
and what's the new b you'll be like
equation yeah
which is i minus 1 times
what times a plus b yeah look is it
exactly the same
except this yeah it's like a fibonacci
number except like i have
minus 1 here right remember the equation
yeah
and i can just return b yeah okay
what's the what's the station complexity
no i just remove the o n what's the
space complexity
what's the space what's the time
complexity time conduct c
what's the time complexity how many
iterations do i need to go here
n and o n what's the space complexity
this is a hard question what did i what
was that before i using the dp
all right that's one and i remove it
what's the complexity time complex
a one because there's no there is no
additional storage except those constant
variables i need
right i remove the storage right i don't
really
know so this is very highly efficient
because it's very
fast yeah it does not have a recursion
it does not use the
remember when you use the cash
as long as you use the cash the notebook
what's the space complexity
if you're using the notebook what's the
spacing on yeah because right now we are
not using any
uh notebook thing so the space
complexity is one which is optimal the
constant and the time complexity is just
a loop for
o n so that's the optimum solution okay
yes uh
eric any questions do you understand
this problem
the arrangement yeah okay let me give
you an example three two
uh one for is this a derangement
yeah what is
[Music]
it's not because four is in the original
place
how about this two days
yeah two is how about three two four
three two one
let's see it
please come back
this is because none of them are you
know original how about five numbers
like five
four three two one say the arrangement
three is
three three is in so it's not a
derangement okay
so okay four five four number five five
numbers can you write the arrangement
and that's it for today can you write a
different different sequence
five numbers you can write one
as well ryan you wanna
three four four three yes
five yes one two
well done okay so you know pretty much
this concert okay
that's very good okay okay you can say
bye bye to people
bye bye see you later bye yeah