go hello hello hello miss mary mr ryan
how are you today
good okay so today we're gonna talk
about today we're gonna talk about
uh subsequence so what's the subsequence
uh right
what sequence it's a subsequence for
example like
a b c
[Music]
yes yes so basically this is the
original string you can
dedic nothing or you can did it one or
more
characters look if i did release did it
please list then it becomes left so abc
is the
subsequent zone and here right right abc
is
a b c s sub sequence of abc
of course i said did it now or okay
but okay so how about if a string like a
b c
d e and then i give you a string which
is shorter is it a subsequence
no no right because this is this is
this is longer than the target like an
original string so
it can't be possible we can't possibly
delete any now if we didn't numb
it doesn't match right yeah okay so
today
we're going to talk about an algorithm
to
find out to check if your string s
is a subsequence of t r r i
i
[Music]
so look this is the starting point so
how can we
check how can we check it with the
subsequence if
this first string is acceptable
okay so yeah and then you check these if
it's in it then what
you can you get the next one but this
may not work
look if you have if you have if you have
this eic
and and r
r e e i c look
you check e in the subsequence but ah
also in the subsequence on the second
string
do you get it these needs to be ordered
so this is not a subsequence of that
yeah this is not a subsequence of that
all right all right
does it make sense so your approach may
not work right
yeah so how can we fix this
it
the is of it so this
is no subsequence of it because e must
come before r but this one
is come after r right yeah so it's not
subsequence yeah
so how can we fix your algorithm so
you're saying that e
you check in between that okay it's and
then you check
the next one yeah
you check it danny
oh that's a good approach yeah yeah that
was all thinking though
yeah yeah that's a very good approach so
you eat you find it
and you wrap it up yeah right but
but again i can wrap it up e okay so
which e you want to wrap it up
i want to roll out the second
section it doesn't matter you drop it or
oh or even
one one so
look this approach still doesn't solve
the it has to be all
in order you find this e the next one
you find is e the next
r should be on the right hand side not
the left hand side do you get it
he finds e
he find r yeah
wait wait wait you find e and if i you
check if his eyes come
before after e yeah
[Music]
so sorry no idea wait wait
wait okay that's fine look
how about you will you use two pointers
pointing to look yeah
yeah okay let it equal yeah then i can
move both sides
there no they're not easier not equal
can we move this one and we know this
one because this is we haven't found it
yet so here ah okay now
both of them why can we move both of
them
because at least we have more match we
need to find next one and this okay
move
and then okay we reached the end and
then now we just need to check
if the point of love s is the end of the
yeah 30. yeah does it make sense
so two pointers yeah yeah okay
so let's let's learn radical
define is subsequence
as we want to check as if it's the
subsequent of t what's
missing here how yeah always
okay let's do the s a l
s l t is the length of both strings so
let's do it
a l and s a and
t yeah and
yeah if air s is bigger than lt
what does it mean if the first string is
the bigger than the
next string what does it mean the first
string is
false return first because in this case
it's not
not a subsequent as it's not subsequent
now we have two points okay i see
i equals j equals zero that means what
means i and j both are equal to zero
so both points are not reaching the end
okay and
one hand and j
is smaller is lt okay look
if s i equals
as f i equals t t j what
what do we do if s i equals t
j what should we do 3
no true if the two pointers the same
the character what should we do
both move one okay i plus equals one and
else
three plus equals one a is one
as if it's not equal we only move the
which one
t t one so two plus equals one look if i
look look this is duplicate yeah you see
two so what can we do is we erase at
least equates at least
but no no it is a ring and i'm putting
three outside okay so j
plus equals one all right okay when we
turn
at the end we need to check which one
which front pointer
which which hand at the end we want to
check which hand
reaches the end
where's your hand which hand the top one
yeah the top one the shorter one which
is sorting
and the pointer of s is which which
value
uh i or j
i or j which one is the i which one is
the z
come on you can read the code look ls
equals length as lt equals length
i equals j equals 0 1 i smaller than ls
t i equals a sorry
j is lt the second point so i want to
check which pointer i
what is the value of the i when it's
reaching the end
lsrt
lengthy yes
what's the term complexity
what's this n can you explain to me
what's this n
it's
[Music]
the name
it's the length of s or and length of t
because in the worst case the tea worse
yeah it goes through the tea
the longer one yeah it goes to the
longer one what's the space complexity
one yeah but you say all in first
okay okay i got you yeah you both are
correct okay
okay have a look i'm going to erase it
okay
okay okay
wait where's the eraser where's the
eraser nowhere
where's the invader can i have it
[Applause]
okay you can say bye bye and see you
tomorrow let's bye bye and have one hand
why
hello bye bye bye see you tomorrow