hello hello mr how are you today
good okay so today we talk about a
program how do you multiply two integers
numbers yeah can you write the function
to
multiply two integers very simple i i i
write the top for you
define multiply simple
yeah yeah a and two integer a b what's
missing
column okay and then what can you write
it
it looks very strong okay how about i
tell you
i tell you you can't use hand
multiply and you can use the multiply
and you can't use the division
and you can't use any bit shifting which
may not be for me you know the brief
shifting we'll talk about that later
okay so can you figure a way to do it to
implement this function without using
these two
and b shifting like r and
shift shift left shift shift right okay
so you can't use any of these can you
figure away how how can we write it
so for example given three times five
how do you calculate three times five if
i don't want you to use the multiple
how do you 5 5
well done that's the good shot yeah so
basically we turn
10 in the multiplier multiplication into
you can do it three times five yeah
or five times three all right
yes so which which way you think it's
the most
efficient way why is that
because it's more short it's shorter so
it involves less
operation right yeah yeah okay that's
good good okay how about the negative
numbers
negative numbers like how to return
how do you handle these negative numbers
like multiply minus three times five
minus three times minus five
yeah and then if there's zeros for
example like three times
zero so i'm definitely zero
yeah i know so so how do we implement
this
e if they're negative what do we do
if the negative uh
is too negative do we just turn into a
positive
we're down yeah two negative ten into
the positive how about one negative
what are we doing one negative
one negative so minus three times my
times five equals one
minus three times five
uh minus fifteen yeah minus fifteen so
how do we do it if it's
minus then we take a minus away and then
we
check this and put the minus okay so
so let's write it okay so easy look it
should be very easy
so look if a equals
zero or b equals zero
return one
zero if a smaller than zero
and p smaller than zero what's
what should we return return
return let's call itself yeah let's turn
this
negative into positive which is
return multiple y can you feel this
blank
two two things uh
turning to positive yeah how can we turn
it to
a is negative now how can we turn into
positive
a is already negative how can we make we
how can we turn a into plus a
negative weight
minus what a yeah minus a and
here minus b yeah minus b
minus b minus b okay be confident okay
yeah okay then look if i if one of them
is
negative if a is smaller than zero b
smaller than zero
can you tell me what to put here what
this is n we can't do that
we can use the not the end this is this
is logical and not the big shifting
you can use this so if a is smaller than
zero
what this this we checking if both
are zero and if n is one
both are not yellow right yeah and both
are not yellow
if what's your equation here
if one of them is zero should we use n
or or
if one room is zero what should i put
here
oh yes if one or one zero but we need to
check
which one is zero so you pretend if a is
smaller than zero then wha
return one if a smaller than zero is b
smaller than zero in this case it's p
small now
because if this if a is smaller than
zero piece more than zero is here yeah
if a smaller than zero return multiply
what what return multiply
a base one and
b yeah okay we're done if b is smaller
than zero
yeah return y multiply multiply
minus b is smaller than zero a is
smaller than the other no no
minus b well done yes okay so this is
b basically these are the cases
yeah these are the cases to turn
everything into positive because we are
focusing on handling the positive
multiplication for two numbers yes yes
if any of them is zero we don't care if
any of them is negative
our pulse of light are negative we don't
care because we we have these four ifs
to turn
everything into positive okay yeah
turn everything into positive positive a
positive okay so now positive how can we
do it
and look if
a is smaller than b
okay so we want to look we want to turn
3 times 5 into
no we want to 10 five times three
into three times five right why
so instead of three plus three plus
three plus three plus three
we want the five plus five plus five
okay yeah
okay so suppose this is a this is b so
if a is bigger than b
then return y return
multiply what
yes and now now we are falling at these
cases
so a is three b is five
so how can we do it how can we write it
uh okay we can return return what
so five times five times five yeah so we
want to
make i add yeah if we want to make
a smaller three times five equals
three minus one times five plus five
all right yeah yes yeah got it so how
can we write this
a minus one times
b add b
look we we can't use these terms so we
need to use this to multiply
return what multiply
multiply what this is a this is b
multiplication a
minus one
multiply no no it's the a and b
whatever b yeah and then add b
yeah okay we're done now let's perfect
okay
so how can we turn these if we don't
want to use this recursion
we want to do it using iterate today how
can we do this
so we add the answer here answer equals
zero right
yes yes how can you turn this into a
white
while loop while wire
wire wire a what
[Music]
is bigger than y where y i is
bigger than zero right yeah and what you
will do answer
plus equals what can you can just
do this one one no
answer e plus equal one
why a is smaller than zero a is three b
is five why a three is bigger than zero
we are adding the answer of one b
b and now we need to equal
that and we and we need to a what one
a
[Music]
become two so what we need to make it
minus equals one okay and then we turn
return one return one
well done okay so
do you see it yeah yeah we we are using
only the plus
minus to deal with the
multiplication right yeah
okay yeah yeah so how about
as a bonus if we are allowing to use the
division
or shifting how do we do it
we have to use those no no no this is
because my original question is
don't use the time multiplier and dv
divide and bit shifting which is to the
left to the right
but to the left to the right is
basically
to the left is basically multiply two
to the right is basically divided by two
yeah got it because
because look uh one basis in binary is
a yeah if you if you get rid of zero
that counts four yeah shifting to the
right if you add one more zero
it becomes 16 yeah okay
yeah okay so if we are allow using this
any thoughts like three times five how
can we do it three times five
equals one equals one
five equals fifteen yeah i know
five that's fine maybe a little bit yeah
yeah maybe a little bit
maybe look maybe what six times five
equals one yeah i know but five and five
guys
no no maybe maybe six times seven okay
how hot do we do this is
a this is b instead of adding
instead of adding six times of seven
seven plus seven plus seven plus seven
seven e we can do this we can ten
because
and multiply this by two so that will
become
low becomes 12 times for uh 40 i know
3 times 14 yeah yeah so that will be
even shorter yeah
but if it's an odd number so we we
cannot use this we can
minus one right when it's even number we
can
we can divide a divide a by two
or shifting a to the one to the right
right
and then multiply b by two or shifting b
one position to the left okay so in this
case it will be faster right instead of
what's the time complexity of reason by
the way
oh
a because a is smaller right yeah always
smaller so you can
all o l mean a b
and because a and b could be negative so
you put the absolute value yeah
this absolute value remember abs was
absolutely
bad remember absolute minus three equals
three is the distance between the number
on the
line to the zero yeah in mathematics you
use this
two this minus three equals three
this three equals three so it's like two
vertical sticks okay okay
yes yeah here minimum absolute value a b
this is the complexity yeah because we
need that amount of time
iterations to calculate to accumulate
another value
all right yes if we are using this
divided too
what's the complexity
you'll be log not the thing right
because every time we can divide it by
two
yeah yeah so that would be log
log minimum mean divided by two
yeah because log divided by two is the
most efficient okay
yeah yeah but that's a very good
question yeah
okay so that's it for today
have a nice weekend bye bye bye
yeah bye bye