hello okay hello mr
mr ryan yeah hello how are you today
good
good so remember a few months ago we
talked about
you know i talked about this these
number of perfect squares
for example 12 if you if you want to
represent 12 in the sum of perfect
squares
what would you represent it equals
4 plus 4 plus 4 right because this is
the perfect square
yeah and thirteen equals one thirteen
equals one
can you pretend yeah
keep going yeah you're all right yeah
four four
plus one nine yeah look a perfect square
yeah
square these are perfect square yeah i
know perfect square so these
need two least needs three number yeah
correct least yeah of course if you if
you know the least
yeah yeah like if it's not if you want
to the most right
then 13 would be one plus one plus one
yeah level 13 because one is the total
number
perfect square number so our task is
given a number like 13 you need to tell
me that
you need a two right and if it is twelve
we need to tell
me three for me you need two yeah uh why
yeah yeah yeah for six what's six later
on six one
six
six four one one well done four one one
yes and
how about how about seven
no two is not perfect square number four
add one one
one so in theory
in series okay it's a very complex
mathematics
theory in theory at most four numbers
four numbers you cannot even if you find
the five then
it's not optimum okay how about 23
23 okay so can you find 23 let's go 23
16 plus
plus one four plus
[Music]
how about how about nine nine
nine nine four one
yeah perfect look at that four yeah
because if you're choosing 16 you can't
make it into the four
numbers yeah yeah because 16 what's left
seven left and then
we know seven is four plus one plus one
yeah so they're five well you can't
actually find four okay so this is the
example of this is the example of
liquidity doesn't work you know
liquidity
well done this is a perfect example if
you 23 what's the largest
perfect square number that is less than
16 yeah but if you pick 16 you can't
finish it in four numbers
you see so this is this is the perfect
scenario
that the greedy doesn't work the greedy
you know what's greedy
yeah yeah yeah yeah 23
i picked the largest largest
number perfect square number left is
less than
23 which is 16 but if i pick a 16
i make the wrong choice because if i
take
16 i can't finish
using less than four less or equal of
four numbers
i have to pick something different which
is nine and nine
nine four one whether okay so any idea
how we are solving this problem
how are we solving this moment
remember dynamic programming what's
dynamic programming
remembering remembering how are we
remembering
look if we are if we if we pick 16 yeah
yeah and what's left seven
but we already know the seven yeah yeah
we all
already know that seven needs the four
numbers yeah so we don't need to
calculate 7 again so if we can find some
way
to memorizing this thing
and then we can reuse it so so basically
if we
use the if we use the function f n
to represent the length the number of
the perfect squares
that can be sum up to n yeah yeah
so f n equals to mean
f n and we are choosing the minimum yeah
choosing what so f yeah
f n minus
j times j
yeah yeah plus one right
and it's j this needs to be bigger than
zero right
all right so look if we can find a way
to iterate
all the numbers and then we can update
these right together
look j we just need to iterate
j between between one between
one two square root of n
right yeah now we need to find out
this f n look this is f and it's a sub
problem
a smaller problem yeah look if this is
23 yeah look f1 23
and then if j equals three
uh four right four and then j equals
four and
four times four is sixteen right twenty
three minus sixteen is seven
yeah so basically f 23 equals
mean this is just an example f 23
we we keep updating the f 23 with the
with the smaller number f 1
f 23 minus four times four right this is
f7 right
yes yeah i need to plus one right do you
know why why we need to plus one here
look f7 let's say
f7 we know four numbers yeah right
f7 we know four numbers four numbers yes
i'm right
and then
7 plus 4 times 4 equals
23 yeah f7
now f7 is 4 numbers
4 numbers plus a perfect square number
equals 23. so the 23 is the four numbers
plus one number all right yes you get it
here
okay so look 23 minus four times four
this is the perfect square 16 we are
talking about
right and we we know this is f7 this is
four numbers
and now we are mine we are
deducting a perfect square which is 14
as
16 here so it means that we have
one more extra number to add right to
update am i
okay so if we check all the
possibilities
between i and square number of n
then we find the answer all right
okay so let's write it and how many
dynamic programming are we talking about
do you know how many kinds of dynamic
programming
how many kinds of dynamic programming
and what's this minimalization what's
that memory minimalization location with
the minimum migration
what do you call it is it a drop down
button
yeah you see the topper of water top
down
drop down yeah minimization we use
recursion is top down because
if we want to calculate fn yeah we are
solving it into a smaller problem right
and we remember it yeah like a fibonacci
number if we want to calculate fn
we need to calculate fn minus one and f
of n minus two right
remember the number of the derangement
remember the arrangement yeah
yeah is is two one on derangement
yeah arrangement permutation yeah yeah
so
look at fibonacci number fn equals fn
minus 1
plus fn minus 2 right yeah
so the arrangement you just times a
minus one
yeah remember you still remember here
this one yeah
yeah it's the same so top down is that i
want to calculate fn
and i need to solve a smaller problem
first
yeah but when i calculate f n i mean so
i may have to solve the smaller problems
multiple times
and in order to speed it up we need to
add uh what
i know what the magic key was above the
function was that
cache yes we are done to memorize it
let's call let's make it
let's make it a top-down dynamic
programming all right
okay so let's let's do this fn is
represent the
number of the least number of perfect
squares to add up to n right
yeah it's been already no minutes yes
yes let's find okay
define f n what's what's missing
column
[Music]
yeah i'll remind you later okay if
n equals zero f zero what
how many how many non-perfect square
numbers add up to zero
zero
yes okay so the answer
answer equals a very big number at the
beginning
in python we can use this a very big
number
floating number and converted a string i
and s what inf stands for
a very thick number what's less than one
yes we're done infinity
infinity and beyond infinity floating so
infinity a string converting to a flow
number so it means a very very big
number
yeah okay okay okay okay
yeah so look oh yeah
infinite so basically it's eight you're
writing the
sideways yeah yeah yeah so this is
infinity and if you put the minus is
means the negative infinity yeah so look
this is a line
yeah this is yellow here and you're
going away
infinity going that way negative
infinity yeah
got it so it's a symmetric line right
correct
so look answer is that then we we have
to do this
i equals one okay so y
i times i smaller equals n
right right
answer equals mean look we are getting
the mean
answer and what f
and minus look tell me what to do i
times i what's what's missing here
one add one add one yes you remember
that
one and then return what with an answer
yeah
so this is eventually making it uh what
uh dynamic programming yeah but there's
something
high that's something that's something
we see here
that's something no because i y i i will
be needed to
increment one so let's miss i equals one
so because we try the one
one times one is perfect square is one
one is two
yeah one is two one is two
two times two is four right yeah f and
minus two plus one
when one i is three three times three
nine and minus nine plus one right yeah
so basically f n equals f n
minus one plus one and
f n minus four plus one f n minus nine
plus one and f
n minus one plus one what's next
what's next when i is four
and minus four times four sixteen plus
one and what's next
5 25 plus one yeah you see so all this
possibility i need to consider and then
i will get this minimum yeah
you are getting the minimum okay so this
is the
this is the top delta let me poke me
what's the complexity is it easy to see
is it easy to see what's the time
complexity can you make a guess
i guess i win oh um
oh and no it doesn't
no because look the here
here is oh oh
what is o square n right square n right
and then you need needing to calculate n
so it's all n square n
squared yeah it's maybe it's not easy
to it's not easy to see but let's let's
turn this into butter up
dynamite programming you still need a
camera
no from the bottom we don't need look
remember this cache we can we can edit
the parameter like a notebook yeah yeah
and then we can either if
the end in no book and we return no book
end and before this we can
answer we will say the answer not to
notebook end
and return answer yeah yeah okay so look
so we for the bottom arm for the bottom
we need a array let's say dt equals
let's make everything bigger infinite
yeah
in infinite and times
n plus one okay because from zero to n
and n
yeah from zero to n there are n plus one
elements i'm right
yeah yeah i'm right
okay so now d p zero is zero okay
this is easy yeah and then for
i in range yeah
one to n plus one right yeah
and then here look j equals one
y j times j you tell me okay
smaller equals i yes look
and then what should we do dp
okay dpi equals
mean dpi
and then t p i minus j
times j and what's amazing here
no no no i from one to n and then j
straight times j one yeah one yeah it's
the same thing yeah remember
yeah and then j what sorry what one
yay add add one you have to add one
because j for one and then the next one
is two two times two
and next one is three three times three
yeah i minus three times three yeah you
see
okay henry ten what we have an array
and what should we return return here
what should we return dp dpi is the
means the number of the least num
perfect squares to represent dp1 eb1
[Music]
dpi
dpn or dp minus one because it's the
last number yeah
yeah dpn or dpi okay so you see
look look this is this is
n yeah o n yeah i look this
this one o
square n yeah so you times it together
what's this
n squared yeah curry
look this is the bottom because we are
calculating
from look we are calculating dt1
db1 look this is 20 from one yes look a
lot of errors
and then tp2 iphone we are calculating
tp from
i 1 db 2 db 3 db 4 yeah db5
we are calculating total up right right
do you get it yeah this is bottom up
yeah
and the other one is uh top top down
right
dynamic programming okay okay so let's
another quiz which is 15 how do you
division 15 using the
this real numbers this perfect square
numbers
fifteen come on fifteen
[Music]
square nine nine four
one four quick no no no
nine four one one is fifteen yeah can
you make
can you better do it better
now 14 no 2 is not 30.
five is not perfect square one square
perfect square number is perfect square
number
[Music]
two is not right two is not four
plus four plus
or you can use it nine four and once
yeah yeah i think this is
this is the idea yeah see i told you
okay
okay okay so let's see
bye bye bye bye