hello hello hello mr eric mr ryan how
are you today
okay so today we're going to talk about
an interesting subject which is called
longest
increasing
how do subsequence know subsequently
we've watched this video
before yeah okay so let's let's
do an example uh do you understand
what's the subsequence
uh you take none or more
okay so for example eric e-r-i-c what's
the subsequence can you
this is a few subsequences of the eric
rick
sorry rick rick yeah
even eric is the subsequence of eric
yeah because you're
not allowed to take nothing yeah and
ryan
what's the subsequent yeah
basically you are allowed to erase
nothing or erase
anything or you can erase uh o
so empty string is a subsequence of ryan
okay in technically okay yeah yeah
okay given an array
with numbers integers yes let's say 0
9 8 10
2 4 5
what's the longest subsequence
um zero eight ten yeah
sorry zero three four five one two four
[Music]
no because when you pick nine you can't
pick a because this is not increasing
this is decreasing
yeah got it so it's always increasing
zero two four
five right so therefore so our task
is to find the longest to count the
number of longest
longest increasing subsequence so that
will be the four numbers
one thing yeah right one
yeah look at it so the longest
subsequent will be four
four elements okay yeah so had any idea
how are we solving this problem just
mine
the longest subsequent so yes how how
are we doing this
any ideas just think about it how are we
doing
sorry nothing
any idea how we're so good wait moving
brute forcing yeah that's a good source
how how are we going to prove our sins
so we find out every possibility of the
subsequence
right and then phi is is increasing
right
yes yes so remember the subsequence the
time complexity of choosing that
that subsequent is
for example like let's say a b how many
subsequent
you can pick from two numbers to
two characters four four yeah
how about abc
how many how many possible subsequence
of abc three three letters
two is four yes that's right two is four
one is one two right
because you can pick or not pick right
two is four
yeah and three is one six
how is that six
abc a b c a
b a c b c
and what a b c so it's more than six
right
it's already seven yeah and then you can
pick nothing
yeah eight eight yeah so then you get it
and four
do you want me to tell you
wait come on two four eight
what's next
why this is the total number of the
subsequence
and elements because for each one
you can choose to pick or don't pick
in the subsequence right yeah so for
each letter
how many possibilities how many
possibilities
for each one so you pick or not pick how
many possibilities eric
how many possibilities for a i want to
pick up nothing how many possibilities
two i want to take on p how many two
so it's two times two times two how many
how many n
times so two to the power of n right
yeah so that's the total number of
subsequence yeah
yeah in other way in other ways because
because n numbers yeah so the
subsequence could be
length yellow could be length one could
be length two to be length three right
yeah and then do you still remember the
combination yeah if c
and zero mean takes nothing
out of n items and then picks one thing
out of entire items picks two things out
of anti-items and
picks anything out of an item yeah
because that's only one possibility
this is only one percentage if you add
it add all these what's the total number
of
subsequence if you i always
i just told you what's this subsequent
yeah i would just i was just checking if
you're listening oh no okay you're
paying attention
okay i am yeah okay that's good okay so
the blue thing yeah you come here the
proof of thing
looks away reversing
complexity o two to the power n and
how uh what's the complexity if we are
given a subsequent we want to check if
it's strictly
increasing what's the term complexity of
of given a subsequent like one two three
if you want to check one two three is
strictly
increasing what's the term complexity
if there are n and n letters in the
subsequence
yeah we're done so so the overall time
complexity is
o to n times n yeah
this is very huge this is highly complex
so it's not feasible to solve using the
computers okay
yeah if n is 100 2 to the power 100 is
is huge you know
okay so uh sure we need to find
a better agreement so so how about i
tell you that this problem we can solve
it using dynamic programming so what's
dynamic programming can you tell me
remember
yeah the key thing is remembering one
other thing remember
yeah that's even better remembering is
is the
common word but the minimization is the
technical word okay
mean minimization it sounds quite
funny yeah it's very similar to
memorized but it's mean mobilization
mimo what's mimo
mimei it's mimo mimo
it's like a notebook you put the notes
in there it's like you're
fish name no okay
so
so dynamic programming we are
remembering how about if i tell you that
f n okay f
n is the we story f n
is the longest subsequence the ends and
ends ends number so f
two what does f2 mean
zero one two so it means that f2 means
the longest
number of subsequence increasing
subsequence
that the last number is eight yeah okay
okay so now if i know f2 is f2
i i don't f2 okay and then
here look because a is smaller than 10
so what does
f3 equal what does s3 equal
f2 i give you we currently don't care
about its value but i know
a is smaller than 10 yeah and then
f3 is f2 what
you see this is the f2 is nothing
there may be a minion items before a
yeah
but i tell you the number of longest
increasing subsequence that the last
number is
a is f2 and then now you know
a is more than 10 so what does it mean
for f3
10 sorry now s3 is the number of the
longest
increasing subsequence that ends and 10
yeah and then now i tell you f2 is
after the value is calculated we already
know we're already memorizing
using the dynamic programming
minimization
and then i tell you a is smaller than
10.
so what happens if we i add a 10 in the
longest subsequence does this feel valid
yeah because look at the last number
ending in a
yeah it could be 1 3 4 a
this is a subsequence previously yeah
you don't care
and now you know a is smaller than 10.
what happens if i put a 10 here
what happens if i put a 10 here does it
still make a longer one
does it make sense do you get it
so f2 equals f2
f3 equals 1 f2
i put the 10 in the end it's the longest
subsequent it's still
increasing something yes i won that's
that's what i meant okay
you get it that's one ad yeah and one
you have one edit do you understand yeah
yeah
and do you see because we we
already know this bit and we can reuse
it
yeah why can't we reuse it because a
is smaller than 10 yeah and b speed
for example a minion if f f2
is a minion and then i know f3
is a medium plus one because i can
always
put a 10 at the end of previous longing
subsequence
and you will increment the longest
by one
so if i want to check this f3 so i need
to check
every number between 0 to 3.
look i want to check every number
between these
and i check if 0 is more than 10 if it's
smaller than 10 then f3 equals
1 plus f0 but i want to get a maximum
of these okay and then 9 is smaller than
yes then 1 plus one a is smaller than
ten
yeah a f two plus and plus one actually
okay do you understand yes
yeah kind of maybe it's better if i
write a code than you will see
you'll see how it works okay let's say
define
remember the top down and primary
programming yeah that's two approaches
what's top-down dynamic programming
usually implemented
in what top down if i want to calculate
fibonacci number every time i like talk
about people naturally if i want to
calculate
the f 100 fibonacci number what do you
need to know
to calculate f 100 you need to know f
99 and f
98 because it's the sum of previous two
right yeah
okay so the fibonacci number f99 and f8
98 so so this is top down because i want
to calculate f100
i i need to recursively call it
yeah yeah i i need to because the
recording f9
and f98 am right and the bottom of
dynamic performance what's that if i
want to calculate every 100
where do i need to calculate first the
butter up
you need to calculate from
the other direction what's the already
where is the first value i need to
calculate
where's the first value e
for what i mean
no i want to test f n if top top down
is i f n minus one
plus f n minus two okay this is called
top down because i start with
n and going down and if i want to
do it butter up i need to study what
study this direction
come on end up end to zero and what's
this
and and i want to start calculating yeah
so i need to calculate f0 f1
and using these two values with f2 right
this is called
do you understand different direction
yeah basically it's the same thing yeah
okay so look define f and
f n okay so look fn is the longest
number longest increasing subsequence
of the uh of the nth number okay
yeah okay okay so yeah
must equal something yeah yeah
so look the longest subsequence the
minimum value is what
is is if i have only one value what's
the
longest increasing subsequence one for
example if i one
yeah because it's one value it's
increasing yeah
okay so if look then for
i in range i i need to
check the values up to n nth right so
let's put
n here look if everything look
numbers if numbers okay so suppose we
have numbers here okay
numbers i is smaller than number
that needs to be a profit j g
if i number smaller than
look answer equals max answer okay
answer and what should i put here
no no no not yet f1
all right j j
there's no j i hear i invent
n if i look look at this remember
remember this is i this is i this is n
if this number is smaller than this
number
yeah and then what should we do answer
would be the maximum of
our f1 f1 we calling itself
f i yeah yeah and one
and one one and one and return one
answer yeah okay what's missing
yeah because if we're not using the
cache these will be exponential yeah
we need to for each fn we only calculate
it once
right yeah because next time we don't
need to calculate it
this is called what what dynamic
programming
top down or bottom up uh
top down top down okay yeah because we
take away fn and we
going with three
yeah we're calculating from i from f 0
to x 1. okay
yeah okay so now another one
another one and remember we can use that
we can
declare a notebook yeah without the
cache we can use this one
we can use a notebook passing as a
parameter if
if n in notebook return notebook n right
and before we return it we can store the
values in the
notebook okay something like notebook
and equals value
and return value yeah remember return
value yeah
define remember define food and notebook
and you can
using what using a set yeah yeah not
understand not the same
book dictionary i know if
and in notebook pretend
no book end right because look it you
need to write this
like this and it's better we just get
rid of everything
and do this magically well it is
cash cash cash okay cash
money
[Music]
numbers yeah numbers and then n equals
length we need to find out the numbers
first length first
if n is if n is zero
return zero yeah because and if
n is one written one if there's only one
animal in in the array
what's wrong with that no if no there's
only one element in array what's the
longest subsequence
longer is increasing subsequent even
there's only number one
one one yeah one okay now we need to
store this
arrays in the dp values in an array
let's say dp equals beginning would be
one right
yeah because each value will be each
the longest increasing subsequence that
ends
at each number is at least one right
yeah
and right times n plus one okay
times n plus one okay then four
i in range
n right then we do another loop for
j in range
i okay so basically look this
number okay this is the number
uh one zero two n okay two n plus one
okay
and then i will be here when we
when we know i this is value we start
from j
j will be this point yeah
to get it so look when i is five
when i is five all right look
when i is five z will be zero to
four when i is ten zero and j will be
one
two will be the range of
will one 089 we're done okay so
this is basically give the complexity of
our
n there's four there's four over
n n square
smaller than lambs i what do i write
here can you write this bit
if this number is look like 10
return if a is smaller than 10
so what should we do we should update
return no yeah we need to
feel the value of tp1 look
if a is smaller than j this this is this
is d
this is z this is i if numbers j
smaller than numbers i then we need to
update dp i equal
equals maxima you need to do this
maximum dpi
is the same thing and dpy
dpi
with our
the longest subsequence that ends the
number i right number one right
so we need to find the maximum value of
the otp value
right tp0 dp1 db2 dv3 yeah i'm right
got it so it's not the last element okay
so you should we should return return
return max dp
max dp so it's all the values the
maximum value in the dp array do you get
it
the previously that one was a those kind
of mistake okay let's write it again
let's write it again so just to give you
a
define f n right and then cache yeah
catch suppose we we know the numbers
here okay
that if n equals
if a equals one return
return one right if
now we do this answer equal
one for i in
range and yeah
answer equals what
[Music]
we need to check if num
i smaller number
n right if it's smaller than we can say
answer equals max every
answer and that will be f
i what fy1
if this i is smaller than n so these
ants economy will be uh
if you are okay
don't look at my nose it's slightly
different okay you need to understand
okay you need to understand before you
know the answer okay
just guess before yeah look this is the
procedure fn and when we calling it we
need to return
return what maximum of
f f i for
i in range
n right because because
f n look because this f n is the longest
increasing subsequence that ends the nth
number
right right so it's not an answer
the last element is not the the longest
increasing subsequence four
minutes the longest stop increasing
subsequent
is not uh needed to be
including the last animal am i right
yeah
do you understand so so so you'll be
the maximum of f i
where i is from from one
from zero to n
right all right look two three
four five and then uh
let's say ten uh
how can we do this the last element five
nine ten eleven two okay what's the
longest subsequence
all right what's the longest subsequence
you can think of yeah three yeah okay so
look
this f f zero is what f zero is one
zero the longest number
not five this is num num is already
zero is five but f zero is one
the longest increasing subsequent that
ends with number five how many
one to five no one to four
do you guess what's the longest what's
the number of longest subsequence that
ends in number five in this array what's
that what's it and
the end ends in number five
how many what's the longest increasing
subsequence that ends in number five
why is two why is it two starting from
left
why is it two what's the answer
ends in number five can you find any
subsequent that ends in number five
ryan what's the longest one sorry
no i mean something something fine not
starting with
five ends with number five t5
sorry why
you don't care about the rest i mean say
any number that long is subsequent
ends number five how many
why is it four come on you still don't
understand what's the donkey subsequent
the answer in number five
one what what are you thinking what ends
in number five what's the number
what's the longest subsequence in the
end number ten
one what is one no
two five and ten you got it
okay what's the number it's coming in
number eleven three
yeah what's the number common sorry
why is it four can you find the four you
know just say one two three four what's
this what's the longest
subsequent that ends in number two
one one yes because you cannot find
anything do you understand there's
gonna be one thing yeah yeah okay so
what's the longest subsequent in this
array
is it one it's not one right that's why
we're not picking the last value right
we pick all the best value highest value
in this array
correct do you understand now
do you understand yeah just to give you
that's why look we check we check all
the value if lambda's i smaller than
most way then we update it this is
dynamic programming
the spirits of dynamic programming okay
yeah so look i'm writing another
sequence okay three
five seven maybe
three five one
zero okay can you write
the f value f f zero
okay f1 that's a teamwork u2 okay f3
f4 and f5 f5
and then and then
and tell me what's the longest
subsequent longest increasing
subsequence of this question and then we
can end this class can you do it please
f3
oh f3 yes thank you for reminding me
okay i have three here
okay can you load it please
that's definitely one there's six of
them
and there's only five numbers oh
okay okay so sorry
okay okay so f zero f1 f2
f3
and f4
come on
subsequently it ends with this number
this number is numberless number in this
number okay the first one is definitely
one
this one okay
okay that's correct
yeah yeah this is correct okay
and what's this come on feel it come on
either way
yeah okay so you got one score okay one
[Music]
yeah yeah the one before i have a
smaller the longest you can find the
longest subsequence
on zero now this one doing well
there's no zero the minimum is one come
on you can start with the number yeah
so what's number one the writing
okay correct f2 f1
okay write it
y is two can you give me a because what
three five okay
and this one one
yeah like that why is one because they
won that's why you can't find anything
that connects with and deal with number
one okay
i think it's true wait wait wait wait
wait wait
number one three no no no you can't go
backwards come on what's this
yeah i think it's two two yeah be
confident come on write two
okay so what's the longest subsequence
here
uh two two because you find the maximum
value of this yeah
yeah do you understand how this problem
is yeah
wait wait wait look the being more than
half
that's okay that's okay look one is
smaller than four
so we know that we know f3
is f3 is f2 plus one all right
yeah let's get it yeah
all right suppose we want the calculator
f3 right
right yeah because one is smaller than
four so we know
is f2 plus one at least it's f2 plus one
right because
f2 we know it already wow okay okay
yeah okay so okay that's it say bye bye
to people
say bye
thank you and see you tomorrow thank you
thank you