hey hello hello hi
mr and mr ryan how are you today cute
okay so today another interesting
problem which is called
removing the duplicate letters character
from a string for example
b b a b c
a okay so if you keep removing look
there are duplicates
look you're fine okay too deep okay
so you know it will become a a b c
and then look hey remove it so you
become bc
okay so i give you at least you need to
tell me this
okay just use a notebook not exactly but
look
if it's a pairing drum what will happen
a a
or maybe a b c c
b a okay so what c c
if it's definitely a b b a now look
when you do this there will be abba and
you can continue removing
a b c d a yeah a b
c b a then it will not be
any anything because you can't remove
any duplicator it's not duplicate
only if it's a range penetrant and
it's a even number and then you like
this even number of pending drum
and you can keep removing keep removing
until it's empty okay
so basically you're giving a string keep
removing the duplicate
two letters neighboring yeah sensitive
letters and here you can't do it anymore
correct so how can we do it any idea
no why do i want to use a notebook cash
how how would you do it no how would you
do it i'm not
asking how many moves i'm asking the
final string so you actually need to
search for the duplicate
letters right yeah how to do it
how to do it normally you know just
intuitively the straightforward you
don't have the first one
you check the others if they're the same
so basically you can do this
checking in the same no you're the same
then remove it yeah
and then how about this a a
can you go like that then no but this is
removed
the thing is when you get rid of this
and then
you need to remove this how would you
able to remove this
you just started again good point so
basically you find any two
you remove it and then the problem
becomes smaller right
yeah because you remove it it becomes
aabc
and how about we apply this algorithm to
this new string again
and here we can delete it so this looks
okay you find two letters
and then bc okay and then you can't
remove it and we determine pc
all right okay so let's try this
problem define
let's do it f okay f s
what's missing
try to be more upbeat okay so look
it might not work and equals
yeah okay then let's start from
i in range it might not work
look why it might not work because
b-a-c-a
b-a-c-a what then you'll return just
lieutenant original because look you
can't find any two duplicates
yeah and you can say
they have to be next to each other
oh yeah okay okay so look i need that
one so we start from the first integer
first one we forgot
column yeah yeah look everything so a a
b c a okay so we start from one so
we start i from one one yeah but we
checked
its previous one yeah right yeah
so if s i equals
s i minus one column yeah look
if this character is is the same as its
previous one which is i minus one yeah
that was what happened we can call this
cell 7 we can
why isn't the first one look look
sorry y i is a first one i
this is one this is yellow one we start
from i
you know because we want to check next
previous one right
look this is the same look if i
is smaller than i minus one okay so what
happens
so for example there are another
character here okay so
we want to skip these two right yeah we
want to peel the string c
b c a right on opca which is nothing
so return what f this look we're calling
itself to solve
a smaller problem we allow these two
characters all right
yeah so that would be s
column column yeah i minus one
so that's the previous part i minus one
plus
s this is i yeah i plus one yeah
column yeah it means to start from i
plus one to the n
this is mean from beginning to i minus
one yeah
all right so calling itself to solve a
smaller problem yeah
and then if if you reach this end what
should we return
can you tell me what should we return
here guess well i am way
so no look and return
[Music]
look if you find if you can't find any
any two characters yeah
and this will not get into the this
eighth chair yeah
yes yeah and that will happen we can as
just written simply as
a copy of s yes what's the capacity
sorry o n no
this this is a single loop but how about
it
look look okay oh and square where's
that
one look at
abc cbi look i tell you why it's a n
square look quadratic look yeah look
it's a square
n look yeah this is calling itself and
look look
a b c okay i find a duplicate yeah yeah
i find that duplicated
but i need to go start from the
beginning to check these again
right yeah every time you need to go n
to go and go and
then let n times then there will be n
squared in a scale n square okay
can we do better can we do better
do we need to actually we want it
because the problem is that when you
do this a b c b c b a
when you find this duplicate right you
are rewinding to from the beginning yeah
if there are any
characters there you need to go back and
then do it again
but actually we don't need to right yes
we just need to go back to once yeah
because look this is delete and we just
need to find out the previous one if his
next one
if it's then we remove it and keep
removing yeah
do you get it if there are lots of
characters here and then you have
bb here right these are not they are not
duplicate numbers here
yeah if you find these two the same
you don't need to go back to the
beginning to check please because you
already know
if there's no duplicate all right yeah
the only difference is this one previous
one could be the same as the next one
does it make sense yeah does it make
sense yeah
so we can use the data structure called
call stack look what's that
can you can you remind me what's
happening
first thing that's stopped okay so look
i have a stack
yeah look look a b
c uh cba okay
yeah look at this this string okay i
have a stack
okay i have a stack
okay hey hey look everything
yeah i look at the string i here s i
a is it the same as as the previous
as the top of the stack the stack is
empty now right
so it's not the same i push it here
yeah put a stack here look look at this
step yeah
and i move it to here is b
the same as a no no i put it push
in b yeah look then c c
is is it the same as the top of step
no i push it in c okay and then look
you see top look the same as the top of
the stack
yes then what do we do we take out
love it out yeah we eat it we eat it and
then we keep going
look the top of that then i'm b we are b
now it's b the tuple of step yeah
i eat it and i move it to a it's a
topless deck yeah okay so let's
put nothing look look if there are
anything there like d
here and then go here it's b component
the simulator is that
no i push it in d okay
so the answer would be in a step
bad yeah okay so
look let's let's do this another e here
so you'll be
you'll be look e
yeah b i eat it a i eat it
b i push it in so the answer will be e b
when you when you pop out let's reverse
all the time
in okay so
look we can do this yeah we can do a
list
and then in each in python we can use
the list to
at least at least to to simulate the
stack yeah okay all right
invite this a little bit look
step step equals look
yeah this is empty stack yeah at least
empty stack
four
x what's called what's missing here okay
look if we said we need to get ahead of
that
step but if if the stack is empty we
we don't want to get it yeah because if
the stack is empty there's no way to get
the top of step
right so we need to say if then
i is not equal
to to the top of the stack what's the
top of the stack
so it's look thing look look at i minus
i
b c you push it to abc what's the top of
the stack
c or a c yeah you just looking this way
you push d let d will be the top step
yeah
rotating 90 degree yeah okay if i
know not equal to st minus one yeah
if the step is empty or the top is not
equal to the new element we push it in
right so
st dot append all right
okay what open what depend
what i i we're done yes
[Music]
is not empty yeah it's not empty
and and i
equals to the top of the stack reversely
object yeah
then we need to pop it yeah pop it pop
so probably
look at a b c look at now
now the next thing you see yeah c
is the same as the top of the stack
we don't need to pop i because pop is
just
by default just getting rid of the last
element of this
array which means the top of the step
hey else column
yeah st dot one we need to now
if this is d we need to push it in so
apparent open what
open what okay what's s
i open i okay now
for example the last one is abc yeah
abc we want to look yeah
okay look look
look now suppose the final stack
is a b c let's stay so what's the final
string is it cba or abc
abc abc yeah so now this is an array we
want to
make abc into a string abc remember we
talked about a method called join
yeah return we wanted to join by empty
string
dot join look join what
join us there okay so rainbow look every
look
all right so look
a b c this is a list if i
if i got space don't join then i'll
become a b c
yeah e okay
what's the time complexity
[Music]
we are using a data structure but we go
going through the string
once or twice or ten times
o n square o n times n
we are going through this a b c only
once so what's the
o m right because we don't need to go
back right
look h yeah look previously
previously eric previously when we
raised the
character we need to go back again right
when are we finished
soon okay but now we don't need to we
don't need to
go back all right yeah yeah for all the
only time what's the space complexity
why is someone eating
using one yeah we're done because we're
using stack in the worst case
the stack will contain all the n
characters in the string
if they are non characters to be
uh next to each other the same right all
right
so that's the worst cases uh
yeah that's it that's it for today [ __ ]
[ __ ]
no no no no no no night time no no no
that's it
bye-bye