hello hello hello hello mr are you mr
ryan how are you today good good
okay so do you still remember parent
germ yeah
penny dog so can you tell me what is a
parenting drum
it's a word that's spelled with
which is
[Music]
so basically if i give you a raise
car and
race car yeah so you need to tell me the
perpendicular i know how many number
of the parent one substrings
what's the substring so basically it's
continuous you know the subsequence is
that
you can you can jump you can skip right
but sub substring is not is that the
substring
look r is the circle i is a substring ac
is a string
ac is the subsequence so it needs to be
continuous piece
did you get it so that the current
subsequence look
race car is a substance yeah yeah
and look c e c is a subsequence
yeah it's a parent of some substring
right
yeah and can we find any others no
no i think that's it oh and look
a c e c a look look a c e c a yeah
yeah okay can you find any other things
no
okay so yeah e and each one is a
parameter so each one r is a parameter
a c e c a r so we need to count how many
of them
right so for example this one you need
to tell me is there has to be a pillar
yeah it has look one two three four five
six seven okay seven
plus one two uh one
one yeah plus one
yeah and plus one so
it needs to it has ten percent
substrings what are they sorry
look seven is each letter yeah
r-a-c-e-c-a-r okay
one is a-c-e-c
a okay this is a parent another one
c-e-c another one race car
okay
yeah i just counted r-a-c-e-c-a-r
yes they already counted one right
the one is already included in each one
yeah yeah so that's ten
or less tens of substrings okay
so how can we count it any idea
if you're not sure the first thing you
need to think about is
oh if it's there's an even
number all you need to do
is you uh
you write it down yeah and yes divided
by
two and write and write what's it
divided by two
and then add it together
no you might not work for some strings i
mean the first first acronym you need to
think of
is what to do is the most stupid way
which is blue force right yeah so how
can we improve first
so the substring we can blue first use
no no subsequence is o to n right we are
talking about the
substring which is only how many
substrings can we have if
n look a b c how many substrings
abc how many substrings zero
b one a b c
a b b c a b
c you see they're not jumps i know but
i'm
talking about the number of the
substrings how many substrings
how many substrings so basically if
there are n characters how many
substrings do we have
so if we define the left of the
substring is i
the right of the substring can be for
anything from i
to n right yes
all right yeah yeah so we can
some if we use in a for loop
for i in range look away
n and now we can do this for j
in range start from i
to n so and then we can get the
substring
between i to j yeah all right all right
all right
do you get it eric this is substring so
what's the complexity of these
what's the time complexity what's the
time cons
complexity if you see two ends two
fourths
until n square yeah we're done i said
that
okay so look look we need o n
square to find to iterate to
blue force no yeah to proof of all the
substrings
in o n 2 o n square and
given a string given a substring what's
the term complexity if you want to
we want to verify it is a apparent
journal what's the term complexity
[Music]
yes we are done so all together you'll
be all cubic right
yeah okay so should we draw this look
yeah n cubic yeah cubic
n three to the power three yeah power
and only three okay so define
s less than s what's missing column
okay so now let's call the answer equals
zero here right
okay for i in
range yes length
n right turn
depends on how you want okay let's play
range
no range starts from i and ends with
lens n
right so what does it mean here it means
look i
love array i i determine
i and then i every time i have i and
then i loop it from
j will be from i to to to here yeah this
is i
and then this is j okay okay yes
all right do you understand look and
then how can we check the parent journal
how how do we check if
the string is apparent remember
sorry step step you can use the step for
company we
how how we use it we take pointers two
points
always reverse it yeah yeah yeah oh
let's do it in the reverse one which is
simple look
look uh look look this is
let's say this stop stream yeah
substring
equals look away how can we get the
s that's what that's what can you write
it as what
s i i yes and column and y
minus one minus one there's j here you
want to use it
we only use it okay j plus one
j plus one look because this is from the
star
this is n remember n is always up to but
not including so we have the plus one am
right
do you get it look this is i and then j
will be
here and only i will be saying so every
time
if we iterate we will have n square
n substring right and look this is
substring and how can we check if it's
the reverse it's the same
look if sub
equals it's reverse we want to reverse
it how do we reverse this
remember we're using this syntax common
column minus one yeah remember this is
the
so we look us up column column minus one
means to reverse this stuff
if look if the reverse version is
exactly the same
then we answer what we want to add it
another one increment answer yeah yeah
add equal
one we're done and then return answer
we're done okay so look what's the time
complexity
oh and square this is what
o and q look this is o right
look o n o n square and
and this another end here look this is a
hidden end
so it's o and cubic okay remember this
can we do better i always want to
yeah of course we can i'll give you a
hint dynamic
programming foundation
how can we use the diagram yeah
memorization so how many kinds of
dynamic programming
we have memorization
so how many kinds of dynamic programming
do we have
motivation
top down yeah
the program of previous approach is that
we have to check
each possible substring for to to check
each substring if it's a
pending term right but sometimes we
don't need to check am right do you
understand
all right listen look if
a if a b we know ap
it's not a prediction right right
yeah it's not paranoid so if i put
another c
is it a challenger no if i put x
you see the paragraph no of course
because this is not parallel so and you
put any letters
around it it doesn't make it pendulum
right but this is the value
i know i know so so look if i use a
i use a function f i j okay look
f i j means means what
means that the s from i
to j plus one j yeah
if to mean if this is a parallel right
all right eric so what does it mean e
equals what
s i equals sj
n right look if if
this is a parent drug i don't care how
many in there right
if this side this is this is an index i
this is at
index j if this needs to tangent it
means that
these two letters must be the same right
yeah and
these inside should be apparent all
right
does it make sense so this is broken
down to list
s i equals sj and what can you write it
and f1 f-i-j means
f-i-j means
the substring between index i to index j
is apparent or not okay so it means what
it needs to the almost
characters needs to match it needs to be
the same so a e
must be equal to b right am i
s i equals x j and and one
and what i need speed
i move here i move here so this speed
what's this b what's the
smaller problem
f what you just need to tell me what
f i z equals f a b
no no no okay huh
i move towards each other smaller
problem
f what i
i one
[Music]
so we can save this value right we can
save
each s i j yeah all right yeah so we
need
o n square to to calculate this is a
value and then we just need a one
constant to get it so over all time
complexity will be o n square
will reduce the complexity to one
uh one scale right i show you
okay so now i'm going to write it okay
if
okay now i i thought if i bigger than j
i would return true for now i'll tell
you why okay
and then else i return
s i equals j
and f i plus one j
minus one right yes yeah okay
so look what's missing in here
cash because i need to cash it right so
after cash
then every
pair of i j will be calculated only once
right so how many possibilities of i j
pairs
how many possibilities are i j pairs
if if i uh if i is bigger than zero
smaller than let's say smaller than n j
is bigger than zero
and smaller than n how many is a
possibility
and n minus one
and one minus two sorry
three what you talking about look i
i i could be from zero to n
and j will be from zero to n so how many
possibilities of i
is a okay n yeah
n times n this is the complexity of
these
all right got it okay now
now look we just need to add a array
look
answer equals zero and we can just do
this for i in
range n right n is the length of s yeah
and f for j in range
range i n right
if can you write any speed for me and i
can say written answer
so can you write can you write like this
is for me
if one it's what i have function for you
to call
if what
before
j
so this is o n look o n square
this is another one square so all your
articular is
how many complexes
is o and o n squared and o square is
what a
keyboard no no no a
o n squared times n is our cubic o n
squared
plus o n squared n squared plus n square
equals 1
2 n square yeah 2 n squared right
yeah but we drop the constant okay so if
still is o n
square all right yes
because this is this is constant i'm
only
performing two times of o n square so
the complexity is still on square
okay but if this is if i
if i look eric if i move this function
if i move this inside this four like the
first one the blue force yeah
right then it's one square times
o n right so in this case it's o and
cubic do you
get it yes and
look uh look this is answer yeah we can
do this in one line
look this is a very very uh python
way to calculate look look eric remember
this a
look you're looking yeah yeah
okay so we can do this we can still keep
it and we can return
return blah f
i z for i
in we can do this using this this kind
of thing like range
and and then follow j
in range i
and right and then what and
uh and this will create an array a list
and then i just need to count counter
one
count true right count the truth
and then you will tell me how many of
them is parent
because f i j because f i j
says is what is
is means that the the substring between
i and j if it's apparent
look at why this i plus i
bigger than j is the true you know what
i tell you look all right bb is it a
paragraph yeah okay this is i
this is z z
p b f i and j next to each other right
yeah s i equals x j right
so n f i plus one j minus one so i will
be
i will be here j will be here right so i
is bigger than j right if relaxing the
case i return true
right so this will simplify the
implementation if
if you say this is written first
that's fine but you you have to make
this a special case
which is if i plus one equals j
and s i equals straight and return true
right
otherwise return s i equals s j and
f i plus one j into minus one correct
yes
so i if i return true then i don't mean
that uh separate check yeah because i
can
in this case i can still handle this bb
okay
how about bab yeah
i j alright look
s i equals sj right
f i plus one j minus one so i and j will
continue to a
still equal right still equal
yeah okay so this is the beauty of
styling programming right
because we know a is the planning drum
we put two similar things on both sides
still parent drum
we put another thing on the both sides
still apparently yeah correct
yeah yeah we don't need to check the in
inside
match because we already know this is
the palindrome we just keep adding we
are
using the previous result okay top down
how about butter up what's butter up
what's top down
all right yeah up
yeah so we we defined look we didn't eat
cash
yeah i don't use the cash because using
cash is for recursion yeah
yeah i have a question i asked for this
value i and j and then
the computer say okay i have put i have
a cache
let's check if i j has been calculated
before
right it has been calculated it has been
we have called it to calculate it then
that's fine
we just take the value without
calculating do you get it
yeah let's see it's like
you're doing homework right you're doing
homework like ryan
likes to look for the answers yeah let's
answer the [ __ ] yeah
yeah without actually doing the homework
yeah sometimes you do that right
yeah i know you do that yeah that answer
[ __ ] is the cash
so it's i pretend i'm ryan okay
write the first question okay okay and
then i check list
i check this in the answer sheet okay i
found the answer and then i just
directly copy right
yeah got it does it make sense
okay
so we need to create a dp array right
for the button out we need to array for
pp alright
dp equals
equals let's see
two times n
for i in range n okay so let's create a
dp array
which contains two dimensional yeah all
right yeah
another story is for i in
range let's start from the n minus one
from the right hand side
look i think i will start from here
to the left yeah to the left and right
let's look star
alright look at the range function can
take three parameters the star
stop step step minus one means
you will be decrementing start from n
minus one stop
minus one but not up to minus one so the
last value will be zero right
and then for j in
range i yeah i start from i
i learn to n then i can say dp
i j equals
s i equals sj
and n1 everything right here
dpij this is array okay
s i equals sj and and what
and what dpy and tp1 can you write it
dpf
dp i j i d p i j equals s i equals
straight and
minus one yeah that's it so now we
put we compete no yeah no yeah
com completing this uh feeling is the dp
array and now we can
we can do the same right for i equals
and for j because then if
if dpi is a now we answer plus one yeah
this this bit is the same the time
complexity is
oh and o and one
no y o n
because this big is all n squared and
this b
is still one square all squared plus one
square
squared but we drop the constant yeah so
you become o n squared
what's the space complexity
one we are using the dp array what
n what is that a one it's a two
dimensional array so one
square o n square come on see
because we need our own square space to
store
all the possibilities of the substrings
right am right
yes okay so
say bye so which one you think is better
i don't know i think which one
boy boy you don't know okay so which one
you like
okay okay let's say bye see you tomorrow