hey hello mr mr ryan how are you today
good good okay so today we talk about uh
permutation
per new patient cheers
do you we talked about this before yeah
commutation always permutation
it's like look at the exclusive numbers
yeah it's just a different way to with
the
you're given a list of the elements and
permutation is that the number of
possible
different orders yeah so look one two
three we're given at least one two three
and then the six ways
whoa yeah three times two times one six
ways so look
two three one is one of the permutation
yeah
yeah all right so if you want to write
this four permutation how many
one two three one three two
two one three two three one three one
two and one three two one we are done
okay so basically this one has three
possibilities the second place
has two problems and the third one one
possibility
so that's uh how many if there are n
elements how many possibilities
we talk about n factorial where there
are n factorial yes because this is
n times n minus one times n
minus two times tier one right this is
exactly
n factorial all right yes okay so today
the task
is to given uh a list of
unique elements okay you can say it's
unique it doesn't contain duplicates
and then you need to generate all these
possibilities
interesting any ideas how are we doing
this
how we're doing look let's do this three
uh one two three for example how can we
generate this
you check how many numbers are in the
list
yeah i know i already this is nums okay
let's say this is nums
okay okay so now how can we generate
these four
permutations any any idea how we
doing this
any idea what brian no
yes yes working yes that's very good
how can we swap and how about look look
look let's say we are here yeah we swap
we swap with with the hourly elements on
the
on or on the right or hand side so we
saw one with one so it doesn't change
we swap look we swap we swap one
and one okay one and three and then
one and two so that comes to one three
and then slope one and three that would
be three two
one right yes all right
that's like when you're here you swap it
with anything
on or on the right hand side okay
and then you go to the next one so when
you go to the next one so let's look
two you're going to the next one right
and then you again you swap
with one and three so that will be
another one two three one
and then again you swap two and one i
know b and
three one two right here
and then look sorry how about one three
two
yeah yeah okay so look three one swap
will use one
and then go to the next one and then
swap
sub three with two so that's one three
got it so this way you can generate all
the
permutation okay they say make sense
look
i give you one i explain one more time
okay so this is
like that okay one two
three okay so now i'm at this position
all right i can i want to swap
one to one then that's the one
possibility one and one
and then i move it to the next then the
next position will be
next permutation will be from here right
maybe yeah maybe i know i know how to do
it
so now the first
first one would be one right and then
the second one would be two
the third one would be three one two
three
okay so when you swap one first one with
one
it's here right when you spur with one
and two
it's here right when you sleep swap
three with one it's real the first one
yeah and then you go down go next
you go next then you'll be and when you
swap one with one
the first one is determined is one and
then you have two three right
all right you need to permutate two
three
two so look you swap two
with two then the second one is two you
swap two with three the second one is
three
right very good yeah when you swap two
is two
then obviously you you can only have
three a lot
because three you move to the next when
you swap three with two
and then here is two round right you
move it to the next so it's two
okay got it okay how about this
you you one swoop with two
right then you become two one three and
then now you move it to here
right again you can swap one with one so
it doesn't change
yeah right you swap with three then
you become three and one is one
obviously you'll be three here and then
one is three and then one will be left
next would be one
okay yeah okay let's take a look at the
last example okay
three one two three look you swap with
one and three they'll become
one three one two but you are not at the
second position yeah all right look
okay you turn your to the right look one
swap is one so what do i put here
one slope is one it doesn't change so
what's your opportunity one
one okay one swapping two so it's two
one and you move it to the next so so
that's two
right and the next one will be one and
then when you it turns off the next one
is two
okay so look
first one three possibilities the second
one right two possibility and the third
one only one possibility because
you pick two and there's only one right
so there's six right
yes what's the complexity time
complexity
um
that's very easy how many how many
possibilities are we give
can we get no how many possibilities are
we getting
here and factorial yeah whether
because look this is they did we need so
easy
[Music]
yes i know it's not easy what's the
space complexity if we want to
store all these in an array what's a
space conversation yeah that's an easy
question yeah
okay yeah easy okay
let's do this look cash no we don't need
the cash today defined because we are
generating
so we are generating these using the
recursion yeah recursion
yeah we define term let's say
permutation okay
let's give a number here right
this is at least to store all the
permutations yeah
and given the numbers like one two three
which is unique okay
okay all right look now we define
another function called
uh let's call it helper helper function
okay or maybe dfs
that's what search okay or recursion
therefore search
yeah because recursion is kind of it's
not exactly okay maybe just to call it
helper
to prevent it's misleading okay and then
we have these current current
okay current position so at the
beginning it will be
one two three at the beginning you'll be
pointing here this is current okay which
is yellow okay currently use zero
helper and and what
and what and maybe that's enough okay
uh look if current
equals
length of numbers right alright
look if this current index is reaching
the end
so we have one permutation now we need
to add it into the answer yeah
so then we say answer a pen
let's take a deep copy all right
remember we need to
take the copy because if you don't take
a deep copy you
you just copy the reference right we
don't want that right
all right so we copy lamp right
and then return that's it
and then now look look we we are from
colorado right
all right current now we need to go
through current current plus one current
pass two
until the end and swap each one to the
carbon right
yeah look then four
i in range
current current and what
the end the end of the lumps so that
will be men's
lungs right all right
and then now i will be current current
plus one column plus two
and for each one i need to swap with
current right
right so look helper
whatever one no
swap current so lumps
i and lumps
left and current needs to be solved how
do we swap
it a and b how do you swap the value of
a and b
how do you solve it usually how do you
solve it
a how do you write it a and b i want to
solve the value of
add one no no no a and b i want to swap
a and b
values how do you slope it you know
n b equals a no that wouldn't work
that's a good try that wouldn't work why
is that a equals b
a and b both equals b and b equals a a
and b both equals b right because a is
already equals to b
got it so how do you fix this you can
you can do this you can have a variable
t equals a i save the value in t right
right and then what a equals b
and then b equals one
t where down look a equals b now b
equals t because t is the original value
of a
so let's swap yeah got it but you can
in person you can do this a comma b
equals b
comma a easy correct
a equals b b equals a simpler
yes okay so look here we only swap
please
numbs i numbs current right equals one
[Music]
and now look we swap it yeah we swap
this value and then we need to move it
to the next one
right all right all right look
this is very useful look i already
swapped it
all right i always look i'm currently
here right
all right look look at my hands i'm
currently
currently here right and now
my hand i yeah i will be current
look i yeah yeah yeah and each one i
need to swap it
yeah look at my hand eh yeah
i need to swap it after i swap it i need
to call this function to
to permutate the next right so you'll be
help
help can you feel the value here
help her and after swapping
i need to move it back right after
sloping i need to move it back so this
this thing will be copied again really
so that look i'm currently here look
after i swapping i need to move it to
the next
so what's this what's here help
what's what's here you're very close
look
i swap it look after i swap it two is
one then it becomes two one three but
now i can't i need to
move it i want to i already i already
determine
this place i want to dominate the
the num no
this is current and i have a current and
i want to move it to the next what's
what what's that
this this is current
and then equals three current
equals no alright you need to understand
this
i'm currently pointing here i want to
i want to try each possibility of this
position right
so that would be one two three i swapped
one with one i swapped two with one i
swapped three with one after i
make after i determine this place i need
to permeate
with the current this is current and i
want to move it to the next one
then
so hard to understand this do you
understand yes
because the current is incrementing and
when it's recently end
it means we have a permutation and then
we editory answer right
so here i'm calling helper what should i
put here value
and then return what answer
return answer yes and help this is what
kind of value is this
sorry k up with the initial value
there's no current here i want to
initiate from my first position first
position
is what length
what's the first position of the array
what's the first partition you just need
to give me a number i want to start from
the first position
no it's not the one where is the second
what's the first position
yes because yeah this is the first one
that's the big zero
yeah it's yellow and then the movement
moving one column which is the end we
have a permutation
do you get it do you really understand
look
yeah look one two
three yeah right current is here i'm at
the
beginning zero y when current is zero
i will be from zero to
three right to two right yeah i
in range current current is zero now i'm
right all right
and then equals one then sum equals one
then
how many elements three three okay zero
two three but not up to three so gl
one two right zero one two i will be
zero one two one i is zero
i swap it with num zero numbers here so
i swap this value with excel so it
doesn't change
right yes when i is one i swap
one with two right yeah when i
one lumps equals three uh two i swap
with three and one right why i need to
drop each time i
that i'm determining this position
i'm checking how many possibilities
that's three possibilities right
yeah so i'm checking
i'm letting each possibility stand
in this position right after i
understand
that position and then i need to move it
to the next one
which is column plus one right column
plus one right
and i'm dealing another similar problem
with this with a smaller size of problem
right
but after i theory with it i need to
swap it back right this is this
this is very important i need to swap it
back
all right yeah okay
so look one two three and then i swap it
swap it like two then will be two
one three right two one three but after
i
i do this i need to swap it back so
i need to swap it back so because if i
don't
swap people what happened if i don't
swap it back like two one three
and then the next time then it becomes
three and two swap it but i
originally i want to swap it one and
three right if i swap it land that will
become three one two then
there will be some missing got it
do you understand this one because for
this one
one two three i want to swap it with uh
there will be one two three two one
three and three
two one right
yeah that's uh i'm talking about the
first position yeah
swap it swap it swap it if i don't swap
it back
look if this is i don't swap it back
then that would be
three and two that will become three
one two not not three to one all right
yeah does it make sense yeah
really yeah okay
okay so
can you explain to me why this is a deep
copy
just make sure you're listening
it would be the same if we not deep copy
then if i push leave answer
as answer append alarms you'll be all
the same
you'll be all the same yeah that's what
i said because it's a reference it's
alias you know alias yeah is that it's
like i call you eric
and call you uh mr lai
mr airy both are the same person
yeah if then if i add a pen lamp
then all i get is
six alright all i get is a six copy
a six reference to lungs then that would
be
the result will be all one two three one
two three one two three one two three
one two three because
they are the same right i'm right
but when i edit when i need to add the
numbers lumps to the answer
then at that point at the point of time
the nouns contains different
permutations right it could contain
three to one right
all right and then i need to dip copy
and i will copy that value three two one
to a new array
right it will be diff so it will be the
right so
so basically it's like that what's the
copy okay
equals all right equals
e r
i c okay alright equals
okay and then i need to do this like
uh here i see r on z
yeah and then i have another one eric
two
eric two equals eric
so what do you think what will happen if
i change look if i do this
erry2 every
[Music]
so what do you think the area at arab 2
will be
so area to be what
i think this value will be what an array
of what
yeah that's what you mean because this
is the reference you're pointing to the
same position
but but look if i say this deep copy
all right so what happened this time
every two append every
line so aaron will be what
eric will be one every two
no no every two equals d copy everything
then eric two dot append line so airing
will be one
error
yeah everything yeah that's what it
means when you copy it then you become
two independent things right
your money for you you manipulate with
one doesn't affect
the other one but if you don't have
listing copy the
especially the list in python is passed
by
reference listener what's the reference
alias it's the same
right so eric two equals eric that means
eric and every two
yeah all right an area too a pointing
look these two are pointing to the same
place all right yeah
and but when you do this area to equal a
stick copy area what happened look
look this line will be gone and then
there will be another
thing yeah and then here you change it
here a dozen of them here right
correct okay good job today
good job today say bye bye see you
tomorrow everybody
bye bye bye bye