oh hello hello hello
mr ryan how are you today good good very
good okay so we're almost weekend yeah
okay so now i can have this piece so
today uh we talked
about uh many data structures long time
ago yeah
yeah then what's data structures
what are the uses data
any other data structures can you
release a few of them
and then we need different stack stack
yes stack you yes all right
yeah also tree yeah linked list all
right
yeah these are data structures so stata
structures are
the kind of containers to hold data
right
day one so today we're going to talk
about this
tri actually it's pronounced as try not
tree try
okay try because look
why is it right in english it may be
pretty pronounced as
tree but in it has to be distinct
look then how do you pronounce this
three
three and how do you pronounce this try
try yes you want to make a difference
between these two right
yeah that's an american yeah okay so try
so try how you just put accent on it
try try as t-r-y okay
try the same pronunciation try okay so
what i'll try
is basically yeah yeah
it's a tree okay
look it's a tree but it's uh uh not a
binary tree it's a prefix tree
prefix tree prefix tree okay
okay so what it looks like eric
what is prefix tree
so for example for example like
what i have a list of
now let's say a prefix to eric and ryan
okay
and and mommy and daddy four okay look
e-r-i-c these these
fours uh i i you were given these four
four string okay additionally yeah with
this full stream
ryan
marvin
and daddy her name is hue
yeah i know thank you so this is least
is the list of
the dictionary right right yeah yeah
and then suppose you are given another
string and then another list of string
and you want to check
you want to check for example like
[Music]
so any any strings and you want to find
out
find out how many of these are the
prefix of these for example er
can be found here yeah right so it's a
prefix
so er is a prefix a prefix
of eric okay right because
yeah yeah like
rice rice
no because look it doesn't right but
look
i can say ric is a surface you know the
opposite is the surface
surface of eric because it looks look
right
it's it's start from the end am right
yeah
can you listen please i'm going to test
you later if you're not listen
i am okay so
look all right so you understand what's
uh
prefix yeah okay so these you're given
these
these let's say four and n dictionaries
okay e c
and prefix no no no so e is the prefix
of area
er is the prefix of array eri is a
prefix of error e-r-i-c is the prefix
now area
c is the surface of eric ic is the
surface of an array
r-i-c is the surface so area e-r-i-c is
a surface right-hander
look i is the prefix of ryan
r y r y a
n and cervix n a
yen rhyme you want to understand the
prefix of
it yeah okay so now everything
please stop drawing okay so look you're
given this
candidate candidate string okay
candidate string
and your task is to find out how many of
these
are the prefix of on the prefix of the
of this dictionary so so how can we do
this
blue first yeah yeah proof so how can we
do this so for each one
dynamic no no no we're not talking about
the enemy problem today look
er today look yeah
we find we go through look if they are
if they are n strings in the first place
and if they are m string in the second
base
okay and if the first first string the
length
is uh the average length i'm talking
about the average length okay so if
let's say uh t
and the second lens will be u then the
average okay
so now for each one you need to you need
to go
through this list right and t yeah
to find out if it's a prefix all right
yes
so the complexity is what look
they are m right m
yes and you need to search for n times
right yes all right
times n times and then each one
you need to you need to search what for
each one
you need to test if
if the if this is the prefix of that
right so you need to test what we how
many times if that you
you average you let the length of you
okay
then you need to test times you so this
is the complexity okay
got it yeah yeah because there are
m strings and then for each one i need
to test
any string and for each one because i
use m
o n or u a lot yeah yeah
yeah that's complexity and the u is the
side is the size of these for example
they are all
size two for example okay size two okay
so look
this is one two three four five four
times
one two three four four times what two
so like how many times 32 times got it
you need for computer you need to
compare 32 times
got it yes can we do better
that's the beauty of a try so we can we
can be
we can be it has more letters than that
it's not it's a look
we are we are checking the prefix okay
if we are
unsufficient yeah if suffix is similar
if we are not checking prefix if we are
going to find out how many of these
strings are in the in the
in this dictionary so can we do better
we can
obviously do better because we can use a
notebook
right we remember these
words in the notebook right got it and
then we just need to
go through these m times
right and then look because there are
you can
supposed to be together no there are
different forwards for dictionaries so
i'm asking
how many of these characters how many of
these strings
appear in here so it's not perfect
enough
then we can record the words in a
notebook
right and then
we can just look it up so so the the
timing
would be these will be removed so the
timing will appear
because it needs to if there are new
characters for each one
it needs the u times to calculate the
key
hash key and i'm looking for so you know
when we're looking for the notebook we
need to hash it we need to
have a key right so this key function
key function of this string like uh a
string
you know and this will give me a key and
then i i go to this dictionary
go to the notebook to find out if
there's a if
there's a an entry can be
can be opened by this key okay so it's a
one time
a one-time lookup but for to calculate
the key because there are new characters
for each each string
then it needs to owe you time to
calculate the key
okay got it let's find the complexity
with the hash book
if you are looking for the words in the
dictionary is omu okay
but now we're talking about different
problems which is the prefix prefix if
you are you're going to list the
profile search is all m times n times u
right
right let me repeat for each they are m
string
you need to end string right and you
need to look it for
in the end string right for each one you
need to
check you characters right you need to
check your characters
for example look er right and i need to
check here
okay e r okay then it's a prefix okay
right okay if this is not arrogant then
if this is ms
okay m not equal like next one
m not equal m equal but u is not equal
then it jumps
so that's n times n times u okay
yes so the three let's try we
come back to the concept try why we need
to try
why we need to try we built it look so
look here
this is an uh look
this e-i-e-i-c so we built a tree look
this is the root okay empty okay
this is empty okay and then i e
so i have an e here ah
[Music]
c e i z
nothing starting point nothing a dude we
call it
okay and then r e r i c okay
so okay and then now ah
why so basically it's a tree like
this is a dictionary right hey
okay okay maybe i have another one
say the red uh
red okay red okay just to compare red so
what will happen
ah e
d okay okay
this is a tree remember the tree
it's not fine on the tree remember but
it has many many many characters it's
the prefix
got it this is a loot upside down a tree
okay prefecture mommy it could be
okay mommy mom
another one uh let's say uh
ethan okay for the eastern i got e here
so
egg oh okay
okay so basically we use this
three data structure to recall a tree
right
so how does this have i
let me build this build building and
then i can look i want to look for the
prefix
e i got e yeah
ah i got the r okay so this is the
prefix
okay so the length is remember the
length is you okay the length is
you know the height of the tree is u
right and then
r y yes
m s it doesn't have s
okay it doesn't have s so s is none
here none so this is not t
it doesn't have t t in
d c doesn't have c okay so what's the
time complexity how about c
i i n times n
times u look this is m characters yeah
and then the length of the is
so what's the term complexity oh and
something
it definitely wins something oh and what
let's how many u o and u right
yeah look at this is the same as the
very tiny efficiency
remember the first approach we look for
the first one yeah
remember it needs how many times times
another m here right
yeah so we basically reducing the time
contaxion from l
n times n times u to o
and u so which is better which is better
this one the less the better yeah
because look it needs
this much of time but now we're reducing
it
yeah we need we need just a new time
because we
we can look it up in a try prefix tree
right
do you see the beauty of it right yeah
yeah look i want to check if ms is in
the in
in the in the prefix of any of these
words right previously i need to go
through each one right
yeah and this is m times c yeah
y yeah now i don't because i have at
least tried three
then i can look it up okay if the root
next one does it have a ah m
yes we have n and i go to m does it have
a
s no i don't have s so i return fourth
okay yeah so how
then now we can implement this define
yeah define yeah
look the surface so how can we find this
service
remember eric if if we are looking for
the if any
i i give you a question this is to
fear the prefix and how about if we want
to find the surface
do we still can you can we still use
this try
if we want to build a cervix all right
can we check for example if i want to
check ic i have
ic here i see here
this is the surface can we how can we
feel this
tree uh try how can we build this try so
we can look it up like
you are you just turn it upside down
turn it upside
quite close not exactly this is a choice
you come upside down but we can
live upside down no no no what we can do
is what we reverse this
yeah so we can reverse this then we put
it there that would be
c i r e right
and then we're looking up even if i see
if
i c is a suffix then we just look it up
if c i
then look ci is here so you see
look at it when we want to check the
surface
we reverse these words and build a try
in reverse order so you'll be c-i-r-e
and now we will want to check if there's
a surface ic
we reverse this becomes ci then we can
find c
i okay so laser surface do you
understand
yeah okay so now this this is so try
it's better to
eat so actually it's called prefix tree
but you can also call it surface tree
you know you can
make surface tree
become a prefix okay yeah do you get it
sorry listen funny
[Music]
first thing first off q yeah but the
dry one it's a tree it's not it's a tree
so
it you're going to find a tree yeah this
tree is
this is the prefix or surface tree but
we call it try
with with different notes right now we
look it up it's used to look it up
look at look at look up a prefix or a
word
in a dictionary but usually is the
prefix of surface
because if you we are simply if we
simply want to look
look to find if a word it is an
additional what kind of
better data structure can we use
notebook exactly because the notebook is
we can just saw the
words in the notebook and we can look it
up in constant time right
yes okay so now
so the brief let's try is better it is
very powerful if it comes to the prefix
or surface search yeah like the star
wars
you know the the python look if this
e-r-i-c if we want to search if
e-r-i-e-r-i-c starts with e-r-i
then we can do this e-r-i-c
okay this is string and we can use this
top star
start with okay
and then look start with e-r okay
this return true okay do you still get
it
and look stars okay this this we can
choose and then
and if e t this will return y
e i see that this star is e t
then this will return fourth okay okay
return first
okay now now we're implementing this try
okay
look class class
p-r-i-e class okay this is a try not a
note of try
column okay and then now define
and store in underscore and then self
let's see and then we can do this
self color dot data
it's gonna be a lot of writing
dictionary okay
because dictionary key value pair okay
key value pair remember key value player
yeah and we need a ver uh
pulling tuning true or false to to
to say if it's uh ending if the
if this is the note for a word ending
like e-i-i-c
okay e-r-i-c then what's it guys he got
e r i
c and here this we need to set this to
true because
the word a word ends here right
yeah but here no here or before because
this is
in the media fourth right it's not the
dominant
terminal note okay first what's true
right because the words end here
c e r i c okay so self doubt
leave let's say leave equals equal is
false okay
by default it's it's not ending okay
now look array yeah we can insert we
need to
try uh define a word called insert we
insert the word in the try tree right
self what self and then
what okay what common word column okay
okay look current we
are current equals self now we have
at least no as a first note remember
eric
listen here no yeah and then now look
for going through this area yes for for
example this is erica
what is eric okay yeah i see
for i in
what
then we need to find we need to find if
this is
this character if this note has a
character
e as its kit right
if it is i then i will jump to it if not
i create a note and put it there i'm
right
[Music]
good question very good question look
then look
if i
in if i in current
dot yeah
then if it's already e is already here
okay if
e is already here look then i need to
this is current i need to move the
current to here right
yeah so that would be current equals
current
dot theta
bracket i right if not
if not then we need to do this
current the data
i equals try create a node
and put it here and put it here right
look yeah
and then i i need to copy this line here
right current equals current
dot theta i
okay so actually you can you can make
this simple array look
you can reverse the logic here you can
reverse this logic
not and then i need to remove this
and then i can i can i can move this a
little bit here okay
so this belongs to that this then i
if not in if not here then i create a
node
and i move it to least no i create the
node and move it to here
right and after that
the end is what current dot leave
because we are inserting the e
r i c right and then currently equals
what
he was what equals what
this is the two of our two of us
leave now
yeah we're done we're done okay so
that's it let's say answer
what's the time complexity of inserting
a word if at least
n characters in the world oh when where
where
what's the space complexity we're done
good job
yeah so this is insane okay now
let's implement the search okay
searching will be
similar define search
search self what
okay say what we are searching the word
okay okay
it's the same look c you are
equal self okay start with the current
note it's going to be
for i in what
is not i
in if it doesn't find enough in the
current dot triad what happens
what should we return return false yes
where we're done okay and what should we
do what should we do
what should we do we should jump to the
next one yeah so current equals current
dot data i right
all right and then here what should we
return
search return one reason why
current current dollar
search we are searching so
look we want to search e-i-c yeah
yeah here at this point i could be a
e-i-c-o-e-r-i-c-k
for example so what's the difference if
there's only one e-i-c-k
i don't want to return true because it's
not an entire word right but eic i see
so what's what kind of book they have uh
what do we need to take away
no no no the leaf pulling
tense if a word ends here right yeah so
return current over
now we're searching the word eric and
then now we are
here current because there will be two
possibilities one is
eic and when one is e-i-c-k or e-i-c
something something you will reach at
this point right
so i want to return to only if
eric is in the dictionary not e-i-i-c-k
right so what makes the difference here
how can we check if it is
the note has a pull-in flag leaf what
does it mean
what does it mean remember i show you
eic remember
yeah yeah so here sets the foot
to two otherwise here to force remember
here so we can work currently
current dot white
come on it's there you pick a wall here
come on what's this
left left knee leave yes leave
that's what i'm saying at the end no
terminal no yeah i see
you inside the word and at last you send
it to true right
yes then you need to check if it ends
here so
current don't leave yeah because if
you're inserting e-i-c-k
right what happened the c
ends at fourth and k ends at two right
don't get it
okay okay so now we want to we want to
change this to star wars
okay only it starts with it doesn't have
to be the same as the same word so
you can only change one thing here to
make it
make it start with implement styles do
you understand what
so which which one do we want to change
all right which one do you see start
with
so e-i-c-e-i-c-k e-i-c-t
so where should i change
okay which which which which one should
i change
remember i will just return to return
calendar leaf
ryan got it you nail it yeah
yeah because because at this point we
could have possibility
e-i-c-e-i-c-k-i-s-d-m right
yeah ready okay so
uh any
questions so far no no
yeah goodbye okay okay that's it
okay goodbye goodbye see you tomorrow
yeah yeah