hey hello mr mr ryan how are you today
good good uh it's friday okay
okay let's do it so
today we're going to count the numbers
with unique digits so what are the
numbers we
unique digits like one two three this is
unique difference
but one two two this is not unity
because two
appears twice twice how about appear
three times it's
any any if it appears more than one
times
it's not unit digit okay so given a
number
and we want to count how many
numbers with unique digit between the
range
okay suppose this is x between the range
bigger than zero
smaller than 10 to the power n
i'll get 10 to the power n 10 to the
power
[Music]
100 yeah 2 to the power 0
1 yes so any number except 0 to the
power of
uh 0. question ideally it's one but
maybe mathematically it's not defined so
any number except zero to the power of
zero is one okay
okay so to use the remember the binary
yeah finally
why is that look so finally one zero one
zero okay so this means one right
yeah yeah yeah it's two to the power of
zero
like 123 twenty-three
this is one what ones we call it once
yeah
this is tens right this is a hundreds
all right yes right so that's
a hundred plus twenty plus three
correct so that that's why
10 to the power of 0 is 1
10 to the power of 0 yeah got it
so look so we're given this
and we want to count how many how many
numbers
are unique with unique digits it doesn't
have any duplicate digit between this
range
for example when n is zero how many
when n is zero so
smaller smaller than one so how many
how many numbers within this range is
unique
isn't it
yeah it doesn't have duplicate numbers
so how many numbers
how many numbers would this range look
but no smaller than one bigger or equal
than zero so it must be
the only possibility is zero right yeah
so it's one the answer is one because
there's only one number which is unique
zero it doesn't have any difficult
numbers right one one
is less than one no one is not less than
one yeah
okay how about n is one so that would be
what x bigger than zero smaller than
ten so how many numbers which this range
has unique
10 yes yeah this is 0 to 9
right that's 10 numbers yeah okay so we
got it yeah
and then how about two we want to count
bigger than zero x smaller than 100.
so any idea how we're counting this if
you're not sure we can always
11 22. no no no no
any numbers how many numbers listening 0
to 99 how many numbers 9
0 99 how many numbers
90 00 99 how many numbers come on
there are 100 numbers 100 numbers yes
100 numbers
but we are excluding we need to
excluding one one
two two three three four four how many
of them
nine okay so 100 minus 9
91 yes okay so if n
is two we need to return 91 okay yes
so how if there are n numbers if any
speaker length
10 for example what's the answer
of course if n is bigger than 10
so the answer will be f10 right because
look
because if it's the
uh if it's if you can't find
any n digit
number with unique digits when n
is bigger than 10 right why is that
because
look if n is 11 you can't find any 11
digits with unique with unique
digits i'm right yeah because you only
how many digits have you got
oh no how many all together did you
you have you got zero to nine how many
how many digits you know tonight do you
want to see how many
ten ten digits because we are in decimal
okay so
we are we have ten digits and we want to
put it in the
eleventh box we count
right do you get it all right yeah
because look there if 11 we call it
pigeons pigeon hole yeah
we have 11 we have 10 pigeons
pigeon you know pigeon animal yeah we
have 10 pigeon birds
and we want to put it in uh in the 11th
pigeons yeah but there's only 10
there's only 10. so what what could
happen so
[Music]
so at least at least one of the pigeon
hole
is empty right all right at least one
can we get that yeah at least one of the
pigeon hole is empty
all right does it make sense
what's the picking home the
cage to put the birds in okay
okay oh for example like you have you
have 10 balls
balls both and you have 11 box
okay and you want to you want to put the
put the 10 balls into the 11 box
and we can get and at least at least
okay we're talking about at least
at least one box is empty can i get that
yeah yeah yeah that's obvious yeah
because you only have 10 balls and
how can you put it in 11 20
11 boxes right you can put all of them
into one but
or you can the best you can do is put 10
10 balls in 10 boxes and then now you
have one more box one box which is empty
am right all right so that coming back
to this question
if you have a 10 digit and you want to
put it in the 11
digits you can't find this without
duplicate right
i'm right if you put you have 11 digits
it must be non-unique am right
am i right yeah does it make sense yes
okay
okay so now coming back to this question
look if there are three digits if that's
related
okay let's define look if last three
digit
how many possibilities i can put for the
first digit if
that's three digits three digit number
sweep each number okay
three digit number how many
possibilities i can put for the first
digit
three nine nine nine what is nine
zero one zero five six seven eight nine
that's ten ten no wait
not there right not yellow so nine yeah
yeah
good question because the first thing
you can't have zero
you can only put one to nine right yeah
the second number how many possibilities
one two nine one to nine nine
yeah yeah no ten
four thousand one more quest uh
yes is it ten or nine
that's one second digit because we have
already used one digit
yeah for the first case but we have one
more
nine yeah nine why is mine can you tell
me because
you actually can do ten but you already
use one
for the first one so you subtract one so
that's nine
yes yes because because for the second
number i can use
zero right i can use zero
and then i use one at the beginning and
i plus more plus zero so that's zero and
that's nine and that's my possibility
including zero
okay so first for third one
how many possibilities eight
yes because we use two and now we have a
yeah
eight so how many possibilities if i add
one more zero here
seven we are done okay so you get if we
have a function
f f n f k
meaning k digit number with unique
num unit digits yes then we can
calculate this way right
okay so let's do it
let's do it define count okay called n
remember count and what's missing here
column if n equals
zero return what
do you tell me how many remember this is
[Music]
remember okay so now we define
f f remember is the n size f k
we can define another function here
what's missing column
okay is the is the k digit
k k digit
number which has which is unique which
only has unique digits right
okay
only one digit how many can we get
how many digits for one
one digit i mean one digit
how many one digit should we return 10
instead zero to nine right ten
okay on then we look then we can do this
answer
equals one right then four
i in range
wrench one okay something
okay um
look look at is what nine times nine we
want to calculate this nine times nine
times
eight times seven right and times here
648.
no look okay maybe k plus one i'll come
back to that okay so answer
equal answer equals answer times
look at the ten uh
the should be 10
minus i right let's do i should be 1
uh 1 k
when i when i
uh when i
is 1 then you times 9 when i is 2
actually let's put it 9 here so because
the first number we want the time is cap
and then when k is 2
we want to times times the times
i right and then return answer
okay does it make sense does it make
sense uh
can you get it because we want to
calculate uh we want to calculate
um we want to calculate
the f is the number of digits uh number
uh fk is the number of
k digit numbers with unique digits
okay with unique digits so
this function will return the number of
number of num numbers with unique digits
for k digit
numbers okay it's a bit tricky yeah
really
uh
yes i think that i i think
i think we probably don't need don't uh
don't mean this
because k equals one k equals one is to
return
nine because only uh this may not work
so we don't
do this okay and now we need to sum this
up
look some return
sum f
k for k in
range
and plus one right
can you say that the answer is what
the answer is what
so look we can do this answer equals
zero
and then for i in
range 2 n plus 1
answer plus equals fk
and we can we can work within what
answer another answer yeah because here
we there's a special case is when
n is one and is zero return one when n
is one you should return ten ten
right because when n is one it should
return 10 and when
n is 2 look away when n is 2
return will be 10 plus fk
which is f 2 right f2 which is what
f2 according to this f2 is
uh f2 is what at
80 81 right
look this function already this function
f1 equal equals 1 uh equals 9.
yeah look eric we're not confusing
everything look in this play isn't it we
are not confusing with f
and count yeah i was a bit confusing
before fk
only calculate f1 equals 9 f2
equals 1 81 right
eight times nine times f3 is times a so
this
this function nine times nine times
eight yeah this
these fk is this function okay and then
now we need to count how many of them so
it's 10
plus plus f2 plus f3 plus s4 okay so
that's the total number of uh numbers
with unique digits okay
yeah this is mathematics to calculate it
right
all right yeah so how we counting we
count
the one digit and we added
two digits and we added three digits
three
so the overall discount is what f
f1 f0 plus f1
plus f2 plus plus fn
okay
okay so this is what 81 plus 10
is 91 yeah it's the same as we a hundred
substrate nine right it's the same
okay so now we can do this look at this
f
function we can do it using the dynamic
programming okay
yeah a dynamic programming so look how
many dynamic programming do we have
yeah okay so look this ff
function is a function so look can we
write this
f k equals
f k minus 1 times times y
so look we don't know times one okay
look
f3 equals f2
times
eight right all right yeah because look
9 times 9 times 8
yeah this is f2 yeah look
f2 equals f1
times nine right all right
f4 equals f3 times one
f4 equals f three
times f2 no no this is f
f3 yeah this is f4 f4 equals f3 times
one
times the last one yeah what was the
last one
sorry look f3 equals f2 times
a f3 equals f2 times a
yeah f4 equals f4
equals f3 times one can you can you
release
f4 equals
f3 f
comma is here why what you're looking 7
7 okay and then i'm going to do it f5
equals four times one
f4 times six
okay got it yeah eight seven six so we
can do this
f k equals f one k minus one times one
times one can you write this one three
okay look three plus eight
three plus eight eleven four five seven
eleven five plus six eleven so that's
what
eleven minus one
three okay
fk equals fk minus 1 times what
these two minus 11
these two parts one sorry
these two this is k and what's this
these two plus equals 11 and this is k
what's this
two numbers added to 11 one is one is k
the other one is what
one is k and the other one is
is what
two numbers added to eleven one is k the
other one is what
f eleven minus k yes
eleven minus k come on why what take you
so long
huh huh okay
okay so look this is this is the dynamic
programming
transition function right yeah
all right so we can implement it using
top down or bottom up
right okay you tell me okay
define f k
if k equal zero return one
if k equals zero return
one if k equals one return one
return one then
nine we're done then return the
complexity between fk
minus one times one times one
fk minus one times one
fk minus one times one the one i seo two
numbers
seven minus k what's the meaning here
cash okay no column my only thing is
cash
okay to to save the values yeah
to memorize the value okay what you
doing
okay can we do this photo app
can we do this for that yeah right the
time complex
day is one why is r1
because it's a one why is a one
no it's not a one oh okay okay
if
okay okay okay but you can make it a one
how
because what did i just tell you eric
listen you're not playing with ryan
ryan said is a one
a one but i'm saying it's okay
but you can make it a one why is that
because remember the eleven eleven balls
cutting into eleven boxes by adding
two together something so i can check
look if
k bigger than ten okay
what should we return what we turn
k if k bigger than 10 return how many
solutions how many
we turn
um
okay
remember the beginning i said 10 balls
put it into the 11
boxes how many solutions can you find
with the unique
numbers every digit can you find any
no no what's that yes
zero yes so do you understand why we can
make it a one
do you get it if we're not putting this
it's okay right
it's okay but if we put in these
any numbers greater than 10 we are
returning directly
because we know we can't find any
solutions eric you need to pay attention
you get it yeah
at the beginning and you know none of
you pay attention
can't remember i can't remember need to
understand
not remember got it right
more important okay and look
eric what sit down don't play okay sit
down
look look dp let's do it dp away okay dp
alright let's see
10 times 11 okay because atmos 11 okay
yes and then now i can do this
d p zero equals what p b
zero equals one d p zero equals d
p d v z along the beginning is what
is nine zero
one is nine tv zero is what
one is nine tv zero come on
how many within this range one
one okay then i can do this for i
in french ten
range range let's do it k plus one okay
so look if if k bigger than 10 will
return
we return one return zero okay just make
sure
and then now we can do this one is
smaller than plus one
uh actually here you need to start with
two okay because ftp
0 and dp1 will already calculated we
start with two tlk
dp okay you tell me dbk dpi
equals what and return
b p what
can you guess d t i
equals okay
remember this dynamic programming
transaction function
f n equals f n minus 1 times
11 times minus k remember remember minus
n
yeah okay so dpi equals what
i minus 1
times 11
[Applause]
dp1 and we starting to calculate dp2 dbt
db4
and here dbk right remember the previous
one top down
if k equals zero returns zero if k
equals one return knife
otherwise return what f k minus 1
times 11 minus k right so you are
calculating from the top to the bottom
this one is calculating from bottom to
the top
right this one doesn't have a recursion
right
it doesn't have a request but the
previous one is recursion
in order to make a discussion a dynamic
programming we need to add
what cache
we're done the notebook memorization
okay
so means f k then we can do this we can
just
do this sum return
return one sum f n
f k for k
in range
range n plus one okay that's it
because we the final number is the
number of the
if the number of one digit the number of
any number of two digits the three
digits four digits until k digits
right you add all these numbers together
right yeah
then you that's your final solution the
number of terms okay
uh so what's the so what do you learn
today
just think tell me what have you learned
so we learned
we learned and you need no wait unique
number so tell me
in one sentence what have you learned
today what's the problem
how do we approach to solving so we just
use for example if the
11 booth
[Music]
okay so that's that's one kind of pigeon
hole okay so for example the other one
okay
you have three balls three bars and you
have only two boxes
yeah so i can say at least
one one at least one of the box
contains more than one balls
does it make sense you have three balls
and you want to put it in two boxes
so what happened so at least
one of the box contains more than one
boss got it yeah and
the previous one is you have
you have two balls all right you have
two balls you want to put it into
three boxes then you can say what
at least one box is
empty yeah so okay do you get it
yeah so why this is useful because look
okay unique look
unique how many digits
in decimal i got long hair how many
digits in maximum
10 10 contingents
how many if if there are eleven digit
size
if a number is eleven digits
does it have a duplicate numbers
is it like unique not easy the numbers
that contains only unique digits
it's not unique right because the the
best case is you can do this
nine eight seven six five
four three two one zero how many how
many this is the number yeah
yes that's ten digits yeah
so if you want one more digit what
happened you're running out of digits
right
you put any digi that makes these
not unique right i'm right that's what i
mean
do you understand do you understand that
ryan do you understand
10 digits this is the best case you need
right
how many how many how many in these ten
digits remember remember
nine times nine times eight times seven
yeah
times times six times one right right
and what's next what's next a few times
another one times zero
it just zero it makes this yellow got it
zero yeah for eleven or
or 13 14 even the digit if a number
has more than 10 digit
you can't find any number with more than
10 digit
that is unique right
that contains unique digits because it
doesn't you just
can't have more than 10
unique digits in uh 11
digit number okay this is one
one application of the of the picture
uh uh pitching principle and we
you this one is we are counting this
using mathematics
we also use the top down of bottom up to
compute the dynamic progression
for programming what's what's this
programming equation
mean what's this called dynamic
programming
transition function because look in
order to calculate dpi
i need to calculate dpi minus 1
and this is the relation between dpi
and dpi minus 1. so you can calculate
dpi
based on its previous i uh previous num
sequence yeah previous item a smaller
problem
right with this 11 minus i equation
right how do you get the 11 remember
f3 equals f2 times
8 s o equals f three times
seven f nine equals f a times one
f eight f nine equals f to a
times what times eleven minus
one equals two yeah okay
good times have a good weekend okay