oh hello hello mr mr ryan how are you
today
good good good okay that's good so today
we talked about
we're going to come back to talk about
an interesting problem about the binary
search do you still remember what's
binary says
is smaller and the right side is bigger
let's find the research so what i'm
talking about is finally true your own
has and most two kids
right yeah which one is the root
the top one what's the number one one
okay okay so that's one the rules and
which one is the leaf
two and three the leaf there's three
two and four two and four we're done
okay so how about
um let's do a little bit of review okay
so what's the what's the
pre-order of the final research tree you
know pre-order
pre-order pre-order
yeah that's it let's put all that the
post order
uh post order so so look
this is the node yes preorder is the
left
what puyota is node node
one
is this no air left left right left
uh so six seven two
four five three one right oh yeah yeah
yeah
okay so this is a little preview about
this um
uh about the pre-order and what's the
binary uh what's the
breakfast search order of list three
breakfast search order what's breakfast
search oh one two three six seven four
five exactly level by level okay
okay so how about if i tell you that uh
you know this work
and censor
what does it mean
is i think it's obviously obsessed
so ancestor is like uh
you the common parent
or grandparent or grand grandparent
like you and you and every conveyance
and the ancestor one assessor is deadly
yeah
because that is your parent yeah your
daddy yeah both of you yeah
mommy it's it's okay are we talking
about that just like yeah mommy is the
same okay so the lowest co
lowest noise ancestor is daddy or mommy
and then your grandma is also one of the
ancestors but it's not the lowest yeah
do you get it with me the youngest
no look 697 the lowest ancestor is two
right yeah three six and four the lowest
ancestor is one
six and four six and four
no which no is the common parent of
these two
six and four okay the guest ryan he's
two
but is not a parent of four one
yes one look because look one is
grandparent right it's also first
grandparent
got it yes yeah does it make sense i'm
six
mine's four yeah okay
so how about you have another brother
sister
yeah how about eight and seven what's
the common ancestor
eight and seven two
close if if seven is ancestor is the
parent of a
you know if if one of node
is if one of knows is the grandparent
or parent of a nano node at least no
it's the common ancestor
lowest so seven is the lowest commerce
sister of seven and eight
right correct we defined it as this okay
does it make sense okay so now
given the two notes okay so these
today's problem is given two notes
which we know it's already existent in
the binary tree okay given to know for
example
two let's do it uh
maybe here yeah okay okay nine and six
nine and six what's the common ancestor
uh two yeah yeah two oh yeah so you can
look
you've got a minute yeah so given two
notes in the parallel tree we find out
the command the law is common ancestor
so look six and nine the globe is coming
and success two
but this is also a command star yeah but
it's not the lowest
because this is the closest closest okay
which is the lowest
so any idea how we're doing this right
think think um
think about it if both of them
on the left you should look for the left
one including the route
and you mentioned the left and hop on
the right
over the right so how about six and five
how do you find
whole okay so then it'll be the route
it'll be in the road yeah if it one is
on the left one is the right it will
definitely be root where down yes and
how about if it's not it's all
on the same side you should
look on the left side yeah and if you
come find on the left side for example
if six and seven another note it's all
both on the left side
it's not on the right side yeah
yeah okay so so can we do
it can we brew first
what's proof
checking checking every possible note
yeah so we check
every possible note to see
so how many notes if there are notes we
need to check and not
and for each noun we want to check if a
note is
is incensed so how how can we check if
the note is
ancestor or both of two notes
uh if it's if
both of my children look one way
yeah so look if i i tell you six and
nine and if i want to check if
two if one is the common ancestor right
so we hope how can we do this
because each kid has only one kid one
one parent right
yeah we can go go we can find a parent
of six which is
two yeah we can find the parent of two
which is one okay
so now we have reaching the one so it
means that
one is the parent is is ancestor of six
and the same thing for nine if both
if both are if the node
is the both ancestor of the six and nine
and we record its level yeah
all right so lee look it needs the how
many
look for each note it means
if the note is h yeah h is the height of
the tree so it will be times
h and then times another edge
all right look at it o h
n h this is the term complexity but h in
the worst case is what
when h in the worst case the height
height of the tree yeah because look for
six in each
you want to go you want to find a parent
yeah yeah
so it needs to one two the height yeah
so the average is edge
so in the worst case the edge is what in
the worst case
big is the same as n right
why is that because you consider the
trees like that
i need water okay can you go whatever
okay look this is the binary tree yeah
yeah so the height is the same the
height is the same as the note right
so in the worst case this blue force
takes
o and cubic time right got it
all right yeah which is kind of
like yeah exactly which kind of slug
because look if we want to find
these two then we need to find go to
and go through this and check checking
those
leaves and chicken chicken chickens and
cubic time which is slow so can we do
better
can we go better
can we do better look let's think about
just two simple three simple notes
right one two three
okay let's let's see one on the left one
on the right
yeah let's p let's kill
okay p and q we're given this two to
know p
and k we want to find find out this is
the load okay
we want to find out if it's the common
sense look
if if the first of all if the p
is the load or q is the load right if
the loop value
is the is the same as p or q then we
return the rule right because we just
defined if one
note yeah if one note
is p or q we define it as a
comma
yeah then what you can do because the
root
is the lowest ancestor of one of them
right
all right look for example if if p
here q here the common ancestor is b
yeah
got it yeah okay so how about if
if we fight though this is rude okay
okay so for example these are here
something and then if
p is here q is here okay right right
yeah yeah
look so this key and q a
look p and q is on
roots once one side on the right yeah
yeah
on the right hand side so we can first
of all we can find
we can find if p and q are on the left
side
if on the left side we just need to take
the left side
yeah we just need to connect that if on
the right side just do the right side
yeah
[Music]
yeah okay so let's let's do this define
find ancestor
loot p q
right what's missing column
because we can't find it yeah define the
base cases
the location we also need the base cases
right
look you tell me if rule the value
is p dot value or
lu dot value is
q the value column return what can you
tell me what
what's what's returning here if loot is
the one of the value will return
well which node is it if
big value
remember that p q thing the weight
yes we're done root okay now we don't
want to find
on the left hand side yeah so look a
let's do this left equals
five ancestor
rule the left
p q right we want to find it
we try alright we try to find on the
left right
we yeah and then again passing with p
and q y look if
left is num
yeah if left is now what does it mean we
just need to take the right side
we already set the right side so we
return one left
his left is number one right right
right because we already find it in the
right and if right is down
what do you think what left yeah
on fire yeah what's that term complexity
um
[Music]
oh n yeah because we need uh what what's
n what's n
the number of the notes in final
research
about energy yeah yeah yeah so okay
let's come back to the discussion
all right all right coming back to this
question we want to find out the common
ancestor
in the new tree given the p and q two
daddies one is 2d one is sweetie
sorry about it there's two daddies one
is 2d and one is 3d
why one there which is 2d and one ah
okay i got it yeah well
very clever if you know it's now yeah
now we can't find it we return now yeah
because there's no
consideration if load of value is one of
the if the current load value
is one of the nodes so then what does it
mean it means that current load
is the lowest common ancestor right
otherwise eric we find it on the left
and we find it on the right if we can't
find it on the left
it must be on the right if we can't find
it on the right it must be on the left
and what's the third cases what's the
last cases
what's the last cases it's only separate
yeah
it's only different branch so what does
it mean it means that sweet
yeah loot is the lowest common ancestor
okay
got it okay so that's it for today
that's it for today good job today you
want to
say bye bye to people yeah and then go
to the front and say
bye bye to the people see you tomorrow
[Music]
bye bye see you tomorrow