go hello hello hello mr mr ryan how are
you today
okay so today we talked about
intersection of two
intersections of
so previously we talked about the
intersection of two linked lists
right yeah the principle is quite
similar how the approach we've taken
today is
quite similar so let's let's take a look
at this example okay
one two three four five
six okay and then eight nine three
four five six seven eight so what's the
intersection of these two arrays
one two three well there's no one here
intersection uncommon elements three
four five okay so these are the unique
numbers how about if i tell you that i
add another three here
and then stick three should appear once
or twice
three times how about if i put another
and how many three
two three so i need to put three here
right
all right so it's the intersection the
common parts
and if they are duplicate numbers you
should only have a
the minimum the less number now appears
because look
if three appears one here appears twice
here
then in the intersection there will be
only one right yeah if
that appears three times here and two
times here
so how many times i should put it here
two times two times okay
the hug what's the one coincidence
i'm not asking anything what's the
approach to
text facebook yeah notebook how do we
use the notebook
you look it up look it up if we are not
using
notebook how do we how are we going to
uh tackle this from
bluefox how to improve us checking every
thing checking every number in going
through each number on the first array
and then check if they appears in the
second array right yeah
so for example like one and i go through
these the second array
and how uh and to see if it has a one so
if this is
n this is m and animal what's the time
complexity
uh
and thailand yeah that's cool
yeah because for each n numbers i need
to go through the second
element to check if it appears here and
there's only uh there's also
ones uh one thing to note is that
how do we how are we dealing with these
duplicate numbers for
over if there are three and then you
find a three right
i let you put a result in three in the
result but you need to remove the three
from
from the second number so it doesn't
count next time when you have a three
got it i'm right
how about if you don't look if there are
two threes and there's only one three
here
if you don't know you move it what
happened three it appears
here you put a three and then three
appears here again you put
another three but which is long yeah
it's incredible because it
only appears once in a second array
right so how do we fix this
is that when we go into the first array
we find
immediately as as long as we find it in
the second array
we put it in a result and we remove it
yeah all right this makes sense
this is blue for us so it's all end
times and
you're mentioning we are using we can
use the notebook right the notebook is a
good for the lookup
what's the time complex yeah but
we need the old end time to put it in
the notebook right leave it at them
and and apples yeah we want to put it
you know
i love apples yeah good and then it
needs the end times right
so so if we put it into the
notebook so we also need to remember how
many times it appears in array right
yeah we because for example this this
one three three
we need to have a a notebook saying like
okay three
appears twice right yeah i'm right
no book so what's the what's the
we we can go through this like this is
numbers then we can say for
i this is notebook okay then we can say
notebook uh dictionary default before
this dictionary which is the type of
integer and for i
in nums and then we can do this
plus equals one right yeah yeah but all
these
all these can be can be converted
converted into what remember we're
talking about a
magic class in python which can count
the number of elements and how many
times they appeared
in in a way what what what's the object
start with c o
c o count counter
yeah so all these yeah can it can be
turning into
notebook equals counter we want to count
what
call the numbers yeah so this this three
lines
is exactly the same because this is
that's the same thing for you
okay so when we have the counter for
these two
counter which is the notebook when we
have the counter for these two arrays
and we can go through the keys
the number the number of the notebook
and then appears it
and append the same numbers
in the result okay let's do it
define let's say in
in the section okay then array one
column let's say a b
column yeah okay so you tell me okay the
notebook
notebook one no book a notebook a equals
counter yeah
a and notebook b equals counter
b okay so now these two lines
just count how many numbers
in the array in both array right and
then put it uh
put it in the notebook okay let now we
go through one array of this yeah
for i in notebook a
right now
then this i for example is three and we
want to find out if three
is in no book b how can we do it all
right
uh
sorry if this i is in the notebook a and
i want to find out if this number is
also in the notebook b so how can we do
it if i
[Music]
so this number appears in both now at
least here this number appears in
both array right yeah so what do we do
now
if this number appears three times in
the first array and appears two times in
the second array so what do we do now
uh pretend
numbers in the the common numbers in
this answer okay so
if the three appears two times in the
first array and then one time in the
second array so how many times
of three we need to add it in the
answers
yes
minimum okay so look for
let's say for in range we want to put it
in a minimum so that's
mean yeah we call the mean function and
notebook notebook a
i yeah this is the number of times
appears in the first way
and now book b i right
okay the mean function and then we do
this answer dot append
append what open what open what
optimization number look i
yes yeah i impose uh i appears impose
array and then we want to find the
minimum yeah minimum of
and i i is the number of times which is
two times here
and b i which is one time here get a
minimum
yeah and attend i and return
[Music]
stop guessing we're not guessing
and if it's not enough for an a even
b is that m is the number of anime in
the b so how many times we need to go
and
[Music]
is
building this mb takes ob time right
yeah
o a plus b and then we're going through
these elements
in the in the number of uh in the
array of a so in this this case is
in uh in the worst case this is away
time as well because there are a
elements in the
array right and the notebook has this
overlay time right
this is a a iteration and it will check
if it's
in in in no b this is om o one constant
we're talking about the checking
something in the notebook is no one
constant
and we're appearing at we're just adding
it it doesn't
uh this may look another fall but
actually if you think about it it only
has one okay yeah
okay so can we use the previous methods
to
uh the same similar agreement you know
the moving the two
uh link list remember
remember yeah
remember this link listing this is
a this is b and how can we
how can we do this we put the last one
together and then keep on going
a has half and b
has half and and uh you're trying to
make
a whole wait if a had half of a knuckle
and b had half an apple
and you tried to make a whole apple and
then
put them together yeah how many hot
apples
first of all these two you take away
half of each one
then put and the always still
there two pointers and two pointers yeah
exactly
so look in order for this aggregate to
work
we need two pointers two points but
these are
this linked list needs to be sorted all
right yes
look yeah look one smaller than two so
should i move two or one
one two and two okay it's the same so we
have
it out we added and then we move it
together three equals three
yeah four equals four
yeah and then and then what when
when these one any of these is beyond
the end then we
call the end okay yeah so it's 23 points
like two and three okay so for example
for example
so we can apply these the numbers look
first of all we need to sort the
array right if the array is not in order
we can apply these two points
right all right does it make sense yeah
okay so look one if we started one three
four nine nine okay and then this one
let's say
three nine seven uh so unite
ten okay look this is already
a result answer one and three
so one is smaller than three so i move
one also almost three one
so yeah equal all right let's put
another
duplicate number three here okay
and then i just put another nine here
and another nine here okay
so three three and three 23 here
and i need to move
both yeah yeah three and nine
move through your nine
three four nine move forward all night
four nine and nine okay put the knight
here and then move it to
both again nine and nine right you see
so it handles the duplicate numbers
perfectly got it okay
define okay let's just do it f a
b what's missing column okay
a dot source okay we're sorting this
what's the time complexity of sorting
array
[Music]
we talked about this before suit yeah
yeah okay
and answer equals we're putting these
the common elements in the array okay
then look
i equals z equals zero right
they're pointing what's i equals z
equals zero what does it mean
i is zero j is zero what's iron what's
j we
so what does it mean here
a equals a a comma p equals
a b equals l a
l b yeah please
you don't listen next a b equals look we
talk about this
a b equals 1 1 1
2 what does it mean a equals 1 b
b here it means what a equals a
okay so it's the length of that okay
then now we can do this
y i smaller than l a
and j
smaller than lt okay this is dying
okay
japan is time okay so look what does it
mean
what does this mean i smaller than l a
and j smaller than
b wire then you move it so
why any of these are not are still
in the range yeah okay if
a i equals
b j what should i do
if less than equal what should i do even
less
if there are two i need that for them
but before that
we should put this number in
[Music]
i shift no j i was j
what one one here add equal
yeah i'm paying attention okay s
s if a i smaller than b
j so
yeah you don't you write you know as if
you write you only write you erase this
you will write it
okay so shorter ai is smaller than bj
what i see
what should i do
i move up move i or move j uh
wait wait let me think
and then
what's the time complexity
[Music]
this is all not n this is all a m
log m okay
and here is what here is
all n plus m okay
yeah equal sorry what did that equal
good question so look this part of
agreement is o n plus
because we are visiting all the elements
from what both two arrays right
yeah these these two parts in the
sorting i can tell you sorting my a
elements oh and log n sorted by another
array
m o a log okay so you add it together
but you discard discard the
trivia ones you know you know the trivia
one
the small one smaller smaller part which
is this pie
this is smaller than this yeah yeah so
the aggregate the timing complexity is
o n log n plus
and log n okay
got it or you if you prefer
if you prefer you can
uh probably you can merge this but i
wouldn't
do it if lesson all right if layer the
number of the elements in both arrays
are
the same then we can we can just
do oh androgen right yeah we can just
be simple because they because they all
complexity is dominating by sorting yeah
this takes more most of time this is
trivial right
yeah if we don't need the sorting then
the term complexity
we need to find out we need to point out
is oh n plus n right
yeah so so for our uh accurate
complexity
we always pick the most time consuming
power
right yes and we discard the
constant right all right o2 n is the
same as o
n or a hundred n is the same as o n
got it because a 100 is the constant
okay
yes uh so
okay so this is the pretty much for
today
i'm going to erase one uh one of it okay
so let's see
you're not looking you're not looking
you're not okay i'm raising erasing here
okay
here something and here's something
peter
okay i went
[Music]
very well done today you want to say bye
bye to people
bye this is my own home
yeah my own okay bye-bye see you
tomorrow