hello hello hello mr mr ryan how are you
today
okay look this here is a triangle number
triangle okay so today
our job is to come up with an approach
to find the
minimum path from the top to the bottom
so can you find every time you can go to
the left or right yeah
and then the number of score is the
number of lump
uh is the numbers you pick right for
example you can take this two
three six one so your score will be
five plus six twelve okay twelve
can you find another class with the
minimum no no wait
what with minimum yeah minimum i wanted
a minimum
minimum plus some pass some
person so you can go to the left three
five two three five one so what's this
i think eleven yeah yeah that's the
minimum yeah you cannot find any
any other parts which is smaller than
this one right
yeah so look two four five three and two
four seven eight is more than the
eleventh so that one is the optimal
answer we're looking for
so any idea how we're solving that i
mean this is
uh oh oh you just add all the smallest
numbers in there yeah
and then each line in good choice
smaller but but it may not be
look um you
you saying you pick the smallest yeah
yeah that may work but in some cases
you may not you may know what i need
okay
okay good question i need to come up
with a case that picking the minimum is
not
uh it's not it's not for example like
uh if i put a if i swap
with i put a
two here right yes yeah
two here right yes and then i
put uh a minus ten here
yeah okay you can contain the minus look
you pick
the num the smallest two three
five but five cannot go to here right
you cannot
pick minus ten all right yeah because
it's not on the left
[Music]
whatever ryan said i'm not gonna repeat
that again
so you know first where is the minus
number
okay so then uh you try to make ten
try to make two the thing is that you
cannot pick the smallest
in the fourth row right because when you
pick one
smallest like two three five two three
five but five cannot go to
minus ten because you can only go to the
left and right do you get it
oh yeah yeah so you'll approach may not
work okay so wait
wait okay okay last thing uh
if you can't find a solution what what
kind of acronym are you trying to
solve okay yeah
[Music]
yeah okay so this is yeah
wait no yeah so blue forcing how can we
prove first we have proof of all
possibilities yeah
yeah and we find out uh we
we find out uh the minimum right
so how many paths all together look for
each one you have two possibilities
yeah if there are n rows and type of
rows
and each one you have two possibilities
how many
how many possibilities how many how many
ways can you pick
how many ways here
why is it two two no what i mean
is from top to the bottom how many how
many possibilities
no four
i have two possibilities here and then
here i have two possibilities i have two
possibilities six
i have two points
sixteen come on how high
will it be each one i just say each one
has two
and then you have n rows so how how long
one square maybe what what
it was a jesus one look look
one i love cheese
right three four
five six six
seven actually seven sorry you are right
because two to the one
one look two to lower power of one two
to the power two
two to the power of three so two to the
power three okay
yeah right yeah it does okay
so imagine if like a hundred this
approach would
two to the power of n right yeah oh
right and for each one you need to find
the minimum
right so that's the time complexity for
the proof of
yeah so we can use the dynamic
programming how how can we do it look
so for example if we are here yeah if we
are here
then you can choose two or three you can
only come from these two sides yeah
yeah so we pick the minimum right
because look
look we can turn this
let's turn this triangle a little bit
tweeted okay tilt it so that will be
two three four so you become a list of
at least
yeah two three four six five
seven it looks like triangle pascal
triangle yeah but
not exactly okay so look so if we
if we you we uh we want to go through
this yeah
let's release this position and then you
can come from here
or here right right am right yeah
so if i'm i want to come here
and then i have two choices you could
come here and then here right
alright
it's mine uh okay let's just matter it
doesn't matter okay so
look i can come from two positions on
the left next row right
all right yes so i always pick the
minimum
so for this one i always pick a minimum
of these two
and a plus itself right so does it make
sense
so so look
if if a
to b right
if a to b is
10 right right and then you will a to c
and to b this is 2 this is 3
all right yes so look
and another if the path can consist this
bit
and then i want to go to here so the
shortest path can always be replaced by
a c b right because a c b is shorter
than a b
right all right so does that make sense
look if a shot is passed come from
come from what i come from five right
come from five here the shortest path
comes from five
then i can always pick the smallest from
from these two
right which is two all right yeah
yeah does this doesn't make sense so so
it means the one i determine
when i determine let's say let's have a
function okay a function
row and column right if
i calculate f column r and c
it does not affect this value will not
be changed right
alright look because i already
calculated it's only based on fr plus 1
which is here and fr plus 1 c plus one
which is
the three and i oh i picked the minimum
right
all right so f
let's define a dynamic programming
function
which is frc so meaning that
from the minimum pass sum
from the from the last row yes from the
last row
okay last row to here to this point to
this position
it doesn't make sense right
does it make sense so it will be what
f r c equals
minimum of what
of what plus what can you can you guess
look
frc is that frc
is here right uh uh rc remind me of
cheese
look it's coming from what
can it come from what connect two
possibilities
two angles no i mean um and r
c and what is next is r plus one
c and also is next r plus one c plus one
right
right because it can only come from this
position if i want to
the starting point is look the starting
point is at the last row
and it's like climbing right you can
climb you can climb in
climb up right or you can climb
kind of this way right so you can climb
from the bottom to the
upwards you can have two positions right
so minimum
at this point rc could come from two
position which f
r plus one c and one and can you tell me
what's here
i was just saying ah rc
this position is rc and it comes from
what
r plus one c and what's this position
what's this partition
r plus one c plus one where down
look so f r plus one c plus one
but look it coming from this this is the
past sum yeah but
when i reach here i need to end the
number of current point right
yeah so let's define it as t rc right
yeah okay so the final value is what
the minimum plus sum with which is what
which is the value we want to find is f
or what
the top value zero what
because the top row yeah zero one
zero yeah this is the value we're
looking for when we calculate this yeah
each value is the minimum of its next
row two values
right plus its value of itself am i
right
it's like picking picking
uh score picking numbers on when you
climb up
right yeah can they get it because
how many how many numbers the past sum
have you picked
previously with these two right and what
can you pick from the current position
is these two
am right so what's the minimum strategy
i want to
at this point i always pick the smallest
right
because i pick a small list that comes
that's a small that's the
ultimate strategy and i attempt it i'm
going to add it
with current numbers right does it make
sense eric
yeah can you explain again
so uh you wanna find
the you wanna see
okay okay so
can um this is a
[Music]
r plus one c and this is our first one
c uh
you pick them
is this one one yeah so basically look
you want to find a minimum per sum yeah
yeah
person from the top to the bottom yeah
yeah you see the same as from the bottom
to the top
right it's the same yeah you want to add
a number find the minimum pass
picking sign the medium plus sum from
top to the bottom is the same as from
water to the pub yeah it's like eric is
here
ryan can pick here or here you can start
with any position at the last row yeah
and you can climb it up yeah look you
are here
you can come here and then you can climb
here when you climb here you you have
four plus two which is six
when you come here you have four plus
five is it's nine
right yeah so here when at this point
you will be nine
here and then you'll be six here and
then here you can say
but but look six this is six but here
look three plus
two is five it's well if you want to
reach this point
it's better you pick this one because
this is five right yeah
two plus this is smaller so you put five
right here so find a knife
you want to climb to the top you pick
which which way
you pick which way when we were
yeah this is fine this is nice you want
to come up to the top
which way you want to five five because
yes overall
five plus one is six and nine plus one
is ten so you predict
the optimum is one plus two plus three
got it doesn't make sense
why can't we do it because when you
reach this point i don't care how many
how many parts you reach this point i
always pick the smallest
so for the following any step for the
one
right it doesn't care how many ways you
can
you calculate before two you always the
smallest which is
which is five two plus three yeah got it
doesn't make sense yeah okay so look
this is the minimum function okay this
is the
dynamic transition function right got it
okay
let's do this away do this one more time
so
you know how we're doing it let me do
one
okay look all right look
let's see let's go in from these the
last row to the top row okay and we want
to calculate
the minimum what's the minimum what was
number three which is
nine yeah yeah you remember this and
that's how we get it okay
four look here he's four yeah
three and eight eleven which is smaller
three three three plus four
equals seven right seven
here five and eight and ten which is
smaller
eight a plus five thirteen
thirteen okay and here
seven and thirteen which is smaller
seven
seven plus two nice so this is
the optimum got it does it make sense
yeah
so for any large triangle i don't care i
just do this
from top to the top right because this
is always
satisfied this is always the dynamic
programming translation function
what's the advantage compared to the
profiles look previously
they might be a lot of paths coming
through right
duplicate path am right look look
previously if you don't remember eric
look
if you if you don't remember the uh
don't memorize
the the past sum till this point and you
may calculate
again and again for example look you
calculate here
for example here is 10 right and then
you want to calculate here you get the
one and the two and the three and the
four
but again for each person you need to
calculate this over and over and over
again
but for now i don't calculate over and
over again i just save it in
frc and i can just use pick the minimum
right so it will be a lot faster right
does it make sense because this part is
fixed
yeah once i kick your id i don't need to
calculate again
okay let me do one
okay seven
[Music]
then you can ask ryan
seven eight three okay
[Music]
one yeah
okay um
three six okay so look
look look this one yeah
one and three pick the smallest one yeah
one plus eight nine i put a nine here
three and six pick the smallest one
three three minus three
zero yeah zero and nine pick the
smallest
zero zero plus seven seven so if the
number is fair
yeah got it does it make sense yeah yeah
okay so
this is smaller maybe you can just try
every positive part but if a
triangle it has a half a thousand a
million lines
then it's not feasible right yeah you
don't know which one but you can always
try this strategy
from the bottom line right and build
this
dynamic programming metric along to the
top
right correct yeah okay look this one
how many dynamic programming are we
talking about
i asked this question though uh
countdown
wasn't enough yeah okay define let's try
this
f r c okay
if okay let's say let's say
if ah equal let's define a number
define the mean mean cost
okay mean cost mean per sum and mean
plus sum
and then we we are given a metric we
which we have uh
we will call it t okay triangle okay
column all right
if r equals the last length yeah the
the last row which is length t right
minus one yeah because it starts from
zero okay
yeah if it's the last row then what we
took would it have
if you only last longer will return if
you are adding this triangle and the
last row what should we return
return r the value as
here right yeah so it's t r
c right yeah all right yeah otherwise
i'll return one if it's not in the last
row then
we return what minimum of
f f1 alright i just told you
oh uh uh oh wait let
[Music]
in here you need to pick up value which
is
our trc yeah this is the value yeah
all right yeah i'm okay what's missing
here
cash cash because if you're not doing
the cash
what happened if you're not putting this
what happened we'll take
that will be the blue force we just
talked about right yeah that would be
that for example now if you calculate
something in
r divided by 2c divided by two that will
be
maybe many many many times you want to
calculate this function again and again
again and again so now what's the time
complexity if you
if you add this cache what's the time
complexity
i quite fast
oh what how many how many values are we
need
uh do we need to calculate the r and c
ah
time c or ltc i think probably
not probably come on there are
let's see how many what's that what's
the area of this triangle if this is r
this is c
times no probability is times okay
remember
come on this is a this is a square r and
c what's the area what's the area
of the area yeah area what's right there
area is the inside
yeah how how many r times yeah
yeah what's the triangle i can see
divided by two right yeah because it's
half of it right
r times c and this is hard times two
right about we drop a constant so it's r
times c
if we're not adding the cache what's the
time complexity
right yeah because each each row you
have a
waffle here yeah exponential am right if
if i and c equal if i equals c right
what i think you could see yeah okay
so now what's the another
approach we're talking about
yeah so
so i think the top down is easier to
implement i'm right
am right yeah because top down we can
usually implement it using recursion
recursion with what top down
minimization minimization with the
notebook to remember it right
define uh let's just say mean no no no
mean past some
[Music]
right okay so look let's let's
define uh we can we can we can
put a value updated value in a triangle
so let's do for
row in range we want to start with the
second to last row right all right all
right
so it's rows the second row is the last
row is rows minus one right
the second to the last row is rows one
second is raised at
nine minus what
-1 is the second last row minus what is
the second
last row minus
come on this is rose minus one so what's
this
rose one minus two yes come on
what's what's the and what's the top one
is yellow right
so about we have to fit it is minus one
because it's the
up two right remember this range
function yeah when you pull the range
range three five what happened all right
range three five how many numbers are in
there
oh fifteen no no no stop
yeah so it's three and four but not not
including five right
yeah but you can do this negative so
it's three
minus one minus one
range this is step so
so what's this range
so what what's the value range what we
get three and then what's next
sorry
[Music]
minus minus one three minus one is one
two and then what's next one and what's
next
0 and what's next minus 1
but not including minus 1 right this is
always the value
before this right so 3 minus 1 minus 1
is actually 4 values 3 2
zero doesn't make sense five
eight what's the value five
six seven yeah we're done okay another
one five eight
five minus one what's the value
is minus one step yeah yeah yes ten so
what's the value
eight seven six yeah not five yeah well
done good job
so look so next rows minus two minus one
you will do it the last value will be
one
minus one the last value will be one
minus t no no no minus zero minus zero
is one
zero yeah zero okay and for i in that
and for
c in range look
the line will be length
then uh t t r right because t
this row right okay look
t ah c
equals what all right plc equals one
mean one
meanwhile right oh all right
another one is t1 tr
[Music]
yeah so actually trc you can just add
add equal right
and add equal and equals please value
right
and then return which one written what
value our we are looking for
we can work with a minimum
return which value is the minimum person
we are calculating from here to here so
what's the
last value
come on i just told you come on remember
t 0 0 yeah yeah previously like
remember the f function rc right so
what's the value
is you need to return return f zero zero
right
when the top down the top down dynamic
programming you
you return f zero zero right but this
one top out
the final value is on the top come on
does it make sense
yeah okay now i'm going to
erase it okay remember okay
i'm going to erase all of it be here
come on
return t i i write this for you okay t
zero
zero i i didn't know the beginning what
do you know
p t r c okay okay
trc we want to update the value in trc
yeah so what does it equal you need to
pick the value from the
next row or equal to
eight okay three yeah
okay
yeah keep going rc
you want to pick the minimum right oh
yeah i forgot min
i forgot your l equal here
because you want to pick the current
value but also the minimum in the next
row right
mean in the bracket yes
or no in the bracket mean you write it
okay yeah
okay bracket yeah now that bracket
uh bracket parentheses
yeah okay next value and the next
next menu next value i guess it's key
yeah
t yeah keep going
next row next is always use crack it
bracket yeah
back back yeah come on he is away
[Music]
you can write it here if you want
no finish yet almost
and then there's a bracket here okay you
need to
do it like that do it like that yeah
yeah okay
okay add as if you want to add trc yeah
okay because trc you want to pick
pick the value you want to keep the
current value with the and then pick the
minimum in the next two options right
got it that doesn't make sense
yeah okay good that's it okay say bye
bye to people and see you tomorrow
bye bye
mr banana ball okay
okay that's it see you bye
[Music]