oh hello hello hello hello mr mr ryan
how are you today good
do you still remember a few weeks ago we
talked about permutation
yeah yeah like one two three
the pigmentation is
yeah one three two two one
three two three one three one two and
what's next what's the last one
three two one so let's permutation
that's okay permutation is with orders
yes
do you get it yes so these are order and
how about i tell you
combination combinations
this is without orders yeah if i tell
you pick three
pick two apples out of three how many
ways can you pick
you just pick two yes three times but if
you
permeate two apples out of three how
many
three no so which look you said
three times three kinds of ways to pick
two apples after three right
when you pick two up there's three three
times away
when you pick pick it after you finish
pickings like for each one you have two
orders right
three times two so there are six right
correct
yeah so remember this permutation thing
how are we doing this we talk about the
recursive the permutation agreement
right
so basically we we have one two and
every time we
we switch swap with this element with
any of these
elements yeah and we swap it right
and then we continue continue remember
yeah
okay so today we talk about combination
combination okay so look
if i have n items if i have n items
and i want to pick k items what's the
what how many solutions do we have
remember this notation c
yeah c and k this this means to pick k
items out of n
right yeah all right so remember this p
p and k pick k items out of m but with
orders this is without orders yeah
all right so these equals
this is equals what p and k
right divided by what this is with
orders this is without order
so i have to divide divided by
k by what i have k c
and k okay what
look i have how many ways
how many ways of k items
with orders k permutations with orders
if not k any k numbers how many
solutions do we
have when we permutate k k
factorial okay yeah cake factory let's
very well done so this is with orders
this is without order so what do we need
to divide
here okay
okay what fat
yeah we picking this this
uh we can do it the other way look we
pick
first of all we pick k items but we
don't care about orders right
yes and how many orders for k items
k factorial yeah and then you times it
so
you can do it this way p and k equals k
factorial times c and k right it's the
same thing yeah
so p and k p and k equals one
p and k equals n factorial divided by
n minus k factorial okay this is the
formula formula okay
so c nk equals 1 n factorial divided by
k factorial and n minus k factorial am
right
yes does it make sense yeah okay so now
today
if i tell you picking two numbers out of
three
c three two yeah you need to tell me is
you need to return it see one two
one three
two three and what's this
i i think that's it right yeah all right
look c32 picking two apples out of three
apples
how many solutions do we have
uh three yeah is it the same as
kicking one apple also three apples it's
the same yeah
look there are three apples i want to
pick two apples
how many ways i can pick two apples
these two apples
these two apples at least two lemons
right how many ways i can pick
one apple three look
every time i pick two apples there's one
apple yeah
all right i picked these two apple i
have this one apple i picked these two
but i have this one above
so does it make sense c n k equals c
n n minus k i'm right
today yes does it make sense
how many ways if i want to pick 99
apples out of 100
[Music]
199 100 yes we're done how how can we
tell it
because this equals one picking one
apples out of a hundred apples how many
of us
how many ways can you pick one up out of
a hundred acres
hundred a hundred a hundred good job
okay so now today look we need to
given a n and k
we want to return a list of the
combination solution
yeah how can we do it
how can we do
first of all we know n the candidate is
apple
okay the apple is one two
three two n right yeah all right
all right yeah look at these valley
apples we need to pick
yeah we can pick we can pick right
i'll pick so this yeah when we pick one
yeah so for each one we can pick for
each one
when we are have less than k uppers we
can choose pick or not pick
right yeah does it make sense yeah so we
can do this recursively
so for each we have a function pick and
then
for these current apples okay we we we
can go from the left to the right
for each epoch we we we choose pick or
not pick
two solutions right all right yes
and when we have k apart we have a
solution i'm right
am right okay so let's do it
define let's call it um
okay put it in a list okay so
this answer variable is used to store
the solutions there so
so that will be containing the cnk
solutions okay so now we have we can
define
a peak function peak function
look listen listen i'm going to test you
later okay
pick so currently we will have what
we will have uh left
left means that we have not the last
apple we have picked is the left okay we
don't want to come back to again because
look
picking one two three is the same as
three to one yeah
these are repeated right am i right
because the combination does not have
orders right
picking one two three is the same as
speaking three to one
so we want to avoid this kind of
duplication so we can specify that
if we pick the last apple is three we
don't want to come back to pick
one and two again i'm right does it make
sense does it make sense
yeah so the left i know we have a
current solution
or a current solution look if
length of current if now we are picking
equal equal equal k if we have finished
we if we currently we have k elements in
the
in the basket let's say in the basket we
have k
apples in the basket what do we do we
now find a solution right
now we do it answer a pen
does it make sense append what
open the left current come on current
and return okay we just return we don't
continue right
let's look for
okay let's do it for ato okay let's do
it for april
all right let me do this let's define it
as last apple okay
last step up okay look
alright you're so busy what you're so
busy with
come on ryan is good ryan sits there
listening and you're so busy
i am listening okay forever eating
in ranch last apple we start from last
april
and we go to n n plus one right and plus
one column
yes and then we need to current basket
of colonies color basket
current let's make it basket okay so you
know what
is yeah or maybe box okay
you want to have a box with the apples
okay
look if the box contains k element
we we append the box to the solution
yeah
for apple in range last apple and n plus
n plus one the last apple will be n
right will be number end
box box dot append
okay let's let's pick this apple okay
and then when we pick this apple we need
to try to pick the next airport so we
pick again
pick what apple
plus one
all right and then this is the
interesting part when we pick this apple
we want to try not picking this airport
so box dot pop you take it out
yeah look box stop a pen the
economy currently will put this effort
right and then when we pick this airport
we try
picking the next apple right yeah all
right and then we won't also
want to try without picking this apple
and then after this we can just return
a peek starting from pick the first
apple
okay thick reports ever and the current
basket is empty we just put it here
right
right and then return
answer okay look here there's a problem
because this
remember last time we talked about when
you append
this this is by reference right because
this box is a references it's an alias
so so we want to make a copy here so we
can use the diff copy box here right
deep copy box or we can simply use this
we can simply do this this is the same
as box
bracket just a single column okay
this means that i make a deep copy of
box
right doesn't make sense why we want to
make a big
box otherwise the box the content of the
box is always changing because
there's only one box right i want them
when i have
k and k apples in a box what i want to
do
i want to remember this solution and i
make a copy of box
and i put it in a solution does it make
sense all right i'm going to start with
picking stuff from
picking the first level with why why
here is empty can you tell me why this
is empty
when we first picked we want to start
picking the first airport with what
what's this empty empty water
bucket i know something what does it
mean
what's the second parameter i was test
i'm testing you if you listen actually
right
[Music]
yes that's the box when we pick the
first apple we want to try
but at the beginning we have empty box
right
i'm right yeah and i can pick the first
airport right
when i pick the first airport i can pick
the next airport
and when when the box contains k
apples look when the box contains k a
plus what should we do
we should what should we do here
we go we will say we know then we have
apple we have a solution of combination
right yeah okay okay so
what's the term complexity i'm just
testing what's the term complexity
what oh what it's not n anymore and they
say i know okay what
what's the complexion yeah sorry
i mean k what's n a k o c
and k right this is a combination
because
because this solution is to pick k
apples out of n and then how many
solutions are there that's c
and k right yeah so the term context is
oc and k
all right what's the space complexity o
k and k what's the space from length
yes it's the same because we have c and
k of solution put it in answer right
does it make sense and where's the
recursion happening can you tell me
where is the location
calling itself remember because of
what's there
yeah and which car is keep calling
itself box
box is a variable which which which way
which method is
calling itself pick pick and where is
the pit
yeah when we pick this apple we want to
pick the next next apple right
pick yeah yeah doesn't make sense yeah
okay i'm going to erase some of it
[Music]
okay okay well there's something here
and there's something here pick what i
think
you want to have to have right
yeah what i think there's something
about
we want to pick this apple but now after
picking we want to remove it from the
box
yes pop what kind of pop this is
there's no apples no oh box
pot okay we're done ryan you're paying
attention okay
[Music]
i love beginning we want to pick last
one one
one yeah picking one up and then with
one
box what box can you write it
yeah empty array okay empty list this is
the list
list in python list we use it to store
the content store apples it means
there's no apple
nothing in the box right now yeah and
we have one two what does it mean we
have the
one and two box what what what can you
explain what's this
one two what's this
can you tell me what's this there's
three no
a way yeah away and there are two
elements yeah yeah
and i don't add perfect apple and second
apple in the box
yeah okay that's it for today thank you
you need to say see you tomorrow
okay say bye bye bye
[Music]
bye bye
okay that's it thank you for watching