go hey hello hello mr mr ryan how are
you today
great good okay so
i'm i'm talking about uh a very basic
uh problem today which is the
uh usually the first questions to solve
when you want to do this
coding interviews okay so it's called
two sum
two sum so basically you're given a list
of numbers
yeah two one seven eight
five right no and then you're given a
target
seven okay so you need to return the
index you know the index
the first number the index is zero yeah
zero
one two three four this is called index
yeah because
in computers the array starts with index
zero this is called
the zero the index zero element yeah the
first element
first number so look the target is seven
so
which two numbers added to seven two and
five
two and five so this index is what that
doesn't have to be two numbers
yeah two numbers that's why we call it
two sum
okay so the first this is what's the
index of two
what did i just say about the first
number starts with the index
zero one zero yeah and what's the index
of five
what's the index of five how many
numbers yes that's right
so you just need to return zero and four
okay and you can only allow to
you are allowed to use the number only
once so you
if they are if the target is uh four
eight
yeah and there's a four here you are not
allowed to use the index
four twice am right all right yes
but you can if there are another four
here then you can return the index of
least and this right
doesn't make sense but you're not
allowed to return two index to some
index
does it make sense seven and one yeah
yeah yeah seven and one as well so
if there are multiple solutions return
any one of them okay
potentially the first first pair right
right does it make sense
okay so any idea how we're doing this
remember we talked about
yes pre-forcing so how are we performing
this kind of thing
so if there are n numbers then we try
each
our power would be forcing
each one each pair right without using
dynamic plugins that's okay that's not
the
problem look so pair they're in numbers
right
maybe we thought about like one two
three four four numbers and we want to
check if there are
numbers adding to six yeah so how many
pairs that we can
we can have one two one
three one four two three two
four three four all right t4
sorry yeah i know but this is the pairs
we need to check right
does it make sense so how many players
one to the six pairs right
all right six yeah it's six pairs
all right so so
so look i we can just do this
okay easy focusing define let's let's do
this two
two thumb and we're given the lumps
right and then given a target let's call
it what's missing
okay so look look the end the index
the maxima will be up to the n uh up to
n but not including right lens t right
right all right so this is the maximum
index the maximum index
n or what is it what's the maximum index
of this
of these t uh
n no n minus one remember it starts from
zero
yeah yeah i'm right if you have five
elements the
maximum index is what
five minus one four yeah we're done okay
so look
for i in rent
yeah and right so up to n right
look this is true forcing look and then
for
another loop right here for j in
range range what
i okay let's just start it from i
alright
uh up to i right let's if num
okay nums i plus num straight
equals equals what target actually let's
not
t let's numb okay okay
then we just return right return what
all right we can return j
i right right because j is smaller than
i right so we look when i
is five j will be in range
i will which will be zero to four right
j when j
when i is three what's the range of j
when i is three what's the range of
three
is one two two zero to two
okay when i is four what's the range
three
okay so look if i plus j equals steven
with 10 ji right
what's the time complexity
[Music]
quite quite how many loops how many how
many
square why is that because look this
means
this is an iteration for each n it needs
roughly an iteration right linear right
so actually this is
this is what n squared divided by two
area look
this is n squared divided by two roughly
okay but we drop the constant
right we drop the constant so it's
quadratic
can we do better this is too slow right
remember remember this is too slow this
is
uh this is too slow yeah when n is a
hundred
what's n square is a hundred hundred
yeah
when it's a thousand what's a thousand
six zero right
right you'll be a minion right when n
goes a thousand there will be a minion
so it's too slow right
and how can we do better how can we do
better
eating using work yeah using something
using what
using what no book whatever why do we
need a notebook
so we just put numbers that we have seen
we have seen already in the notebook
right
right and then we find out look look one
two three four if we want to find out
if the number added to six what do we do
one so if now i've seen one so how
what numbers do i need to make it up to
six
five yes it's five in a notebook no
okay let's put one in a notebook okay so
this is no book okay i put one here
two is what what
what number do i need to make to six
four it's four in a notebook yeah
not yet no yeah we haven't seen them we
haven't seen it yet
right yeah so about we put a two in here
right
is three in the number what do i need
for three to be in the notebook
first six yeah is three in a notebook
i put this over here four what do i need
three two is two in the number yes yeah
okay so we return the notebook which
will be
two two which is zero one we always
return the index here
okay so look it's one four right does it
make sense
yes how many paths do we need we're just
going from beginning to the end and
that's it
right yeah what's the time conversion
we're done why is the wind because we're
taking through
all of the notes only once
just one time what's the space
complexity
why is that one because they're using a
network
okay let's try this did you see that
great cushion
come on you don't wanna let people over
the world see your cushion okay
define two some okay
nums nums and t what's missing
how do you find a notebook no
book look let's let's study look at
scene okay
sim we define the notebook as the name
scene e chorus one d4
before dictionary
this is the same as this but tomorrow is
mommy's birthday
yeah yeah but for this is better because
when you
when you haven't got the key in this
general at least we
report an error but this is not okay
let's do this yeah
so uh actually we can do here to do this
dictionary just do this yeah curly brace
yeah okay
okay look
do you still remember the enumerate
function like if the dumps
numbs equals
a b c okay
abc what's the enumerate number in
newnan
in you know what's these words nouns
what does it mean
this will be will give you what the
index
0 a and
1 b and two
what c yeah well done the first one it
will give you the index the second one
will be the value right
yeah okay so that would be easier for
i in v
i will be
the index index and v will be
what
[Music]
verb the values of the numbers okay
the numbers okay
okay so look we we now
we have the v right all right we have
the week yeah
so what do we need what number are we
looking for in the notebook
i'll be looking for t
no we want to add it to t but now we
have v so what
number we need to uh looking for in the
notebook
we need to look for look we are look we
are now l4 but we are on the top
no we need to look for the two numbers
at to target yeah and one is t then
one is mean one is i
no come on what is v v plus something
equals t so what's to be something we
are looking for two numbers adding to t
we now have v
uh what's this one minus 19
yeah yeah look look
if t minus v in c
yeah you know in a row yeah
so now that we return we just because
what's the current index what's the
current index
what's the current index uh i yeah and
what's the target
now this is the key right then we stole
the so
t minus v this is the key right so in
the notebook what we saw
we saw alright we store the key
as the value and we store the value
as the index right all right look at
everything
one two three so let's place in the
notebook what we are storing is that
one will be zero the key will be one
yeah two will be one three will be what
it will be one three will be yeah two
done so look the index of index of t
minus v is c t minus v right
so what's what's meaning here don't say
we
don't say now so what we need to put
this v
in a notebook with index i right yes
[Music]
equals one target
the index what's the name
okay does it make sense yeah doesn't
make sense okay so
let's let's so doesn't okay let me let
me
let me okay write it
come on i just erase it in front of you
if t minus three in the scene what will
you return we need to return those two
indexes
return yeah return you already know come
on return is here not not here
index no let's not
what's the what's the index of current
index v
i yeah in return i yeah
and what's the next index in making up
to vb
v is the value come on t minus v t minus
three is the value what's
its index in the number what's the index
in a notebook
[Music]
come on the scene the scene is the
notebook right
yeah the key is the value
so what's the index it'll be this one
right all right yeah
okay so read it okay come on
you're not remembering
sing because this is the notebook yeah
and this is the key which is the value
and basically you're looking up this
value
in the notebook and then you will find
you out the index all right
all right come on and then because you
want to return to
an array of left so we return return
these two numbers okay a
and b f a is the v b
[Music]
doesn't make sense does that make
any sense so far no no okay good job
today
okay let's eat that's it for today