[Music]
okay so hello
uh hey welcome ryan how are
[Music]
so you you tell me what's this anagram
okay actually i don't know how to spell
endogram
underground how do you spell anoda i
don't know
uh endogram
a-n-a-g-i-m a-n-a-g-i-a okay
so almost okay ground
do you know who has anagram so today
we're going to check
write a function to check if two strings
are everyone for example like
that listen listen
and silent these two are l
so can you tell me what can you do
they got the same letters yes exactly
the same letters only ones yes
s
[Music]
ow oh
yeah yes exactly yes so this is
underground energy
okay
[Music]
okay that's fine okay so underground so
today we're going to
talk about writing a function yeah
define check
check analog yeah check interval okay so
we just write it as check okay
s zero s one and s two okay s one and s
two two strings
and you need to return two if you lay
out energy
okay otherwise return first so tell me
if
if two two strings are different lengths
different size
are they n grams
no they must not be n one right because
they are different size right
it's right like let's try
10 or i don't know
okay yeah yeah yeah turn the net uh any
one
but turn the nutty are not everyone
right
nothing yeah do you understand i don't
know i just made it up okay
okay so how do we do this that's
the question how do we do it i move with
denominator okay
define if i
is anagram
taking two parameters s1 s2
what what am i missing here column yeah
okay
so how can i how can we do it
we need to count yeah we need to count
the number of
the number of the frequency for each
letter
am right and right yeah yeah
so we can do it in remember we talk
about the dictionary objects
right traditional object in in in
python every grind ryan please
right so in in python we've got this
what what do you call it curly brace
yeah calibrate
clip way so we can have look if we do
this
if four if we have this uh
let's call it a1 okay a1
look alright maybe call it a1 yes a1
um this curly brace curly brace
and then if i loop i can't see if i
i loop it i iterate the characters in
this s1
for example if this is 10 okay if this
is 10
if i alpha i in s1
what am i missing here and then i can
say
if i want in
if this is no no actually if i in
in a1 then i
i can do what i can a1 i
plus equals one else
a1 i equals one okay
so what what what it means is that i do
please tell
t for example and we look t t
and then if t is in a1 a1 is empty so
so it's not like s then
and a one t would be equals one so what
do we have
this curly brace and then we have this t
and which is
one okay and going back again t
e also is not not appear so we put an e
here and then n here
if i have another like uh tennis
that means okay it is tennis and n
okay if n it appears on in a1
so these will be increment one right
okay
yeah you'll get it yeah do you get it
and then i will be i and
s will be one as well so basically this
is the map
of counting that
each letter and the how many times
they appear in a word am right every
look at this
yes okay so we can copy this to the s2
and then
return a1
equals a2 right then we can compare if
two mappings are the same
got it yeah but this is
too much complicated right and we can
we can avoid checking checking this the
key if it's
already there so how do we do it we can
use it another way
look look
a1 for range
no no no we can do this actually
actually we can do this look
we can do this
dictionary one equals
look this is the magic word counter
counting what's counter mean powder f1
and then and then d1 d2 equals counter
s2 and then what do we do
there's a magic plan here can you guess
are you
kidding me yes you got the first part
what's the other one another one how
many two how many i want to compare if
two are the same so what's that
equal double equal okay so you see two
mapping so this counter as one
look if a s1 is uh what do we call it uh
10 yeah
let's call it 10 for example so after
this
what does this what what is d e 1 e 1
is a dictionary alright look
which is t equals 1
e equals 1 and
equals 1 yes
and d2 if this is net
and et right you'll be also this
remember the mapping in
in in the dictionary it
is not have order does not have other it
does it only has key value pair so it
means
t letter has only appear once in these
and these okay so there are two mappings
that is exactly the same
yes so got it so this is the
an object that we can use counter which
is
already taking this string and mapping
it so count how many times
of letters appears in each in in each
string
okay yes so another way of doing it
let's talk about another way or
simplifying
please traditionally remember we talk
about this decision area
and we can have another object called d1
equal
default what's deforming
before what does it mean before
[Music]
no it means that it's the given one if
you don't specify it okay
yeah okay can you sit down please
otherwise people want to see please
sit down i'll be good boy eric can you
sit on the chair please
yeah okay now before
and then another one p2 equals default
date so what can we do before d
we will give an integer okay so we say
it's uh this mapping will
map into integers so now we can do this
for i in s1 we iterated
right instead of checking this key
appears in addition
we don't need to check it this is the
beauty of using the default div
we can just do this d1 b1 what
i plus equals one okay
and then the next one is one for i we
iterate over the
s2 string d uh d2
i plus equals one and then what's next
what's here everywhere what's this
return where is that
d1
okay so this is one way of doing it okay
and
how many how many messes have i tell you
have i told you today
yeah three actually three yeah this one
the previous one and then another one
um what else
this is
so any questions which one which method
do you like best
this one this one no
no remember we have the shortest one
remember it's number two
if you shortest one you don't need this
right and then you just need to replace
these
in what using what counter remember
counter f1 counter x2 right
okay so these two methods are
easy simple this one okay so pick one
and then code it on your computer and
then the last thing
don't forget to say goodbye
oh baby
okay okay now