[Music]
how are you today it's friday
good good okay okay that's it okay so
today we'll talk about binance tree okay
so what's behind
the street eric actually
and what spinal issue can you draw
example on the ball please
just any example yeah
yeah any examples yes any banana tree
[Music]
only ali just i need anybody
oh that's a nice drawing we don't need
to draw that perfectly this
wow that's good like a shooting star
uh okay yeah we're down here
yeah i'm gonna do
one okay
pick any numbers three three four five
okay let's rest very good any
any numbers will do please okay so i'll
choose
okay i love to eat burgers okay
so what's uh what in this particular
panel tree what are the leaves
[Music]
why is the leaf because it doesn't have
any kind
of children and what's what's the loot
how many loops does that bind and three
have
what does it do what's the root one one
and how many binary of you have okay it
doesn't have performance
only one root in the final three okay
yes does it make sense
yes okay so now look if you cut with
we see the numbers from the root to the
leaf so what's this
if you if you get the numbers
continuously from the root to the 12.
it's not no i'm saying that
192 okay and at least
18 18 plus 18 so you've got
210 right yeah okay so this
is the task for today so we we first of
all we get the
least numbers from the root to the leaf
and then we sum it together okay does it
make sense
yeah so any idea how we can do it
how many ways of traversing the chip
financially
how many ways of traversing research
deficit
preferences so what's the difference
between professors
and differences sometimes they are the
same
yeah but what's breakfast search level
by level so in this particular message
in this particular cell is one nine
eight two
one nine eight two okay one one nine
eight two and what's the definition in
this case one nine two eight
one nine two right so it's the same yeah
yeah
uh oh it's not the same okay and how
about can you list the example that the
preference is the same
can you draw a tree or can you think of
example
that
you just remove these two and then the
first search them will be one nine two
right one nine eight right
and the first search will be one nine
eight right
as well yeah still erased at two right
does it make sense
yeah so that's the case when preferences
your definition is the same or a single
note
yeah even a single note the definition
professor is the same right doesn't make
sense
so today we're going to use the
preferences to solve this problem and
tomorrow we're going to use the definite
search to
solve this problem it's okay yeah
okay so in order to preference what kind
of data structure are we using to
implement a buffer search please
practice search no a preference says
what kind of
data structure can we use data structure
i'm talking about
q yeah and what's q first thing
yeah first thing the first step so so
first thing first of all for example
like
one two let's do this and three
and that's uh four here right okay so
at the beginning the q is empty and the
first note we need to put in the kill is
which
we know which is one
which is one all right okay then we take
this one out
every time when every time when the q is
not empty we take it out and what do we
do next
we take it one hour to kill we call it
the queue
and what do we do next what do we do
next
we take we take the kit out and we
push push it in push pull it well topic
which is the queue and we push the kids
yeah we do two and three two and three
into the
key yeah so i take it off yeah i put a
two and three okay so next time i take
one off
what numbers out next time i take which
number two or three out
uh you take out
two two yeah the beginning of the queue
yeah because the dq is the beginning of
you like you were waiting in the queue
yeah you're buying something in the
queue
the head the beginning of a queue gets
served next right
and when the people coming during the
queue they join
at the back of the cube right does it
make sense oh wait
we take it two hours and what happened
if i take a two hour what should what
should i do next i take a two hour and
what do i do you should
no no no i take the two out what's next
i need two oh
abby yeah i take it
out and then three take it out but it
doesn't have a kid then
then what's your order if that if it
doesn't have a kid then i need to
sum this value 13 yeah i need to know
that
the value of 13 yeah and then take the
4r which is
the 14 134 yeah 124. that's it
so look this is the basic procedure of
preferences but we also need to remember
the current value from the root to the
from the low to the leaf to the current
now right then how can we do it if we
look if it's one look alright
look it's one i want to make it
alright come on if current load
is one and then we we have current we if
the root now is one and
we know the next node is two so how can
we make 12. so i have one i have two how
can we make 12.
uh yes
one and two make one two mathematically
it's not string you know mathematically
you put it together
no and how do you put it together like
what 12 and 4 how do you make a 124
you're not putting it together
mathematically there's no operations
yeah that's what i'm asking 10 one times
ten plus two yeah so every time
you want to push in the kit you need to
times current value
by ten and add the new value all right
does it make sense
yeah okay okay let's do this okay prefer
search
does it make you hungry professors
yes breast first session not breakfast
okay there's one
preference and we call it root the
beginning the root of the
tree what's missing color if not we
first
first of all we have to check if the
root is empty or all right
if you lose is num we should return what
if it's empty tree what what's the sum
of the mt3 zero
yeah and then in python
what kind of what we are implementing q
so q
equals what what kind of
and then i need to add what we should
know is it
weight load this is a set and i need to
i have a tuple yeah load and
lose of value yeah because i need to
remember the value of the current of 200
roots of the camera
this is means that the integer from the
root
to current node okay okay then y
you what we need to check if the note
if the q is not empty how do we check if
the q is empty or not
why why why q
is what not
no zero bigger than zero but q how do we
check
how do we check the size of q there's
something missing here length
length yes we are done and now we know
we need to get the cube
and how do we kill it how do we get the
element from the kill
pop it yeah pop left or pop
put left okay now now we need to
assign it to current and then value we
have radio so because the
each anime in a queue has two elements
right each anime
and the queue is a tuper with two two
values right one is the node one is the
one one is the value so look is q dot
problem right
right all right okay now we have a
current we have a value and
if how do we check if a node is a leaf
node
and it doesn't have any
it doesn't have anyone children
and how do we check if it doesn't have a
children if current or left
is what is what if it doesn't have
children what what
what should we do if current love is
what
is the magic word is what doesn't have
it so
what's the name
this one come on now
yeah yeah and
look this is n yeah current all right
is what and current
line is none what's missing column
whether even if it's a need to know okay
then
let's edit this answer in the answer
yeah so what should we do now
if it's a different now what should we
do now
all right if it's a leaf now what should
we do
we shall add it editor
very well done okay then if current
if it has a if it has a left node
what should we do all right if it if if
that note has a left node left kick
what should we do if it now has a left
node what should we do
we push it in what
kill the what
what's the value times one this is the
value value
and then this is the previous value and
then this size can
add as one column value
current dot left value because we're
talking about the left
okay and if current all right
what if current on the right what should
we do a comment.right
q dot append current dot right
uh value times 10 add current
right wait all right
yeah and what's missing here
well there's something missing in the
code so what should we do now
pretend return yeah
yeah come on you're paying attention
yeah good job
yeah oh he's just guessing oh no
guessing
okay we're down you're paying attention
very good job as well okay for answering
this
it's very good job what's the time
complexity
oh definitely um oh something or
something
yeah if there are end nodes in the
binary tree
yeah because we're visiting each node
exactly how many times
and we are visiting one time okay what's
the space complexity
oh n
yeah dq yeah because we're using the
additional space to keep
the notes in the yeah we are
in queueing in kill means push something
into the kill dq it means take something
out of the queue okay
and this is the different operations
okay let's that's very good that's very
good okay so
that's it that's it for today say bye to
people say bye to people
see you tomorrow
bye bye good job good job