[Applause]
[Music]
problem
the problem is that we have three binary
tree one
two three four and then we want to sum
the loot
to the leaves so which is one two four
plus one
three yeah all right which is 137.
so yesterday we were using the
preference search yeah a little bit
review okay
so we we we visit the travelers tree
even
in level by level order which is
breakfast search yeah
breast first search and then we use the
queue
all right to push the note
and every time i take a note i need to
push its kit
back to the queue right back to the
queue and then
when it's a leaf now here we accumulate
the answer with the common value all
right doesn't make sense
and we will push it to the kill we how
do we get
12 how how do we
push 12 or 124 174 into the
cube from 12 so it's 12 times 10 plus 4.
am i right
yeah yeah okay so now can you tell me
what's that research
you can then yeah as long as
far as you can as steep as you can
travel yeah for example like
this is now one two three
four and then five
six seven
what's the order of the death star
search one two three four five six seven
eight
yes one two three four five six seven
i want to go to the left as steep as i
can right
now and then i finish here and then i go
as deep as i can from the right okay
not including the route again not
including
because look it's a it's basically a
recursive function
okay so because function like
okay so what's that what's the worst
meaning so look
yeah look if loot is now this is the
basic framework about definition if
bluetooth is numb we return
right yeah yeah and then now
now i need to visit the current note
right okay all right
yeah yeah okay let's do it
loot okay visit and then then we need to
visit
the left tree so we should lose our left
all right
all right and then visit
the right tree all right okay yeah so
that's the
framework of the deaf research so how
can we apply this to solve this problem
first of all what should we do now so
it's basically the same but we need to
remember
the the value yeah we need to carry over
the value so how about if i
change this with a current value right
yeah kind of like look
if root is noun then we return
zero right obviously yeah definitely
okay now i don't need to revisit the
loot right
look remember i have lose here but now
look what
i need to i need to
change one line of code which is to
return
the current value when we are at leaf
right
so let leaf know how do we do the
difference how do we check if it's a
leaf now
come on how do we check if it's not it
doesn't have any parent
so if you tell me if do you have any
kids not parents if
lou don't what
left left is num right
and read the right is none yeah we're
done
it's not the same but just right left
is toronto okay so now look if let us do
this now and left of life is numb so
what should we do
we return we don't work
ah yeah this current is the previous but
now we have this neutral value so we
can't stand on that
right okay now look dfs
pfs blue top left yes
and then we don't no no no this kind of
value how hard you
put push it here and we need to return
this is a okay and then we say b equal
dfs
rule right and then do this
and then we return what because look
this is the sum of the left tree
left tree this is the sum of the right
three and the answer is
one answer is one can you feel this
plant
doesn't make sense or blank
blank okay so this is the sum of the
electric look everything
look yeah one two three
and then there's one so this a is the
left string which is this
this one two three and right b b
is the right trick so return one
reason why come on it's all very obvious
so this is a this is b
and one
go to the left if you want to go to the
left
then we currently we know this value
current value
so how do we pass current definitely
current
current and what
we know value we are
right
right yeah because we are now adding
this
loot value yes we are adding this
bluetooth value but now the previous one
is current
current right look here suppose we are
here right
so the current value is what current
value is one
right and then the load value is two
and now we know if we want to move to
that three so
we should get 12 so it's current
this is current yeah times 10 is 10 plus
root of value yeah this is the lunar now
it's 2 so 10 plus 2 12
and then you'll go to the next line okay
that makes sense
so let's look with the little
modification we change we are
successfully changing this the
default search template to solve this
problem right therefore search
what's the current thing can you explain
to me what's the second parameter
current
current um what is it what why
what's this what's this what's this
parameter why are we
why why do we need to pass this
parameter current
yeah what does it mean this current so
look this current thing what does it
mean
it means that the lower
what are we doing here why we need to
pass the current times 10 plus
the what's this
uh it is it's what
what's the current it's it's 90 times
it's look if we are here at three what's
the current value
oh one weight what's that what if we
if we we are loot and if this is the
root now and what's the current value
a little bit yeah
leaf seven why is it seven no that's not
seven come on
one it only will be one five twelve
one two two three which number pick one
two
yeah twelve okay another one if the root
is here what's the current value
one four five one hundred forty five
okay if like
look if the load is here what's the
current value
if you don't know that is here what's
the current value is
14. yeah we're done so you know what's
color value yeah it's the value
let the previous from the root to the
node before to its parent
right now we need to pass this value how
do we pass this value we just times
these
10 we pass we times this 14 10 and then
plus this fight will be 145 right am
right
yeah what's the time complexity oh n
what's the n the number of nodes in the
binary tree
okay what's the space complex
because we are using the recursion the
question has the
complexity effects use of
stat you know navigation users do you
understand yeah yeah
okay so uh let up that will be it yeah
we're done today good job so
quick yeah yeah good job say bye bye bye
bye bye bye bye bye bye bye bye you want
to make it 10 minutes
so take a look okay i'm going to erase
this you know easily what's this
x b okay you actually you don't need to
assign to a plus b you can just return
these
return leads plus plus this okay doesn't
make sense