hey hello mr mr ryan how are you today
so can you remind me what's the binary
tree
what are your numbers numbers can you
draw a final two please
i'll draw it's not numbered it's a tree
you know but with the numbers yes upside
down yeah and where is the loot
okay can you also maybe you can make a
binary search tree do you remember oh
yeah oh can you make a partnership
obviously by the research tree is one
kind of binary okay
yeah and that's yeah we're done
i'll put
okay
okay so can you explain to me why what
is this man is a street
[Music]
the next one is smaller than the loop
and the right one
is bigger yeah strictly bigger so look
at these all the notes in the left tree
are strictly smaller than four right so
even these
if you can put a here because a is
bigger than four
yeah even if satisfy a is bigger than
two so all the left trees
must be smaller than the parents all the
right two must be bigger than right
now yeah yeah that's very good um okay
so
no that's it so how about look if if
let's say eric
yeah is seven and one
okay okay okay eight eight okay
eight a lion is what i'm seven
oh then i can't put a let's pretend you
are two okay
can i because it it doesn't satisfy the
final
street okay i can make one okay
hmm that's that
but this does not satisfy though let's
change this to 7.5
right and then this needs to be bigger
let's
put it at 7.2 okay and then that would
be one okay let's apprentice that's true
and then
seven is y and eric's is eight is okay
yeah my parent is 7.5 okay that's fine
okay so now
the target is like the if i give you uh
if i want to find the sibling you know
the sibling
brothers yeah brother sister shipping
okay so
suppose i want to find the brothers of
eric that needs to
how do you do this what's the idea how
how are we dealing with this problem
so basically you're finding the cream in
the binary search tree
okay remember it's final research
yeah how are we using these finances but
first of all
paul we're finding a node in the binary
search tree
uh we start from the root yeah if it's
smaller
you go to the right
which one is smaller go to the right oh
yeah
if if we uh if the one you're looking
for is smaller
you're gonna don't need the project a
long time no go to the right
go to the left because you wanna look
you want to find the area which is
bigger go to the right you want to find
the right and which is smaller
you go to the left right yeah okay so
this
what's the time complexity of this one
if there are
n and trees in the final
sorry i knows in the balance search tree
are you sure we are using the final
search tool
if if the tree something if the tree is
highly balanced you know high dependence
right so so in the worst case if it's
not
high dependence it's all one but in the
optimum case no in the optimum
i mean the tree is highly balanced every
time i cut into the search space
by two so what's that i'll end
the body waiting no we're not talking
about constants here so every time i cut
look if there are eight notes every time
i search it i i cut into four
at two and i search for notes and i
again i may get
one check and i search to two so what's
kind this kind of thing
every time i cut into half remember
remember the binary search remember
every time
look at yeah yeah my favorite one
yeah again yeah if the tree is highly
balanced
if not kylie parents what's the term
complex
why is that can you give me an example
what in what cases
it's not oh uh
this yeah yeah well it's hot it's like
linked list because the final two binary
research it can be still final search
tree
and it will be like one two three four
but in order to search for
you need to find sweet four times yes
yeah does it make sense so this is not
making use of the binary system
the the characteristics of that okay so
now
so they we know how to search the note
in the binary session
how about we search the siblings so when
we go to the
brother so look we know we look for eric
right
so we know it's on the left side right
but when we before we go to the left
side we know
the plot of area of of the
next node is right right did we get it
yeah so so we just need to add one more
step is that before we go to the left or
go to the right we remember
the product note of the number you want
to visit next
right and suppose okay here i i found a
ryan here
right but before i go to come here i
know
this nose brother is eric so and i
can find it right because each but in
front of the trees
you only have two kids am i right yeah
does it make sense yeah
okay so yeah you supposed to read this
one
yeah okay so this has some
assumption that the planet now always
exists okay so you
what does that mean it means that my
little tree or
we have each dough will have zero or two
children okay does it make sense yeah
okay so
we can do it let's do this okay
tell me what to do okay define uh let's
do
find five brother okay
fine brother okay that would have to be
brother
okay i'll see you there anyway root and
let's find
this one maybe like let's let's name it
early okay
okay okay
so given eric we want to find ryan yeah
okay
yeah okay so look if
no no we're not going to because we know
ryan is there so
and the root is not empty so let's skip
for now
so let's say wire root you know what
root then
let's do it answer okay maybe let's do
it in ryan
y n equals num beginning we
we haven't found it yeah right because
now
now why are roots
if root
top value is
is airing okay look it's eric and then
what should we do if you found a root if
come and do this everything we return
ryan right because ryan is here right
ryan is there yeah yeah does it make
sense
yeah okay now look it
look the value is smaller than
eric so what does it mean
so so the area is bigger than the
current root
so look this is 0.5
you are looking for eric eight yeah so a
is bigger than three point five so what
what do we do that's seven point five
we gotta take that right yeah so
how do we go to the right e root
equals root
and then because we go to the right so
we know we need to update the lion to
the left right
i'm right does it make sense down here
will be y n equals
does that make sense no there's no
answer come on
okay yeah but here look the eagle
look we are here rude enough are we
going to the right right
right and where's the right where's the
right
on the left so before this play
so look here's
[Music]
here because it always changed
so this has to be here right so ryan
equals loot
on left and then i go to the here right
am right does it make sense
does it make sense yeah okay so here
about this
this one and me so look this one loose
value if it's bigger than every what
should we do
what then here so if it's on the left
hand side so what should we do
every
[Music]
yeah always go to the opposite okay yeah
okay what's the time conference
what's the name
come on it's the same as the previous
one come on
we are editing just extra bit ryan
look if we are not look it's almost the
same as searching the note in the
parenthesis
except that we are returning y and not
returning area here right
right we are returning by look if you
get rid of these
returns then it's the same it's
basically the same as searching a note
in the final research
search but we are retaining the parent
and the ryan's though okay
so how how do we update ryan snow every
time we go to the left
we update the ryan snow on the right
every time we go to the right we update
the
lines on the left yeah yeah okay can we
do this
using the recursion
cache no no no
let's do it
let's do this
okay let's do a search function here
define
look a fine and then let's add one more
parameter here right
because we need to know past the
sequence okay so let's play root
uh we are finding the right end and
we are passing the sibling which is okay
yeah
correct
with the ryan and eric okay everything
is the sibling okay
this is the current sibling we are
looking we are returning
okay look look if
karen root is if caroline is right and
what should we do
if carolina is generic well done whoa
that's great
yeah listen yeah okay that's good
all right now look if loot
okay let's say if lower equals
let's let's
look the value is smaller than lion
no if it's smaller than ryan look if
ryan is bigger than the root
somewhere where is the lion when ryan is
in the right tree or rough street
remember left
look this is the root right and then
ryan is bigger than note so it's in one
right yeah yeah
and we can look return return fine
every and then we do this or what
don't lie i know he's still passing the
lion
and then what's going passing here right
now do the left right
all right you're not paying attention
again
okay so look return find loot and y
what what should i put here come on
no
look we are going to the right we are
going
right with the 5000 now
can i ask you to be good boy i am
we can find blue dot y we're going to
the right
we want to find the right and we want to
find what's eric's value now me
no no what's happening
right we're going to the right of left
come on do the left
and then return here will be the other
direction find the rule
it's on the left side left and then
right end and then what's the ceiling my
please
passing what's eric come on i need to
update everything
we are doing right come on does it make
sense
does it make sense yeah okay i'm going
to erase some of you okay
please please
no no here maybe i i'll write it again
and then you tell me okay
five five okay fine
brother brother
okay you want to find orion okay
wire something okay right
okay that's good if luke
dude equals
okay let's have eric he's very close now
if luke was right if lulu's
smaller than wire
do this
do this to this okay there are two here
two things can you read it
uh something with something
we did yeah i can write one for you if
blue
and white smaller and y and then every
would be equals what
the line is more longer than that yeah
yeah i know don't what
and then that's all right ryan is bigger
than the loot so ryan is on the right
hand side so every
left hand side and then what should we
do here
and then we possibly can return
everything
here because it's none right if ryan is
not found and then this
this loop will be ended and then we'll
return eric
right does that make sense oh written
down i think it will be written now
which is better
written now because if ryan is not found
we return now it means that
the brother of writing is not there
right yeah
okay what's the time complexity oh logan
what's the space complexity
log end no no do we use the extra space
here
oh one yeah we're done okay so can we
say bye to people