go hey hello mr mr ryan how are you
today
yes okay so remember a few days ago we
talked about a two sum yeah
so it's given an array one two five
three two seven and given a target like
uh uh
five and then can you find the index two
three two three yes all three two you
know it just doesn't matter okay the
first one
or any one yeah so what
what how how are we doing this remember
the blue falls
will take the long time what's the time
complexity for the blue force
oh one and i think
something squared yeah look every time
you
you check you iterate these n numbers
and then for the second number you
iterate and
right yeah all right
okay so we can use the which which data
structure can
we can use to speed it up
notebook notebook yes because we when we
visit
once we remember it on the notebook and
then we check
if the target minus the current number
if it's in the notebook right do you
understand yeah
i'm gonna talk about something like
three of them
oh good good point the other maybe maybe
not not today but maybe
later on for some five some right so
today we'll talk about
if the array is started what happened
so even arrangement much easier really
okay let's say
one two four seven you need comments
okay one two three four thousand hey
let's try find if there are five
so how do if this array is sorted
it's auto three yeah how do you get it
how do you
do you can you come up with the fast
agreement to do it or
in one time can you do it and i went
down
remember we talked about i'll give you a
hand how about if i
start here and here
one person yeah yeah okay so
if if you just add them up together
and then if it's bigger
if
[Music]
yeah yeah okay okay still bigger yeah
and go here yeah and you'll find it
if it's smaller you move it right yeah
that's time complexity okay yeah does it
make sense
so the this requires the array to be
sorted yeah
all right yeah okay can we cover this
quickly
define
okay look
i j equals zero
lengths t minus one okay so i and j
pointing to both ends all right yeah
wire i smaller than
j right come on yeah all right
okay then we pretend we know it's it's
there
return this i or say or we just return
to
if to to to mean that we will find it
okay
if not i plus nums
j smaller than t what happened can you
tell me
if m i plus number j smaller than t
uh we move i i what
[Music]
yeah okay another
another look okay so this is all end
time and what's the space complexity
i think owen where are we using the
space here
which which do you think is always in
space
are there any space we need to use nope
no what's it
one constant okay so one constant
and how about that yeah that's okay one
two three four five seven
nine okay so let's look for number five
and if we can hold
yeah i know we can use the two pointer
just like that moving
towards until the mid in scenario how
about if we use another approach like
you know we because this array is
already sorted let's
just check this number yeah
fix try the first number like 1 and
let's find
if the rest of the numbers have the 4
because 5 minus 1 is 4 yeah all right
yeah and if let's try 2 if there are
3 in the in this part right
all right so basically we can try the
first number
1 2 three four five and now we try the
the number next to it right to it
because it's already sorted
and we're looking for the number which
is five minus one
minus that number so what was this
finding a number in a sorted array
what is it what what it is the time
complexity
finding a the number in a sorted array
what's the time complexity you're
finding
sorry i think n o one
finding it in a sorted array sorted or
refining a number
you always checking how right uh go
again log n
okay i don't tell you what the first
number is n right
yeah so it needs time n times log n all
right
okay so let's do it
let's do it yeah so look first of all i
need to define the binary search yeah
define
final research okay yes and then let's
do
uh i for the left okay maybe left
and right okay and then we're looking
for the number t
right yes yeah yeah
okay so how how do we suppose we know
the numbers here while
left smaller equals right okay
what's the meter the middle is
equal left and right left and right
divided by two okay the right you will
use the double double divide okay
and look if nums
if nums
meat smaller than t
what should we do if t is bigger than
half so
look this is the meter if
the number we are looking for is on the
this side
so what should we do
we should t is here because this is
middle this is
l this is r and that is meter and then
the number we're looking for is t
we cut it in half again yeah but so we
need to move left to mid or otherwise
what
it is if it's smaller
if it's indeed this half or also if this
thing is in
this half
right equals minus one
[Music]
this complexity is 01. yeah
what's the space complexity for this one
or something here oh what do we need
also or what do we need a space one
this yeah b is left to right okay that's
right
b is left right here okay remember this
function here
and then look so what should we just do
look
for i in
range lens number yeah the first number
yeah
the number first number is i the index
is i
right yeah and the number we are looking
for is
let's say a equals t minus
nums i right yeah
this is normal we're looking for look
alright yeah
all right yeah because we want to add it
to t
and we know we are we we are now numbers
i right
and the numbers we're looking for is a
right yeah then
if bs what's the left
what should i do the left left
right will be length num
minus one right and then a
returns true right does it make sense so
can you fill in
here we can return what here return what
which entry
remember this is the left this is the
right so what's the left value i should
put
i should give i have to find a research
so look
we are fixing this this is i we are
currently here
and we want to find the value the final
research here because the
entire array is sorted yeah we try this
first number one
two and we want to find the for example
five minus two find the number three
in the rest so what should i put here
the left what's
why does the e go left what's left
i add one yeah that's what i'm looking
for come on yeah
place
so look this is o and yeah this loop
yeah all right and this is final
research in
in the
in the rest so it'll be o log n normally
actually look because every time if
you're not putting a i minus 1 if you
put a 0 it will still work
right it will still work because your
brand is in the whole
array right yeah but there are some
repeated
range because look i already tried one
two three
right i don't need to search for the
elements before me right because i
already searched it right
that doesn't make sense yeah so you're
narrowing down you're narrowing the
search space for the binary search
eric does it make sense so you'll be
quicker but actually the time complexity
is there
oh and log n actually is o n o
and log n and this n is getting smaller
right array
this n is getting smaller but its sphere
is in the
same square of this n so it's a constant
here
so we we drop the constant all right
does it make sense so
it's still oh and open am i right look
yeah
yeah i'm right so can you tell me what
should i put here
okay that's it what for i in range
this and a what's the a what's the value
we are looking for
what's a equals something about
because a lumps
i this is current the first number
plus something equals the target number
so this is the number we are looking for
so a equals one
t this is x t
one minus
i yeah come on this is super easy yeah
right and then we search it for remember
this p is from here yeah
oh log n yeah this is o n n times
log n times so the complexity is what
oh and log n what's the stake some
complexity
one yeah well done yeah my favorite your
favorite but sometimes
it's not true yeah you're just guessing
guessing okay
that's it for today so does it make
sense today
good say bye to people