today we're going to talk about
sweet song so can you guess what's
threesome
it's just the same as teaching but it's
picking three
picking three yeah i'm taking three okay
let's see
two four three seven
eight ten one
picking three numbers let's see if you
can make a
number eight can you make a number eight
with
picking three numbers picking three
numbers
it has to be three four three one we're
done
four three one okay all right so
that's the three songs any idea how
we're doing this
how are we doing this if it one sum it
will just be
eight yeah i know there's no one from
okay
anyway any idea if you
don't have any idea we can always what
three fourths yes whatever improve us
how are we moving it
we check each pair right okay
listen i j k so how many ways of i j
k so first of all i have a loop
going from i to this way yeah and then i
go
have another
okay so what's the current complexity if
i go i i i blue first
the pairs i log in o and
square a1 oh and cubic
oh and come on yes because you're
picking three yeah yeah look
exactly because because look it's like
that alright look for i
if there are numbers yeah in range and
yeah
yeah and then what's going here for j
in range range i
right right and another loop all right
listen to me right
4k in range range what
numbs range j because look
i t yeah look i
is from zero to n and when i pick i i
will pick
j which is zero to i right pick j yeah
and k will be zero to j right so in this
case look
this needs to end right all right
this is another n this is n okay
so what's the term complexity
cubic n times percent okay that's it and
then okay you can say if i
if not i plus num z plus numbers k
equals target then we become two right
yeah all right
and fourth okay so can we do better
can we do better all right can we do
better not brief
thing no proof of thing how how can we
do better without a profession
i give you a notebook
may not help me have this case okay how
do you
propose that with the notebook thing
[Music]
no booking no book i think you will work
you'll be working yeah
how do how do we prove uh how do we do
[Music]
it
and subtract it from your target
and try to find it
yes i think your approach might work so
basically we don't work
yeah it depends on how you implement it
so face basically
we go through these and then we go
through the first number yeah
that's the first number and we remember
it right
we remember it yeah oh maybe
remember the the two sums let's talk
about two sum and then you'll find out
why
the why the threesome can be based on
twosome
so two something look if we all find two
numbers
remember we can go through and then if
it's not
if the target is not in the notebook we
put it in the notebook and we continue
looking for the target minus current
number right for example
look look two i'm looking for six yeah
okay it's six in the notebook no
no then i go here but i put a two here
right
yeah it's 4 in a notebook if a plus
a minus 1 ignore book no i put a 4 here
in the notebook do you get it
yeah all right does it make sense
yeah yeah okay so how can we apply the
two some
angle to the three sound
how do we apply this
we go through these need to be looking
at the two okay
hold on the first number eric look how
about the first number
try two right yeah i know the first
number is two
and i'm the the sum of yeah the sum of
the next two number is six yes
yeah okay so the where's the next the
next where's the numbers i need to look
for
it's in excluding these two right all
right
so the problem becomes finding two sum
of six in this array right we already
know how to use the two sum right
so look if you can't find it you're
going to the next one next one okay four
i'm looking for four two songs in this
array right how about
t because i already tried two so i don't
mean i don't
i don't need to look for this anymore
right all right
so look for can i find five six in
a four here three one
yeah three one so look three four three
one that's it yeah
does it make sense
so how remember how we're doing these
two thumb
one approach is to number three
no no sorted
two pointer yeah yeah that will be
easier so if we sort it
so first of all we sort it and then okay
i'm ready okay
okay
we can brew first the two sum as well
but if we profess the two something the
complexity will be still and cubic right
and because both sum of two sum is n
square
using the applying the two sum on the
three sum
because the first number we need o n
right n times right
right all right yes yeah does it make
sense
okay using the uh
notebook make it end that's that's right
or two pointer using that so all
together the term complexity is what
n squared yeah one square so look we are
reducing in from blue force always
cubic to one square it's better right
it's much better right
does it make sense okay define threesome
find lumps and target t
okay target okay look okay
and equals lens
then we how how are we sorting these
numbers array
how do we solve it merge
nums let's see what's the term
complexity of this one
login and login come on and log in okay
and log in okay okay then
look for the first number let's say i
in range 10
range n okay because the first index for
i
in column yes
j will be the second number j k
will be will be equal to r j will be
equal to
k will be equal to what can you guess i
already know the first number is i and
then i need to
do the two sum here okay so this is the
first
first index and then this is the whole
array
this is n and what's here
what's here i plus one yeah i plus one
and then this
and minus one and minus one because they
default
yeah because the index is start from
zero okay
now all right look now y
j smaller than k what's missing
okay then let's let's put it s equals
let's put it
as numbers i plus
numbers let's put it in a number okay
you know s variable plus numbers k right
now look if s equals t
return
what if s equals
[Applause]
[Music]
minus one minus equals one now
because you're moving if it's smaller if
it's smaller i need to move the
lower hair lower lower pointer
i need to move it yeah return forward
here all right
yeah what's the time complexity
i think
here look actually look at the accurate
complexities o and log n plus
here's o and here's our square
this this is trivial compared to oven
square right this is
o n times n this is all n times log n so
which is bigger
one yeah so we we just
discard this one and we remove the
trivial part because this is more
dominant
yeah this is this bigger part so we
don't
we ignore this right because this is
bigger
this is domination this is more
important almost
uh consuming okay
so what's that space complexity i won
oh i went square and four oh one yeah
because there are no
one you're guessing you're
oh not understanding oh i see you okay
so any questions so far
no no and i'm going to erase it okay
okay so what what what what
i am
what's the beginning j k equals
writing beautifully not i plus y
boom e
[Music]
yes
this is this is the same as j equals i
plus one and
k equals n minus one doesn't make sense
bye yes does it make sense
okay that's it
bye bye bye let's see
see you tomorrow