[Applause]
can you give me an example about the
binary okay
yes yeah oh where is
oh yes dude
[Music]
one and i'll put one in here
okay okay so good so basically eight to
eight
so basically uh how many loads which one
is the root
eight eight and which one are the leaf
notes six
one one okay that's good what
what is binary mean two so that means
that each node could have
most two kids right and each now could
have
at most one parent except the
loot which doesn't have turns okay does
it make sense
yeah and for the pineal tree it does not
have cycles yeah it doesn't
have cycles all right it doesn't make
sense okay so for this binary trees
how many ways can we traverse the binary
trees
breakfast difference breakfast search
definitions okay
so if we square for search what's the
order
can you give me the order zero two six
one one well the answer basically is
level by level yeah
and what's the definite search order
eight zero six one two
one we're done yeah that's good so look
if we look at each levels
we sum it up some of the nodes in the in
each level so this one is level zero
with sum eight this one is number
level one which is zero two and this one
is number
eight with yellow eight number three
okay let's make it another one so let's
say
is uh nine nine okay
okay so that's three oh okay
nine okay so our task
is given a binary tree we want to find
out which level
has the most largest sum which is the
money right
okay so if if it's
if it has more than one level has the
same
uh same sum we can just return any of it
okay does it make sense
yeah yeah yeah what you're doing
what are you doing what's that jeffy
trophy okay okay trophy okay okay yeah
yeah yeah trophy yes number one three
yeah
okay so how are we doing this
how are we doing this is breakfast
breakfast
is easier you can also use the
differences but we can talk about it
tomorrow okay it'll be more harder
yeah it'll be less intuitive you know
because this we are calculating the sum
we need to
get the maximum sum right for each level
so obviously it's quite straightforward
is to use the breakfast version right
all right because it travels the tree
uh level by level okay so what kind of
data structure are we using to implement
a implementation
p q okay let's do it secondly
p f s root what's missing
if root is noun
so if root is not which is a special
case of binary tree
we should yeah we can define it we can
argue it's you know or
nothing because we are retaining the
level which
it doesn't have any levels
of the nothing right so we return none
which is
more which is better yeah because mt3
does not have
any level remember the first route and
it's a level zero okay
okay so look yeah q equals what kind of
data structure are we using in python
deficit dude we initialize with the load
what's this what should we put here what
kind of data structure are we
implementing are we using as the key
thank you yes welcome bq so thank you
what's dq mean
double and the key okay whatever so
for the follow breakfast search
we already initialized the queue with
the loot and then if how do we check how
do we repeat one layers element in the
queue
so we will use the wire loop right yeah
so we can do this wire length q bigger
than zero right
right what's missing column okay so all
these can be replaced by just y
cubed which is simpler yeah it means
that y still lets the element in the
cube
correct yeah okay y q
then normally we take we kill one
element one by one right
but now for this uh
actually we every time we want to dq
the all the elements in the queue is the
pointing to the same level it's the same
level right for example look
the first one is a right now is a a is
belong to the level zero right we know
it's level zero right
if we take it out we push all the kids
of a is zero and two and the next time
we wanted to kill
we know all the kills in here will be
same will be the same level right
yeah that will be zero and two will be
level one if i take him out
and i push all the keys of zero and one
it will be six one two
and next time i take it out i know six
one two is the same level does it make
sense
okay that's good so in order to do this
we need to
have a value of value to store the
level yeah we call it level equals zero
at the beginning right
and then now current notes
let's say sc equals nanski then skill
what that means it means that we want to
know how many nodes
in the next level all right okay so now
for dash or i
in range sz
column yeah so now we we need to
do this dq how many times we need to do
this dq or how many times
so for in ranges sc
this underscore yeah means that we don't
want to use any variable it doesn't
matter you can put the
i j k or we are not using this variable
here so that's why we just put a dash
it means we don't care right that
doesn't make sense
yeah and then repeat as the time and z
okay so now we also need the variable to
to sum up the value right
let's call it x okay x equals
zero okay and then look eric
s equals zero let's play some equals and
x
equals let's do pq right q dot
one how do we kill top one left
first always left and always next is
right always no it's
usually okay pop left we take a kill
eric
and then take an element which is now x
and then x
plus equals one we want to edit the sum
to the x variable
so it will be x stop value yeah
right yes yeah and now i need to
push its key to to better the kill yeah
if x dot
left what should we do and and if x dot
y what should we do
can you tell me key dot
[Music]
open a pen yeah open s
now we have this sum so after this for
loop we know
that s is the current sum of the current
level so we need to do this
if s bigger than
we also need another variable called the
next sum okay
next sum and then
next level okay next time next level
okay and then initialize to
minus infinity okay this variable how do
you initialize to minus infinity
you do this float float
i and f converting the i n f infinity
okay look eigenf means infinity
converted to flow negative so
so look if s e bigger than maximum
alright if x equals bigger than s sum
then what next sum equals x right
yeah and then we need to decode the
level at this time next level equals
level
okay we forgot the level thing look the
level here would be
level plus equals one yeah because every
time you're doing operation
you're increasing that one level i'm
right yeah and return let's return
what are we returning return map max one
v level next level we're returning level
what's the space complex why is
okay look because look there are lots of
variables that we
introducing right look at this maximum
next level right
and then we need to check it with the
bigger the max sum then we update the
maximum equals x and remember the next
level at this time right does it make
sense
yeah okay now we can also
we can also remove these and then use uh
let's let's just record it in in a data
yeah and every time
every time no no no every time we
we don't check this evil we just put a
theta
theta put it in a dictionary and level
up yeah because this level is
increasing from zero to one to two to
and equals
so after this we have a dictionary which
has the key
as the level level and then value
as the sum right yeah now then how do we
return
how do we return if the maximum
the key of the dictionary when the value
is the maximum for example look at
like traditional yeah using this
like this p let's say p
dot com look at p equals
eric let's see l equals a
okay ryan equals seven
equals seven okay and then how do we
return
the key of the item which has the
maximum value
is you get my point first of all you
need to
scale the value this is key this is
value which value has the biggest is the
biggest
me eight yeah and i want to return the
key yeah
doesn't make sense does it make sense
uh yeah we can sort it um we can do this
look we can first of all get the value
v because we get one max key top values
yeah
now you need you need a values yeah you
know the value which is
eight and then you can just do this for
i
in p and then if
if p i equals this v
then return return i yeah does it make
sense
does it make sense does it make sense
first of all we get the value which is
a maximum and then we look we iterate
the keys with arie and ryan we check out
which value is equals to a
and we turn the i which is the key all
right we can do it using numdah which is
simpler
you know the one-time function so we can
do this max
look this is this is one line look p
stop items
and then how are we checking the maximum
we can use this
lambda x column
do x turn the key which is one x zero is
the key
x one is the value right and then after
this
this will return the item which is a
weekend eight and which i want the area
and i put a zero
fancy syntax do you see it all right
yeah
yeah does it make sense this is the
lambda function number is like a shock
function
which is take x and then return
i mean x is the pair it's a key value
pair and i want to
i want to get the maximum based on the
value
here right and when i get a maximum pair
which is airing an eight and now i want
to return
the key which is zero which is area okay
so why i'm talking about this is
previously breakfast search
buffer search will store the level and
sum
into a pair into additional data right
which is this is level and then
this is the sum error i'm right
dictionary
key value right and after this
i can just use these next return
data items number xx one
zero and then you will return the key
which is the level
am right yeah yeah does it make sense
yeah
okay uh yeah
so breakfast search okay so can you tell
everybody now what have you learned so
far just one one or two sentences
yeah it's your turn begin your show
please
can you all you know using this can you
just
just tell everybody what have you
learned so far
you don't need to write a code you just
explain what have you learned so far
okay okay you can write a binary tree
and then okay
write properly not drawing it
yeah that's a very giant
giant gigantic loot
huge loot oh okay
all put in yeah
hurry up okay i'll say
yes
so
explain it like explain to a
two-year-old boy okay
come on explain to tv
[Music]
the next level equals 13 13
the level which has the largest sum
right yeah
which is 15 but we want to know it's
yellow
level okay so what algorithm are we
using
what's breakfast search level level
okay and what kind of data structure are
we using what's kill
first thing first out in python
what kind of how are we creating a queue
in python
we are the both ends what's that
double and dq dq yeah thank you and then
at the beginning we need to
initialize the kill with switching out
which with the internet at the beginning
are we initialize the q
we're initializing the key
with
thinking no no i mean which node has to
be put in the queue first
loot okay that's it okay that's it for
today thank you
say see you tomorrow okay what are you
going to
what are you drawing a pineapple okay
that's good
pineapple it looks like a turtle to me
turtle is on on fire look this is the
head of tucker
this is back
okay okay that's it see you tomorrow