hello hello mr mr ryan
do you still remember what we talked
about yesterday
something about breakfast search here
yeah and it's like the binary tree
and we want what we want to do here
[Music]
the maximum we find the level which has
the largest sum right
in this case regular level zero is one
level one is five
level two is four so we return level one
because if it has the largest sum five
right
remember how are we doing it
how are doing it uh using
this cube yeah which is what such
uh first breast research okay
so breakfast because we visit the world
uh visit the binary tree level by river
level by level and using a queue which
is
first thing what q
what's what's cube yeah in python
what are we using the stack
not the stack q it's just no queue what
what from
what class name of the queue are we
using in python
dg dq yes dq double ndq right
so now today we can use the differences
so what's different search can you tell
me
we're going as deep as we can okay so
for example if there are trees like that
five so what's the difference search
[Music]
yeah five and then what's next six
seven maybe three and maybe five
four yeah it's not maybe it's it's maybe
or maybe not
it's one two five six seven three four
and what's the professorship
what's the order of the present search
one day three five
six four seven we are done yes we're
done you're listening yeah okay
yeah okay so so we can do a different
search but we also need to
[Music]
work so we visit the note and then we
put the sum we
accumulate the sum of that level
with this the value of the current note
so
in order to do this we need to be
passing the
level in the definitions right yeah
somehow
when we recursively visit the node we
need to remember
which level it is right yeah yeah
yeah okay so so
define different search roots
so we also need a level yeah level
and labor and then we we let's
let's put it uh put it in a sound
sum so sums is uh is a dictionary okay
something is dictionary with key
key is the level and the value
is the sum for that level right oh yeah
okay so look if load yes
is now what should we return what should
we do we just return
because it's now i know we just return
yeah okay
we can look we don't need to return
anything
because this is the function with return
and we don't need to return anything the
the purpose of this function is to
accumulate to update the level
to add the sum of the of end
node value of the load to the level
right all right all right yeah so look
so how do we add the root of value to
the levels
with the sum so look something is a
dictionary what did i just say
the key is the level okay okay all right
can you pay attention not just
okay so what's your iphone here the key
what's the key and then press equal what
plus plus equal what
huh what's the key here the key
is level level without and then plus
plus equals
this is the left tree recursively so can
you tell me what's dfs
here passing what passing which is
really
where what valley dfs we want to visit
the left tree
so what's this left tree is
dot
[Music]
okay i know what's level value what's
the level really
we go down and then what's what happened
to the level value
the level
yeah the left current is level and we go
down one note so what happened to the
level
what the what happened level yeah
wow
and then what's what should i do
visiting the right tree can you can you
do this
we don't write yeah
level one yeah
okay okay so look this is
definitely simple yeah that's it so when
i call this i just need to call
therefore search look before that i need
to
create a look this is the root and the
value
i'm passing at the beginning is zero
yeah and the sum
look this sums all right this is the
function yes
i need to do this before before
dictionary and in
okay then they'll create a dictionary
with the integer by default okay and
then
i just need to do this depth test route
what should i pass with the level and
then sums
at the beginning what's the level the
level
is what's the level
so you will look you will recursively
call this if you notice now
then just return otherwise i would at
the level
look the first time the dictionaries
is empty alright look the decision is
empty and then
by default because we are using this
before dictionary in
it means that by default if the key is
not existing in the dictionary the value
will be zero
if look if you're not using the default
dictionary
if you're using this this simple curly
brace what happened
if because there's no items in the
dictionary if you reference it it will
be a problem because
there's no such item in the dictionary
that's why we use the default dictionary
there's a small difference okay
with the default dictionary we specify
the type
it means that if the key is not existent
in additionally by default
we mean it's zero so at the beginning
the sum
of the level zero is zero and plus equal
to the value right
then you will accumulate right and on
recursively you go to the left tree
which is the level plus one and go to
the right tree which is the
level password and eric the difference
says actually because
here we are traversing the binary tree
in o n right the what's the time
complexity by the way
what's n the number of nodes yeah same
as yesterday yeah yeah
yeah yeah okay so look
one question yeah so does the other
matter here
that's the other matter here don't don't
maybe or maybe not
there's no other matter here if we need
it in the tree all right
is it okay if i visit the right tree
first
but it doesn't have to be left three
maybe
or maybe not look the task here is we
are traversing the tree
and then we update the notes after the
decision
with the with with the correct
correct sum yeah so does it matter if i
i do list first is it okay if i do this
first
for example i this three left look i
like one two
three these three line
does it have to follow this order or can
it be
any older yes or no
yes or no does it have to be this order
can that be
one three two or two one three or two
three one there there are
six permutations right yeah that's the
element sixth permutation all right
so does it have to be this way
if i swap two and three will happen i
visit the right tree
first and then visible tree yeah and
then
does it still work yeah yeah yeah it
still works be confident it still works
it's just the way different
the purpose of this function because the
function is to
update is the most important thing is
this one right it doesn't matter when
you do it you will do it
you'll be impressed you'll be exclusive
this line of code will be executed
anyway right so it's like adding
the root of value to lesson right it's
like a notebook
yeah key with level and value is the sum
okay does it make sense
yeah okay after this look after this we
have
this sum which has the key which is the
level
with the different value and how are we
getting the maximum
level for that key do you remember
yesterday i'll erase all these yeah
all right look okay all right
sums like you'll be
something like that okay additionally
okay let's say level 0 with some
30 level 1 with the sum
40 and level 2 with the sum 10
so i want to return level 1
because level 1 has the largest sum 30
right
0 1 2 is the key 30 40 10 is the value
a sums is the dictionary key value pair
which is the notebook right
yeah okay so how do we return this one
remember yesterday
there are two ways one way is that you
can do this max
you can get this all right max
this is the values yeah when you do this
sums
dot values what does it mean what what
does it mean
some stock value you will turn this into
a
at least which is what 30
40 10 right yeah this next
and how about some keys can you tell me
what does it return um
what's key what's that
zero one two we're done okay so look
some of the value is this and then if i
do the max of this
so what does it mean it will give me 40
right yes
and then i can fall the key
in sums then if key if the sums key
equals this 40 then i return the key
right this is what i am doing but
another way
more easy is what max you do this
max yeah look you can't do this maximum
because what happens maximum you will
return the maximum of the keys
this is by default right which is two
which is no we want we want the number
one right because number one is
very right and if we do the max sum the
values
will return 40 but i only return one
right
that doesn't make sense so how do we do
this we can do this max
sums the items
what's items items that will be this
value pair yeah and then look
key i want to use the a key function
to determine which is the next key
equals
number
[Music]
item x item right which
is x one which is the value right
and after that are you look at me look
some of the items will give me this yeah
140 yeah
yeah and then i watch this on the key
then i
do this yellow which is the key if the
one is the 40 all right
does it make sense so after this we can
can compute the maximum level
which the level which has the louise's
sum does it make sense
okay so can you tell me if i put a one
what do you want to return
what return wow
[Music]
what's yellow is one and one is what and
when
we come back
come on this sum the item is this one
will return because i specify the key
which is the
value i want to get the largest value
which is by salted by this 40 yeah
yeah so this this whole thing
this whole thing is 140 it's a 2 per 140
item so if 0 is it's 1 and how about if
i put a one
what does it return come on there are
two numbers here
one where's the one forty well done come
on yeah i just said yellow is
ten one and one will be the ten forty
okay does it make sense
[Music]
and of oh and also we are using the
recursion
because you have normally has us
as a stack you know if we are doing
recursion
it means that usually there will be a
stack
it makes sense yours okay so that's it
for today
good job today 15 minutes okay so
can you say bye bye to people i see you
tomorrow
okay let's