go
hello mr miss away and how are you today
it's friday today it's friday okay
so do you still remember telling jump
yeah
what's telling them
[Music]
come on give me answer what's the parent
can you give me an example
it will be the same you'll be the same
okay so can you give me an example
race car yeah so for example s if it's a
parent jump like what we can get
is it's river is still the same so how
do we reverse it
this one this will remember two double
column minus one
and that will be equal to s well that
will be returning the truth okay
yeah doesn't make sense okay so today
listen carefully okay listen carefully
so today we're given a string given the
string
let's say
[Music]
so let's say they have key
t different unique letters right
t unique letters remember it's unique
okay t
equals three but length is four because
there are two c but there's three
three unique letters yeah
yeah okay and how about i tell you that
i want to make a pending drum
that is size of 10. size of k
size of k pain
but you can use the letters
the characters in here look look many
times
as many times as possible okay so let's
see as
many times as possible for example you
can use a
k times it doesn't matter it's a
penetration right so for example if k
equals 1 so what's the answer
how many how many parent terms of
single size why is it three
because you can pick three is a good
answer yes
so yeah so what's three there's three
unique numbers
yeah so three okay three so let actually
is t okay let's put t
right yeah k equals two you got how many
[Music]
how many k equals two nine no no no no
no
no k equals two okay so this is two two
parallel okay so how many how many
possibilities
whole three how many i can pick for the
first one
uh three three when i take the three i
this one is just the middle right yeah
you pick one and you determine this one
is fixed right because if you
pick a this one must be a right so it's
t
this is again t how about k
equals three
maybe nine why is my can tell me
i think it's like okay three okay three
inventors
like many possibilities for the first
one
three t but if this t this has to be the
same right yeah
so let's measure one that's an odd
number in a meter
it means i have i can put how many
chairs here
if it's zero three yeah you can pick for
example
you you a a that's two yeah you can put
a a b c in the middle right i think it's
nice
a b c you know it's still apparent right
so each one
your t t times t right
nine okay
how about k equals four
four can can 40 uh penetrate size
string of case for k equals four size
four how many possibilities
sixteen sixteen why is this thing can
you give me a number
um
[Music]
the middle two have to be the same
so yeah so when you know there are two
options for the first one you also
the the last last letter is also fixed
there yeah
and the second one is to the second to
the last right so how many possibilities
here
uh t so it's t times t
okay yeah so that doesn't make sense now
so what's
what's the conclusion okay okay
and let's give a string and then give a
k or what's missing
okay now what should we do we need to
count how many
how many unique letters in the s right
yeah
how can we do it what are we using
no no list s so what
if k is one return
yeah you can do this if k equals two if
k equals three k
can be unlimited are you going to write
a thousand a million times of if
yeah we're not going to do that it's not
possible right
so as what kind of data structure are we
using here to
to count the unique numbers
in uh remember the one we in python we
start with the stream
oh can you can you read it optimism
yes counter so after counter culture
a notebook with the keys what's the key
key is the unique number
and then value is the number of times
they appear
in a string and right yeah
okay yeah but the number of times we
don't care here we just
we just want to know how many
how many uh how many unique
numbers oh we can use the set alright we
can use the same look
let's say look already t equals
yeah remember this is the t object
option
lens right set we use the set as
a does it make sense okay
we're turning this string into s set set
does not contain
duplicate elements so you only give me
t that will be unique okay then how do
we do this very
very then look we need to know if
k and one
oh let's say k module two modulus two
okay it's the same yeah
equals zero if it's the odd number
all right it's if it's the odd number
what should we return
yes what's your way to ten that's it
look this is even number so what what's
the answer written what
return what what's the even
[Music]
t times of k divided by two right
yeah that's not square right because you
need to look they are
they are this is even numbers what how
many is this
this is k right and how many is this how
many
okay this is k how many is this
uh t k divided by two
yeah and each one has two options so
it's t times t times
k divided by two times right all right
and how do you calculate this in python
remember
t you can use the power function or
drop us double multiply right okay
yes everybody follow me are you
following me
yeah okay divided by two
okay and how about it's old number so
what should we do
what number
can you tell me you just square it i
think
look if it's another one what should we
oh yes times one more yes
so it's return t times
one more time k divided by two k divided
by two is still this with this video
and then times t right that's it right
yes what's the
term complexity and square
n cubic oh n yeah yeah
wait let's see what's this bit set
count we need to go through these
num the characters in s so let's let's
say
look look there if there are n
characters in the s so this part
this part is okay okay and how about
this part
we want to calculate the power function
remember
what's the what's the complexity of this
remember we how do we calculate 2 to the
power
let's say how how how do we calculate
again
2 to the power of 10. do you time do you
multiply 2 10 times
this is 01 right but you can do it
better right remember
how do we do this 2 to the power of 10
equals 2 to the power
of 5 times 2 right
yeah does it make sense now
so so you can square
or you can you can do this square on the
base
yeah does it make sense yeah
maybe this is maybe not obvious maybe
look
two to the 100 128
the blue 4th way is to times 2 128 times
right
below then you can do this 2 to the
power of 2
square it and that becomes 64 right look
i just need to listen space i just need
to square the base and then i can reduce
the exponential right
half yeah and i can keep doing this
right
and 2 to the power of 2 and to the power
32 right yeah look this is
again half and right
so let's log in right in in this case
rotate right
all right so oh log k
oh maybe
no i'm just saying this is o and this is
all okay
so what's the time complexity
why you multiply it's two different
things
two different events please take this
this cost a this cost b how much does it
cost
a and first okay yeah look
this is costing a this is crossing b you
what's the homage together
add it together when when do you want to
multiply
look if if this this thing
cost 10 times and then for each k
you need to enter m times does it make
sense
so so how much complexity is this one
okay yeah do you understand when to time
when to add
yeah if it's adding it's separate
if it's multiplying what does it mean it
means that
one is inside another right
am right does it make sense yeah okay so
look
om plus dot k which is bigger i don't
know
i don't know because k n so it's may it
may be better
we just do all m class not k
because we're not sure which one is
bigger right yeah
or maybe you can do this all max
and o or locate so you pick the maximum
one
okay this is also okay good okay
does it make sense yeah can we
can we erase this if
you raise this if
maybe because look yes look because this
is the same yeah
the difference is comes one more time
right yes
yeah yeah a hashtag hashtag that's okay
hashtag is the comment okay it's that
for computer
for human it's not it won't change
anything okay
you know what's common common yeah in
common
it's for for people to agree to
understand it doesn't
have any impact on the logic
right okay so look
so if k is odd number
so we need to times one more right so if
k equals three
k equals three we want to if k equals
three we want to times it
k divided by two plus one time if k
equals two or even number we want to do
this right
and four we want to do this right and
five we wanted to release
why does it make sense if it's all
number we want to add one more time
right
yeah so we we can introduce one more
function called syria
you know what's here
here is shot for ceiling what's ceiling
yeah exactly let's see and then what's
the opposite
floor yeah where that floor for
but in python look if three
do this this is called this is already
flow because it will give you
one right right so what's three divided
by two in mathematics
if it's singles divide what's the same
divided by two
one and a half one and a half we're done
one and a half
right if you use two two double it gives
you the flaw which is one right
because it's not yet two it just weighs
this
how do you do the top top yes zero so
look
here three divided by two that will give
you two
that will give you two okay doesn't make
sense
this is kind of original three divided
by two is one
and a half and in person you want to the
floor
which is i don't want uh i can erase
this bit yeah
the fraction it's lower half it's like
one point half here
four one zero two doesn't make sense
so look so we can just do this
oh yeah t yeah how many times of t
sia k
divided by two single k right that's it
yeah all right look does it make sense
if k equals 3 3 divided by 2 1.5
0 will be 2. right yeah
if k equals 4 4 divided by 2 is 2
co2 is two right yeah here any integer
of half
a part is fear a hundred is a hundred
zero ninety nine
ninety nine right here ninety nine point
one is what
um hundreds yeah
floor 99.1 is what 99
from 99 is what uh
4.99 is 99 so any integer power one two
three four that
cl and cr or floor is there right yeah
see ya like that's one more time eight
point one two three
zero equals uh nine
eight point three two eight point nine
nine nine nine nine
flaw eight yeah
you got it okay so look k equals four
four divided by two
two c is two yeah t times two right t
square right okay that's it that's it
for today so what
you remember f complexity o n
plus log k right why is it okay because
we want to calculate this
uh power function power function a
k is all okay okay
yeah does it make sense does it make
sense
yeah okay good job today you want to say
thank you i'll see you tomorrow see ya
tomorrow yeah
that's it see you tomorrow