hey hello mr mr ryan how are you today
good good yeah okay wait
a little bit yeah so today we talk about
uh graph do you remember what is graph
remember
we talked about the gravity
is not exactly like kind of like wow
we're talking about the graph data
structure remember
the tree is also a graph right yeah the
link is is also a graph yeah
so graph is like with notes and edges
right yeah with notes and edges
so for example like an edge edge
the graph and the edges in the graph can
have directions or not directions if it
has direction like arrows
like one to the two then we call it
directive graph
directive graph yeah and if it doesn't
have
the error we call it what i'm directing
graph yeah
all right and i repeat what my bank is
automatic
and graphic and the the
you can associate the edge with some
values so we call it weight
yeah weight right
okay does it make sense okay so now
the task today is very simple so you're
given a star
graph you know what star graph so it
only has one
stars one in the middle and then many
edges
yeah when it is you have to have one in
the middle
so basically it's like a a common node
connects to all the rest of nodes right
and then
for the only one one edge
between each other nodes to the middle
okay so and you're given this node a
graph
you're given this graph g in the format
of
uh in the format of a
b so a list of that yeah h one and
two right like some c d like that
so this is that from for example like
a to the b okay and then maybe
b to the d okay something like that yeah
doesn't make sense
yeah right
so this is the list of the flow
list of edges for each one is the edges
from
vertex to two vertices
okay so now uh given this graph can you
find the one in the middle
for example and then and i have a c here
so
here would be c to b or b to c it
doesn't matter okay so as you can see
the edge can be represented using two
notes
from and two and these can be solved
yeah it doesn't matter yeah because it's
undirected
[Music]
yeah so any idea here omo you're very
close to it
what's the idea how we're doing this and
we can
look you know what we can what's this in
degree
what does it mean of the vertex b okay
so let's say in degree of
vertex b equals equals what
one two three four five six and a
index let's say this is i found
i a equals one i
d equals one so can you tell me what's
in degree
in degree of a note b is six integrator
of adc is or one
so what does this in degree mean
[Music]
so in degree is the number of ages
coming in like yeah right out
oh oh because it's on degree and
directly so it doesn't matter so it's
not basically the number of edges
connected to this point
so in degree of b look at how many edges
six yeah
yeah so can you tell me how do we deal
with this from my input
any idea so how do we find the center
one
come on it's all very obvious right it's
in a star graph
there's only one edges one one vertex
vertex we call it vertical okay we know
that vertex that has
the is it has the largest
in degree right or it points in a 3d
shape yeah yeah yeah but to these as
well
so if layer and point
so look n is seven right seven seven
vertex yeah
right one two three four five six seven
so what's the integral of the middle one
it given us a
star graph what's how many edges
connected to this
uh six so what's what what it is
and what
any seven so how many edges connecting
to the middle one
six yeah i know six is what
six is n minus one
yeah come on okay so we can compute the
in degree right of each vertex right
yeah and then return the one who is the
maximum
into it i'm i'm i'm right yeah and
what kind of data structure are we using
can can we use to
compute the in uh to store the key value
players
in degree key value pairs key value pair
you know key value pair what
what's the the thing you like you know
look at me like that what's that yes
come on notebook
okay look
let's say define find
center okay center and we got given this
graph which is the list right right
yeah so let's say maybe
uh graph okay let's say that in degree i
equals
dictionary right dictionary so
default additionally
additional and integer type because we
are
going to store the number of edges
connecting to that node right
all right four
let's say h h1 h2
so h1 is this error the first number s2
is the second number
in g then i
e1 what i
e2 can you tell me what to do yeah
because currently a b and then we have
edge
connecting with we have an edge
connecting between e1
and e2 right it's undirected so
what's the in degree what happens in
degree for both vertex
very simple look we have we now finally
find an
edge connecting between e1 and e2
right and what happens in degree of both
e1 and e2
we just need to add one yes yes we're
done
plus equals one right and then here
across equals one right where did you
underline
okay so after this now we want to
we have a i map we want to return the
key which has the most in degree right
so do you still remember how we get the
maximum return the maximum return the
item
key in additionally which has the
largest value
all right look return max
i right and then you can just do this
key equals
i dot get let's say so that will return
low return look if if if a map
in here is e1 3 and then e2
2 right then you you will return e1
because
e1 has the largest value error three but
this is
what it means right alternatively you
can do this max
i dot items
right and then key equals
a a1 is a bit complicated
and then return the first value yeah
because this this tells the
max function how are we comparing with
the
uh how are we comparing and get the max
this item is like a one three two two a
pair
a tuple i know we're saying that we want
to compare with the value
and then you will return this pair and i
i
get the key by square uh uh by the
bracket square bracket zero right
by square bracket one is three but it's
it this way is simpler i mix i t with i
don't get
i don't get it's a message to get a
value okay so this is basically having
that i want to return the key which has
the largest value three so if the
this one and it becomes center that
makes sense yeah
[Music]
so look we can because
because all we know we know uh it's the
graph is
a star right right
so what does it mean if we found the
edge
which has more than one in degree it's a
center right
does it make sense yeah yeah
okay so we can just do this if
i e1
bigger than one then return
e1 and here if
i e2 bigger than one we take y
[Music]
yeah so what's the term complexity
between this one and
the other one it's all o and
where n is the number of notes
uh edges edges i in a graph okay and you
can say it's a number of notes because
that
yeah input we know that the inner star
graph
declare n number of nodes and they are n
minus one
number of edges connecting to the center
right yeah
am right okay so
can we do better can we do it
maybe i will
a wait c so look
let's do this a b and b d okay uh
okay a b all right look at this square
let's let's see i have
[Music]
okay actually look at the first two
notes bbc
so okay tv so look
we know this is the first edge this is
the second edge
and a connecting the b b connecting to d
so can we find by comparing the first
center note
comparing the first two notes
yeah can we do it
[Music]
think about it look hey let's see if a
e if a yeah the first note first edge of
the first note right
is also one in one of second edge
then is the center right yeah i know y
is b
right because look b appears in both
right
it's the center note because b b
appears in both edges
right so what does it mean if it appears
it's a sentinel right like if look a is
not in the center it's not in the post
80s
right so it's not sentinel it must be on
the edge right
yeah if a is not a center of b must be
your sentinel right
i'm right does it make sense
because in an age there must be one note
in the edge that is a sentinel right
does it make sense
yeah look at this is star 12
so every age there must be one of the
note in every age
it's the central right
it doesn't make sense okay so look how
how can we write it look
if g the first no
first note of the first g zero eric
look you tell me g zero is this one and
g zero zero is a right
if equals g
one zero if equals to this one
or
[Music]
so basically if this now is the same as
this now or this now right
return one reason why
um
that if it is now it's the same as this
no all this no then it must be essential
otherwise
this one is essential all right does it
make sense
yeah what's the time complexity
come on oh
i won a one yes because look i'm just
checking that
but yeah i i heard you say oh oh and
right yeah oh
which one is this one better open this
one why is that
because i said
why yeah why this one is better i won
and why o1 is better than quicker
it's quicker yeah because look one means
constant it means no matter how big
the graph is i can always check the
first two
elements i'm right yes and that's
constant time right
but for the previous one i need to go
through
right possibly edges yeah to to count
the edges
but not the second approach remember the
first approach
is o n the second approach is actually
not o n
is one because we know we know what we
know
this is a star graph right
so for the second approach remember if
it's bigger than one
then we return that immediately right
come right yeah
do you still remember the second one so
we checked we counted in degree for each
item
we integrated for each vertex and if
it's more than one
in degree now we return that so by going
through that look
you can always find that in degree more
than one
for the first two for the first two
edges right because look
b b and the second point and the second
iteration of the for loop the b
in degree will be what area
all right will be what the integral of b
going through the first edges second as
the integral of b
is what in degree of b is
a and the integra how many edges there's
this one edges there are two edges how
many edges is connected to b
two two okay then we found the answer
immediately so
for the first two first algorithm is our
n for the second
one is a one for the third one is also
one which is quicker
right the second and third one is almost
the same yeah
but this one is more straightforward
because it's just using the if
yeah right does it make sense yeah okay
that's it
for today bye-bye