go hello mr airy mr wine how are you
today good
good okay so today we still talk about
this binary tree
okay so what's final retreat remember
which is
okay so what binary means two
two mean okay so
so it means that uh for each node
it can has you can have a maximum two
two kids and for each kid how many
parents does it have one at most one
except wait look where are the leaves
what are the leaves seven
two five seven two five seven because
later they does not they do not have
any children any children okay so how
about
if i give you this financial any biology
i want you to find out
the we i want you to count okay or find
out how many
how many kids are the only child
of their parent so which one are they
what does that mean
only child of the parent
only child of the parent for example
like which one is the only child in
inspiratory of their parents
any child yeah there's one
only try means the parent has only eats
only a single child
okay so yeah no because four's parents
three it has
three um seven come on
look because seven it's the only child
on four right
oh yeah yeah it doesn't have the four
any others if
i put another one here if i put another
here
then two is the only child
don't know uh this one this one is the
only choice sorry it's excusing
no not confusing so the only change is
that six
is the only child two right because two
has only tried
one two ones two three
two one two and each other one two only
oh okay so this only is not means
the the only in spanish it means that
the only
child of that its parent and i want to
count how many of these so in this case
there will be
six and seven because these two
are the only child of their parents all
right
does it make sense yes yeah okay
so how can we count this we would just
return two for
for example there are two only try
uh we can do
what it's five one five no because three
has two child
does it make sense uh yeah okay okay so
uh only
you check all of these first i think
yeah but it doesn't have to be the leave
thing you know for example if i put
another no yeah like
nine nine is the only trial six six is
only trial two so
you have to include six nine seven so
that's it okay it doesn't have to be
like this
right basically for me to try the only
child is parents
it doesn't have to be a belief so how
can we do this
when we talk about the finance tree how
many ways are we talking about to
track with the deficit okay
so so let's do these preferences today
okay
yeah so
tomorrow so we'll visit the finance
in level by level which is the
preference yeah so which order
if you're going through this breakfast
one two three
six four five nine seven well done
what's the difference
in the order one two six nine
three exactly in order to use the
preferences what kind of data structure
are we using
oy cue or stack something
sorry something like hugo stack queue or
stack which one
i guess you're not guessing q or step
okay when we talk about the breakfast
search is
one of them is one of my state one of
ladies q come on
k q q first thing first of all q right
remember for the stack
we're using definite search but usually
we implement it in recursion
and that involves the stack but it
doesn't have to
we don't have to deal with the stack
manually we can use the recursion
letter computer compiler to deal to
generate these calling stats right
okay yes so prefer search okay so we
have a queue
and first in q is first thing one
first thing first out okay so yeah
exactly the kill luckily this q
q-u-e-u-e yeah q is the only letter
that's pronounced in this world
in this world yeah q and all other
letters are silent it means that the q
is being served only the head of the q
gets being served all others need to
wait quietly right
and when the new element during the join
at the end when the q1 needs
when the next element to be served is
the head of the queue right
okay so at the beginning we want to
initialize the queue with which element
in the finance tree
which element in a binary tree if you
want to
do this implementation no but
look at the beginning the queue is empty
so wait
look yeah we put the load which is one
right okay
and then we we repeat until the q is
empty
all right so every time if the q is not
empty what should we do we take one
element out of q yeah pq yeah
take it out and push its kids which is
two and three two and three okay and
then next one
two take a two out the head of kill and
push is
kid six and he has one say
yeah i only have a one yeah so if in
order to put the yeah this is a perfect
source but in order to
tell which does it have a uh
does it is it only try we have to
recall the number of tried when we're
expanding right so for example
like three yeah i take three hours yeah
yeah when i take three out i push the
kids area at this point i know
how many kids the three has right it's
four and five right
all right yes so when i push the four
and five
i also need to know okay it's parent
three has two kids
right okay then six i take it out i push
the
nine right but six i know it's only
caught one kid
yeah when i push in the knife and also
notice is one
so it looks like two yeah yeah look when
i take a fall off
but i don't know it's it's coming from a
parent which has two kids
too right so i don't count this as the
only child right
yeah but i keep expanding four i push
the seven
in right i put the color seven here
but i also know when i put when i do
this
i know how many kids does
the four have one right yeah so i put
when i push seven i also
notice this is coming from one
child's parent why are you okay
yeah you want to speed up
so one child one child parent so in this
case we're doing this we accumulated
yeah
yeah does that make sense yeah so let's
let's do this now
let's do this okay
[Music]
okay so so
what what are the data structure we used
in python to implement a queue
dq and what's the q mean double
energy double ndq
double double and the cube okay so
so let's say let's at the beginning if
blue is
now what should we do return what
return
okay and then double cube ndq q equals
dq
and then we take a list of the initial
so at the beginning we take a two point
load
and we and we said the second element of
the tube area
is zero we mean that it coming from the
zero parent
animal the parent if it's one
it's coming from one child parent
if it's two it means coming from two
triangular right
yeah i don't need to call this answer
count
another equals zero
okay so look wire wire q
yeah y kill eric we want to dq
dq yeah so we only have a current now
another count count is the
this is a variable okay equals to q how
do we
kill q dot one pop one
i think left yeah left because with the
q we take it from the beginning which is
left yeah
yeah oh yeah and then because why this
is this current because
look the first element is the low boost
all right
the second element is the count right
yeah yeah
okay so now look if car if count
equals one what should we do it's coming
from one child parent so the current
note
is the one trial right only try yeah
yeah
so what should we do with this answer
answer
we found it so what should we do
increment it
add one add equals one okay right yeah
no no let's say look s equals zero like
we are starting to counting how many how
many kids
does this curve this note have so look
if kai scotland left
yeah x plus equals one right
and if command y what do we do
x
this means the number of child for the
current note the left note i found it
yeah come on equal
one yes so now look i i know how many
kids does this
listener have right and now what should
we do now i need to check
right okay then look here
i put it here if caroline does that what
should i put push
push into the kill yeah kill the append
right
open what can you tell me open what
there are two things here
append left turn on the left and
what's the second right now
we are pushing the key to keep the count
so what's the count here
what's the number what's the number
what are we doing here we are
counting yeah and then what should i put
here
x come on x we are counting how many
kids are this now have
about yeah if our current dollar y what
should we do here
yeah if carbon double what you have here
i kind of write kudos
current
you you use the black uh bracket
parentheses okay point the face
the cubers are immutable means that you
when you declare it you can't change the
elements in that
in mutable yeah you can't change like
the string
like the string in eric look if you
don't is p
equals arabic this means that it's
immutable you can't do this you can't do
this p0
equals like right ah you can't do this
right because because when you declare a
string it's immutable it means the
constant you can't change it
right that's that's particularly
impressive right
immutable immune immune
um immutable
what's immutable what's in mutable
mutable
[Music]
you can't talk or you can't talk no no
me
mutable not mute mute is you can't talk
mutable means the change change immune k
mutate okay so immutable means that you
can't change it
it stays the same it stays
immutable okay okay now look after this
we push the teeth
and then what's missing here we have a
last thing nothing
what's the space compromising we're
going to talk about my search how many
notes are you know
oh n n is the number of notes
uh okay what's the space complexity all
right
why are we using the why why
not stand we are not using the style
it's the key
q we are using the queue to store the
number of nodes yeah in a
preference okay yes it makes sense what
you doing
from different okay so and
any questions if we if we want we don't
want to count if we want to return it
look this answer is a zero yeah if we
can change it to
every can change it to a list
and then instead of answer equals one
what do we do here
answer the append
open what current right
yeah all right yeah this is to
return a list of the only child right
but if you can also do this you'll
return the tribe and then you if you
you want to return the count you can
also return then answer
yeah yeah it's the same yeah yeah does
it make sense
it doesn't make sense but but in this
case you are storing all the
notes only try in the answer and then
keep
counting it okay and it it might be
better just to increment the counter
okay
doesn't make sense yes okay that's it
for today
say thank you say thank you i'll see you
tomorrow
okay see you tomorrow