so
today we are going to learn something
about the
gcb yeah
okay good and how about this
multiple okay so what's gcp
can you give me an example like 25 and
35 what's the greatest common device of
these
five five weather and what what's the
least common multiple of
of these two
[Music]
it's hard yeah seven five
okay you can turn how hard to do it it's
easy
so yeah times it multiply together
divided by their greatest common divisor
which is five
so do you get it yeah yeah at least
common multiple
of a and b equals a times b
divided by greatest common divisor of a
and b okay
got it yes so what is common divisor is
that both numbers appear in
a time table for example in five times
the table right
they are both in five table right yeah
but it's the biggest one okay so how do
we do this
25 and 35 how do we do the
how hard we calculate the weight is
common divisor
how do we do it remember
we need we need this modulus yeah
this modulus you know modulus
yeah modulus so
i
[Applause]
look so yeah so
let's do this 25 divided by 35
equals what equals zero remained
25 yeah yeah and then we move this 35
here and we move this 25 here
okay then what's this 35 divided by 20
by 25 equals 1 remaining 10 10 right
then okay so what do we do look look
look 25 here
10 here so 25 and 10 equals
2 divided by 2 it remains what
remain 5 right ok what do we do
10 5
so let's equals 2 divided by 2
5 equals 2 remain 0. when we get this
0 what does it mean it means
this number is the greatest common
divisor you see it
you see okay so how do we implement this
into computer
that's easy yeah look it's just three
lines of curve
define where it is common divisor
a and b yeah
why b is greater than zero
what should we do now with a
b equals b a modulus b
and then we turn a right
is it right a
yes within a yeah we can do this 35
uh 25 and 25
and 15 okay a is 25
b is 50 okay b is 35 okay b
is 35 now let's do this table
so let's do this table b is bigger than
zero right
okay so a equals b and
b equals a modulus b so which is 25 okay
so now we just swap if it's smaller than
if a is smaller than b the next one will
be b a b
is so okay now next one
b is bigger than zero right
a will become b right every time you put
a b here
and then and and b will become a modulus
b
which is 10 right and then i'm copying
here 10
and then these will be 5 right
and then these five here and then it
will be zero zero one is zero i return
a you see you see
a b a comma b equals b
comma a it means that i a will become
the value of b
and then b will become the value of a
modulus b
do you get it okay so now
now how can we do this how can we do
this lcm look
define scm a
b okay that's the magic glam how do we
do it
what's this what's
[Music]
remember 25 35 how
what did i teach you before at the
beginning you say it's a big number
25 times 35 divided by what is common
divisor of yeah
so so what's this
[Music]
right i said that yeah okay look yeah a
b
right you see yeah okay so
yeah let's today's code can you put it
on my computer
i'm gonna check okay the last thing the
last thing don't forget the last thing
bye goodbye