hey hello mr mr ryan are you all right
yeah yeah okay so remember what we
talked about yesterday
the only child can you only try using
which agreement
we are counting this uh only trial using
the preferred search okay
so how are we implementing this
professor
um level by level and what kind of data
structure are we using to implement
research
uh key yeah and the queue is first thing
out and in python what can or what
function
class name is the used to implement a
queue what does dee stand for
double ended what does it mean by double
ended
you take it out and you put it on the
end
okay so basically double ended so it
means that i can
two sides yeah well done so i can append
and pop from both sides okay and then
the complexity to push and pull from
both sides is
over what's the term complexity
constant time right yeah constant time
so it means that it's very quick
okay if you are if you are popping one
element from the beginning of the list
you know list remember in python we're
using this
to represent the list if we if we pop
the
beginning of the list is pop zero yeah
from zero it takes linear time right
but in dq you can use top top left
which is a one constant so this is
better so that's why we're using dq
instead of list
to achieve this the q thing okay
so the counting only chart using the
perfect search
yeah we put it in the kill everything is
i
went yeah when i n is what is this the
number of
notes in the premium space yes yes this
kind of what that was
it's the same so look the key
important things to take away here is
that uh
we are pushing the note together with
the number of
the number of children for the first
parent
right so then one way expand the note in
the next level
we can accumulate or we can we know
which are the only child by checking
this total if it's one
then it means that its parent has only
one child which is itself right
yeah okay can you put it yeah we can put
it in the answer
or yeah answer if it's a
integer to count how many only try we
can just
increment one or if you want to get the
list of the
if you want to get a list of only try
you can put it in the
list right and then you can count it
using the lens from here okay
basically that's what it is so we can
also solve this problem using the
device search yeah so can you tell me
what steph says
you can't okay i'm gonna do one example
okay so you tell me what
what are the different search
what okay so what's the difference
search of this
of these if i want to perform the
difference one three
eight nine seven five twelve
yeah okay so you go you can go
the definition is go left as much as you
can
if not you retreat to the cheat and you
go to the right
and then finish it you go retrieve you
go to the left yeah okay
so using the desktop yeah yeah yeah
uh using the deficit
deficit we need to remember
passing down the the number of the
triad of the current node right so in
the next level we can check this counter
if it's
one then we accumulate it right
all right yeah okay so
you tell me okay i tell you therefore
search
let's say define define
different search and then we also need a
counter right
what does this counter mean can you tell
me what's missing
okay so yeah so look if loot
okay i asked you about counter things so
what's what does they mean
counter that sound was funny what does
the counter thing mean
that counts via constant it means that
the number of
look the counter means what it means the
the parent of the dude yeah
all right the parent of a root has how
many
children that's for the count of me does
it make sense
yeah okay so if lu is numb what's your
return
zero yeah yeah it means that nothing
yeah
it doesn't have any homies like this
okay
so look if we have a counter here yeah
so look
answer let's say answer equals yellow
first right
and then look if counter equals one
right if it's parent if its parent
has only one kid then we increment the
answer here
answer plus equals 1 right yes
does it make sense okay then what should
we do we should
this function will return the number of
the
one only triad in this root
tree in this sub tree so we also need to
add
answer equal plus equal one all right
can you write it here
this is do the left loo the left and
then what i think
okay we are missing something here okay
count to something
so first of all let's say
we we are now reaching the root now
right but now
we want to know how many kids current
node has
right let's call it x okay x equals zero
then if roon turn left
okay so common node has the left child
right
so x plus equals one right yeah yeah and
then
what's happening what what's next one
plus one equal to
i check on the left and i also need to
check a lot right
[Music]
so what does this x mean what does this
mean can you tell me what does
this mean i think x
x what does x equal what what does x
mean
what's x mean why are we calculating x
what's x mean
uh x means like
what look if x equals if root is left
then
x will be one if load right and x will
be
plus one right so it means x is what
the number of what the number of nights
or the number of nights that breed
has yeah the children knows yes okay so
look yeah and then now
i know this x yeah then i need to plug
answer plus
equal definite thirty now we are
counting with recursively counting
what left three yeah blue dot left and
what's your way past this count
here what's your right passing lead
what's your
pass here we are counting the left tree
it's left tree we remember this cnt what
does it mean
counter what's the c
what's what's the cnt mean do the left
what's the parent uh what's the parent
of blue dot left
what's the parent of luther left come on
wait dude
okay and then the and the number of the
children
of the root is what what are what oh one
so yeah well we are calculating before
so what what should i
pass this value come on one what is one
well answer plus equal
to search and then now below downward
lower right right and then again
what what do i pass here the second
parameter
come on the cnt i just said is the
number of levels
for the lord's parents parents
the number of rules of left the parent
is of loser that all the parents do the
right suit yeah yeah
and the number of the kids from the
blood is what
come on it's there remember the kids for
the route yeah the number of kids on
blue is my name
it's come on how how would that be right
i was missing here the last lesson
[Music]
people will watch you all over the world
okay they don't want to see your feet
[Laughter]
so when we are calculating the loader so
the first
first cnt we can pass any number like
zero
minus one as long as you long past the
one right yeah because the number of
the number of the dude's parents kid
is is yellow right yeah
there's no parent of a root right louis
is the only
only kid only note in the binary tree
which does not
have one we do not have
i have one i'm just testing you if
you're listening it
it does not have
[Music]
right no no no is the only
note in binary it does not have a parent
that's why yeah and
the leaves the leaf notes are the notes
in binary tree which does not have what
we do not have children we are done okay
well let's try okay what's the term
complexity
what's n the numbers in the binary tree
so which one is better you think the
difference search preferable search
the very same complexity yeah and which
one you think is more
easy to implement it's easier to
implement
but first search you in breakfast search
you need to
you need to implement the preferences
using the queue
right but here we don't use the queue we
use the stack but there is no stack here
so how
are we going to you where are the stack
here
nice there's no steps but there's
recursion when we talk about recursion
the computer maintains a stack for you
doesn't make sense
okay so you can implement this different
search we allow the recursion but
in that case you need to do as a stack
and then you
you'll be more complex that's why we
prefer using the recursion
the computer with maintenance stack for
you okay
so what what does it mean if there's a
step what's the space complexity
okay that's it what's here
what's here let's see what's here hmm
let me check so and answer you guys
yellow so
what happened when answer is
[Music]
happened
what does it mean what does it mean eric
it means
dad what does it mean why why are we
doing this
what's this bit what's the speed
right yes counter if card is one then we
found
yeah then we found it from the current
note is the
only track when we add it because we're
retaining answer here and then
answers the variable we are accumulating
the
we are we keep counting we only try
in its left sub tree and the right
subtree using recursion right
yeah okay that's it for today
bye bye bye