oh hello hello mr
mr lauren how are you today good good
so okay so i've never drawn a tree okay
finally
yeah we know the price of the chip what
does binary mean
k okay
it means that any notes in the binary
tree
can have mmos how many kids two kids
and every note except that which no
has does not have parents wait okay how
many parents does one now have
except for good uh one yes okay and then
a final retreat is also a graph yeah
a graph and it doesn't finally treat is
actually
how do you call it a cyclist a cyclic
a cyclic diuretic undirected one
undirected graph another negative yeah
okay ti
a cycling means does not have cycle it
does not have this kind of cycle okay
yeah and directly means the the age does
not have direction okay
so it does not have a direction yeah
a and directed graph
okay and direct graph and directly about
probably aug okay i don't know what's
the initials okay but anyway
so this is a binary tree so how about if
i tell you what what kind of binary is
this one
every no every level is the first note
first level has one note which is two to
the power zero the
second level has 2 no which is 2 to the
power 1
the third level which is 2 to the power
2 yeah
yeah so that's how many when you add it
together 2 to the power of 0 plus 2 to
the power 1 plus 2 to the power 2
equals one two to the power
of three minus one okay so basically if
there are n
n levels how many nodes does these
three we call it full binary yeah
because it's full yeah you can't even
for level three
you can't have any more notes right the
maximum
binary uh the maximum
nodes of a binary tree which has three
level has how many nodes
uh come on count open it up
one two eight seven
seven that's what i'm saying and how
about how about four four
n equals four how many notes uh
fifteen i don't know m equals five
2 to the power of 0 plus 2 to the power
1 plus 2 to the power 2 plus 2 to the
power 3 plus 2 to the power
4 plus 2 to the power 5 equals
[Music]
yeah because it's 2 to the power of 6
minus 1 yeah so look
2 to the power of 0 plus 2 to the power
1 plus
here plus 2 to the power of
n equals equals 1
equals 2 to the power n plus 1 minus 1.
okay yeah yeah look when n is 2
this added together equals 2 to the
power 3 minus 1 does it make sense yeah
this is called 4 minus 3. yeah
how about how about if not particular of
a value you can have a few nodes missing
particularly on the right okay so
if i erase that what what does this call
on and uh uh okay okay it complete final
string
so it's complete but not four one is
four is every
node is four but you can erase some of
these
look this is also a complete binary
but this is not right if
a node is missing it has to be on the
right hand side right
look this is not this is not a complete
binary okay
all right so okay the question is
how given the binary tree how do we
check
it's a complete financing okay so let me
do this okay
so look this is the finance this is the
complete biology also for binary and
is at least a complete biology
yeah is this incomplete yeah
yes yes is this no
yeah yes is this no no
is this no yeah no because look there's
nothing here
come on yeah yeah so if they're missing
no it has to be on the
on the right hand side right you'll get
it yeah okay okay another one
uh oh wait okay
uh
is this no
no because every every level has to be
full
except the last one yeah yeah these
n minus n minus one it has to be
all the notes have to be occupied except
the last one
and even the last one it has to be on
the left hand side as left as possible
okay yeah okay
so do you any idea how can we do this
what kind of the what is that well where
are the first ones
what's the price masters mean level
level by level and how are we using this
breast
how are we using this breakfast search
uh
it's key yeah yeah so
yeah we're using a cube so in
in python what kind of data structure
are we using i mean what kind of eq
what does d2 double ended yes
okay so yeah we're using the key of
binary search level by level so
what's that's a thought how how can we
check if it's a complete binary tree
oh we just look at the last one look at
the last one
and i and the others are you guys uh if
we
uh others are just we're going on
sorry on the thursday sorry
sorry can you tell me how you do it yeah
just any thoughts would be nice
[Music]
any thoughts would be nice so yeah never
mind
but how how are we checking how are we
validating level one
yeah how do we check the level by level
for example if this is not
this is not a complete binary tree so
you travel here right
one two three four five
six so how do you know it's not a
complete financing
you travel one two three four five six
so how do you know it's not a complete
[Music]
balance
and the last one is not so that's
okay the second one is for which second
one
this one the second one is one
it's four yes okay yeah but the last one
look how do you know it
it's last level yeah yeah
okay then
any idea any idea just any idea
this is a bit tricky think about it
preparing ryan i mean
think about it how are we dealing with
that yeah it's breakfast search but how
do we know
if a no i mean so basically we want to
look
for the empty hole there yeah right yeah
am i right
if it is an empty hole yeah if
this should be empty this is empty yeah
if it's an empty hole before
we reaching the last one then it's not a
complete
financing so look with level by level
but look
when we visit here it's not empty yeah
but it's
it's not supposed to be empty right all
right
look for a complete binary tree complete
binary
you walk level by level yeah and it's
always very
not empty when you reach the end that's
fine
right all right but look if there's a
hole somewhere in between
between look look
one two three four and then look these
are holes
holes yeah then it's not completely
binary
does it make sense yeah so we need to
have a
we need to have a pulling you know
what's pulling
pudding pulling what does this mean
yeah pull it
[Music]
yeah we have a hole we we set the hole
to first
then we if we meet the empty hole we set
it to f two
right yeah and we when we mean the
middle
node if the whole has even as a whole
before then it's not a complete binary
am i right
does it make sense
so look if i i will perform this binary
search
uh by breakfast level by level but when
i meet the whole
i notice okay i have already met the
hold yeah
and then the next time when i keep going
if i meet a note what does it mean
there's a hope before the end then it's
not a complete binary
right doesn't make sense yeah
okay so look look i i'll give you an
example okay
okay let's let's label it let's label it
one two three four five
six okay
q yeah q what's what's kill first thing
first out first thing first and what's
the first thing lasso
stack okay good look
that kill we initialize which we snow
root which is one one
okay so we repeat wire
y and the q is not empty okay yeah all
right i mean look
y q is 90 with q one right way to kill
yeah
the q which is top left i take it off
yeah at the beginning i send a hole
to fourth okay because we haven't met
anyhow okay
right yes i take one off what should i
push
t two and three
i keep doing this yeah okay i was in the
next to take out
three three okay look this is
interesting part
uh i push i push the empty note here so
i need to push
it let me know right look what
previously we don't need to push in the
preferences but now i need to push the
empty hole
so i press the empty hole which is i
actually empty
okay yeah okay what an and
and push the six in yeah
right and push the six in okay
are you okay push the six in and
look what's next to take out
[Music]
okay what's it what is a kid nothing
yeah i put
nothing in okay
and then what's in the next hour
five and then also pushing
nothing in yeah oh yeah okay now
somebody else could go in the scene no i
take that i need a hole yeah
yeah i mean the hole
i need the hole i take it off i sent it
to tune
why yeah
okay so next if it's empty i don't
explain those kids here because empty
does not have a key there
and what's next
what's next
what's next here the next element of the
queue
six six okay look
i mean a meter not empty now but look
it's true
what does it mean it means that there's
a hope before six
and i return fourth right yeah it's not
complete financially all right
yeah so i will i can keep doing if if
there
if there are five here right this is
still false right
because and then you put another five
right it doesn't matter so you have
plenty of leads empty by which which you
take it out but
but you don't expend any kids and
eventually the queue will be empty
and at last you return what
it will turn on in in the happy pay
happy case true yes does it make sense
yeah okay so then the key thing here is
we expand we push the empty note in that
as a placeholder to
for next time if we meet the empty hole
we send this out to
true right am right
yeah yeah i know when we meet the note
if we have no end there's a whole before
then we return force immediately right
does it make sense
should we do it defy
complete final three okay finally three
is complete final three okay load
and the column
yeah if if loot is empty what happened
if our empty tree we we call it
we can we say it's a complete binary
yeah doesn't make sense
okay it's a very special case so if if
if it's a mt3 empty tree we we
uh we call it the complete binary yeah
yeah yeah okay okay so now
what should we do next what should we do
next
okay so q equals dq yeah
and at least of the beginning we put the
root in
right and we also have a hole which i
said to
two of us so false yeah whatever
so now i keep doing this twice yeah
quite q
yeah or y lens q bigger than zero it's
the same thing yeah
i take a q our p current okay
current now p okay equals
q dot one
so if if p
is num if cannot know is like what
we do we should we do
we set a hole to okay
yes as well
as one that's what so as we need to push
the
kids um
so look if p is not noun it means we
currently know we have meter counter
but in this case if ho is hot if there
is a hole
what should we return should we
take
look remember if we we meet the whole
and and now this is the valid note
we about left there was previously i
hope before i know we return first and
then now next we need to
append what p dot append one
key no no no
left left right left and that's right
q dot
in the binary tree yeah what's the space
complexity
oh n what's why are we using a cube
additional additional space
to store the notes yeah
[Music]
yeah find a missing piece
pop is lowercase not uppercase it's case
sensitive okay you know case sensitive
uppercase and lowercase
are different okay oh that's a very
small p
okay okay
okay pop left left okay and what's next
ep is long what do we do if
p is now if p is not what you will do
we sell how to false
yeah yeah
come on i understand it come on why yeah
and
equal false no and how this is different
than what i wrote
in the notes i'm just checking if you
understand okay not copying my notes
yeah yeah does that make sense yeah
right
yeah because at the beginning hole is
false we haven't met the whole
and now if p is now it means we have a
middle
and if p is not empty if there is a hole
we return force yeah
otherwise we'll push the kids to the
back of kill
and every when the kill is not empty we
need to kill yeah we take an animal at
the beginning of the kill yeah for the
next time
yeah okay that's it for today i will
smash
say bye bye and see you tomorrow