hey today we're outside
hello mr ryan how are you today good
good okay so come on
come here come here okay so today we
talk about
um consecutive ones in binaries
so do you still remember what's binary k
two means okay so what's 15 in binary
one one one five one one yeah because
look
this is eric come here yeah
this is 2 oh no this is 2 to the power 0
this is 2 to the power 1 this is 2 to
the power 2 and this is 1 2
4 8. yeah so that's 8 plus 4
plus 2 plus 1 it's 15 yeah
okay so given the number our task today
is to find the longest consecutive ones
in binary so
how many ones four four okay so how
about a binary like uh
let's say one one one zero one how many
consecutive ones here
no consecutive three the longest one is
three yeah
okay so any idea if given 15 you need to
tell me it's four
given this what's what's this number 2
to the power
0 2 to the power 1 2 to the power 2 and
2 to the power 3 2 to the power 4
so 2 to the power 4 is plus 2 to the
power 2
plus 2 to the power 1 plus 2 to the
power 0 what's this
16 plus 4 24 plus
2 2 plus 1 okay so let's try now
this one yeah yeah 23. okay given 23.
so you know it's list binary and then
you can you need to give me the thesis
the answer is three because they are
the longest consecutive is one one one
here right
yeah so how can we do this
we need to be louder because we are
outside yeah so
from the end yeah and then
stuff only and what uh
which side for example like this one
zero one one one so where
here yeah and then you go
back and it's still one but when you get
a zero
uh wait wait wait when you move
uh you add one
you wear one to something but
then the key thing here is that we need
to remember
uh we need to count the consecutive ones
yes
am i right okay so how about we start
with something very simple
come on hold on no no we're running let
me know i'm not running
yeah no i'll not doing some things
working outside that's not good
what okay this is bad
15 this is the number yeah so in
python we can use this pin function to
convert this
if i say this it will give me what you
will give me this
0p which means finally one one one one
right
yes okay after this
this is a string now yeah if i i just
only speed
so what should i do
so look so this zero p
one one one one i want to the substring
start from the third position right
then i can do this two
two yeah that's the start
means i won't i don't want these two
characters
in the front i use the star column
and that means
no it's just a bracket so you you return
this one one
one right yes and after this
i i need to split by zero right look if
there's
maybe this is not a good example for
example this one
uh okay let's let's do this what's this
number in
customers in decimal
this is the final what's the least in
decimal
one plus two plus a
11 11 okay so look if i do this 11 then
it will become
1 0 1 1 yeah
and to this you become 1 0 1 1 yeah
and one zero one one dot split
remember a split thing split i split by
zlo
right what what does it give me you'll
give me
one a list
and one one right all right
yeah because i split it by zero yeah
yeah
yeah okay so now i can count it yeah i
know the county yeah
then i can do this max then
x for x in
for example if this is a way okay
that's it that's the answer how's that
does it make sense
okay so how about we we implement this
and i tell you another
method later okay 35
once okay
s let's uh the input is end
right yeah what you doing it's still
good
yes it is okay
look so now look s equals
what bin bin
and beans for binary and
bin for beans look
right yeah and
that's it return return max
next lens x
for x e a r
r why does it make sense now look
what's the term complexity oh n
finally g o now it's a bit tricky
this one look at the one
this one this one
this is and the splitting function
for spirit function is what
because this is not okay and then i need
to turn scan again right so login
and log in this is also log i'll look at
this end
actually this is om but this end is
referred to this location
again okay and login and then length
so actually it's locked in oh look at
does it make sense yeah doesn't make
sense okay
and this one we are going through this
array to find out the maximum length
okay yeah yeah
all right so look another one
11. how about look this is this is in
binary
one or one one yeah all right how about
we
we go through this from the right to the
left so we know the last bit is one
right right the last bit is one and
we change this to 101 right right
the last the last bit of 101 is one
and then this becomes one row right yes
and then the last bit is what
and then it becomes one right the last
bit is one
and then it becomes zero one is not and
then look when we do this
if it's one we make a counter plus
equals one
otherwise we make the counter become
zero and then we can
we can we can have another answer value
to remember the maximum right
what's the term complexity look at
because every time we are
happening right why is the hovering when
we moving
one bit from the right how do you do if
this is n
in integer right 15 how do you make it
seven
15 is one one one one how do you make
this one one one
integer shifting yeah and then how to do
this
and
right right figure figure
equals 1 15 wide yeah all right
that means i raise the last digit right
is it okay yeah so let's
write this
define count
one and what's missing
okay look answer let's begin with
answer equals what what's the answer
and then let's say once the ones we have
so far is one
the ones we have
y n right
all right y n is bigger than zero or y n
right yeah
it's the same thing i know look look
how do we check the last bit the
rightmost speed
if n
n one right yeah
it means if any one equals one then what
we do
one is what one yeah
if the last bit if the one zero one if
this bit is one what should we do
no if the last bit is zero so what you
what what happened to this one
it will become zero because i this one
means that
how many ones i have met from the right
to the left right
if it's one i end with one but if it's
zero here
that means that we make it zero yeah
once will become zero so the next time
you have a four
then you start incrementing from one
right from zero all right
and then what should we do now here
answer
equals what maximum answer of what
of which value here once
yes i'm going to have an answer
[Music]
answer come on does it make sense
what does this mean answer equals
maximum answer one what does it mean
it means that
[Music]
you keep the maximum value because
current answer is yellow and
now kind of why
what happened to the answer this is
come up or you can say if one is bigger
than and if answer
if one is bigger than answer then answer
equals one
so what is it what does it mean max max
a max one two equals two max is a
function
max max yeah yeah max is a function come
on
let's you see writing is much harder
than
reading yeah and it takes two variables
two parameters you will return the
maximum of the
yeah yeah function and there will be two
variables
yeah once and what
answer equals the maximum of two things
one is answer the other one is one
yeah yeah you just say once and what's
this
what this what this is what
answer okay answer one okay does it make
sense
okay i'm here what's this
wow that's great yeah yeah okay okay
that's it for today say thank you and
see you tomorrow
[Music]
bye