go hi hello hello mr mr ryan how are you
today
good okay so today we'll talk about an
interesting problem which is called
zero zero
so given a positive positive number
integer n
find a way find a ask to return an array
which contains
integer let's sum up to zero but this
integer has to be different unique
so basically two requirements
requirement why is
all integers unique
okay you can only use one integer once
and all integers second requirements sum
to zero
okay okay another certain equipment use
an integer okay
so if n equals one can you find a way
which
uh satisfy these three requirements
actually there's only one array zero
yeah
yeah okay when n equals two
can you find an array um
one
once you make sure is one and one minus
yes so how many how many kind of
possibilities
for this answer uh
is it unique you can you hop there one
if n is one only one possibility and
when n
is two or any what was it how many
possibilities
how many can you find any other man
these two
can you find this
one come see two
minus three yeah so you can find i
limited one right
okay what does that mean
minus one one minus one so you find two
numbers added to zero
right and all these two numbers needs to
be different yeah it's easier one
minus one yeah it will be zero two minus
two
you can say three minus two yeah yeah
okay how about n equals three
uh three zero zero
one minus one yeah you see so when n
is in odd number see if you first put a
zero right
yeah and then you'll be reduced to n
equals two right
all right okay so this is
one kind of strategy yeah so what how
can you think of alex strategies
like if n equals a hundred so what do
you put that will take for ages to write
yeah but you can always write it
generally it's a hundred numbers i give
you 100 minus one
minus t minus three minus four
and then how do you put it minus minus
nine
minus ten okay
so n equals a hundred i give you a hint
how about that's generally the first 99
number in the sequence and then we can
calculate the last number
so can you find a sequence
any pattern yeah yeah any pattern how do
you generate the first
one yeah you can start from zero as well
yellow
one nine one keep doing two is it
different right
and you get 98 and then after this you
know
the sum of the first 99 numbers right
and then you put it you put the negative
to that
right and all you can guarantee all
these numbers are different
and they sum up to zero right does it
make sense
okay so let's try the first solution
okay should be
easy uh where's my eraser the end of the
first line
when we started yeah but we can write to
number two if you want okay
so this is just the way to generate this
and
array of any integer unique integer
let's sum up to zero okay so let's say
defined
so let's say this number starts from the
first one right
yeah and then we put this answer put the
number in the answer right
at the beginning is empty empty this
yeah
so wire while
i want to put one minus one two minus
two so if
x naught is bigger than two right be
gone the thingy
and then minus the thingy right look so
what should i put here
when n when they are more than t
two or at least two then what should we
put to the answer
a penguin
and then when i use the i i need to do
one
i one i is one the next one is one
uh well now i
is one and i want to in the next turn i
will be
2 2 so what i what
add at equals 1 right
now i i use two numbers so what happened
to n
i have put two numbers so what what's
the what should i do to the n
n is the number of integers we need to
put in the array
and then i put one one number i put two
numbers so what should i do with the n
two what two and
minus three minus equals two okay and
then
after this loop okay when n is bigger
than two
so after this loop what happened to n n
will be
smaller than two right yeah so what kind
of value
possible value for the n
[Music]
possible value yeah
zero and one
yeah zero and one so one is one what
does it mean if n
equals one it definitely gets zero
sorry if n is one what what's what does
it mean it's original is odd or human
number
odd odd yeah because it always changes
by two
it's all it doesn't change it's uh
the fact that it's even or all right
because three is
odd and in minus two is one still odd
four is even your minus two is two is
still even right
doesn't make sense so when a is one it
means original number
is odd number so in this case
what should we do with that we are
missing one
and then there's one thing missing
[Music]
returned
okay so we're implementing the second
approach
okay so does it make sense yeah yeah
okay now
using the triangle thingy what triangle
thing
nothing okay so i will be start from
zero okay so now
answer will be start from
at the beginning and then we have a sum
equals zero okay
i add one until n minus two so look look
wire and bigger lens
yellow are bigger than one okay because
we we need to save the last value right
the last value yeah yeah so look our
answer columns
[Music]
column okay okay one okay i plus equals
one so i will become zero to one right
yes and then sum i need to add the sum
to
n sum equals and actually i need to put
it here
apparently i so the current sum is what
and i right
yeah and then i plus equals one right
and then
and what i i put one number so what
should i do with it
so now n will become
zero right yeah becomes zero because
it's smaller
even it will become one because n is
bigger than one into this and
now n will be one right okay so there's
a special case
if n is zero
no i can do this answer to a pen
open what minus what
right when n is 0 s is zero minus
s is zero that's fine when that is one
no n is one because n cannot be zero n
is one
it does not go inside and a minus zero
like this
one is n is two i add a uh
when n is to look when n is two
i add a zero
okay so i think i think this should be
one stop number one okay i
when i put a one and then
i i just put up s right
put minus s yes all right oh yeah
does it make sense look this s is this s
thingy
is the first n minus one numbers the sum
of the first
and minus numbers yeah all right and the
minus
n is the last number because i want to
negate the
the the sum right yes so let's let's
write that one let's let's do this one n
equals
two n equals two right
append one
and n will reduce by one level which is
one and go outside
s will be one minus one you'll be one
minus one that will work
right when n is three
music when only so you print
one two right the sum will be three and
the last one will be put
one two minus three right it's still one
when
n is one it doesn't go inside look
it doesn't go inside right well n is one
because
and th this loop you only go into this
loop when
n is bigger than one switch bit bigger
than one right
now it's is what happens if it's the
same as one
yeah yeah n is one it doesn't go inside
so append minus
s will be minus zero will be zero so
it's still up okay
does it make sense when n is four
so look for i one two three
one two three yeah one two three six
yeah because the sum will be be six and
then minus s
will be minus six right does it make
sense okay
what's the time complexity a
and what n yeah and because
we are generating numbers yeah yeah
what's the space complexity
i win yeah well done wow that's very
quick we're done because
we are using uh what
thumb no why are you using a list
at least yeah quickly yeah that's good
that's good boy okay
so the last thing to say to the people
and then
bye-bye see you tomorrow