hello hello mr eric uh
today we talk about binary trees so
what's binary trees
i'm good yeah you're a very good
apprenticeship what's minority
is a upside down tree with numbers okay
so can you
write a tree please any binary tree
yes yes
okay let's let's okay great so
how many how many leaf notes in this
manager okay
how many loot no in this final three
one only one yeah so for any final tree
it only has one
root right which nose has the
zero parent uh root
okay and for the leaves how many kids
do they leave oh yeah okay
what's in order in order
let's talk about pre-order first what's
pre-order
pre-order and then there's in order
and then that's the post order these are
three ways of travel
i think it and there's the best resource
yeah
which one is the default search
[Music]
which one is the death switch i think
blue dude root left right yeah
so this is nude left blue the left
right uh so no the left to right okay
note left to right okay and breakfast
is level by level right and in order is
what
uh
right left
left right no
look post you just this is in the middle
these
is in the previous the first this is
in the last right that's what they
called breakfast so which one is the
default search
okay so that's good um so we are given
we are given a pre-order and
uh in order and we can determine
a binary tree right yeah so let's do an
example
uh four zero
uh forward four two one zero three okay
four two one
zero three so can you really
on balance i'm balanced yes i went down
so what's balance what's unbalance
what's balance a balanced one
is like a flu vibration
normally the violence is like the
difference the maximum difference
between any left and the left and
right is smaller than or equal than one
right
so look this is definitely not right
because look
this is a lot right it's not balanced
yeah
okay so what's the pre-order of these
what's the pre-order
pre-order of these can you give me an
example
okay so it is four two one
zero three we're done four two one zero
three okay four
two one zero and what's the in order
uh two one zero three four
two one zero three four okay so now
given this final three you can calculate
you can you know we know let's
pre-order in order how about we don't
know this binary
but given these what's the stress is to
be at least from these two right
yeah this is thinking backwards right
we given this financing we can we know
the pre-order you know that but now we
are given these
how do we bear these three okay
right right we order is not
left to right okay so what does it mean
which is four
yeah okay well let's go good job so four
is the lose right pre-order yeah so we
know the four
and then this in order is what in order
it's
a l and i right so this
is given right this is given right so we
need to find
this in the n in the second which is
yeah
and then we know this we find it here so
we know this bit
which means that no right yeah this is
left
and then this is right right yeah does
it make sense
yeah so in this case we can't
yeah i know we can but in some cases
they are right right
but here we find it and then what should
we
then we will need a beard right for
example let's
let's build a tree with the right okay
okay so let's see
okay let's see this nine okay so four
two one zero three nine right
and what's the in order uh
one zero three four nine okay
yeah i put the knife they're very fast
yeah
okay so look the first thing is i need
to build a route with the
with the number four yeah right yeah
and then i find this four in here
yeah then i know everything after this
is the left everything after is the
right right
yeah okay so now can you build the right
tree
no no i put i i look i i use the four i
take it out yeah
yeah okay so now look look please
two one so look um
so let's pre-order pre-order 2103
it's on the left so the left is
again two right yeah yeah
and then 2103 because we know 2 103 is
on the left so this is 2 103
and then that's 9. so look 2 is on the
left 2 103 and 9 will be on the right
right
and 2 103 again i take it out and then
you'll pick one 103 right
one or three
so um so we can do this recursively
right
because two and i find a two here in a
two here so there is no left
all these are right right doesn't make
sense yeah
okay so let's do this
let's do this define
beard here
uh let's totally pre-order
and that's in order oh yeah no yeah no
yeah
yeah okay so look if
let's say if in order okay if if not in
order okay
if we are using using all the elements
in the
list in not in order right or not
preorder is the same
with return we return just return long
what okay yeah yeah because we it's
empty list we just return it right
so now we need to find a try
find the root do the let's say the value
is i okay i
equals preorder
which which element in the pre-order is
the current load
which anime in the pre-order is the
current root the first one
the first one yes so how do we popular
how do we use how to remove the first
element from the
list which is i just sell a word
pop yeah pop zero right yeah pop zero if
we don't specify
zeela what does it do you will pop the
pork which which one pops yellow is the
first one if we don't
supply this zero what does it do it
pops pops which animal
which is the other direction of us lost
yes we're done if we don't specify this
zero you'll be the last one
so leave home what's the temperature
what's the time complexity of this pop
zero
oh and yeah but if we are using double
nbq it will be
you'll be pop left and which will be
constant right yes
okay so now we have this blue and then
uh
the left so let's say dude okay equals
three okay okay sorry about my alarm
so so order equals
three and then we're given this i right
this is the load right
so now we need to build the left tree
and appear the right tree yeah right
yeah
and then we just need to return what
return here
i'll be on the loot i'll be on the left
tree i feel the right tree i need to
build the one
return what victory return route okay
so the thing is how do we feel this so
we need a beer
right the preorder we already taken one
element out so the first element is
uh pre-order right and this is the same
yeah because
we already taken the first element now
right yeah yeah so that would be
because we it's always the first element
right
that's the root right so now now that
the the thing is we need to find it in
uh the in order in order thing okay so
look
before okay let's say let's say this one
two three okay
one two three just three elements yeah
what's the in order one two three oh
what we ordered one two three yeah
the in order is two one three right yeah
so we know this is load yeah so we need
to find
five fine here right yeah which is good
okay so
this one is right and this is my
favorite
okay okay this the left and this is the
right
yeah okay so wait there's a there's a
slightly problem which is that we we
need to find it
let's find it okay let's find this put
all the pop zero
right but we need to find it then uh
let's let's let's do it in let's see how
do we find it is you can do this in
order
you know the dot index right
index you will find this in that right
this
is i will be index but now the tree i
will be
you can say is you will be pre-ordered
the
because it's already top it so i can say
in order i right
it's the same okay right look
the reason i want to find this index uh
i slightly write it
because i need to find this index right
look maybe
in order to order the top zero i take
the first element out of this
which is one and i find it in the second
one which is there
which is this position yeah and then in
order i will be the loo
it's the same yeah i i equal one and
then now and now
everything up to list will be the left
everything after will be right right so
these here so that would be
in order everything
up to i but not including the load right
yeah and then here what do i do here
in order the right three what what
should i do what do i do can you write
it here
after i so what
i plus one column right because
this i is the root right yeah
up to i eric this is this format from
two not including two right
so up to loot not including that's fine
but here
is wrong will be inclusive so i would
need to be
i plus one here right does it make sense
yeah what's the term complexity
[Music]
yeah this is every time look every time
i would need to
pop one from the beginning and then i
need to search it
for the second one right i need to
search it these will take
all n right what happens if uh this
this uh the range was one and there was
two ones okay that's a good question but
we are assuming that pre-order and in
order is both correct to
uniquely di identify a binary tree okay
so if you so so there is no such case
when there are duplicate numbers right
yeah because look we need to index this
is finding an element in the list this
is our
n time but how many times we need to
potentially look for these
n n times so the complexities o n
squared doesn't make sense because they
are n loops yeah
they have to be unique yes yeah for
example if a level 3
is like that yeah always the
uh always please which is definitely
a balance i'm balanced yes and then you
need to look for these every time
the root yeah doesn't make sense
yes so you take om time and each one you
need to take a search for n
so look please pre-order doctor we can
do this
so look we can we can write this here
look look we can say uh
root of value blue value equals
pre-order the first one yeah
pre-order for the zero
right we're gonna know the value and
then
i will be in order
we know the top index
load of low value yeah this is the same
but we need to
get rid of the first one so we can we
can do this
we can we can do this we preorder then
we do this one
dash yeah one dash
this is the same thing so means i i will
this this would uh discard the first
element i will use the second element
right
this is exactly the same as the pop zero
right yeah
so this is much clearer right root of
value will be preorder.0 the first
element right
and i search this root of value low
value
in in order right yeah
i don't want like because it appeared it
because i already know the first element
is the root of the current node current
so i will when i recursively built it i
will pop 0 i i will
disregard that discard the first one
yeah it's the same as purple 0.
does it make sense okay so let's
let me let me quickly
no no no okay okay okay okay okay
okay okay okay
huh in order
in order what's the key word to look for
the element
index yes index which index index one
pre-order index which one we want to
index the
we want to find the which element in the
in order
good loot and low value yeah let's see
okay we are done today bye bye bye