hey hello mr mr ryan how are you today
good okay we've got a new book today
we're done we're done okay so let's move
down
one two two three
two four okay so this is the
royal numbers what's the maximum one
four four what's the minimum one what's
the
average
average you add all these numbers
divided by one two three four five six
yeah okay let's average right
sum divided by numbers that's average
okay
yeah it doesn't make sense one three
five eight yo you're okay with this
concept yeah okay so what's the
what's medium remember what's medium
what's medium medium is used
you saw these numbers right if if
one two three what's the medium
if it's odd number you pick the middle
one it's in the salted one right
how about one two three four what's the
medium
medium what's the medium
do you still remember you picked in the
salted you saw these numbers yeah one
two three
you'll pick the meter two even number
yeah
you add it together divide by 2 which is
2.5 that's medium
got it okay so today we're going to
introduce another concept called
mode mount
what's mode oh
yeah it's true yeah it's the most up
yeah
appearing yeah most appealing one which
is three two
okay i'll get two appears three times so
it's not okay okay so that's a little
review so
another concept lucky number
lucky number okay so lucky number is
that
uh no no no no let's put it into three
okay
so what's how many times one appears
one how many times two appears
how many times three appears three how
many times four up here one
okay so if they they appear the same
number of times equals to the
value itself it's called lucky number
right
that one and that one that one and the
one yeah
and we find we need to return the
largest one which is two
does it make sense yeah so if a number
appears
n times and then if the value is n then
it's a lucky number and we need to find
the number of the yeah doesn't have to
be sorted
no it doesn't know how about one and one
one and one will be two times then it's
not a lucky number and sometimes it
doesn't have this number and return
minus one right
for example one
one two okay one appears how many times
two two appears how many times one so
there's no lucky number
minus one okay minus one yeah doesn't
make sense
yeah okay so how can we do this how can
we do this
any idea there are a couple ways to
how do we use the object in star wars
with what what kind of object and can
allow us to recall
to find the number of frequencies
occurrence for each item what's that
called i think if we can do
c what's that called c o
count counter remember okay look
define define
largest largest lucky lava okay
lumber okay let's call that lums
and what's missing okay look
counter equals counter
yeah what does it contain it contains
how many numbers the key and the value
yeah what key is the number
and the value is the number of times
they appear yeah
okay and then now what should we do
what should we do look we can appear we
can put it the
order we can put all the
put all the lucky number in this list
first okay so let's do this for
i in in one
in c right the interval is the key
if the key equals
the value of ci right and i put it
push it into we found a lucky number
right
i is the value c i is the number of
times they appear right
answer a pen
i right and then we need to
look if answer if there is a lucky
number then return
max we want to determine the maximum
right
yeah and then return minus one here
why does it make sense yeah what's the
time
[Music]
oh complexity how many times how many
iterations are in here what's the space
conversation
what are you using a notebook
[Music]
there's no numbers in the list okay yeah
look here here
um
no counter and we can we can we can
if answers return that yeah we can
return max answer
if answer is minus one yeah you can you
can write this
in in one one sentence yeah return max
it's the same thing yeah written max
answer if answer
yeah as minus one okay yeah
you can write it this way this is called
pythonic way hyphenic way
pythonic way okay sometimes people
programming in python they like to write
this kind of code
but this is more clear if answer even
the items in the answer
if they are more than if they are there
is a lucky number
we return maximum moving right yeah
otherwise we will ten minus one and we
can also
uh we can also do what we can also do
this
uh return max
return max what next
i for
i in c if i equals c i
right
and and and otherwise otherwise how can
we uh let me just
uh no no maybe we need to do this two
steps i saw
look here this one yeah we can do this
we can put it we can combine these two
into one
one sentence answer equals
what i for
i in c if i
equal equals c i i right
you see so this is the least
comprehension
so look i i create a list which is
contents
element i but what is i is in c
and what condition if i equals yeah so
it's the same thing as this right
all right doesn't make sense yeah but
you're not trying to you're not required
to
remember these these are fancy way fancy
syntax
sugars you know what syntax yoga a much
neat way to write it but this is also
does the same thing
doesn't make sense no no no no it's
all one none return back that you've
answered yes it's all one none okay
okay so can we can we do it without the
notebook because no good for them
yeah fake people maybe not okay
look it might be thank you and square
where down blue forcing
in this case is one square okay so
look we are trading now we are treating
the space
that's okay we are treating the space
with the time okay
okay we are treating space here we are
using the o and space
counter right yeah okay so how can we
improve first
how can we prove first we
iterate through each number right yes
you tell me how to improve false blue
false okay blue fox
num okay look
look let's let's do a answer equals
minus one okay let's suppose
this the initial initially we can't find
lucky number right
yeah okay so now we need to
four look for i in
num right we go through each number
right all right but for each number
what we need to do we need to count it
how many times right
yeah so we can use this if
nums look every dot count
yeah that's a function called cow cow
what color i
if equals i right right all right
then i is a lucky number so what should
we do with the i
put it in the answer there's no answer
is the value
we want to we we don't have a list now
we we well we need to you can put it in
at least
list right then it would be written
maximum i
answer right if there's but we can do
this look
then we can say if i is bigger than
answer
right right answer equals i right
all right and i can just return answer
i'm right
does it make sense does it make sense
all this one you can just do this answer
equals max answer
i doesn't make sense look we are
iterating these numbers
each number we try each number and we
count how many
i mean count how many times it appears
in the list right
if it appears in the same value of times
then this is a lucky number right and we
need to
compare the store the largest lucky
number right
what's the time complexity
why is it one square brief was in the
excellent i went to go
oh well done look at this
we're done this is on but this count
look this
is calm counting this number in an array
takes
another n right yeah so this four and
inside it needs another four
that's all n squared what's the time
what's the space complexity
it's not let's face the
a1 you can create a variable it doesn't
matter
this is a one constant means that there
are constant number of the spaces
right because if the n numbers egg on
this chair
okay okay um yeah because if like
numbers they are abundant numbers we
still need to
use one variable right it doesn't change
right that's why
or one constant okay so what how can we
do better
how can we do better look how can we do
well
we can solve the numbers from the
largest to the smallest
yeah and y
and what we can solve the numbers from
look if
three we can solve the number three two
two one
right we saw the number from largest one
to smallest and we go through this
if if this is not the same as the next
number
if not the same as next number then i
will
check if it's the same as next number i
increment the count and now look if it
look
if these two two two they have two two
two right and it's the same
then i will return it because i always
try from the largest to smallest
right i will immediately return the one
the first lucky number i'm right
yeah does it make sense i don't need to
find the largest right
okay can you repeat okay then you find
one the largest uh
[Music]
because the first first lucky number
five would be the largest right because
i
already started from the largest to the
summary cycle
but you need to express it say slowly
other people can understand okay
nobody understand what they mean only
daddy i can't
okay okay so let's look better stories
lungs what's what's the time complexity
of this one
[Music]
every time about assaulting me
square o n
yeah because we are using a quick salt
much softer
every time i have one right look okay
much so how do we solve cut it
so look i emerging from two numbers i
know how to multiple numbers yeah
and right and then two numbers much two
numbers i know how to do here
right and then four numbers multiple
numbers yeah
you see remember how we merge two sorted
list right
we we have two pointers going through
comparing each
yeah right okay after so and then we
have a
number of the let's call it straight
you know what's trick the number of
counter for the current number yeah
straight
c equals zero and then four i
in numbs because
yeah look this thought is from the
smallest to the largest
so now i i need to add a keyword reverse
equals two right then you'll be from the
largest to smallest
all right yeah and the time complexity
will be still the same okay
for i in numbers then we i will see plus
equals one right
right yeah the current number and
if uh probably
probably i i i'm not going to the
numbers i will go into the range
range the indexes length
lumps okay because i need to use the
indexes
if if one i if it's the last number
then minus one or
or what or if the grams
i not equals
next numbers okay if it's not equals the
next numbers
so what should we do if
we start in c equals
now if c equals num psi right this is a
lucky number right
when we determine we right
otherwise look otherwise what otherwise
we need to set c equals zero and then we
turn minus one doesn't make sense
um take a minute to think about it and
i'm going to
ask you questions okay why because i
need to
check if you understand why
stop saying that why why
okay okay
okay look right what
so ryan ryan
i i will go through the ranges each
index right
and then i will increment the current
number counter
strike c will be equals one and if it's
look if
it doesn't go inside it means the
current number is equals to the next
number right
right and then next iteration c will be
equals two right
and i know look if it's the last number
or
if it's not equals to the next number
what does it mean if it's not equal to
the next number
then it means that the current number
appears
c times right and what's this if c
equals
i what does it mean c
it means that uh lucky number well
i will return the first lucky number
right yeah yeah and if it's not a lucky
number what should i do i should reset
the
check so the next iteration you'll be
appearing one time up right
okay two times appears to design does it
make sense what's the term complexity
log n okay is that a separate sentence
again oh and again this one is a one
right a bracket
and l o g and bracket okay
so look this angle is consists of two
parts
the salting the saltine and this our
part
which is dominating which is bigger
this one yeah oh and nothing because
it's time again yeah logan could be
bigger than one right
yeah so this one is take is most time
consuming part so we
when we talk about everything we pick
the most dominant ping pong which is
this one
yeah and you got that one yeah yeah okay
does it make sense yeah
okay and if if i tell you if the numbers
are already sorted
is like numbers
yes and what's the time complexity
yeah oh and you're just in the race list
okay stop checking okay okay i'm going
to erase this okay so
what should i put here yeah
and what else just left her you want to
do two together
what what you just say
if it's a lucky number how do you tell
your writers
what i not i
which one is the counter c c c equals
one
c equals what i
no no what's that
is the ranges what's the value of i
i learned what's the value i is the
ranges
uh index so what's the value at index i
the number number's array what's the
integer
one
is an integer if c this is the number of
times that appears
which number appears come on this is
this is the list
this is the list and what's the i in
that side what's the index
how do you write it the number the first
number is number zero
and what's the ice number zero nums i
yeah come on oh my god come on be
confident okay
you see you just saw that and then i
raised it i asked you and
you're not sure does it make sense you
forgot something
column yeah that's not bracket does it
make sense all right
yeah does that make sense yeah okay i'm
going to erase one more time what what's
the what did i
erase him
[Music]
what should i do with the c every time c
is the number of times equals
one come on be confident okay
so i go you raise one more
okay what's this i got an answer
no return lines are returned minus one
come on
i'm listening okay you're listening okay
that's it that's it for today
bye bye bye bye
oh yeah