go hello hello mr marion how are you
today
good okay so can you remind me what is a
binary
search tree okay so on the left side
it just right now is such a it's like a
fun
[Music]
okay i'll do
you don't need to draw that perfectly
just draw a roughly a binary search tree
okay
but the final research tree is a binary
tree right
but it has to be he has to satisfy
some requirements to be a binary search
tree
and the notes on the left hand side are
strictly smaller than the parent
and the notes on the right hand side on
the right subtree are
strictly bigger than the
parent right okay
and why why do we need a binary surgery
so in
what what travels the order does the
binary search tree
produce assorted order
saltiness uh yes that's very nice look
this note even it's on the left hand
side
but it has to be strictly larger than
the parent this parent right
it can't be like three if this is three
it's not
but bst doesn't make sense even it's
smaller than a but it has to be bigger
than
five hey i mean i know yeah that's
that's right that's right yes
okay so what what what kind of order
what we have what kind of order we have
in order pre-order and and
yeah professors is five to eight level
so which order produce a salted beast
which order do we apply i mean if we
apply it to the binary surgery
we'll make a salty mist left
the one we've left tonight and
i know what what's that called i think
it's post
in order because the new note is in the
middle so let's
let's let's put in order so it's one
left note right right because look
left node is strictly smaller than loot
right
and the right now is strictly smaller
than the
metal root so if i go with this that's
in order yeah
in order in order because this is in the
middle if it's this in order let me
produce a sort of list right
am right does that make sense okay so
today we are given this final research
tree and i if i tell you
what's the successor you know successor
so the next one next one what's the
successor
if it if uh of the note
for example if if i give you the node
five
and you want i want you to tell i want
you to tell me that
the successor of five is eight right
which
is the the smallest number
no no the success of the successor of
the
five is six sorry five is six
because it's it's in order
yeah it is what two five
six a right yeah let's start it so
let's try what's the other fact six okay
yeah that's all right so now
yeah we're done that's a good question
you just written nothing no
you can't find anyone but let's yeah
that's one
education good question so basically
you're finding
the large the smallest number
like is bigger than five right the
successor
of five is that i want you to find the
smallest number which is bigger than
five right
so it's six not eight right because six
is smaller than eight which is
these two are bigger than five do you
have a
i mean how do we solve this
in order yeah you know that yes
and then you just do the next one over
thingy that's what i think so so yeah
we we can traverse by the final search
tree and then put all the nodes
in a list and then we look for the node
right the index usually in that song
here yeah
and then we return the next one right
does that make sense
yeah okay let's let's do this okay let's
do this
okay so define uh
in all the successor
and then loot i know we have a target
this is the this is the target good
good okay so yeah so now look we have a
list of us let's call it data
okay equals this yeah
yeah and then we do this define
definition we define the function which
take a animal
that is tremendous the binaural street
okay look
if look is now
we just return yeah okay we can just
pretend
then then what we travel a lot we travel
uh
which number first the left note right
yes
so d f s one
and then what we travel the left
look is is recursive we are calling it
and what
what should we do we we add the the note
do the value data dot add
no append right a pen
apparently value yeah i want you i do
after next
what should i do after the next
what should i remember i travel
no and now what should i do what's
missing here
what did i do i visited that i reached
the left tree i visited
i i put that note you visited the right
tree
yeah the way down
after that i have this data yeah this
data thing yeah
yes yeah let's take that thingy
uh i think i have to put this non-local
thing remember
yeah because this is not in the scope i
have to reference it here right
and then here i have say the mspfs
load okay and after that data will
contain the
sorted resulting list right yeah and
then now what do i do and then look
i will have this i equals
theta dot i find it look index
i find the index of the t
right yes then if i
is smaller than length theta yeah if
there is a
if it's the in the smallest data i
then plot minus one yeah because we if
it's not the
second to the next and i can return one
return theta
i will return the i plus one right yeah
because this is the next one yeah what's
the time complexity
what and something yes
because we're traversing the final
street if there are n notes there will
be
n times i i have to visit the nodes each
node and put it in the data
list there what's the space complexity
can we can we do it better i mean if if
if the binary search tree is highly
balanced okay it's very balanced still
on right because we have to visit
exactly at
every node in the binary search tree we
don't
use the fact that the left nodes are
smaller this then
yeah the the note and the right notes
are bigger than
that right we have to visit all at once
can we do better we can
maybe we can okay so so
this is clear yeah eric this is clear
yeah
look if if ice we find a t the index of
t
if it's next one if i plus one is still
then smaller than the length theta then
we can return the
next one right otherwise if this doesn't
if this if condition doesn't satisfy
what does it mean
what does it mean it means that
it means what it's the which of which
element and you can't find the next one
which element
the last one yeah if it's the last one
it doesn't go in there right because if
the last one theta i plus
one is out of boundary you can't find i
plus one right
yes doesn't make sense look this in this
array
uh is one two three right four is
exactly okay
zero is what are zero is one
one yeah and ar one is one
two ah three is one i don't know
two is one are you gonna ask me
no no it would be the computer will
complain
because look ar only has three elements
you're asking for the fourth
okay and then that would be a runtime
error
so the computer will complain and and
we are throwing exception and then you
left you can't do that
okay there's a problem there's a bug
yeah doesn't make sense
so that's why we have to check if if i
plus one is smaller it's still within
the boundary
then i can return the next one right
otherwise it's the last element and we
can
we can find the successor okay we can't
find the
smallest element that is larger
than the last element right yeah
okay so another agreement
another angle look look let's do this
two
one
four three okay
this is the final first three right yeah
what can you do
oh you can do three or four it's the
same yeah
you know that would be what zero one
two three four yeah okay
zero one three it's a thought
so look if i just tell you if i want to
look for number two
it will be number four yeah yeah i know
if i want to look for number four
for example okay i want to find the
success that
next to one zero there will be one right
okay so
if one is zero smaller than two
yeah yeah i go this way yeah is zero
is ecl smaller than zero
no no i go to the low right so
what does it mean it means that what
does it mean
look if so we can we when we are given
this t
we can traverse the tree by comparing
the value to that node yeah
when the value is smaller when this
value is smaller than the root value
like if i want to find it zero and then
i i
will update the answer the note
because look if if i
this is the answer we're looking for
right at the beginning it's none right
yeah and this target t is
equal to zero right it's the number
where we are trying to find like next
bigger than t the smallest number bigger
than t which is one right
okay so if t is smaller than the lude is
here right
yeah it's smaller than 2 so
i should i should update the answer to
2 and go to the left why is that because
if if this number is smaller than 2
then 2 is bigger than
the 2 is bigger than the answer right
all right
yeah look look you need to think about
these logic okay
if if if this number if this number we
are looking for
t is smaller than a 2 so
so 2 is is bigger than the t is bigger
than t
right right so we we set this to answer
to two now because we're gonna find a
number which is bigger than t
doesn't make sense so i go here okay is
if zero is smaller than zero
no no i go to the right right then i
i don't get it i don't i don't need to
do anything but look
if zero is smaller than
one yes smaller than one so i
every time it's smaller i i update it to
this right and i go to the right left
which is not nothing and
i end it so look the answer is one yeah
does that make sense yeah when you go to
the left
what does it mean it means that the root
the current node
is bigger than the value you're looking
for then
it's possibly the answer right it's
possibly answer i have to update the
answer what happens
is we read the answer if you do the
answer okay how about
uh okay so good question how about if i
put zero and then i erase that one thing
okay
okay at the beginning we are still
looking for zero which is
the next one will be two right yeah if
zero is smaller than two yeah yes then
it means two is bigger than zero right
yeah and then that absolute answer this
is the candidate it doesn't mean
it's a final answer right it just means
that two is bigger than t
but we are not sure if it's the smallest
right okay now i go to the left
okay is zero smaller than zero
no i go to the right which ends nothing
ends and then the answer is two
the last one yeah okay so we try another
example like
what happens one there sorry which one
it is okay
let's be somebody just i just show you
right remember yeah
how about let's take this example three
three and then
you give me the answer for right yeah
let's let's do this number three
the at the beginning is nothing is three
bigger than two
smaller than two nine go to the right
when you go to the right you do nothing
what is three smaller than four yeah
yeah
i go to the left but i also update the
answer to four right
because four is bigger than three it's
possibly one them
right okay it's three smaller than three
i go no and i i just go right
and and let's let's end it and the
answer is well doesn't make sense
yeah okay so it's a bit tricky right but
it works yeah
it's a bit tricky right so the thing is
that when you turn to the right when you
compare
10 to the right it also means that the
load
is possibly one of the answer right
because it's bigger than the thing
you're looking for
but we are not sure if it's the smallest
right
then we keep visiting we keep updating
right when you go to the right you do
nothing when you go to the left
you you are you are
making you you are towards in your air
towards the answer right
because you are you are making these
answers smaller right
yeah right when you go to the left
it's bigger than the answer but we
smaller so we are getting close
to the final answer in this way yeah
define okay look answer yeah equals
nothing okay now yeah you tell me okay
why are root okay while root yeah
if t if t
is smaller than root of value
what's missing okay
s what
and here what's right if key is smaller
than the root of value what should we do
all right what do i just say i need to
do what you
show
[Music]
okay yeah i know what should i do if
it's bigger if it's not smaller what
else should i do
low equals root or what we do
yeah we're done and then what's missing
return what
okay you see this is shorter right
compared to the previous one the
definition right remember you still
remember yeah
what's the term complexity
yes and what's h equals you can say o h
and h equals one if it's a balance
if it's a highly balanced finance stream
what's h
o h h is the height you can say okay and
also if i want to say
n is the number of the nodes in the load
one
and
how many notes are there uh
seven seven notes okay height is worth
three yeah yeah
high equals three and no equals seven so
it's roughly eight okay so log
log eight which is three all right does
it make sense
yeah because look 2 to the power 0 2 to
the power 1 2 to the power 3.
in the reverse it will be locked right
that's why in the final
3 when you are every time look every
time i go to the left or right
right so every time i cut i
i abandoned another half right am right
so every time i abandon half so let's
lock
lock n does it make sense or you can say
o
o h because h is the height does it make
sense
what's the space complexity i uh
oh what come on do we use any space here
one
come on be confident one yes we're not
using any face
right we're not using any list but
previous one we have a list right
i'll answer this that's why it's aware
right yeah yeah that's good
okay wait wait wait wait wait wait wait
okay
what's two here we are definitely come
on
come on answer sing it yes i think we
want to
equal okay answer equals one we're
updating the answer
answer equals one answer
we go to the left we update the loop the
answer to
load yeah
write it like a man not like a little
girl so small
the printing okay and now we go
we go to the left or right left yeah
because it's smaller we go to the left
bigger go to the right yeah
okay that's it for today