okay so today we'll talk about the
three different aquariums to solve the
problem which is called max
sub array sum next
sub array
okay so given a list of numbers like 1
3 minus 5 6 0
one okay so we want to find out
let's max the sub list the sum of the
maximum
uh sub list yeah the sub list sum
which is the service which has the
largest sum
so what's sublist what's up this
can you say tell me what's sublist
and what how how is the difference with
sub
subsequence the frequency is the
subsequent remember we talked about uh
we talked about the subsequence planning
yeah the longest
planet yeah so what's the sub list
continuous consecutive yeah and plus
sequence
can be any yeah for example the surface
is one three
one three five minus five three minus
five three minus five six so basically
you pick two ranges
you pick two power and then yeah yeah
yeah
we're done yeah consecutive so it has to
be consecutive elements but subsequence
is not right you can pick one minus five
zero y
you can pick three minus one right so
you you'll get
one three six okay so the task is to
find the sub list which has the largest
sum okay so any
i mean if if the number even this has
all the positive number what's the
sub list that has the largest sum all of
them all of it of course yeah we can
keep adding i think right
yeah and how about if the subject says
if this has only the negative numbers
the biggest one biggest
biggest well done yeah because for
example like minus one minus two minus
three so you only you pick the
largest one which is minus one right
yeah and it has the largest surface
because if you keep adding
then you become smaller and smaller
right but if you pick minus two
you can pick minus one which is better
right all right okay so good
so any idea how we can solve this
problem like if
it's reinforcing yeah we're done that's
a very good
way the most stupid way but sometimes
the most effective way right because the
proof forcing is the most
straightforward
most intuitive way so how can we profess
this problem like
justin sorry
no no how can we prove that how many
sublease
positives yeah
i know but the blue forcing it doesn't
care about if they are not
positive or negative right the home but
we prove
us all the pairs of sublist right
because each service is determined by
two
by the left boundary and the right
boundary right which can be easily put
forth
in in two for loops there was a time
complexity
and o n square right yeah
o n square for the proof force in the
sub list yeah
so maybe um
look if we if we determine the left
boundary
yeah they'll be the left boundary will
be from zero
to n minus one right
actually minus two minus one yeah minus
one and then the right boundary
will start from the left until
and minus one right right so for each
length i can start with the right
boundary right
so let's be o n square right all right
because if this is n minus one choice
actually there's n choice and for the
right one
that will be and will be n
minus n minus
look if a if left is
n choice and then right will be n minus
left choice
and because when n is getting when the
left is getting bigger
so this n minus left to the right is
getting smaller but
eventually is not the number of the
number of the pairs
of these sublease is n
is roughly n squared divided by 2 here
but we drop the constant
so the complexity is always square to
find the sub list
then for each subnet we need to compute
the sum of the sub list
in which may take another n right so the
overall time complexity is o and square
o and cubic right but
but we don't have to we calculate the
sub list
every time we determine the suffix right
so for example right
using dynamic paragraph we're going to
remember it look if one
two three four the list is one two three
four right
right alright this is one two three four
when we determine
the we when we determine uh
the sub list one two one
one two we know if the sum is three
right
yeah but and then we we want to is
extend this surface to one more element
now the surface
of new surface will be one two three
five
but when we calculate the sum of the one
two three we don't need to
start calculating from the beginning
because we already
know this surface new service is one
element
more than the previous sub list right
and the sum of the previous salaries is
three
and then i can just add another three
right so this will save us
o and time right and what's the new icon
complexity
complexity complexity
and squad yeah it's good because i
i just said we optimize it and
how many iterations a hundred times a
thousand
a hundred times a hundred how much
i think it's ten thousand
yeah oh yeah ten dollars sorry you're
right yes
what a thousand times a thousand a
thousand times a thousand
one thousand thousand one minutes
one million million if you turns another
thousand that will be one billion okay
yeah doesn't make sense so it's a lot
right oh cubic
is a a billion if
it's quite slow for computer to
iterate that much right it will be super
slow right
sleepy deeper still personal okay so
let's let's
forcing it first okay define let's just
call it as
f numbs okay what else means
[Music]
initially the answer would be a very
small number so we we can set it to
negative infinity right and you used to
know right i
you i already teach you how to do this
flow
to convert a string if it to a number
and i put a
negative right i think in fact you can
do this you can do the same as
this you can do it with
mass dot i and f this is a constant okay
it's the same thing okay
it's it's a more straightforward right
because i want the
the infinity constants along the mass
which is belongs to mass
package yeah domain
let's iterate okay let's learn length n
equals lengths
nums right then okay
now look for let's say that
i i will be left moderate i in
range range n right
and then now i have determined the left
boundary i have studied
s zero which is this which is the sum of
the
current sub list right and now i need to
extend this
surface to the right yeah in range
start from i and then to m n right all
right
and then look s plus equals num
num which element
j j and then
what happened if i got a sum then i need
to compare with the answer yeah
so if s bigger than answer what should i
do
then answer equals s i'll return y
and then we turn of cards
can we make this into the next one here
max yeah the max of also
yeah we're done look because this is
basically we want to update the answer
to the maximum of both right
so i just have to do this answer
equals max function max of what max of
answer and x okay it's the same or as
an answer so they maximum actually you
can
pass many many numbers in the max
function and you will return the maximum
amount of it yeah yeah okay okay so
leave this time from next
remind me what's the time complexity
square
what's the space complexity a
are we using a different additional
space yeah one constant okay that's good
okay so now can we do better
we we can do it we're using o and loop
okay so we we have two approaches
uh one is called dynamic programming the
other one is called greedy algorithm
they are both quite
similar in this case labels have this
owen
time and 01 space so for this
for example let's say
let's say we we uh let's say we have a
current sub list right so now
we want to consider the next element
right
so we can we want to consider next next
animal we have two choice
we can either include this new animal in
the current subways or we start a new
subject with
this element right yeah we only have
these two choices right
do you have another choice no right so
in this case we can do this yes so for
example like
one two minus three
four okay let's just try this let's try
with the sub
uh let's see there's an answer here and
then let's sub this sum okay sub list
sum
sub least sum i think it's four
okay look let's say start with one okay
one
both are one yeah the global answer is
one yeah
next number two i can add it which is
three
or i can pick that code oh i can pick up
two which is better
what i can pick two or i can pick one
and two which
is better uh
one and two so it's three
and then yeah makes a new record here
right and then now
minus three zero zero oh
my my i can pick minus three alone or i
can pick i can use the previous my
plus minus three so it's zero right yeah
which is better zero it's better i put a
t over here and then
still this is three because it's not
bigger than three okay then
four zero plus four or i can pick pick
and four
it's the same right it makes the same
answer it's the same because you can
you can edit okay there you go you can
pick one so it's the same answer it's
easy
either way okay so we got this right
let's play another so look one part one
pass or one time right because
every time we make a decision we have
two choice we either include the next
number in the new
sublist or we start a new service with
it right
okay let's try this formula it's quite
easy yeah look
let's say let's say answer
equals the surface equals the first
number okay let's try the
first number so look you can write this
a equal b equals equals c
which means a equals c and b equals c
okay so in this case you can write it
it's the same thing as answer s equals
num
zero and num zero okay in person you can
write it two way right or you can
separate to that but this one is shorter
right
yeah does it make sense this is the same
right yeah
yeah okay now i for the beginning i
choose the first number and then i need
to start with the second number right
for i
in nums i can
i can do this start with the second
number right
column okay now look i can pick the
next number so which is s equals one
next
take the next number which you want i
can only pick the
next number which is what the next
number is
the
and then what should i do here we shall
which what do we do what should we do
now we have the current so we want to
check if it's bigger than the global
answer right yeah so we can say if s is
bigger than answer then answer equals x
or we can use the max function which is
what
answer equals max of s
what's missing
what's the timetable actually what's the
spectrometer
oh one okay well so look this is this is
the dynamic programming okay
yeah because this one is we are making a
dynamic
programming choice we pick we pick
we pick this the next element oh we can
pick or we start with the new list right
yeah we only have at least two choice
right you don't have any rituals okay
okay so now there's another approach
called gritty
grading yeah
greedy so so it's quite similar to
dynamic programming except that we have
a
current sum and then we only added the
next number if
the current sum is greater or equal than
zero
if it's negative we start the next
element as the
uh the sum okay so for example let's say
this
one minus two
three minus four five okay let's do this
okay
so now we have the answer here we have a
current sum okay current sum current sum
let's just do x
s equals 1 yeah
s equals 1 yeah the current sum is 1 and
the answer is 1 right
minus s minus 1 plus minus 2 is minus
one
right okay i put a minus one here i
think
you think yeah i put a minus one here
and it's still one
and now s is smaller than zero
so i don't add the next number i start
with the next number
yeah because now it's negative i don't
want to keep this negative sum
so i will start with next number which
is three right
and then this is bigger okay three minus
four
yeah because three is positive right the
sum is positive i can add it and which
is minus one
three okay and again now my my running
sum this is called running somewhere the
coming some yeah
minus one so if the sum is negative
it means that i don't want to keep these
i don't want to keep these
uh negative some array and i will jump i
will use the next one which is five
no no no we can't because this is not
equal to zero
right yeah yeah this is also work so
this is based on the fact that
we don't want to keep the negative
sublet the sum is the negative sum right
when it's negative sum we just jump to
the next one right
yes we start with a new one okay so
let's it's it's quite similar but it's
slightly different than the diameter
yes it always well good question it
always works yeah
because even a thumb is negative i can
i prefer to start with a new one right
yeah
yeah does it make sense it's a bit
harder to understand but
with the name programming is easy to
understand right yeah
okay don't worry if you can't get it out
it's a little bit tricky
right little bit think about it when
you're at school when you don't have
anything to do you just think why it
works okay
yeah think about it and and if you don't
understand tomorrow
and you'll tell me and i'll explain
again okay
okay look let's
sum equals sum equals one
zero answer equals
max mass dot infinity
okay now let's do this for i
in uh okay
for i in num okay
look if this is slightly different look
area
if s bigger or equal
zero then i will add it the next number
right
otherwise i prefer to
[Music]
start with the next number all right
look look
if if the sum is bigger if current sum
is bigger than zero it's not negative i
prefer to start with the edit
with the next number otherwise i will
start with next number right
yeah and then here answer equals
max answer and what
next answer what
correctly
yeah okay so okay okay okay okay
just this bit tiny bit
[Music]
what else could be so
if the sum is bigger than zero we add
the next number otherwise we start with
the next number right
yeah so which which is what s equals one
is
good job today good job say bye bye