friday yeah good
good it's friday okay so today we talk
about a problem which is called set
split set split we want to
so given a list of numbers yeah this is
the number like
four nine five okay okay
let's read numbers uh okay so this is a
set of numbers we want to find out if
it's possible to split
the numbers into two groups okay so two
groups
each group should have at least one
number okay it cannot be
an empty group yeah doesn't make sense
so two groups
and first requirement second requirement
is
the sum of both groups are equal
some of each group some of those groups
and a third requirement says one group
the numbers in one group are strictly
smaller than the other groups
one group one group numbers
strictly smaller strictly smaller than
another okay
so for example i can split this into two
groups four five
and nine four plus five equals nine
another good
yeah the second okay and four and five
are strictly smaller than nine okay so
can we do this with nine and nine
can we do this can we split it into two
groups
no why is that because
no essay and it can be three and nine
and nine
and nine is not quickly well done good
job
okay so so how can we do this so can we
find a way to do this how how can we
do this
very important yes how can we prove
something
how can you prove us how can we prove us
so the blue forcing would be picking the
numbers
of one group right picking the numbers
of one group
so for each number we can try to pick in
one group or not pick one proof right
right so eventually these will be in two
groups a
and b so if we decide the numbers to put
in
a then we also mean that we have numbers
in b
right all right so this number
i can have two choice the next number i
can also have two choice
if there are n numbers how many choice
do i have i have two choice i have two
choice i have two choice so
for n numbers how many choices do i have
n times two to the power of n
right because two times two times two
right yes
so this is the number of ways to spin
the groups
and then we also need to find out if
there's some equal it takes
n times right it takes n times to
to find out the sum right
of course we can we can have uh we can
calculate the total sum right
yeah total sum and then if we find out
the sum
of one group we can use the math to
calculate the sum of
the other group right does it make sense
by the way these numbers
are all you are positive okay it does
not contain the
negative numbers doesn't make sense okay
uh so this approach is a bit slow yeah
because the overall term complexities is
this right
this is exponential yeah it's very very
slow yeah
yeah i'm right yeah okay so can we
can we do better we
so i give you a hint how about we sort
the numbers
we make it the numbers from the smaller
to the biggest
so in this case 459 495
we saw the number four five nine
okay all right you guys like that
this is not then yes
while this is working because it's small
from we saw the number from smallest to
biggest
yeah so because the the eventually the
sum
has to be divided into two same right
so if i pick if i i continue
picking the smallest number smallest
number eventually you will be the same
it will be a cases that you'll be the
um you'll be you'll be
either half or more than half right
yeah okay so let's
think about other examples like um
so look is that four look
first of all we need to calculate the
sum of all this which is
18 right this is can be done using o n
time right
yeah yeah then look then
i have a running sum so four is it times
two equals
if if it equals half would be nine right
yeah you say half to nine now i add the
five you see how nine yes
right when it's yes it means that i have
uh
i i found a half but i also need to
compare like if this number is
strictly smaller than the next number
right right yeah
if it's smaller then yes we found the
group if not
it's not let's say if not uh
okay so let's do this
like nine and nine okay so
right look for here nine is half of it
take eighteen
and it's not strictly smaller than the
next one and it's not right
yes doesn't make sense
okay so um so how
i mean any other possibilities that this
echo may not work
i mean can you think of any example like
it may break
foreign
oh yeah no no i mean is it that will
still work i mean we just need to return
it
so for example like uh let's try another
example okay so
you pick one example like 2 4
10 okay
yeah so can you
after adding these numbers what's the
sum
25 right you can't do it you can't
first time i calculate the sum of all
numbers which is 25
so i know it's impossible yeah why is
that because 25 cannot be divided into
two
okay that's what it says yeah okay so
now if i put
11 here okay so now
that will be 26 yeah 36 and then i'm
looking for 13 right
13. yeah
number n2 okay wait wait wait
no so that's what uh
six plus four 26 26 is 13 right
13. so
okay so so that agreement woke or not
look two plus four
two two plus four six six plus
nine fifteen fifteen
fifteen so i can't see
so it's not but why you saying this is
okay because look
two and eleven four and nine
this group and this group the numbers
here
are not strictly smaller than this one
because 11 is bigger than that
right doesn't make sense that's why
that's why we need to solve the numbers
because we want to make sure the numbers
in one group
as 60 smaller than the other group does
it make sense that's why we started
even though you can find two plus eleven
equals four five but
still it's not possible to split into
according to the third
requirement which is the numbers in one
group are strictly smaller than the
other one
so this may not work all right so so the
excellent we pick is
right here because look two four which
is six
six plus nine fifteen is bigger than 13
then we know it's not possible to find
such thing yeah that's why we need to
start it
does it make sense yeah okay any
questions
no no okay let's do this
define set split
okay now look let's say sum
equals sum we how can we find the sum of
the all the numbers in in
in numbers can you write a for loop
like look s equals zero and then one for
i in num right look
what should happen here if i want to add
all numbers of i
but all the numbers in the numbers
yeah i want to sum all the numbers in
numbers how can i do this i'm putting in
s
so what should i do
[Music]
i want the sum or add all the numbers
and put it as
s1 what s
what should i do with s and i come on
little quiz
come on it's easy come on add
one add pie come on this is simple yeah
but
i know that yeah but you don't need to
write this right because this is getting
all the numbers sum to
s we can just do this function sum
yeah yeah that's it the same thing
you see the same thing huh okay now
if s is odd number how can we write it
if it's one one and i know it's not
possible yeah we can first
okay model two can also be like written
as
s and one yeah it's the same thing yeah
remember this bit
binary yeah if you end one if the last
bit is one is
e autumn if it's zero is even number
yeah
so this and this are equivalent the same
doesn't make sense
model two is the same as at n1 okay now
i have a continuous sum c equals zero
and then look for
i in range
length num okay i want to iterate the
numbers the index
okay then look c i need to
end equals i right yes
if c
times two right c at c equals
y equals which number
[Music]
right because if 82 equals sum it means
we find the half right
and also also num
i needs to be current number needs to
strictly
smaller than which number
more okay ten columns ten two right
we don't
okay if c times two bigger than
s it means that we are crossing the half
right we're crossing the half
no we turn forward again no after this
yeah return force again because we can't
find it yeah
yeah see i doubt you okay yeah what's
the
time complexity
[Music]
here i forgot that we need to sort the
number there are numbers
yeah remember yeah and this is all wow
this is all oh and logan
a few days ago and he
which one which one is bigger um
okay oh and again come on
can be bigger than one so n times
something bigger than one is
definitely bigger than n right all right
logan look
look 100 log two base
two equals one equals one right log two
base two
equals one that's four you have two four
equals one
two times what two to the power of one
equals four
two two yes okay log two
sixteen equals one two to the power of 4
equals 16.
uh 8. 2 to the power
4 yes come on so you do you get it so
this n
this will be bigger than zero because
log n is like that
is this yeah
why is n and this is n
so when n n is one it will be zero when
n
is two there will be one so you'll be
like that right
doesn't make sense yeah so this is
negative you don't need to worry about
that
so n look log n this is 1 this is 1
because log 2 1 is 0 yeah because 2 to
the power of 0 is 1 right
look yeah 2 2 to the power 1 is 0
so n when when n
when n is 1
x coordinate is 1 then y will be 0 right
this is y
right does it make sense yes look
another thing okay
log log
2 to the power of a
times a times b
times b equals log
to a plus log to b
let's try if it's all right okay look
log two let's say uh
two times two times
uh maybe
maybe four okay let's see if it's what
log2
hey this is three yeah all right all
right
two to the power of three equals eight
right at least if
if this will be log two two
plus log two four right two to the power
of two is
two to the power 1 is this is 1 right
this is 2 right 1 plus 2 equals 3 okay
does it make sense
log 2 ap so basically is log
x a b equals log
x a plus log x b and another formula
yeah
look only times you you can plus right
so when you divide
like when a divides b right
and then this will be minus right
because a times b
equals 80 divide look
a times b actually is the same as a
divided by
right a quarter over b yeah i'm right
does it make sense it's the same thing
yeah
it's the same thing this is the same as
this right
all right look 2 times 3 equals
2 times 2 divided by
1 over 3 yeah 2 times 3 equals 6
equals is the same as 2 how 2 divided by
a
3. yeah i'm right it makes sense okay
another thing
and nothing okay a little bit more okay
log 2 2 to the power of 3 here
equals 1. hey
just equals you can put these in the
front that would be three times
log two two that would be three yeah
let's try
log two to the power of four to the
power of two
okay so you can please here four
and that would be two so that would be
four yes does it make sense
because log two to the power of 16
is four yeah it's the same thing yeah
does it make sense yes okay so
so okay so a little bit far away okay so
this is
o log a o log n right o n log n this is
o
n so this is this is this is bigger so
we pick this one
this one is the most dominating most
time consuming part of the aggregate
right
but this one is triggered compared to
this one so the overall time context is
o
and log n what's the space complexity
with space complexity
[Music]
uh
okay what's here something with two
what's the math here okay the last one
what's here why are we checking here
what are we checking if we if we need to
find
the half right so how do we check it
there
see what
c times one how many c were equals two
yeah yeah yeah c
e a two uh times two equals one
equals equals
yeah or c plus plus e or c plus c
you can also see plus c equals s right
it's the same thing yeah or c equal
equal s
divided by two yeah it's the same thing
yeah yeah
the thing is that we want to check if c
is
half of s if it is half of s
it means that we find half of it right
and we also need to check if the current
number is next is strictly smaller than
the next number
if it is that it means we find the two
groups which
one group is a strictly smaller another
group that will determine true
yeah in all other cases we return first
and can we actually remove this
what if anymore this bit does this
accuracy still work
maybe it does maybe yes or no come on
yes or no
maybe or maybe not what are we checking
here we want to do ten fourths right
if we're not returning force it will be
returning false here right
so it will still work but why are we
adding this
to make it faster right because as long
as we find
we can't find such half we can just
return first right because it's no point
to continue searching the heart another
half of the array am i right
does it make sense yeah are you sure
yeah
okay tell me why we need to at least
okay so it is a 9.2
uh check the other half of it why why is
that when when
when is that true uh when
okay so uh understand what why
when c what when c is
and two c makes
f yeah when c is more than half it means
we don't need to continue right because
they are all positive numbers
that if we continue we will be more than
half right
so there's no point to continue so we we
are returning
early return and early access so that
makes it faster right
does it make sense okay okay let's see
okay that's it
thank you thank you very much as i say