mathematical problem
which is called a complete task so
you're given a list of cash
you're given a list of tasks in numbers
which means the efforts you need the
hours yeah you need the complaints of
that
okay listen up yeah so for example like
the time
you say okay the numbers meaning that
hours you need to complete yeah
work out all the assets first yeah this
effort for example like three
five four nine okay for example
there are four tasks yeah and then there
are people
okay like me people okay so people
have to equal right
yeah can you listen up please the people
the people
yeah good question it's a list of the
tasks
so these are the uh candidate tasks that
we need to complete
we may or may not complete okay so the
people
like uh a given list of people right
and each people has these the
strengths yeah strength so like yeah
yeah like three four
six one like strange that's a baby and
it's people
yeah yeah exactly and that's that's ryan
that's
eric i got you let's tell you okay okay
so each people
can only be one
each people can only complete one task
at most
right when you complete we only pick a
task in complete yeah
all right he cannot he could for example
if the six can complete
the task of three five but cannot
compete with nine after six is the
strength yeah
can this is the strength needed to
complete the task right
can you do that one six and four yes
because yes
but one can't do anything that's right
yeah so that i can
how about if it's the same it's the same
yes yes four can
it just has to be bigger or equal yeah
okay
okay so the problem is uh
how many tasks maximum can be completed
okay which one can be
so for example like three i think
each people can only complete one okay
look look look so in this case
let's say three can be complete with
three yeah
okay so i i put it yeah
and four can be completed by
four yeah and five can be compared to
six yeah that's it yeah
all right but the thing is that for
example like uh
uh look if
if you look look if you please
look if you uh the three tasks if you
use the six
right yeah look six can complete with
tasks and then five five
like you you can't find anything that
can compete with five right and you can
completely fall
right all right so it doesn't make sense
so we want to find the maxima in this
case only three
let's see but if we if we let that six
hundred the class three then we can't
find any
people to kinda to start flying right
because see
six is used all right doesn't make sense
okay so how can we do this what's your
strategy what's your strategy
what's your strategy
so if a task can be completed if either
task
com company say let's see let's say if
class 3 can be completed by
people three and four which one you
think
should pick the task three or four
if even the class requires the strength
three
and we've got people three and four the
strength with three and four
and and two three four five so which one
you think
we should let the people say
so it's uh only the target three
yeah so we have a task three and we have
a few people four people who can
uh these three people can handle this
but number two right
yeah so which one you think we should
pick to to let the
people we can you we can we can assign
the task
to three or assign the task 24 outside
half to 5. so which one you think is the
better
it's better strategy because the
very task is three
i didn't know it i think it doesn't
really matter
okay okay that's a good question let's
go a point that it doesn't matter in
this case but i'm saying that
there may be a lot of other tasks and
then lots of other people
okay maybe lots of other tasks like look
three
and then maybe i have uh
four uh i have uh wait wait wait yep
wait wait i have a 10 here and i have uh
ten and i have uh
not eight seven eight okay eight eight
and then i have uh
seven okay
yeah so look three if i i can add a
three and eight
so it's better to let the lowest
people who is qualified for the job
right if i never ate
what happened if i then a to under three
what happened we don't have we can't
handle seven
we can't find the seven so so the thing
is that if a task is three
if your task is requires effort strength
a we we want to find the smallest
people the people with the smallest
strength that is
qualified to handle a right doesn't make
sense so coming back to the question
three and then three four
five so three is to qualify because it's
the lowest
smallest number bigger than or equal
than three right
all right so it's always the optimal
strategy liquidity strategy because that
if we let the four because we know the
three can handle this
and it's the lowest one right if we land
the three hundred then we can have four
let the four hundred some job bigger
than three right but if
that if we have four here right
look if we let the four hundred number
three
what happened three can handle the
number four
exactly right okay so so this is the
strategy so in order to do this what we
need to do
what do we need to do what do we need to
do
what do we need what do we need to do we
need to
find complete us so
look complete task okay and then
i have a task task
and i have a people right all right
okay
so the numbers are not in order so what
should we do
what should we do we should what
what's with that you shall throw them
[Music]
i told you many times for the sorting
it's especially
uh special complexity every time we
log and lock it in
again okay
the size of these two does not need to
be equal okay
let's say the the the task the
this is n n task and m keeper okay so
the time complexity for this task
is o and log n and
people is o m log m right right
so you can choose the maximum or you
place it together because we know she
always likes it
come on listen listen come on
it's already salted but yeah good
question but
if it's already sauteed now we don't
need to sort it okay but i'm assuming we
we
we need to sort it okay okay okay good
question now
now look let's say the answer answer is
the number of jobs
we can complete the maximum yeah at the
beginning so now
let's have a two pointer i equals z
equals zero okay right
maybe let's do it look task equals
people
equals zero this is the point pointing
to the beginning
coming into the beginning which is the
one smallest right
smallest task the smallest people the
index right
okay the length let's just store it why
t smaller than lens task right
because we haven't run out of tasks
right
and we haven't run out of people right
and p is smaller than lens
[Music]
so what do we do now we need to check if
current people
can handle the job right yes
if people
people what p p bigger or equal
to t right all right
all right yeah look if people can handle
this
t then what should we do we
should one two three four this is task
right you should add one to the thingy
yes look people
let's say two three four okay
let's see look one two three four four
tasks
people two three four yeah then it can't
be four
sorry what look because we already
started okay now
look people are two bigger than
one right yeah so we we can let the two
hundred
one right because 2 is the smallest
number bigger than
or equal to so let's say answer
plus equals 1 right and what happened to
t
and p what should we do the p can handle
t so what should we do after next
it because yeah because when i am
completely stressed i have to move the
next
big task right and people i have uh
these people is is already taken a job
right a task then i have
moved to next people with yeah so what
p plus equals one t plus equals one
right
all right now look okay so
let's see if this is zero okay let's say
if this is here the people with
strength yellow okay no strength at all
okay so what happened
the people cannot handle t so what
should we do now
what should we do now we shall
we shall move right we should try
next people to see if we can find it
right right yeah right
yeah yeah okay so let's s
as p plus equals one right right
in both cases we need to p plus or equal
one right so we can
erase this erase this
and i will put a p plus one here
this makes sense because if then i do
this and do this as
if this is not eq not true then i would
do this right
it's shorter and much better right
it's the same right doesn't make sense
think that one yeah yeah yeah does it
make sense are we
yeah okay so what's the term complexity
of this one
all of this this one just this one if
you're sorted
you don't need to consider this but this
part
n is the number of tasks m is number of
people
o max and and which one is bigger right
doesn't make sense so which which one is
dominating if we need to sort
the arrays first this one yeah
this one so this one is taking the
the most time-consuming part in this one
okay
so this is trivial okay so now
okay so if a answer is
one yeah because people can handle this
task and then what should we do now
sorry k sorry
what time t p what i
what l equals one
yeah not okay
okay so that's it for today so this is
called greedy okay because
we have greedy strategies yeah greedy is
hungry
that's it see you tomorrow bye