up hello hello we stay when we stop
riding higher today
okay so do you still remember what's
ugly longer
yeah not kind
yeah so what
so yeah it's about it's a number that if
it's
prime uh it's um
if it can be expressed as 2 to the power
of a
times 3 to the power of b times five
times
power to the power of c if a bigger or
equal zero
b e bigger or equal to zero c bigger
equals zero so it's a positive
positive
yeah if it's prime factors only two
three five for example like uh
obviously these two two three five is
the prime factor yeah
it's a ugly number the first other
number one it's a special case
does it have to be three no it doesn't
look this is the prime
this is the other number this is also
open number because this two to the
power of one
this is two to the power of zero this is
three to the power of
one 4 is also rb number because 2 to the
power of 2
is 1 prime factors only 2 3 5
5 6 is is it 2 to the power of 6 yes 2
to the power 1 times 3 to the power one
right
seven is seventy no because seven it
cannot be x squared since the factors
two three five right so this is not ugly
number right
eight is it two or no
it can be two express that two to the
power of three so it's a
arcane number right and nine how about
nine is it
remember three
to the power of two so it's argument so
if it's a number it's prime factor only
two
three or five right it doesn't have to
be two three five all together it's
just two three or five then it's
actually number right
this is not right ten is it a aggie
number
uh
it's what two times five it's the
argument
because two to the power of one times
right number how about eleven is it an
early number
um yes i didn't fix that no because
eleven is the point number one which is
not
equivalent these are our prime number
prime vectors that's what i'm saying if
it's a
point number that is bigger than
if it's a prime number like it's bigger
than five it's not a
argument right now
does it make sense if because we are we
are asking the
the plan the prime factors if it's only
containing the 235 yeah
do you still remember how we're testing
it how we check if the
number is number yeah we talked about
this before
it's ugly yeah and right
and smaller than 1 is 4
right all right and then now look eric
y n can be divided by
2 we repeatedly divided by 2 right
yeah and
y and and the right can be divided by 3
we continue dividing by 3 right
wire n can divided by five
we continue to divide it by five and
then we just need to check return
n equals one j equals one
and equals if we can divide it if it's a
number yeah yeah because yeah because we
are these three
means that we are repeatedly removing
the
just you know if it can be if the prime
factors can contains two we just
you know keep dividing it and three and
five as well so
look we can we can write this into a
nice
for loop yeah for i in
two three five right column
wire n can divided by
i and then n keep dividing by i
right yeah so this is shorter yeah you
please for i
remember that three four and then i put
this using the four loop
and then i keep dividing it what's the
time complexity of this one um
oh logar and let's say okay
actually yeah because it could be
two three five so roughly overlook scale
so how about if i give you this function
and i want you to
to generate the nth nth
rdv number okay so this is today's topic
so if n equals 1 you should give me
one the first active number is one yeah
n equals two you should give me
two n equals three used to give me three
i equals four usually give me one
four n equals five usually give me five
n
equals six equals six and then you got
seven you give me one
seven no that's a trap come on seven is
no
ugly number right these are numbers so
what's the next number
eight yeah yeah and does it make sense
yeah
so you give me i want to generate that
as a
number yeah so how can we do this
ugly number other general keep
generating
yeah so so this is the
proposing right so we're checking each
number
yeah and then we check each integer if
it's an argument and then we reduce it
but there's a problem that because
because most numbers
are not ugly numbers right yeah because
there are many many numbers are not
every number so it takes time to
to check even those not ugly numbers
right
right so can we still can we still
write this as a uh as a proof of
like look define ends
ugly yeah ugly number and okay
so suppose we already know that it's
ugly function right
so let's say the first number is i
equals
let's say uh let's say
the first we we start from one right
then
look wire why something
let's just write wire two it means that
why are two what does wire two mean and
it is loop
always always right but we are breaking
look now
look if is ugly
okay we will notice it is ugly
i right if this number is if i
is a rb number then i need to
end n minus equals one i reduce n
right and one n is equals to zero what
hap
what does it mean it means that this i
is the n's argument right yeah
and then i can just return reason why
i just said return what yeah okay so
look
if it's ugly number if i is argument
number
i reduce n by one and then if n is equal
to zero and number i is the
argument number okay then every
iteration if it's ugly and now what
should i do here
then i should do this if it's not ugly
number i should do this
i plus equals one i check next integer
right
all right so look if it's seven if it's
adding number seven
no then you you will not count this part
right you will
keep adding eight is ugly number i
reduce one and check it with n0 right
does it make sense so look if
n is 100 you you need to at least
increment
a hundred times right but there are some
numbers which are not ugly numbers so
so you will keep checking every number
you want to keep checking
every number between one
to you know n at least n
to see if all the numbers inside is a
algorithm right
the best cases is all the numbers are
again
right right all right doesn't make sense
but there are some cases that like 7
is not ugly number so you will not if
you need still need to check if
it's actually seven it's it's not then
you
keep if this is true then
execute this but it's not seven
it will return fourth so you will not go
in there you will go here
right i will equals one and the next
number will be a
right until it breaks the loop return
right
here's the because look look
why why something why true
and then you say twin
hello right so computer
y2 do something right the computer will
keep printing hello hello
infinity right you're not exit right
yeah because this is always condition
always true why to do something you keep
doing doing doing
in your mind endlessly no more than a
million times trinia mean
it won't stop because
no it's it's not a finite number it's
infinity entries because that's why it
happened 2
is always true right so here y 2
and when one is when this loop will
become
or be exit is only the case when
n is going to say zero right
it doesn't make sense yeah okay so now
as you can see this is not very
efficient right because we are skipping
we still need to check most not
aggregate number right
so we can we can generate the
argument using the other approach which
is to
become which is what because
look the aqua numbers only only contains
two
three five these three prime factors yes
all right yeah so how about if we have a
a pool a pool of numbers two three five
and every time there are two numbers and
every time
we we take the smallest right we take
the smallest
look if the first okay i show you
the first one is acting numbers in one
okay and then i have a number to see i
the acting number i have seen this is a
notebook right
no book yeah yeah so look
the first article number is look now
i take i need to repeat the entrance for
the ends num
n's algorithm right i take the one
take the smallest from this floor yeah
one yeah
this is the number i've seen
i i i use this number two times two
times three times five right if they are
not seen here right
so that would be two three five right
and then i've seen i've seen two three
five yeah right
okay so next next time i
i need to take the smallest from this
this one which is what
okay two okay and then like times
times two will be four times three
will be six right times five will be ten
right
these are our big number right because
every time i would turn take an argument
number and
multiply it by two three five it's still
an argument right
yeah and i put it here look like yeah
okay now the second arg number is two
right
and now
that's four six four six ten i i need to
i need to put it here as well four six
ten this is remembering this is pretty
put it back right
25 okay so what's the next what's the
smallest
number so yeah take it out and times two
six yeah yeah but six is here right
so i don't need to do anything i've seen
this before
times three nine right nine is not here
right i put it here right
one times three times five fifteen
right and fifteen okay okay so next one
is four all right
four four times two
it's not appearing eight
four times three twelve
right these are the number i've seen
right 4 times 5
20. right so you get it now i get the
next one is 5.
right all right so keep doing this
these remember the numbers we have seen
the argument numbers we've seen these
are the current number
we haven't multiplied by 235
so we're doing this n times every time
we take it out with the smallest
what does it mean we repeat this n times
then that would be the ends
acting number right okay i'm going to
write this okay
so the uh the notebook thing
notebook thing using we can use the
notebook as the set
right defined and
ugly and okay now i have a
scene equal accept
okay okay so let's say
first number because we have seen one
okay and then the current argument
number
will be uh let's say theta
theta equals one okay
look for
i look do you still remember what
uh if we want to get the smallest number
from a pool
what can we do what kind of data
structure can we use
the minimum the priority queue and heap
remember the hip the smallest here hip
okay so for uh so this is a hip
well we can say this is a hip okay let's
let's write it as a hip
hip and then look we we need to import
the hippie file
my front hip p
import
uh hippie important epi file
hit push yeah and hit pop
okay so this is the two functions we
need to use
to to manipulate the list as a hip right
hippie by
hit p5 is to we can also import
heavy fight hp5 function so i will have
a hip
and i will have at least pp5 ep5
is to turning at least into a hip right
hand thing releasing into here
right and now
i need to repair already
so look we are for
end time in range
because we are going to do this n times
two is n times i and then look
we take a current number current ugly
number the smallest current argument
number from
the pool right so we use the hip
hip pop from the hip right
so now we take this number
and we put it into the scene value we
have seen the
i need to multiply this current in the
in the value but
new equals current
times i so this is the new
argument number but if it's not been
seen before look
if neo
not in sin right if
not in sin then i need to push it to the
scene then i need to add it right this
number i need to remember
no actually i don't need to i just need
to
um hit pop he push
he push one push this hip
and then new and then
and what was uh
probably i can move this here scene dot
add new so i don't need to do it in two
places
here and and then i need to return
return current right okay
does it make sense amazing
uh sorry yes i think so
i don't know what he he pushed he hit
new yeah all right look
the first number the first rp number we
know is one we put it in we've
seen it and we the the poor remember
one one yeah this is the number of
arcane number we have seen yeah
we have seen yeah this is the current
uh hip that the the
this hip is allow us to get the current
smallest
audi number all right eric please don't
do that
and then look would we tell we repeat
this end time eric can you tell me
what's what's this
current he pull up what does it do
um
yeah what does it mean it means that
the current equals heat
sorry so we are taking the
taking the smallest aggie number from
the here
here right
no it's already ugly number because the
first one
i can multiply 2 3 5 and i put it in
here and here and here right look if
it's not seen
two three five and then the next one is
two three five
i take it out and i put it two three
five okay so now you tell me what to do
next
so look at another iteration k-pop right
take away two because of the smallest
and then what multiply by one
so it's four six ten right yeah and i
put it for six ten here right as well
and then the next one is three i take
the three
and i times eight five two
six five that will be what three times
two
six five i already have six yeah yeah
and times five ten three nine
right and then you times it by five
fifteen yeah 15
okay so does it make sense yeah yeah
yes yeah okay
15 okay okay so look
so these will be more efficient why is
that because we're repeating
n terms and this is our one constant
right because we're taking
we're taking an element from the hip
it's one constant right push and pop
usually right yeah and then look sin
this is a one constant yeah that doesn't
make sense
why why this is more efficient because
we are not dealing with any non-ugly
numbers
right how much does it make sense yeah
look the 7 is not here any anyway we
don't need to check if 7 is ugly number
or not
right instead we know all we know that
every number is the factor of 235
so every time we multiply two so if it's
still a negative number right
yeah it's just how many two how many
threes and how many fives combination
right so hip-hop uh it's always one
constraint he pushed may not be
he put when you push something into the
hip
it's actually all locked in right but
this is
but this does not execute
a lot right this is executed
a lot
okay yeah okay
uh any questions any questions
hippie fights to turning into the
turning into
turning in the list into the hip do you
still remember what's hit
do you still remember what's hip he
looked at this
remember hip is actually a tree right
look so
every time all right look this is look
so it's a data structure tree that
i don't know okay i don't know other
notes but the root of a tree
is always guaranteed the minimum or
maximum right
by default is minimum it's called mean
hip
yeah it's a tree mean here right so look
i i know i want to take one element from
the top
right so i know it's it's it's always
the smallest or the biggest right
all right does it make sense
yeah that doesn't make sense yeah this
is the hip maximum
my maneuver okay so uh i'm going to
i'm i'm going to take a look okay
i'm going to erase these i erase
okay so you tell me what to do okay
don't look at my nose okay but i am two
three five oh you like it i guess sorry
no i'm just looking into something okay
i
in
what do you think i guess two
yeah three five
so what do we do there for i we multiply
if
if the number is not in a
we need to push it into the left left
hip push
and i also need to put it into the scene
right
we also need to put it in the scene
yeah how do we do that
thingy
what are we pushing with and then we
want to need and the common
arcade number is new right so we just
need to add this
to remember in the new right yeah
yeah add new yes
new okay okay
[Music]
and new and new with the bracket okay
okay so i
so okay so i i need to correct something
so when we retrieve the
value from the load the the load
is a one but if we want to remove it
it's all locked in
the same thing as a key push it's
usually all locked in right because you
need to
arrange rearrange the the hip
at some point right but why this is
still faster
because because the numbers in the hip
here is usually smaller right
it it it contains the rb number right
it's not it's the argument it does not
contain any non-ugly numbers right
all right yeah okay so that's why this
approach is
much faster than the previous one
because for example if there are
many many prime numbers which are bigger
than five it's not a big number you
still have to check it you still have to
check it right
yeah doesn't make sense okay so can can
you say bye bye see you tomorrow