hey hello hello mr with mr ryan how are
you today
good okay okay so today i will talk
about an interesting problem is called
integer break or split product so
basically given an integer like
seven yeah i'll give one seven so
so we want to split it like seven how
many ways you can split it you can
spread split it you can say one plus one
plus one
plus one plus one plus one plus one plus
one right seven ones yeah two
four six seven so the
the product you multiply all the one
together you give you the one right
okay you can do it as twos two plus two
plus two plus one
and if you multiply all these numbers
together you'll give me
the what uh it'll give me
what what can we get one no no
eight come on yes i know you can do it
in three and three and one
that will give you nine okay so any
other ways
yeah of course look you can do this at
two plus one plus one right
yeah that will give me eight right
yeah or three plus four will give me
12 right yeah yeah so this
is the optimal we want to maximize we
want to maximize the product by
splitting
the breaking the integer right look
any other ways we can do it i don't
think anyone bigger than that
how about three plus two plus two
that's also 12 right yeah
this is also okay yeah and
how about two and five two and five
let's give me ten right
this is another way right right yeah all
right yeah
okay so let's try another example let's
try another example remember
this is optimum right just remember okay
let's try
another example like uh five okay
eleven i'll give you yeah okay
five alright obviously you split into
all
ones it's not optimum because the
quarter is one right so we skip
skip that two plus three will give me
six two plus two plus one now give me
four
what another one what three plus
two give me six eight yes three plus two
plus three is the same
yeah how about four plus one
give me four okay all right
say this and this yeah so
so any idea how we doing this
we're using squeeze where down that's a
good observation yes the three it's
optimum to
split into threes look because look
if i uh five right
if it's five we can split into two and
three which is the optimum right
because three is preferred right and
then the seven we should
split into three and then four right and
three and three until look at this three
and four because
4 so we can split we can give a 3
and here until the remainder is less or
equal than 4 right
that will be give the optimal right can
we try to write this problem
if and look equals one
okay by the way for the integer we are
we're looking at
is the positive okay no yeah not yet
no yeah oh and equals two so what's your
return if n equals one or n equals two
how many ways can you
can you uh one one yeah because there's
one is
you know you can't spell you can just
speak this one right one or two right
two is one one right okay then look
there's another special case equals two
what should we return
one three oh no no three three actually
three
because two is here three three two
two yeah because one and two right yeah
yeah and
one and one yeah oh one more one one but
one
right one and one and one they give me
the product one
which is smaller than two right yeah
it's only ten two yeah the difference
okay so now let's
let's store this answer the maximum
product
beginning one why why
n is bigger than four okay then
we times look
if n is bigger what is it is four
sorry what is it is four what is four
and e or is four okay that's good
question i need four then
look if n is four what can you expect
can we join two and two right will give
me the four right
give me a four yeah all right all right
of course because if you split into
three and one that's not
optimum right so four is about uh
separation
between because we got a separation if
we
put more than four we can times equals
three and then we we take one three out
right
right all right for example four four
look four and let's do look at the five
five equals three and two right right
yes so i take the three now i take i
i have one three and then now n is two
so what should we do
return what answer answer is three times
remains times n right doesn't make sense
all right does that make sense we take
we can take three uh
if if we can't if it's more than more
than four
we take three right and
when when is y loop x6
the n is smaller or equal to 4 right now
we just multiply what we meant
right what's the time complexity
[Music]
look what's this how many iterations
maximum
n oh and yeah because look every time
we're taking three three three so the
loop will be n divided by three but
look at our m divided by three but we
drop the constant right we drop the
constant so it's all n right does it
make sense
okay okay okay that's it that's it
so listen listen up so
okay so
okay good job can you tell me what does
it mean i mean yeah
the ultimate is allocate in three
schools until
the remainder is less or equal than four
right
yes okay no here not yet this is one
part of it we can also solve this
problem by
oh by the way
oh yeah it's something to do yeah
remember
me mobilization dynamic programming yeah
yeah yeah yeah all right eric look
so let's say fn is the maximum product
that we can get by splitting the integer
and right
don't don't come along you're making
people dizzy okay
yeah okay doesn't make sense yeah yeah
okay so
if if n is one or
n equals two then we return we know
return one right
right yeah okay so now the the
thing is how can we split this okay so
is it equals to is it equals to
i'm i don't know because how many ways i
can split into this
uh for example i can
try with one and then f and minus one
right
yeah all right yeah look if i split
one and then i i can do another f and
minus one
or i can oh it could be if i don't speak
don't want to split these i can do this
one and and minus one right
why does it make sense but this one can
be between one
and one to n and minus one right
doesn't make sense because look f5
i want to split this integer five right
so i can
i can make it as one and four right
and two and three right yeah
and three and two four and one right so
this
i can go from one to four and this is
this is n minus i right right
for each one look for each one
i can choose to split it which is f
and minus i right or i decide
not to split it i just use the integer
right does it make sense
so look so f n is the maximum
of y oh let's do this i okay
for i times n minus i yeah
i just say if i have eric if i just
split this integer between
i and minus i right yeah or
i what something
f n minus i yeah if i spread the integer
i but i don't want to split it
i i will keep splitting it right
and where i is between 1
to n minus 1 right does make sense
this is called dynamic transition
function doesn't mean
yeah do you still remember transaction
function
does it make sense so can you explain to
me come on
um
yeah yeah so what i'm just talking about
yes it's friends with the people all
over the world okay
so okay okay so yeah come on
see us today
[Music]
vfn yeah
can be the maximum
of the i and
times the yeah yeah i know so what's
this bit
and what's this bit so look f5
so i want to split integer five right
yeah
so let's say i will be i will be between
one one two three four right
all right slowly it will be two choice
i can split one and then four
right two and three three and
two four and one right this is this bit
i times it together
or i keep splitting these
this will become f4 that will be two and
two or
does it make sense yeah yeah yeah
which one you tell me which one is
complete uh continuing splitting this
function
the sub problem because dynamic
performance yeah because look we have
f okay okay why maybe it's a bit too
late
okay all right okay so look we are given
this function and we determine the
condition and we can implement it
using how many approaches and
how which how many dynamic programmings
are we
talking about remembering uh
two okay what are those top
top down and the other one
okay top down top down and bottom up
okay
so which one is the recursion with me
momentation
yeah top down okay so look let's let's
do it define
okay fm column yeah and then we're going
to we
look if n is one or
n equals to return one
return one we're done okay and now
look at let's let's say this answer
let's a answer equals one okay
look for i in
range range one can you tell me what you
are
when you are the i remember the i how
many ways we can split it
between array i
i will be from what one
one to one uh n
and yeah so actually it's one to n minus
one but you're given the one plus one
yeah the second finger
and then look answer will be equal the
maximum
of of what i
i times n minus i right
or i times f n
minus i right this means we keep
splitting it right
and then yeah yeah yeah
of course what's missing here cash
cash yeah we are down cash cash yeah
because if you're not using the cash
what happened you'll be
exponential yeah we're calculating over
and over again
we want to take it we want to avoid
computing the same thing over and over
again
what's the time complexity
think about it with cash no cash what's
the time connection right
what you doing nothing what are you
doing nothing
come on what's the time domestic what's
the tango recipe
the time complexity is
it's actually o and square because look
it's it's
really all right look because we are
having a four and then here
this is because we're calling that right
what's the space complexity
what how many values of n f n we are
calculating
how many how many maximum items can be
stored in the cache
one why so why are we using the cache
come on how is that aware
all right come on because we are
calculating we need to store the numbers
in the result of f
and values in the cache right yeah and i
know
f1 f2 f3 and therefore so let's the
complexity
the space complexity is always right
come on come on eric ryan
uh why this is this this is o
n but here
we are calculating another right so that
will be o n square right
yeah okay okay come on
dynamic programming which is not usually
implemented using the question of
improvisation okay let's
write this down with the another
approach
[Music]
approach how what kind what's the first
value we need to calculating
what's the difference between top down
and bottom up
down is we remember
meanwhile yeah so i'm saying this top
down because
because we are we want to know the f1
value right
in order to calculate fn value we we
need to explain it f
f n minus one f n minus two right
side etc using this
uh direction into o
f one right this is called top down but
in the bottom up
from the bottom so which is you are
constructing the values from f1 f2 and
then you're going this way this is
called butter up right
yes this makes sense okay so now we step
with the bottle out we usually don't
need to use the recursion we use the
array right to store the values right
yeah yeah
so let's do it define f and
and then look let's have a dp array
right dbra equals at the beginning will
be 1
times m m minus 1 right and pi
okay now look we want to stop we
we want to start from i in
branch let's let's do this one to m plus
one right this is the
first iteration is the fl we are now
calculating
and second second loop
second iteration is to to
to to list the number of different
different ways to split the integer
right all right
so for j in range
okay what's the two values here
how many ways we store uh splitting the
integer
j for j in ranger
you just give me the answer it's the
same what's the answer
one and one what's the second there's no
end no
i'm just saying i i plus one
right now it's i yeah it's not true
because we're splitting one
to i minus one right we are going to
with
i minus one okay so now dp
i right because i'm calculating this
equals this is dpi we're calculating
equals
max of dpi
yeah we are getting we're starting the
maximum and then look
j j times
there's no n i i minus j right
or j times what
p p y i
minus y yeah you see this is quite
similar i'm putting this one right
right yeah all right
does it make sense return which value dp
ppu is valuable minus one
minus one which minus one is which value
is one which value is plus minus one
last one last one and which which is the
last one
yeah yeah okay dpn yeah because this is
n plus n plus one is actually dp
0 to dpn right why does it make sense
so you your last one is ppn is the look
we are
it's the very one looking for the tail
look yeah the term convexity for this
one is quite easy
it's just quite easy to see yeah
stressful yeah what's the time
comparison
what this is and an iteration
and this one is from and squad yeah
what's your space complexity
[Music]
we are using a db array and because
it is look and size yeah doesn't make
sense
look hey look this is quite similar to
the top-down dynamic programming yeah if
you remember eric
yeah yeah look at this one if you choose
to split with j
and i minus three two numbers or if you
choose to split it with j
and continue splitting with i minus j
this integer right
doesn't make sense yeah okay so i know
what last week we
we returned back uh last name look this
is more straightforward
and more simple to implement right yeah
and it does not have a location usually
it's faster because the recursion
is uh contains the functional cost yeah
because of the computer we call a
function and this there's an overhead
but this one is just the array and we're
just iteratingly array just to update
the values so
it's usually faster does it make sense
yeah which one is the fastest
three ways greedy the first one
mathematic greedy split into three
do you still remember the second one top
down and the third one butter out which
ones
greedy yeah i just do still remember the
greedy the complete
the complexion
oh and yeah yeah so which one is faster
oh and
square we're done that's what i want
yeah
i think it's slower than everything
where tongue where the hair is
okay that's it for today so you can say
bye bye see you tomorrow
bye bye bye bye bye