hello hello mr
mr ryan how are you today good okay okay
okay so do you know the uh
excel that's office spreadsheet yeah
question
yeah spread [ __ ] you know your own
computer where you
you put you know we call your parents of
your pokemon
right yeah yeah let's just squish it
yeah
remember okay do you still remember look
it's like that yeah
and then yeah and it's it's like a
a grid yeah and then look this is a and
here
this is one
two three
right four and so on yeah abc yeah yeah
yeah exactly okay
okay okay okay okay look so this
here this there right this layer is
referenced as
b2 and this cell is
references e1 okay so if i put a 1 here
i put a 2 2 here and i can say here
i can say here e i can put this as a
formula equals
b2 plus b3 right
you can put an equal and then reference
the cell you put it here and then you
automatically
update it with three because you tell
the computer that
this cell is equal to the sum of these
two right and then you if you change
this to
four and then you automatically change
updated to six
yeah do you understand yeah that's
pretty okay
this is this is what uh
the topic is based so the columns is
star lemming as
a b c d and e f and i'm just z
yeah and the next one is what
two letters a a a b
[Music]
essential a z and then the next one is b
b a right
yeah so look the c and the next one is a
a so look at this is the column yeah so
how many columns the next one after that
is aaa
uh no no no no no so
a a will be look this is one column one
yeah
column two column three and what's
column z
six twenty six and this is twenty seven
yeah
so okay so today's task is very simple
you give me a
letter and you need to determine which
column is it
okay so the b so your b you should tell
me it's two
z used to tell me is 26. why it's the
second column
this is the 26th column column okay
i voted the 25th a a will be
27 right yeah doesn't make sense
how many letters are in alphabet gen
five
26 letters come on what are they
a b c d until z right see all of them
yeah no i b c d m g a j i can't even i
hope you guys like
[Music]
doesn't make sense
does it make sense yeah definitely okay
so a
you tell me is one b you'll tell me is
two
c the same is three and c
tell me it's 26 a a you take me is 27
a b you tell me is 28 okay
so any idea how we're doing this oh
if it only happens wait
yeah do you still remember the ascii
ascii code
a of capital a is what
uh i guess it's 64.
five come on and ask him
no 97 smaller case is 97
okay okay level okay it's not smooth
okay
okay lowercase okay so let's go in
please thank you i would i will okay
okay so aaron look if it's a letter and
do you
do in in python
if we want to get the ascii code of the
letter we use the function called what
do you remember order order and then the
opposite
is chr chr 65
is what uh
[Music]
the opposite come on hey
okay
okay so now look so how we're doing this
how are we doing this
any idea how we're doing this no i did
you have no idea okay so look so we can
go
switch letters eric yeah we can go
through it it's better a a for example
yeah
right so look this data is
at the beginning is zero times a order a
65 and we might
please no shaking minus 65
plus one okay all right
and then we turn 26 again
that'll be eight times 26 is 26 plus
plus these okay and then
26 will be one right that would be 27.
does that make sense yeah so it will be
similar like
it will be similar as one
all right yeah well
binary do you remember 1010
what's this in in maximum
what's this in decimal i hear music yeah
why isn't the music coming from
mummy mummy phone okay
that's okay look at everything so
we go through each number right
at one zero one zero so let's do this
one
all right look one the the numbers
is one and then i every time i times two
and a plus the next one is zero right so
that will be one
two and two times two
plus one is five
five times two plus zero is ten so this
number is ten
doesn't make sense eric yeah listen
you're not
paying attention oh yes we are
all right look so how do we evaluate a
binary number look
one one one zero how do we evaluate this
uh we uh uh
start from the end yeah how do we
convert this defined into
a technique we can we can read it from
this way look
because the first number is the first
one
is zero and then zero times two plus one
right when we take this number is what
is one now
one times two plus one this is three
right so this two number is three three
times 2 plus 1
is 7 so these three number is 7 7 times
equals 14 plus 0 right so the whole
number is 14.
doesn't make sense so it will be
something like 1 2 3 in decimal 123
right 1 times 10 so at the beginning we
got zero zero times
ten plus one is ten is one right
yeah all right now we got the first
number is one
one times ten plus two twelve right
these two number two l plus ten
times ten plus three is one hundred
twenty three doesn't make sense
so we can evaluate from left to right
but every time we have
existing number we times it multiplied
by the base which is 10 in this case and
plus the current digit
doesn't make sense 123.
so in this case look a a
right where is the music coming from i
think it's from the laptop
where's my pen where's my pen oh
all right
okay convert okay let's say
uh this this is a square sheet okay
let's just do it convert okay and we
have a number
s right so look at the beginning answer
will be zero right because the beginning
yeah
yeah yeah and then look for
i in s right
so now answer me because it's 26 numbers
so it's base 26 right
yeah so look answer equals answer times
what
answer equals the time
can you not break my thing okay please
oh my god
what kind of base it is abc what's the
what's the base
how many letters how many characters uh
26. okay so times 26 right that's
what i'm saying did you get it yeah
plus plus what current number what's
current number
odd i right ask him out i i need to ask
ask it
i need to minus which number which which
number is it
which uh which because it's all capital
right
this capital i need to all out
this a because and then i need to plus
one
right because it starts from one not
yellow that's why we need to plus one
yeah does it make sense
yeah what's the time complexity when
what's
m
the number of characters in the stream
where is the banjo we're not talking
about the bounty street come on we're
talking about the spreadsheet
yes press it yeah does it make sense
everything
yeah quite sorry quite so okay so okay
what one okay okay so okay just tell me
what's
this okay a b c what's this how which
column is this
okay tell me what column is this
a b a is the first column c is the 26th
column
a is the 7 and what's abc
abc is right hmm
[Music]
come on i was just telling you this
agreement
at the beginning is yellow come on you
say you understand
you can do the math here 100
how do you get the 101
you you do it calculate it
no you're just guessing
[Music]
um
how can we do this how can we do this
what's the first number a that's how you
do
it or
731 okay from the computer well how far
we're doing is look i i show you all
right
look look listen listen you're not
listening
answer equals zero at the beginning
answer equals zero okay this is answer
okay
yeah okay now we have first number a
right yeah 0 equals 0
times 26 plus all the a
65 minus 65 65 plus 1 is 1 right
right and then i put a b here
so now answer is one one times 26
plus b minus a is one
one plus one is two so now it's 28 right
yeah now c 28 times
26 plus c minus a
c minus a plus one
is three right okay so this is the
number
28 times 26
a mommy singing
music one sixth and this is
56 7
28 plus six plus three
seven thirty one right yes does it make
sense
does it make sense how do we get this
number that doesn't make sense
okay another another example
another example okay let's do binary
okay just binary
one zero zero one zero
what's this in binary intaxima
thanks uh
[Music]
what's this in taxi man so
it's
what's this
yeah what's this
okay so it's how do you how to calculate
it
how many tools can this need needs to be
multiplied
by two multiplied by two yeah
that's four and that's a that's ten so
it's ten
plus one uh is it ten
one two three four no it's not ten two
nine
two four a sixteen
plus one plus
what's this number environment uh three
three two look you can look one
one times two times two
four times two
times two plus one nine times two
eighteen doesn't make sense yeah yeah
it's the same thing as this
147 in decimal
one okay so this this
we go from left to right zero times ten
plus
one that's what one right
yeah one times ten plus four
that's fourteen all right fourteen times
ten plus seven one hundred forty seven
doesn't make sense
yeah does it make sense this is the most
important takeaway going from the left
to the right
every time i times the base multiplied
by base plus the current
value right am i yeah
that's it i mean there's no magic just
it
okay that's it for today bye