hello hello mr erin mr ryan how are you
today good
good okay so today we talk about prime
numbers so what's prime number can you
tell me
a number that can't be divided into any
one
by seven one and itself yeah that's one
number one
okay so can you give me the one is not a
prime
prime is not pro one is not prime number
can you give me the
smallest prime number okay so we are
talking about positive
nothing negative one is not this two is
the smallest
point number so two in the one table
yeah okay so what what number
are even numbers how many even numbers
there are prime numbers
one what is that two yeah that's a very
special case that's
the only even number that is the prime
number all other even numbers are not
right
remember that okay so do you know do you
still remember how we're checking the
prime numbers
we are for example like 10
result for a number if it's
no it's no prime number you can go in
five or two
as i say it's even number it's not from
l if it's an
even number yeah it isn't to
return yes and other even numbers no
okay okay so given the number n how do
we check it with the
prime number or not
n is any number any number i mean for
example like a
given number a number integer n and how
do we check with the prime number
we can't write that
divide it by 2 and divide by 3 and
divided by
4 divided by 5. okay actually we don't
need to check if we
by the even number because 2 right if
it's even number we just cross out right
right yeah i know we start with three
yeah it's three it can be divided by
three
if no we check the five right we don't
need to check the four right
yeah because it can be divided by four
it can also be divided by two m right
yeah yeah because it's in uh because
we just check if it's uh it can be
divided by two one all right
okay so and how many which number the
maxima we are going to check
like if it's a hundred how uh what
number
i think 97 is the biggest i know i mean
i
what i mean is 100 and then which number
the maxima i need to check if it can be
divided by
i'll give you trillions okay
99 50
10 what do you mean so i need to check
that like
three it can be divided by three five as
i said
two i need to check the two but i don't
need to check if it could be divided by
four right
seven nine eleven you know
up to ten fifty or ninety nine
doesn't make sense yeah
so we should pick one
i don't really know what you mean okay
so for example
100 normally if you want to find out if
it's in
one times table or a hundred times but
it's always true right
then there's nothing between one and a
hundred that can be divided by
a hundred right then it's a prime number
all right
yeah and we need to check into the
number can be divided by
uh a hundred in between the two and
between one and a hundred doesn't make
sense that's the equilibrium to check
right
for example like 97 you're saying 97 is
the largest point number under 100
9 is no prime number i know but but
how do you know 97 because we are trying
2.99
[Music]
yeah but look we suppose we don't know
97 is the point number right
okay then then we need to check any
numbers from two we need to check two
three four five to see if they that's
eight
yeah because to see if ninety seven yeah
yeah i know i know so so the thing is
how many numbers can we
we we need to check given this number is
n
we need
[Music]
okay so you still don't get my point
right do you
i'm saying that this is number 97 so we
need to check
as uh if we don't know right we need to
check the number two
three four five okay six seven eight
nine ten
and year two ninety seven that until
ninety six that's a
one solution right we check every number
between
two and m m right to see
if it can be divided right if it can be
divided it's not a prime number right
doesn't make sense yeah okay so what i'm
asking is
if you remember
that's right yeah so so certainly not
this one right if a hundred
yeah because it's more than half we
don't need to share right it cannot be
divided that's what i'm asking okay okay
so you're saying this
100 certainly not 99 because it's too
much right
50 you say because over half is comfy
divided right
right
yeah that's one good yeah that's the one
solution
but how about i'm telling you is 10
is that 10 is the square root of 100
why is that because look if two number
if you find the number
100 yeah if you find the number two
right
yeah this is this is a
right right it must be
a number which is a 100 divided by 8
which is 50 right
if it is 5 this is a that must be
100 divided by a which is 20. does it
make sense
so you always come with pair if it can
be divided right all right
four okay what's the other pair
oh 25 yes yes you see so
you always come with pair and here 10
right because everything
up to look 10 10 times 10 equals 100
right and then you go to the next which
is 20
20 we know because when we we go to 20
we know already in the five
right yeah does it make sense
yeah two numbers comes together equals
10 and 10 right if you increase one
number the other one needs to be lower
down right
if 10 goes to 20 and the other ten needs
to go to the one
five all right if these ten go to twenty
five
at least ten needs to go say this one is
this one double this one
huh so that's what i'm saying it's
always come in half so
it means we just need to check the
number up to square root of n
right so which one is faster
which one is faster you're saying half i
i'm saying square root so which one is
faster obviously which one
pick one yeah of course 100 this is 50.
this is 10.
i just need to check 10 times you need
to check 50 times
who is the winner daddy yeah okay so i'm
not going to write this
okay me i'm the winner so that's
the the time complexity of checking that
is what
[Music]
i
and small equal than one we know
is what return one false
yeah false
even if n is two return one let's say
it's a special case here
two come on two is the special prime
number you just said remember
yeah if n can be divided by two
return one folks yeah because because
because it's a even numbers right
be divided yeah because we just we just
have this special case for two
and all other even numbers we return
four because
obviously 100 200 104
uh not for numbers and now we just need
to check
i i equals 3 right yes
y i times i
smaller or equal n right because look
why why is this one
look why i times i smaller than equal n
right
i just said two numbers comes in
together ten times ten smaller than
hundred right
all right yeah yeah what do
if n can be divided by
i equals zero return one
represent one fourth yes
okay so now here i plus equal one
one or two
uh now i'm three okay after checking
through
what's the next number to check
five five yeah because we don't want to
check for already we want to skip
even number we already check here right
yeah so i price equals
and return one if we go through this
written one this is return fourth after
the university cases
what will it take what should we do
we should tell you what after the checks
okay look lisa we're looking out for the
factors that can be divided by i yeah
it can be divided by 3 you can divide by
if i can't find anything that can be
divided by n what does it mean
j yeah it's a point number okay
does it make sense this is the agreement
to check if the number
if t equals 2 does it make sense
if n look if n is 2 return 2 if n is
3 come here right
if n is 3 3 times three smaller than two
it won't go in there right return two
even hundred
answer 97 let's say 97
smaller than angular 1 return fourth no
two no even number no
i equal three three times three nine
smaller than ninety seven
yes if 97 can divide it by three
now and then let's check the next number
five
five times five is 197 yes and divided
by
five no and next number seven seven
times seven is more than
97 no the next one is nine times uh
nine times nine smaller than 97 yes
and 97 can be divided by seven no
and next number eleven then eleven times
eleven is bigger than ninety-seven then
we return true we don't come in here
does it make sense yeah okay
how about if i tell you a number okay
look what if i tell you number three and
you need to give me the list of prime
numbers
that are no bigger than three so three
you'll give me a list two and three
right
and ten what are the prime numbers after
ten
[Music]
two three five seven
well done that's it okay so yeah given
these
given this function and we want to know
the prime number we want to collect left
point numbers in the list under that
so what kind of what's your approach
okay
so so what's your problem we just need
to
well how how can we do it
how can we do it
[Music]
so what's your approach it's it's one
step forward yeah
so so basically check all the numbers up
to n right to check
each one in this point number and we'll
push it into the into the
list yeah so you'll be simple like that
look answer
yeah equals empty this yeah then four
i in range
that's okay i'm just doing this star is
two okay
yeah and up to m plus one right because
we want to check
check the n m plus one means the last
number is n right
then we say if is prime
i learn what answer dot
append open y open right
and return what
yeah okay so all you can do in one night
look you can say return
all right return bracket
yeah x x book
four x in range
you can do it in one line range start
with two and plus one
and then to what if it's one
yeah this is a fancy way of writing it
it's the same
uh x i know bad thing look at
the imagine we take that yeah this is
the traditional way though
yeah this is a traditional way of doing
right but we can write it return i want
to return what a bracket
which is the least what kind of this
return x contained as y o t
what's as x is in the range of 2 to n
plus 1.
additional condition is if a square is x
yeah
does it make sense yeah this is called
this comprehension
comprehension in python coming together
all of
these things look at this is always
right
yeah all right this is our loop and
combining with
o square n so the overall complexity is
o and square n right doesn't make sense
all right look iterate anytime and for
each one you need to iterate
square root and right so also again
combined
right because this thing this thing is
inside the loop right this makes sense
if you want to complete these tasks you
need to do this n times for each end
time you need to do this
square row and time so comes together
multiply together is one square
can we do better wait we can
can we do better yes of course okay so
what's your approach
what's your approach you don't any
okay that's fine that's right so we
we're talking about another new problem
which is
more efficient in this case it's called
s-i-e-b-e-c
something but you can just conceive
everything
this is actually
okay so yeah okay let's look so how can
we generate
the the numbers more efficiently right
because for the previously we need to
check each number right
there's no way to skip it right so
you get a
what okay so so you put two in it first
yeah and you check everyone not me
not the other even numbers and not over
half
no and over half i mean they're the
biggie
and not not the other even numbers you
are
a little bit close but not too quiet
okay why okay so i'm telling you look
so look let's say i want to generate all
the numbers under 20 prime numbers
okay all right so we know
we know one is not right we start with
two okay
2 3 4 5 6
7 8 9 10
11 12 13 14
15 16 17 18
19 20. these are the candy bases
of the numbers okay we want to find out
the
the prime numbers we want to generate
all the parameters under 20 right
yeah so we start with 2 2 is the prime
number yeah
yeah of course so we set everything to
two we
we we just assume every number is the
prime number okay
okay for now okay so first so you
you cross out all of the even numbers
except from 10.
we're down let let's whoa how do you
know yeah that's what i'm saying yeah
two
i and i crossed every multiple of two so
which two is
four is not six is enough every two yeah
okay okay now i cross halfway
okay now i move to the next point number
three
and i cross out every possibility of
three multiple three
six nine twelve already crossover
fifteen eighteen
okay that's it and i go to next point
number which is five
and i cross out every multiple of five
now they're all closed ten
okay seven and seven fourteen yeah
and then eleven it's awesome yeah
so these all the rest you see
you see this is more this is efficient
right y needs to work
right because every time i have a prime
number it's multiple it's not a problem
right yeah all right and then remember
if we keep
doing this we the remaining is the prime
is are the prime numbers right
so then you need to go over here
because uh you know yeah
yeah yeah because we don't need to go to
the half right what's the complexity of
this one
is that enough time yeah of course this
complexity is our end right because we
need to go through
we need to possibly cross out numbers
yeah all right
but not less than that yeah yeah okay
let's do this
okay this is far better when we want to
know
we want to know uh list of prime numbers
under range right because we can keep
generating it right does it make sense
do you understand right
yeah it's easier it's fun yeah it's easy
peasy lemon
okay okay that's it that's totally
if i uh let's store it demultiply plan
france okay france let's do n column
yeah
okay now look let's say
uh let's say
the east one let's do this this one
array right equals at the beginning four
zero and one zero and one are not
zero and one are not prime numbers so i
times two right
and plus all others let's say it's all
prime numbers
two times a minus one right so all
together you'll be n plus one numbers
i'm right
yeah zero to m n it will be n plus one
number
now now now what should we do
we should cross all the numbers right we
should start crossing
all the numbers let's say uh let's say
i will be equals to 2 right
yeah all right okay so now let's say
y well
i i times 2
right because if y times two i
times two smaller than n right smaller
or equal than n
right because when you passing me half
there's no point to
check the multiply right yeah as you say
you don't need
y i look if
if it's prime if it's a prime right
if it's a prime if currently it's a
prime number
column yeah then we need to mark
multiple of it so j
will be i plus i right
and then while j is smaller or equal
n and then we mark it as the fourth
right is prime
this prime j will be fourth right
all right and then j
plus equals i all right
all right and if if it's not a prime
number what should we do we just simply
i plus equals one right
all right and after this if each prime
is true
then we know it's a polynomial so we can
do this return
and break it like the syntax
x for x in
range right yeah when you are
n plus one right
if or or you can put stuff with two we
know that
zero one is not right if what is prime
fun bracket x right we want to check i
yeah doesn't make sense look we start
with number two right all right
we start with the number two when i is
less than half right we want to find out
we want to find out if if it's a prime
number
we start with 2 plus 2 which is 4 and we
cross out
every number which is 2 right so 4 six
eight right and here until it's j
is bigger than n right and if it's even
if it's not a prime number it means that
the number has been crossed so
we skip it we start so like next one we
find next part number and
cross our rest doesn't make sense this
thing makes sense okay
so i'm going to erase
embrace this one and erase this one just
two here
are you kidding me yes of course baby i
know you can do it
i can't why is sound okay so j equals
i plus y okay so
we want to cross that yeah of course so
j
smaller than i smaller than n j is four
for example yeah add equal one we want
to add multiple equals
yeah add equal one two two
two which one is two i yeah
okay i know why we are doing this yj
smaller than
equal n what should we do we want to
mark these prime to false right
cross other numbers i think this is
false
yes how do we cross all the numbers
how do we cross numbers we this is the
array it's
planned array it's a way which is two
four two first and we want to
cross out j
in the array to force so which array are
we using
which where is the no this is prime
array come on
yeah it's prime what is grand and how do
you reference the j number
yeah j bracket
yeah you see it's easier to read
but but when you actually write it you
it seems harder right i'm right yeah so
practice
makes perfect even you understand if i
erase it again you
you think about it yeah it doesn't make
sense doesn't make sense
no no no because every time you come and
we start with the next standard with
some
some space before right does it make
sense
yeah yeah uh okay
one more time okay um
[Music]
said raising in front of you i yeah
i plus one
i pronounce what i is two then j we
start with one
we want to cross all the numbers
starting from the next one
two what's the number two come on j
j i is two all right i'm going to cross
all the numbers four
six eight so what's four uh
that's okay does it make sense does it
make sense now
okay what okay is it
do i do you really understand yeah okay
if i say yes okay that's it for today
bye