hello hello mr alex
good okay good okay so today we talked
about an interesting program called
an obstructive buildings so you're given
a list of the
building heights and building heights
like
1 five five
three okay i have a good one
okay that's it so so this is the
building height so you don't
get any commas yeah yeah okay so
what you actually mean is that look at
this disappearing high one
and then five right and then five
and then three and two
okay so so look at
this ocean here ocean yeah the sea
so so when you which building can
see the ocean if you if
the the buildings can see the ocean if
there's no other building which is
taller which is
i mean which is taller or equal so
this one this one this one yeah exactly
yeah because this
this is equal so no at least yeah
obviously
so you need to tell me it's time
obviously zero one two
three four
[Music]
so yeah it's just somewhere so as long
as there's no
taller buildings or equal business
versions yeah always on the right
that's right i mean always this one
yeah you're right yeah the right most
building is always
in a list right so let's still output a
list of the
index yeah any idea how we're doing this
can't see it yeah but how about the
other buildings
if we are not sure what kind of
suggestions refusing
performance how do we perform it how do
we prove once it
we check each building right yeah and we
check if there are buildings on the
right which is taller or equal right
all right and if it's uh taller or
bigger than equal then we will always
give it right
so four i in range bearings yeah
and then for j in range
on the right okay and then if it's
bigger than we skip it okay i can
quickly write this code okay i watch the
thumbnail
if you're like defined okay before
maybe like um
if you are not given any numbers right
and then return
we just determine the entity list right
and do this
right and then and it will be the length
of these
numbers okay
so now look at this that has we have the
answer right we want to return this to
an answer
so let's see for i in
range and right
we're iterating look are we going to
iterate in this index yeah the building
index right
right then we need to find it look
look we we have so any taller let's
let's do this
any taller on the right any tall
on the right on the right on right okay
let's set it to false
alright this is the body what's pulling
true or false
yeah so look for j in
range let's start fighting on the right
which is
i plus one to n right right
yes eric it's not there if
num j
bigger or equal num's i right
so what does it mean here i am i here
and i start from this on the right which
is j to the n i if i check these range
if that building is taller or equal than
that right
what do i do any taller
on the right
[Music]
look this is the keyboard break break
means that i want to
i want to stop the iteration right
i want to stop this iteration so after i
stop iteration this any toilet would be
true
right then i said if not any taller
right any taller right or
on the right okay then i push this in
the answer dot append
open which i put it in the i o z
we want to check if there are any
building on the right which is i plus
one to i
which is bigger than i right all right
yeah yeah return what
um
there's a loop there's another loop or
what n square all right square come on
what's the space complexly
if we're not considering the answer here
come on come on
yeah yeah that's right okay what's the
term convex now what's the space
complexity if we are not considering
this is an additional space because this
is the output we're going to need anyway
so we don't use any other space so
what's the space complexity one
oh one or one one okay we're done can we
do better
maybe we can maybe we can
yes we could definitely okay so look why
look if we use the the thing here is
that
eric the thing when the previous
approach is though because
every time we're checking this building
we need to check if there are
taller buildings on the right right yeah
so this is slow yeah
can we do can we pre-calculate the
pre-calculate the max right does it make
sense
so look i mean if at this point
i know the max right so if the max right
is smaller than the current building
then we know right
we know we can see the option right does
it make sense
so we can do this we can store this next
right array
for each point um on the right right so
look
look at that let's do this defined now
let's let's do a
fine that's something i can just define
it to make sure
yeah if not this is the same yeah return
return empty empty yeah
so n equals what lens num right we want
to know this
right the length and then we do this max
right
next right okay just max r okay
it's the same array which at the
beginning we set it to zero
times n right times n okay
all right so this is this max y is the
same size of the buildings
and for each each animal it means that
what's the maximum height building
what's the maximum building
what's the what's the tallest building
on the right right
doesn't make sense okay now let's do
this look
let's do this current maximum equals
zero let's start from zero okay for
i in one range
we start from the right most n minus one
tl
minus one zero and every time i
decrement one right
yeah so this will go for locally
so i will be from n minus one and minus
minus three until zero right because not
up to minus one
every time i decrement one right this
one's mean way down
look and then now look max are current x
max our i will be equal to current max
yeah
the rightmost building the current mix
look eric
the right monster this is ocean yeah
yeah this is ocean
the rightmost building it's let's see
the right most
building height max right will be zero
right
because you can always see right yeah it
doesn't have any building on the top on
the right
to this year and now we can do this
color max
equals max color max
yeah and then building numbers
nums i right does it make sense
yeah does it make sense look at it so
look
we are scanning the building we're
scanning the building from the right to
the left
yeah so every time we remember because
we're going through the right to the
left we're remembering the max
buildings met taller buildings on the
sofa does it make sense
yeah yeah so with this now we can do
this answer
equals this and then four let's do it
from the left to the right yeah
for i in range range
and yeah we go through this index yeah
look and then
if
can you tell me if current building
height is bigger than what
the white max y yeah
yeah because we already know this array
max drive i right
right let's make sense if current
building is
maximum it's more than the maximum on
the right
then we push this index right right
append i right does it make sense and
return what
answer what's the time complexity
here is a loop and here is another loop
the number previously was
two loops together now i have two
separate loops so what's the term
university
yeah that's right because this is ln and
this is d independent right
two o n you can say it's two to n right
but we drop a constant right does it
make sense so it's on
right what's the space complexity
what's the space complexity
no look we are using this right here oh
n
yeah o n because we are using this not
not
we are not counting this output anyway
so police we need to store the number of
the
the maximum right but can we do better
without storing it do we actually need
to store the max height
on the right all right do we need to
store the next
next right on the i mean on the right i
mean every time we start on
can we just do it on the go like can we
just do it here
yeah yeah because look current max is
the max right that doesn't make sense
look
current max is the maximum we will we
can just use it here
does it make sense yeah
so how can we do this we can do this
look uh in
current max yeah max then uh we don't
need this yeah kind of max
so color max equals zero
right and then look at zebra no we don't
need this yeah
uh we just do this for range for i in
and maybe here answer answer answer
equals left
for i in when we start from like right
look and
if nums
i bigger than color max right
does it make sense when we answer
stop append append
i and then comma max
equals max current max
and what what what's your play here huh
what should i put here column x equals
max current max we are getting we want
to store the maximum of current
which is columns carbon max is the max
building next total building on the
right
so now i'm at this no it will be lamb's
eye right because this is the
current building right does it make
sense this is the same as
if nums i bigger than current max
then i updated column x equals max times
i doesn't make sense
and look because we are going through
the right to the left so every time
we're pushing this book
so for example the rightmost if it's
four that we're pushing the array as
four
three two one it's all it's in a reverse
order right
yeah so what should we do we can answer
what we should we should reverse this
return all of them do it now we can
answer
which is the reverse order how do we
reverse this at least remember
how do we reverse it
[Music]
yeah we can do reverse yeah reverse
answer or
answer remember this special magic
column
column minus one do you remember this
means the reverse copy of the answer
yes magic does it make sense
or you can write it as reverse reverse
reversed answer right
yeah or or something that you can do
this answer
uh i'm not sure but just this all you
can do this two pointer thing to reverse
manually yeah if you want to but but
this is the
clean syntax to reverse it does it make
sense
does it make sense yeah okay
so can we i mean what's the time come
next yes breaks complexity here
oh and here we only have one loop now
right it's one
end right yeah what's the space
complexity
what's the space compressor area are we
using any space here
no so what's the space company
okay so these are the different ways of
doing it and we have
another way of doing it which is called
monotone
monitor decreasing monotone decreasing
step this is a new concept
so what's monotone monotone
turners decreasing decreasing step
what's the stack can you it's a
step
[Music]
stack yeah what's that is the one
first but blocked
it's like a pile of things so you put a
thing in you put a thing
look you're pressing one two three four
right and when you take it out you'll be
four three two one all right
yes so you pick up put a bigger plate on
first but the bigger play you always
take in the last right
you put it one two three four in this
order but when you take it out you'll be
four three two one doesn't make sense
yeah because this is the bottom step
this is the top of the step
so the thing here is the monotonous
decreasing step what's monotonous
monotonous means the thin finger you're
always increasing or you always
decreasing
look please remember eric i told you
this concept
before look y equals x the graph is this
right array array look this same i'm
going to don't draw this is not drawing
lesson come on
this is x this is y this so this graph
is y equals x yeah
is this smaller than us increasing
maybe yes because when x increases y
also increased right yeah awesome
so is this monotonous decreasing
nope why not why increase x
x increasing y decreasing so monotonous
means
you're always increasing or you're
always decreasing right
does it make sense that's what it means
monotone mono terminals
single right all right doesn't make
sense
so monitor the decreasing step is that
every time we making sure the stack
the elements in the stack is always
decreasing so so look
so let's say three five
four two
one okay so what's the answer here maybe
i have a maybe i have at least
four two four one okay so what's the
answer here
what's the answer which building can see
that on the right
this is zero index 41.
sorry so it's four not this one
definitely yeah
not this one right so it's it's this one
yeah you can see this from here
and only this one yeah these two right
so you'll be one
thing oh yeah yeah yeah this one see i
told you
okay four to one yeah you're all right
four to one okay okay
yeah so can we look at can i simulate
this monotonous decreasing stack so i
have a stack
i have a stack okay yeah yeah
so look i'm going through
i'm going through three i put a three
here i put a three in here
all right yeah there's nothing uh
there's nothing
in a stack so i put it put it uh put it
in a stack okay
okay now look for
when i i want to put the four in so i
want before that
i want to make sure all the elements in
the stack
are strictly bigger
if it's smaller i just don't want it
does it make sense
so i only put a four so is three bigger
than four
is three smaller or equal than four
yes what's bigger no i mean three is
smaller than the fourth
so i take it out because i don't want
any
numbers they are smaller or equal than
common number yeah and it's empty and
put the four here
one is four smaller now right
four is bigger right let's try i put one
in so always
this direction it's always decreasing
right two
you take one out yeah because i one
one and not two is not if i put the two
here so it's always decreasing yeah when
you read it from the bottom to the top
it's always decreasing for two and then
one
it's okay yeah because two is bigger
than it right i only take a smaller one
yeah
okay so the answer is four to one
yeah does it make sense
do you get it all right you together
this is why is common
monotonous why is it common can you
explain to me
why this why this is monotonous all
right
all right okay so uh yeah you know
where you
ta-da so what why is this explain to me
why is this what's my mother i think
this is
x and this is y and this graph is y
equals x right
so what's one answer say uh
when x is increasing y is increasing
okay so let's look at this square for y
equals x square
okay y equals x square right look all
right
is this monotonous increasing or
decreasing no why is that
because uh you know where like
what it's like
the it decreases then yeah on the right
or the
on the right half of the graph is
monetary increasing but on the left
right left part is one thing
decreasing yeah when x is bigger y is
smaller along this part when x is bigger
x is y is bigger right all right so this
is not monotonous increasing or
decreasing
so let's stack here eric can can i have
your attention please
can i find your attention please so
the monotony decreasing means that we
want to
maintain a stack that all the stack
elements
right are strictly decreasing right all
right
yeah okay doesn't make sense how are we
doing this we push before we push the
new element into the stack
we pop out we pop out all the elements
that are smaller or equal than the
current stack right
current current element right yeah and
if they are smaller i just pop it out so
that it the remaining element on the
stack
is is what is bigger or smaller than the
current element
if i pop all the elements that are
smaller or equal than the color anyway
and then
the remaining is bigger right yeah okay
okay let's do it let's do this
define f lumps
okay if not
this is the special case when numbers is
empty now with
10 return here okay let's do this stack
equals 20 right look
for index and hide
in innumerable yeah still remember
normally
eric do you still remember this in
numeric function
uh maybe okay look
maybe look at the numerator function
look is
look at this already is 5 3 2 right yeah
so in illuminate i and s will become
what i will become i will be index right
is 0 1
2 h u will become 5 32 that's why
it is look does it make sense
yeah okay okay let's say normally if you
don't
immunize you can enumerate over the
value you can
go through the value which is 531 but i
want to have the index
right yeah i want to have the index
so it's it's a clean way of doing this
so in this way it means i will be 0.2
and h will be the value by 3 2.
so i can have access to the iron h at
the same time otherwise you
you need to write the i for i in now
wrench
in range right that's num right and then
actually will be
nums i doesn't make sense
this is the same thing as what for
i in look array wrench
wrench lens num and then i was
asked what's that i just told you
what's equivalent to this one actually
would be what
equals what the height yeah
what what's that i have an index what's
edge i
noms i come on that's why it is
yeah you iterate with the x right
yeah yeah this is the index this is this
alright i can also be
writing in this way if you prefer this
look away
i equals zero and then i can do this for
for h in num i italy over the
lambs right and every time i do this h
equals my and then i do this i plus
equal one so this is my preferred way of
doing because you are creating this
variable and you're doing
adding new manually and this is okay
this is the most elegant way because i
can iterate over the index and the value
at the same time because they come in
the pair right
yes okay so now
look i always iterate inh before that i
need to check
wire wire stack this and
the there they are elements in the stack
and we are pushing the index right and
what
nums what's the top of the stack
um here is the stack what's the top of
the stack what's this
one yeah and st
minus one this index yeah and the
numbers look
if it's smaller or equal than current
height right
what do we do we want to can we get rid
of it yeah
so if we want to erase the last one how
do we what's the
functional st come on you know
talk yes pop just pop pop is
is talk we know the last element is
a one constant but if at least you want
to remove the first one what's called
power
if you want to remove the first one it's
pop one
yeah and popping the first one is linear
time yeah
this this is slightly different than the
dq double ndq which is
you can push and pop on both sides which
are all one constant okay
so after that look and then the
remaining of the stack
ah what other elements that are bigger
right they are bigger or smaller than
the current element
[Music]
this is to remove the smallest element
before
current height so the remaining is one
[Music]
thing is look i have
four and now i want to five here and i
want to remove this
the remaining thing is what is that
right i know if that six six is not
removed right so the remaining are
bigger than the
current height equation remember yeah
right so now i need to put st dot what
what i want to push this height
yeah we want to push the index and
return let's just return this answer
yeah
uh return st not answer yeah because
they this is the final
remember the final stage in a step which
is which
can be uh simulated using a list right
in python you can use the list to to
simulate the stack because this is the
top of stack yeah you can pop it in your
squishy right does it make sense and
then look
okay so can can you explain to me just
this one can you explain to me what
oscars
so like you know uh say like
uh yeah yeah yeah
[Music]
so you know then you put this bit
okay look at that current stack is that
three
five uh
two uh
one okay and then now let's say i have
an email four h is four
so what happened here what happened here
if i have four coming in
what happened so a four yeah because if
because it's uh the top of the stack is
st minus one right
so that means it's it's as
small as so we pop it out pop it out and
then
and put four in it and then put this one
no no you're not poking
too far in you you keep popping until
the end top of element is bigger than
that right
you're not popping one you keep popping
that's a why why
why there's anime in a step and the top
of the step is smaller than
four right it's smaller than four and i
get rid of it and here is bigger
yeah and here is bigger then i don't pop
it and i put a four in this is probably
for it
so what what happened here is that this
is my
it's the stack will be always decreasing
this is st right
that's t0 as t1 is there so it's all be
decreasing right
that's called the monotone decreasing
step does it make sense yeah
yeah okay what's here what's this part
okay come on
write it
thank you let's let's do it return st
okay what which
which measure is the best and which one
you like why we
what's the term complexity of this one
all right what's the term complexity of
this one
um oh and yes what's a space complexity
are we using any additional space
somewhere
just yeah straight yeah
and which one is the best it's the
optimum
number one before the one before o o n
and o one right we don't need the space
but keeping the maximum all right right
yeah and which one do you like
personally there's no right or wrong
answer which one you like
we want to be called yeah alone before
okay let's