hey hello mr ryan how are you today is
friday today okay so it's a good weekend
yeah
starting off the weekend okay so today
we talk about the graph
remember what's graph erica
[Music]
is one of the graphs three is the one of
the graphs
the linked list can be also one graph
graph
remember graph is the vertex graph
gonna have this vertex right vertex
vertex and the edges right
yeah all right so leave these a graph
a graph we use a g to represent a graph
and it's it contains the two elements
took two sets of animal one is the
vertex v
and it's their edges e okay
so for example you know you know the
value of the tree yeah finally choose
that
uh uh none but
actually are the graphs a simple graph
all right look at it
look there's one two three it's a one
special kind of graph
and look at the edges are they are not
that they're not directions
yeah they are unidirectional yeah
right undirected and directed graph
right
and directly glass
and there is because the edges does not
have the the edge does not have these
directions yeah all right this is the
vertex
okay sometimes you've got the weight for
example you have the weight on it like
that's two that's three that's the
weight yeah
yeah okay so today um
so all right all right listen up listen
okay
so today given the graph in
in uh you know adjacent
j j
how do you spell this one basically
how do you spell adjacent let me check
okay
a t j a c n c a
d j a and j a c
e n c y list
okay adjacent list this is bad you can
have it
so what is inside it
okay and then that's three okay so
this graph how do we represent it in
these
adjacent um
adjacent this look if we have a
direction here
yeah direction yeah means the age i can
have a direction
right right all right so how do we store
it
we store in a list okay a list
a list we can store in a list so the
first one is zero so we have
age zero to one
and that's it right or maybe we have
another one 0 to 3
0 3 so for the first element which is 0
for the first element is 0 so we have
this 0
to 1 and 3 okay so that's the first
element of the
list and for six seconds
which is one one only goes to two right
yeah yeah so it's one and
it's two right this is the second animal
two
and the first is for the third one three
goes to zero only so you put a zero here
on the fourth there's no fourth okay so
that's it that's the adjacent look
they're only zero one two three right
zero one two three
uh oh sorry two two gives nothing go two
doesn't have anything so left
like that and three is zero yeah yeah
so this is the list a list of lists
right
does it make sense the first element of
releasing
gives the edges coming out of the first
element which is zero
so this two one and three so i put a one
and three
look eric so what's these two can you
explain to me what's these two
the first one goes to two right
yeah and the third one third one goes to
zero okay uh no no no so
let's no no okay that's yellow let's one
that's two that's two two doesn't go
anything
so it's empty right and then that's
three
doesn't make sense so adjacent
adjections
adjacent list is a list
right a list of lists a list of the
ages for each each vertex right does it
make sense
so now look if i give you this this
graph okay
uh maybe a simple one if i give you this
one
0 to 1
okay 0 one and one
two two okay i'll give you a list this
list yeah
i want you to reverse it so you just
need to represent
uh using this kind of syntax and then
just reverse the link
how do we do it all you need to do is
check yes
wait what if is like that
that's a good question when you reverse
it it's the same right
yeah because we look you you have two
ways like when you reverse it one pen
still has two right okay so how do we do
this
all you need to do is reverse it yeah
how to university
uh dot dot minus one i think
minus one okay so that may be hard to
i mean i i i see this is uh easy to
understand about how to code right so
look define
let's say reverse reverse we have a
graph which is the adjacent list a list
of lists yeah
a list of these okay can i list these
it's always not very nice okay so now
if the ground is empty we obviously when
we reverse it it will be empty right
right then we just return right
right yeah
okay now we need to create a new graph
right let's say new graph is
ng new graph is ng so what kind of
uh so when we reverse the graph
what happened to the vertex does it
change or not
what change it doesn't change right does
it change
well if there are three three vertex one
two three
when you reverse it how many vertices
are there
what are we doing with the vertex
no i mean the vertex not the edges edges
we swap it
vertex doesn't vertex doesn't change
right that's what i mean yeah
what is what which they will reverse the
graph you only reverse the edges of the
graph you don't reverse the vertex right
so in this case how about let's do uh
let's create
and locate the space for the graph so we
allocate a list
adjacent uh js
list right so now we look
at the beginning got empty right empty
each one is empty now how many of them
we don't care in
range length graph right
how many how many vertex are there
length
lengths graph yeah original block yeah
am i right how many volumes
are and i want to create a copy of it
but the copy the list
the graph is empty right
so what's this so original is
this one one two three
so what's up ladies and g what is ng
store what's our energy store uh
what's ng stop
after this what happened what's this
this is
g this represent is g this is g
okay and what's ng here empty list for
for air length g times so what's
happening
ng is what is the what
can you draw can you say what was ng
what's ng what did i just say
about this ng is the length of
g yes and i'm copying a list for each
one so what what what's
what what
[Music]
if black means what each edge each
vertices does not have any edges
right yeah so what does it mean can you
draw the graph of ng
come on it's very easy come on
it's just the opposite you do the same
about the other deal
no it's not yet i'm just creating this
i'm not yet
wow
[Music]
what are you drawing come on this g
with the edges i'm just copying
allocating
length g times each one does not have
any edges
so what happens so like
yeah you just need to draw
is there any edges come on that's what
i'm saying does it have any edges
no and but but what else can you have
the vertex yeah all right so one okay
put the two here
yeah that's what i mean yeah does it
does it make sense
yeah this is the how we store the mg
but it does not have any links here
because we putting it empty but it has
lens g because the number of vertex does
not change
right does it make sense okay now we
need to go through this
goes through this right just the edges
so now we do this
four
so that's okay
four look u v
in enumerate okay yesterday we'll talk
about this function what does it mean
enumerate graph
what does it mean like you
uh yeah enumerate it right
enumerate so you you will be wrong
v will be two so you you'll be a link
between u to v right
that's what you mean yeah yeah all right
actually no because you
okay so that's a mistake here u u
will be 0 1 2 3
the vertex right the vertex v will be
the list
of edges that u points to right all
right
okay so for example all right so for
example one also point to three
right so for u u the first iteration the
u
will be zero and the v will be one two
and three
will open list of two and three right
yes
yeah okay so now i need to go through
these each edges which is zero two
zero three right right zero two zero
three
and i need to reverse it which becomes
two what
two zero and one
come on okay so this is okay let's do
this zero okay
zero two zero three and then when i
reverse it it will be one
and then v is the number of edges it
points to right
so when i reverse it it means that u is
pointing to two
u is pointing to three there are two
edges but now i want to reverse it so
you'll be two
zero and two is yellow right so i need
to go through each
edges which is one four okay
v yes u is the from
the zero v is two and three of course v
yeah
right and then now what we have these
edges
we want to add edges to the new graph
which is
v1 which is what k
which is what k and what is the edge the
reverse edge will be k1
k vertex k
u of v come on uh u
yeah okay now we do this ng okay
don't worry u don't you ng is at least
so what matter are we going to a ng
which measure the opposite of pop what's
the opposite
a pen come on doesn't make sense
what are we doing here which is the
reverse graph
return
what's the term complexity
okay so if they are if they are
v and v vertex and each one has
e edges so what's the term complexity
if they are v vertex and each one has
has a varies if they are el
edges
uh v v vertex
and each one has e edges i'm just saying
each one has e says v
and what yeah the total number of edges
will be v and e right so
the terms and velocities of o v e right
what's the space complexity
um
there's no n i mean
yeah over here we are retaining this
yeah written in this copy yeah
all right all right okay so can you tell
me which part is that to reverse it
reverse the graph how are we doing with
why this is reversing it
yeah something what does this mean
what's this mean
k in v what's v vertex
yes with the vertex which vertex
so look what's this what umd what's this
mean
u is this and v
is this yeah u is that
each vertex we are checking and the v
will be the the edges it points to right
yeah like two and three and then we go
into this two and three and what we do
is that we add
at the two and three pointing back to
the u
right right does it make sense
okay doesn't make sense yes does it does
make sense for you harry
yes yes okay uh
i think that would be it for today yeah
okay that will be it for today let me
let me remove one of these okay
yeah okay can you write this just grab
it in front of you
okay
so what are we doing there
you need to understand what it means not
remember it okay you need to understand
first
okay you need to understand first i need
to buy more pants
this one is good yeah
okay a pen i want a pen yeah
[Music]
which is the start of the reverse edges
so because look we want to we know the
current energy
is what is u
to k right what's the reverse
kt okay to you so what okay to you how
do you
put it in the graph how do you put it in
a graph
if it's what if it's k to you
right a pen g
yeah what a panel you put a pen yo first
come on open yours
yeah you told me so so heavy you just
so what what graph is are we modifying
what graph
what graph are we retaining what we
modify
which advertise okay
yeah you just said k to u right because
now it's u to k
all right okay and g
remember ng is the list a list of a list
each list is the number of the number of
vertex that current vertex points to
right so nguy
yeah how do you pull the ngk come on
what's good bracket yeah break it put
it there yeah this bracket
you're missing one thing column no
column dot
this is the list we need this method
you're calling the method
dot yeah not a pen you're not putting it
together
doesn't make sense now okay say bye