hello hello eric hi
how are you today good okay so today we
talk about the sum
the maximum sum maximum sum
of a binary tree finally maximum sum of
binary subtree okay
sub three max subtree sum okay so
actually it's okay
okay uh a bit special is that
you're given the binary tree one two
three and then let's say that it can
contain negative number
so let's see what's the how many
subtrees
are there you know the substring
subtree so you can pick any rule and
including all its descendants
right look how many routes are in the
balance sheet
one which is here doesn't have any
parents right and how many leaves here
two two doesn't have any kids yeah
all right so how many subtrees are there
unique substrate
come on sub trees pick how many nodes
you can
yeah pick can pick based off
no no no therefore four notes yeah
when you pick a note it's a subtree all
right you pick
ten minus ten it's a subtree three it's
a sub tree three and ten
minus 10 1 sub 3. d4
2 is the subject so four i just said
four how many kinds of subtrees
how many different four because you pick
each note
you pick each note as a root then it
becomes a unique subtree right does it
make sense
yeah okay so that subtree of minus 10 is
minus 10 right right
the subtree of 3 is what
look at here sub 3 of 3 the sum of the
sub 3
3. set minus seven the sub three
the sum of sub three two two the sub
three
sum of sub three one minus four
well you click yeah minus four yes and
the subtree of
empty thing right zero okay so now
we want to find out the maximum sum
of the sub tree in the binary string
okay so let's work it
yeah so how many ways uh can we
traversing the tree final tree or three
two what are those
professors deficient processes
normally but definitely actually you can
have the preorder
in order post order you know rivers
in reverse the order yeah reverse in
order yeah something like that right
okay we'll talk about the different
search so what's different search
go indeed actually you can right go into
this okay
okay so now recursively with the sum
the sum of any sub tree is
equal to the sum of the current node
plus
the sum of this left tree and the sum of
its right chain
all right yeah this is recursively pro
that definition you know the binary is
because of it
definition it's equals to there's a root
note and it's
left three and the right three and we
know
that the sum of the sub 3 of the list
this one right
look the sum of sub 3 this one is equals
to 1
plus the subtree of this it's left 3 and
the plus 3 of its right three right
i'm right so in this case we are
recursively dividing the problem into a
smaller problem right because we're
going to calculate the substrate of this
entire tree
but we know this one the answer is one
plus
the left bit and the right bit at least
it's a recursion right
all right because that now we only kept
interested in two parts two and then
for example the right three is three
plus
minus ten recursively okay so when we're
doing release
we know we can keep the maximum of any
subtree right
the sum of the unknown substrate when we
do english d recursion
doesn't make sense yeah um
define let's do this called the max
sum okay and then we go root
good oh yeah and then we need to have a
answer here okay at the beginning we set
it to the
negative infinity which is minus what do
you still remember
how to call it yeah max master what
infinity mess.inf
yeah okay now look define we define a
different search function inside this
function
root and when
if not root when the root is empty we
return zero right
yeah am i right doesn't make sense
because the empty note is zero right
it's a zero okay now because look inside
this function we want to
reference we want to update this answer
right very good
we want to empty these answers so we
which keyword are we using
which key are we using answer what do we
need to put in front of it
which keyword in order to reference this
even your
if you're not putting this keyword then
you if you say answer
and the compiled computer will say okay
this answer is here
what's kiwa which cure remember
[Music]
okay now we got the value x equal this
is the sum
of the current sub tree equals to root
of value right
plus one i just told you plus one
this is the integer value plus one we're
going to recursively call what what's
your input
what's your approval what's the
retention function load of value and
then the left pin and the right bit yeah
and
what's left what do i do
here is through the left and here is to
the right so what was the upper left
the sum of the current subtree is equal
to its value
plus what the left bit and plus the
right so what do i put here come on
come on understand it come on which one
come on which function calling
wait root sorry
what
the sum of that tree the sum of right
three plus itself is the sum of the
current 1.3 right
but now i got this and then i need to
update it so answer
equals max max what all right can you
tell me
maxwell answering was metro left right
left come on answer equals one we're
going to keep the maximum
on the sum what what are we doing here
and so i know which value
loot is not a value root is the node so
what
what values yes x is the sum okay and
then we turn what
we know what answer
[Music]
the biggest one is here okay the biggest
one is here we just
i'm operating but we are not returning
this one we're returning what
the max this function returns the sum
of the current subtree and which one is
the sum of the current structure
which one is the sum yeah return x yeah
we are choosing
just using x to obtain a maximum subtree
maximum sum of subtree okay and then we
can call this dfs
load yeah and then
does it make sense now what's the time
complexity
our first time capacity
that n is the number of nodes in the
financial what's the time capacity
okay specs complexity is also when all
right
why is it going because we say
no actually it's all h right oh h h is
the height of the
no no no no it's not always it's one yes
it's
because we need to visit every node in
the in a parallel tree right
we need to reach any node every node in
the priority
so it doesn't matter if it's you know
the tree is highly balanced or not right
does it make sense
okay
[Music]
answer it come on come on
write it understand it not remembering
well and you need to tell me what why
you put
that thing there right what
x equals one right well then
loose yeah you don't need to write it so
hard just quickly
faster faster
yeah v
value value it's value plus so can you
explain to me
what's learned x equals what what does
it mean x
equals hmm all right
okay can you explain to everybody
so what's x the x is
equals to read the value
and the dfs of root.right and root
and the left and right so what's x
what's x in this function the sum of the
current subtree right and then we need
to keep
updating the maximum maximum sum of
the x right yeah does it make sense yes
yeah okay
any questions
right why why this is working because
look every time
the loot when you're calling according
and you when you're reaching the
loot when it reaches the leaf it will
return
zero right within this yellow
and then according back according back
then it will be
the sub tree the root of very easy so
that's gonna repent
okay so actually because i just said the
empty subtree
has some zero so actually you need to uh
if if answer is smaller than zero it
needs to return zero so you'll be
actually it's max yeah that's why i said
answer zero okay so that's a small
mistake okay but then
the whole thing eric look one
two three okay let's let's see this okay
just this easy all right look you're
passing the rule right
and then you're going down because it's
calling you say it's calling that yeah
yeah look look look loo the left right
so
when x x would be equal to three
equals to four and equals to
two plus three plus four equals two so
so when you're calling this recursion
you're calling this way right all right
but when you're reaching the leaf you
are
caught you are returning the result in
the reverse order
that's why this works right because your
technique is
x in in the reverse order due to
recursion right
the stack yeah the stack yeah first in
nasa
you're calling look when you're calling
the root and you're going deep
deep and here you go into the leaf and
when you go into the leaves you return
zero and you
roll it back back up so you'll be three
four
and then you'll be nine and then you go
back to
ten right doesn't make sense okay
okay that's it for today