hello
hello eric hello ryan hello okay so
remember a few days ago we talked about
the trees
and breakfast search right boundary
what does it mean
anyway what does this word mean
press finger guess
orion do you want to take a guess breath
as opposed to death
do you know what this mean
beep deep yeah so look
if this is a tree remember
eric look at daddy please
this that's the root yeah
all right look ryan
if this is a tree the depth is this this
dimension yeah
this is the depth right the breast is
this dimension
horizontally so it's broad horizontal
breath so look if this is the tree like
this is a
b c b e
f g h i okay
so breakfast search bfs will give the
order
a b c
d e f g h i okay
do you get it so you will travel level
by level
that first search dfs definitely search
it goes this way can you take a guess a
b d h i
e c f j so basically i want to go
okay g i want to go as deep as i can
if i can't go deep here then i go to the
right
yeah and like go go back go back and
visit the e
and then go back go back c and f g
okay yeah that's d f s so what is
how does that have so look that's an
interesting problem today
yeah that's an interesting problem let's
say
let's at least like two
zero three one
five two
three okay three and four
let's see so let's at least if i give
you a starting position
like uh here
yeah this is your starting point suppose
eric
and ryan you're here eric ryan
yeah you're here yeah so now you're at
this phone yeah
yeah one means that this point you can
jump
forward one or jump backwards one
right
that's okay zero is the destination
target destination yeah
so yeah everyone you're here and you can
go this way or go this way one step
right
if you go this way if you're here
then you can choose go three step more
but there's no more so you can't go that
way but you can jump backwards with that
one two three and then you
reach the destination oh yeah but if you
if you
here if you go to here then you can jump
straight
forward one two three yeah and then you
can do
one two three four or you can do three
four three more
you can do three yeah because you are at
three then you can jump forward or
backwards right
yeah okay so this is an interesting
problem so given
given a list at least this is the list
so we call it uh
then okay let's just call it n this is
the list and then
you have starting point position as s
okay and then you want to find out
you want to find out if you can if you
can reach the zero
by this way yeah
it's interesting this is an interesting
one okay so how do we do this
we use the preference search so this is
the breakfast search
remember remember so we have a queue
yeah can you remind me what is the queue
every line what is the queue
first in and
out first thing first first interest
left so we use the bracket this is the
key right
here we already here so these we are
currently at this position
this position is zero one two three all
right
we are currently at three index three
okay eric can you focus please
[Music]
okay ryan yeah we are three so we push
you into the queue
right three here so now
if we take a three here then can you
tell me how many next position can we
have
we take the three up and what's the next
position could be
yeah and then this one yeah so it could
be
these would be four and five right okay
right now
right yeah because we could choose this
way and this way right
one yeah right so now we take the
beginning which is four
what's the four which is which is uh
four for the next position will be
if i'm here what's the next position it
could be it can't be over
the boundary so it can be only this way
yeah yeah
so that will be zero a block would be
one
and then then and
two three yes two one
and then two two is here so we can have
uh
one two three that's five
[Music]
one two three not one
sorry which one four it isn't one
83 it can't go this way right so it
could be
let's we are here on another three step
one two three so that's zero one
that's the one i mean one index one this
is in that one
and then i take a two what's the next
zero one two it could be
three two two two more uh three more
that would be five
and then three less will be nothing
right so i put it one
five okay and then one yeah
look one we are attacking so we do them
two
right still get it
okay at the beginning now one
look we have a kill every time we take
the beginning of the queue
and push its next step either
forward or backward into the queue
right until we one of the items in the
queue
or we reach we find the one
which is zero that's our target y
zero one plus two which one
y zero one you want to download one
index that's the index zero
1 that's the index that's the current
position
okay this is the let's say index
and n n 1
n 1 will be 0 okay we are looking for
the destination zero
so we i let me write it down then you
can have a look
and i will have a few blanks for you to
guess
what okay that's so first of all that
yeah definitely b
f s we've taken a number
and a list of numbers at least the
number and the starting position
what's what am i missing here that's a
good job
so now we have a keo
which is bracket empty
right if
first of all we check if and if land if
the given
length is empty then we return
we just return false right we just we
say it's not possible
return first it's not possible okay
otherwise
otherwise we we put
actually actually we can move this layer
i already written down that that's okay
that's okay you can keep it that's okay
q equals the first step is
the first first of all we pull us s into
the q right we'll put s
into the q so this is there's only one
item in the queue
so now
now we we need to say y
length the q is not empty
right this means that the q is not empty
there's still elements in the queue
we take the first element so the current
step will be
uh let's say now let's put it now
equals dot pop zero
right remember we use the top zero to
pop the first element in the
remember this remember if i
let the q is one two and then look if
it's one two and q
dot pop 0 we'll take this away
and then now we'll become one okay let's
go pop zero
sorry i haven't seen the one now that's
the variable you can call it
any or baby you can call it you know it
doesn't matter
yeah we're gonna call it all right yeah
let's call it okay stands for eric and
ryan
can we yeah so now eric and ryan
is at this position and then what should
we do we should check
if the next position which is do we need
the support
no no no there's no stuff
you know in person every every line has
only one statement you can use the
what's this
semicolon for example you can say a
equals one and semicolon b
equals one it's the same as a equals one
new line b equals one or is also the
same as
a b equals one one okay there's three
different ways of doing it
so here
remember if we are at this position and
we can jump
jump three steps more or get both go
back swing for step
right we are eric ryan is here
and then the next partition will be er
plus
n n
uh so now this is er the er plus
n er right right
and all er minus and er
so there are two positions to go so we
can do this is
4 i
in because it could be plus or equal
right
minus 1 plus one
if it's plus one it means that to go
forward
if minus one is go to backward and the
next position next let's call it next
equals now would be er right
we are everything ryan is at er position
and then the next position will be i
times
because it's plus 1 or minus 1 times
what times n
er right
yeah now let's but again we need to
check the position here
so so i'm keeping writing down that way
okay okay then if
if if what er
if next next bigger than zero
and next
smaller than equals then length
m right because it can't go smaller
equals and smaller than lens
because it can't go beyond the boundary
then we need to push
q dot push q dot append
next okay so there's a slightly tiny
problem here
look look what even away is here right
uh if it's not currently is one if it
all one
right look if ei is here
now we're pushing we're jumping
one step forward right but the next time
you could be jumping backward again
right and then you're jumping forward
backward backward forward
so you see the loop right it means that
so we need to check if
this if that step we already visited
then we don't jump because we have
jumped
before right otherwise you if this
one if ever gets here ryan is here
you're jumping forward
and then you're jumping backward coming
forward jump backwards
forward yeah i know
you never end right so we need to avoid
the situation like that so we have this
uh
scene let's call it scene are you
kidding me
that's why i left a space here i've seen
or we called it visited all members
and we call it as a dictionary right
maybe we call it the set remember we
call it the set
and
so so so what's next so look
here if next we need to we need to
add here right we need to add a add
something here right
okay i'm going to write here okay so if
if seen if next
next in sin
so if not next not in scene okay if next
not in scene
then we do this then we can add this
scene dot
add next so this
will avoid us to repeatedly jumping
backward and forward backward and
forward
okay and then where do we check
if they're already there so look if er
er is right if we are currently at this
position
we added one more here if n
er equals zero
means we already do it right return true
do we have a space here yes yes and then
otherwise after this while loop what do
we do return what
can you tell me what was your return
here false yes because
if if we are writing out of choice
we return first is it clear
this is very interesting problem yeah
ryan do
do you see this this in
the here now this this is right
here below here and then this is
this is below the y at least is
the and the next before because now we
are checking if it's inside the boundary
right
we don't want to check beyond the
country and we also need to check if
if this is the position we never visited
before right
we use the scene right notebook yeah
yeah yeah no book
okay this is the notebook remember we
put down the
put down the petitions we already
visited
here right do you get it
okay so this is called the breakfast
search yeah i'm going to come back to
this topic because this is very
important in the future right this is
one of the most
important equilibrium algorithm yeah
how do you pronounce this aquarium
can you pronounce this
ryan can you pronounce this
means none
of them okay okay smaller
yeah ecuador perfect okay
okay so yeah i'm going to watch you uh
put it in the computer okay
laughing please say goodbye
bye bye ooh babe bye bye
oh yeah