hey hello mr eric mr ryan how are you
today
good okay so today we talk about uh
interesting problem which is called
combination sum so look
given a few numbers unique positive
numbers yeah
unique positive
positive doesn't include zero yeah
positive it doesn't mean
zero so one two three but it's unique
let's say
one two three four
five six no that's it there are four
numbers so you can think of
four numbers no it can be any let's say
we need this
yeah yeah let's say i you have
a few items which item these are the
these are the um
these are the weight yeah how much it
weight how heavy yeah wait
unique items
yeah one kilogram two kilograms so you
could have gone four kilogram yeah
i like i'm like 30 kilograms okay okay
so
yeah and then i have a a bag a
neck sack yeah a knapsack yeah what's
next a bag yeah
knapsack a bag a bag a bag
okay this is bad i don't know how to put
a bag back yeah
yeah right a bag some item
a kilogram two kilogram
three kilograms four kilogram yeah
okay now the best
no no i'm just saying these are items
okay and then
uh next step uh let's say the next
second
can be packed with almost four kilogram
volcano yeah how much you can
how about four kilograms this bag can
hold
[Music]
so these are the weight of different
type but you you can have
unlimited number of the items for
one kilogram
one one one okay this is one okay can i
have
two one one two right because all these
x over four right
one plus one plus one plus one equals
four one plus one plus two
equal equals four right any others
one plus three equals four yeah
and i can just choose four yeah or
two plus two equals four two plus one
plus one
equals four look this is different this
is different than these they have
different order okay
and what else one two three plus one
equals four can you think of any anymore
one two
one one two one is it one to one ah
yes one to one one to one
so we have one two one one two one
how many one two three four five six
seven eight
oh yes yes eight anymore
anymore okay hold on
let's start uh okay one no i need you
anymore anymore
[Music]
uh
yes okay hold on let's see let's let's
see we don't have any bs4 okay so make
it easy okay
just like that okay we don't have this
item for so we just have one two three
three items
three out of ten and we want to come up
with the solutions
to pack up to four right so that's one
two three
four five six seven seven okay yeah does
it make sense look
one three and three one are different
one one two and two one one are
different all right
all right so look so given this
input one two three and then four take
it you need to tell me it's seven
any idea how we're doing this three four
things how do you profile him come on
how do you propose
how
but the thing is that look this type of
the
this type of item you can have a limited
number of times how
how are you going to profit
so kind of we can backtrack
you know backtrack therefore search
respect tracking look
for each for each item i can choose
i can i can for okay i can choose to
pick
the next item for next item i can choose
pick this one
right or not pick this one right
if i pick this one i can again pick this
one until
it's bigger than the target right
yes i'm all right does it have to equal
four yes it has to be equal for if
it equals to four then i increment the
answer does it make sense so look
so i can i erase look
look this contrast is that these are
unique positive
what happens if there's zero
unlimited number of times combination
right
because you can put zero and zero zero
zero zero little bit
unlimited number of combination am right
and how about negative numbers
look if if it's one and minus one there
are two
and then you want to sum up with target
zero how many
how many possibilities you'll be
unlimited
right one minus one yeah and then you
can add one minus one
and you can add one minus one so you get
it so you'll be one plus minus one plus
one times
plus minus right you can keep adding
that and then that's another
combination right so it doesn't make
sense so that's why we said it's unique
positive all right
all right okay so for comment coming
back this is
to do to the proof of what kind of proof
of status search
for each item we are picking we were
picking
for the next item i can try to pick this
item right
if it's no if it's if the total weight
is still
less than the maximum weight we can
take right yeah and then
i know what's next if i pick this one i
can keep picking this one
right and here it's more like that oh i
can start picking the next one right
all right until okay so let's try the
sugarcoat okay let's let's see the dough
but it's very inefficient right because
you
you keep trying and keep trying and here
look yeah
right all right pick yeah pick okay
pick we are we we're gonna pick the
formula numbers
and let's start from picking the index
from
i yeah let's say from i and then
currently we need to pick the target
right right yeah
target and then we have uh
we have an answer we we have count
answer
currently equals zero right i'm right
okay so now look
t is the number of total weight we still
have to pick right now look
if t is zero what do we do
we increment answer equal plus equals
one and we tend right
does it make sense yeah look if if
there's there's nothing to pick if the
the back
it has empty space left right and empty
weight
left right yeah t is the
weight entry no we increment the answer
right does it make sense eric okay then
we can pick we can start we can start
from uh let's let's
make it left okay so we we have this one
two three
at the beginning we start with zero uh
index zero okay so now we can say
for i in range
left yeah we still can pick the left and
and what kill the length of lumps yeah
then sometimes
okay and then now what look i know
if if nouns
i
if norms i is the
weight of the this item is smaller
than that or equal than the target right
right it means we can pick it then we
can do this one
we can do this pick
click pick i
yeah i'll pick nums okay
and then we can pick still picking this
number
and i y and then t
minus nums i right
why right
look if if none if this item
is smaller than the target now we can
pick it right we can pick it
right all right yes and then we need to
then that's it and actually that's it
because i will be wrapping up with
iterating from left to left right even
smaller even smaller
right if it's smaller t
pick t and then the next iteration for
example left uh
left last one you will pick it you will
need to kick it and then
right yeah yeah so that's it so look
this is
called the uh backtracking yeah
so so it's very uh how
you simulate the process
yeah it simulates the process of picking
right for each one you can pick or not
pick
right you can keep picking picking until
it's smaller it's yellow or
or look if it's not yellow if you're not
yellow then i have to say look uh
do i need to check if it's more uh if
it's less than yellow or no
if you can't pick it if i pick it that's
fine but but
look if you don't check this what will
happen if you can pick
when this will cream could be negative
then you say here if t is smaller than
zero
let's return right right return right
because
for i in range i try to pick but it's
smaller
it's smaller it means that this current
item is more than the
remaining weight right capacity of the
bag then i need to return
right yes all right so look this is the
front
in global counter we are only
increment the answer we will only
increment an answer
if t is zero it means that we have
packed
exactly t weight right
all right the target yeah yeah okay so
this is one solution
but let's do another solution which is
better remember
remember what have we taught
we learned before we have learned before
so all right
so how about if i say f function f n
is the number of number of solutions
that combination that we can pack item n
right we take the weight
and this and this enough so does it so i
have
numbers i have numbers like one
two three right right one two c these
three yeah
so look at the fn let's say f4 remember
this type is four right
so i want to know f4 right i want to
know f4 right is it equal
to the sum sum
of f four minus one
plus f four minus two plus f
four minus three doesn't make sense yeah
look because it's 24 yeah
so i want to get the total item to four
but i know i have one two three right so
if i get the f
if i have the last item i put is one
then i have this solution if it's two
it's like this solution if three is
listed
is it like climbing stairs remember
remember we have talked about the
climbing stairs yeah
the first one you can jump one step or
two step right
yeah remember yeah and you want to reach
the end step
then how many ways can you do it you can
think of this the last way
in order to reach the step end you have
you can
jump to the n minus one step and a minus
two step at a time right
yeah the two possibility you if you want
to reach n
from here uh you if you're going to
reach n
then how many possibilities the previous
step you can
jump on the n minus one and i'm minus
two right
and then once here you can jump one step
or two straight
this is the same better thinking
backwards so in order to pack the
weight four i can take the last one
which is one
or two or three right as long as it's
smaller
smaller than the weight and then i can
add this solution and look at these
we can keep keep doing this right and
then we can remembering so how many ways
we can do this
what what's the approach where we are
what is the agreement we can use to
solve this
kind of problem um
[Music]
what's this yes notebook what what's
that what's what's the ignorant style
with t
there are two kinds of this kind of
address and the one you like would like
to
i login no no no no i'm not saying the
complexity
i mean same the
[Music]
and how many ways of doing that three
two what's it what's that what's that
enough and don't don't leave no need to
catch
it okay okay good job good job yeah
remember yeah
so look in order to do this fn i can do
it as sum
up yeah this is do the sum sum f
n minus i yeah
this i is from the numbers yeah from the
numbers yeah i'm all right
and f your and e 0
is n is smaller than zero
right yeah because negative there's no
way
if if n is negative f n is yellow yeah
because there's no way
f and f one f zero equals one yeah
because
you've got nothing there's one solution
to pack nothing right
all right all right so this is the
recursion
this is the dynamic programming
transaction function
do you do you recall yeah yeah and the
terminal condition is
f n is is yellow if n is smaller than
zero because there's no way to pack
negative weight am i right yeah and f of
zero is one because
there's only one way to pack nothing
yeah if you have an empty knapsack
that's only one solution right yeah does
it make sense
yeah but remember the items are unique
positive right it only works for the
unique positive if it's
negative it doesn't work okay
so let's talk about the top down first
the top down which is easy one
to implement okay
define cash fn
column cash okay yeah remember we put a
cash
if n is zero return
one one come on
if n is smaller than zero return
return zero okay then we're going
through these numbers yeah for i in
numbers yeah remember
then let's have a answer here right
answer equals zero
answer plus equal s
f1 can you tell me f1 here
okay stop jumping okay
look remember we're counting the stairs
to end
and we can every time we can climb
the steps in the numbers yeah it's like
we can pack the items in uh
using these items in you know different
items right
right and then how many ways are doing
that so we add it all together and we
can answer
i need what's this case doing here
what's this case doing
do you remember to remember because we
are
calculating these f numbers yeah
over and over again so this is top down
because if in order to calculate
everything
we need to take the f m minus all the
items which is smaller this is top down
right
yeah it will be extremely little
whatever you say
exponential okay okay the complexity
but with the cash the the fn
we always cache the numbers f0 to fn we
only calculate each number every
function only once right
so what's the term uh what's the
complexity of this one
um
maybe it's not obvious look we have a
four here and we're doing this so
it's the same as the look n is the
target and
let's say let's say this is t okay ft
t okay let's do this maybe
okay okay then and something to do with
t
o t times the length of the length of
the numbers right
because t we need to calculate t f t
f zero f one f two f three until f t
yeah that's
for sure yeah for each one i need to
iterate
numbers numbers here that will be length
of numbers does it make sense yes
okay okay okay
let's do another one bottom yeah so in
order to calculate which value we are we
need to we need to calculate it first
we also calculate the f we calculate
from f 0
f 1 f 2 until we get a f t i'm right
yeah okay can i have your attention
please
okay look defined let's say
uh let's let's just say f function okay
something we have num
okay and i have a target yeah
look we have the bottom up we need to
store these f functions in a
array right let's call it dp array okay
and look
and is length of num right
okay all right
so let's step here right is it size of n
or size of t
all right all right i'm asking
so yeah because we um to know the
value d p 0 d v 1 d 2 under d b
t and the result is in each value
the result is in which value p p
equals 0 times t plus 1 okay because
then
we want to get the dp value those are
the results is in which value alright
the results in which value dp dp which
value the first value on the last
uh value it's the
dp is the look is the f function right
it's the same as a function
so tp what db or we already dp 0
db1 db2 dbt which one is the value we
are looking for
we are looking for the dpua
come on db 0 is the way to pack
not tl1t because t plus one is that the
the the size of the array is dp is t
plus one but we are actually using db
zero to dbt
right so there are t plus one element so
the result is in dp
t which all you can do is p minus one
right remember
yeah the last element okay now the first
one tp0 is actually one right
we're talking about right yes yeah yeah
doesn't make sense because there's only
one way to pack
empty bag right if you put nothing you
know back there's one solution yeah
and now four i
i i invent one
the first term is one two t
plus one yeah we want to calculate dpi
from i will be from one to t all right
all right inclusive
and we need to increasing o j
in numbers yeah we want to know we want
to
iterate all the numbers items in the
numbers yeah the different ways
then if i is bigger or equal to z
what does it mean we can pack j in
in a bag right yeah so dp i
plus equal y dpy can you tell me
a little bit close okay i i want to pick
them this is the
i want to calculate dpi and then now i
can
i find out that the j i we can pick the
j
in in the back so what is equal remember
f4 equals
f4 minus 1 plus f4 minus 2 plus data
so this this n is i and this
this is an item
what's 0 no come on i what
this is
[Music]
keep going um i understand it not
remember
what wait the okay i minus
for
[Music]
i have a four look for loop j in numbers
if i huh t
sorry t don't guess okay don't make a
guess
i understand i want to pack this item j
so how many
what's the way i need to increment it
okay
yeah jane come on
how high your brand would be
yeah t you can put a t or minus one is
the same thing okay
yeah because t is the last value minus
one is the last variable
dv zero is one because there's only one
way to pack the
empty knives and we want to calculate
the value dpi
from one to t for each one i need to
calculate
i need to iterate the numbers and the
numbers
of different weights in items if
if current if current
current back has capacity to pack
item with weight drain then
the solution must be added
dbi minus j right yeah because i already
packed this j
then i i need to take the j out of the
maximum weight i
right does it make sense
the communist stale fn equals fn minus
one plus
fn minus two right or using and
s minus three if you can work one step
two step or three step at the same if
you want to climb up to n stair
yeah so the previous state would be
minus one
yeah you have you are here this is the
top
you can go to right here go to here or
go to here
after reaching these three steps you can
all jump to the here right
all right so that's the number of ways
to reach the
item a stereo end it's similar i want to
pack the item
up to weight n and i can pick one
item pick all the items j yeah numbers
if you like this number is one two three
right
and you iterate the numbers one two
three and you'll be the same as
fm minus one f n minus two and
minus zero j will be g one two three
doesn't make sense larry
does it make sense do you have to get it
quite three
sorry okay so you're we no i'm not sure
that's okay ask me questions come on
okay you need to understand ask me
questions
we've totally summoned the problem
before right what the term complexity
the time connects to here it's easy to
see look p
and length of i right remember rt
length of lumps yeah that's all the
complexity
sorry good question what's the space
looks like it's oh
there's no onion or what a one oh yeah
there's an in here you say one or a what
come on which one t o t come out be
confident because we are only using this
dp which is size of t right yeah which
is the size of t
okay okay ask me one question come on
i'll answer it
ask me one question you need to ask me
questions then i can answer it
okay why do why did you teach this today
good question because i want you to
learn another question come on
okay why why did
wait where did the oval
come on come on last question come on
what's up
why are they kind of messy y'all have
asked your turn already
come on i've got lots i don't really
know what to do
you don't really know what to ask so you
understand everything
i do i don't know what to ask you i
understand everything right
not really not really know why you don't
you ask you don't understand you don't
want to ask
so which one you think you will remember
it
you understand it better the top down or
butter up
i think top down top down this is butter
all right
this is butter up is the reverse
thinking but top down is the
straightforward thinking
the only key thing is remember to use
what cash
cash okay okay so can you can you at the
right time
yeah can you tell me how to drive let's
let's revisit the top down okay
okay catch be
so tell me what to write
fn is the number of ways to pack up the
items
like you know i think
if we know that something bigger
[Music]
uh zero okay and then now we have our
answer we want to return this answer
which is zero and
what should we do we should iterate the
numbers how do we iterate the numbers
oh come on
[Music]
what happened to this answer how tall
are we adding yeah
add yeah equal yeah one
what why we what we cash for
f1 we're calling itself right f1
[Music]
come on and what feel this plan come on
so we turn off the at the end yeah
yeah and thank you
what are we doing here remember the
camera stairs this is the key point
column instead
no wait i i i i
i we are currently n and there are a
number of ways to crack
so what's that what are the previous
states of i of n
n minus one
what y is one all right come on does
this make sense
how high is that how high is that eric
okay all right that's it for today
boy boy bye bye bye