do you still remember the pre-order
yeah yeah what's the other we ordered
do not remember the binary two yeah
pre-order what's pre-order
so it's like so what's the pre-order
very very nice so pre-order
pre-order remember pre-order uh note
left right yeah okay so what's the other
what what does the pre-order give for
this
binary tree it's
deficient i know i mean the order which
order is it
numbers one two
five three four okay
what's the preferred search order one
two
four five three okay so leave this level
value okay
okay so this is the primary how about if
i tell you that today we're going to
do this pre-order in the end
and re okay how do you spell annual
retreat okay all right
all right so it doesn't happen
it means that it's more a parent can
have more than one kid
more than two kids so it will be
something like that six
eight nine yeah yeah it could be
you know a lot right so what's the
what's the
move let's see that's it what's the
pre-order of this one
similarly yeah the note and then the
left from left to the right right
yeah five three three
nine nine ten ten
eleven eleven six six four
eight we're down yeah basically yeah
basically and then the left to the right
yeah
okay and today okay so how can we define
c how can we define this energy tree
remember let's visit the primary tree
first okay how do you define a binary
tree
how do you define the balance define
how do you define the binary remember
the final thing is cash you have what
we should have a class class class
if it's a binary three note yeah
define int
init the constructor yeah with the value
and the left and the right right
let's just call it left and right okay
left
and right and then you can say self
dot value equals value
self dot left
left self top right
equals right right so this left and
right
is also node type right all right
this value could be landing number right
or the
anything right basically it's the value
all right this is a class yeah does it
make sense the left and right
points to excel right points to the type
of itself
and how about we change this to another
retreat
another three so instead of having two
kids left and right we could have a lift
yeah a list of children right
all right so we don't need this we don't
have particular left and right
we just have to change itself the
children
right children equals children and we
just
push a children a list of children so
this children
is a list of a note right a list of
notes
type all right list of notes
yeah does it make sense does it make
sense
no this children okay
okay so let's do this do you still
remember if it's the final
uh tree we want to do the breakfast
search uh do the pre-order it's very
similar you tell me yeah
pre-order if it's uh is the final tree
load yeah all right yeah
if not load
we should return return one
okay nothing nothing we can return empty
lists
empty this yes look and then we need to
visit the load first right
no we have an answer here right answer
will be a list containing the load of
value right load of value at the
beginning
this is priority then look we can do
this
answer plus equal
pre-order
what what and then answer
plus equal pre-order yeah recursively
calling what
do you still remember and then return
left right
[Music]
and i will recursively recursively
er listen we travel a little left and
with the customer
travelers all right does it make sense
yes
yeah okay so how can we turn this into a
energy energy remember yeah
this is still valid right but instead of
having two kids
we have a lot right right so how do we
do this we raise this away yeah
all right and we we need to
iterate the kids so far
i in rule
children right because it doesn't have
more
instead of having to keep you have a
list of cured children right
and then look answer plus equal what let
me write this
for me answer plus equals
[Music]
okay that's it look this is symbol yeah
this is the
recursive recursion because it happened
here recursively
because look i i take a little value
first and then
from left to the right look at me
from the left to the right the kids i
will travel
i will need to travel so it's kids with
the country okay
does it make sense if there are any
notes in the annual
tree what's the time complexity
[Music]
all right what's up
okay so today we will talk about another
approach which is let's not have a
basically question look
all right eric where is the recursion
happening where is the
question no
point point to it more specifically yeah
where then can you point it to it
because you recursion why is the calling
itself
no your point where's the calling itself
come on
don't wrap it up calling itself yes
yeah look this is the function name
right we're calling itself right
to deal with it but we don't want to
reach the question how can we do this
we remember location involves the stack
right
yeah and we can use the step to emulate
the location right does it make sense
all right
okay look
now we have an answer first answer we
want to do this and then we have a stack
stack we we can use the list to do it
right
yeah yeah the
stack and the beginning contain the loot
right okay
because we put a load in it right yeah
does that make sense why are
stack why there's anime in the stack i
will pop it out and current
will be stacked up how do we populate
element here right and then i need to
put it into the answer right answer plus
equal
what current
dot value right now this is the
interesting bit
how can i how can i
i mean the stack look there's a stack
right okay
look if i have a tree right let's just
do it one
two three
four
five okay what's the pre-order of this
one one d three or five
no no one two five three four
okay so at the beginning look at the
beginning i put a one here right
load right yeah one little element you
can guess i
i want to return what i want answer
okay that's so obvious obviously yes
if i change this to something else is it
obvious
if i change it to eric do you know still
you want to listen to
me okay okay
look at look here come on come on
okay return answer look
attention please may i have your
attention please one
step one and i pop it right
pop it and
i put an answer now i answer will be one
right this is i know
interesting now
what should i do what should i push the
kids
of the two three four i need to push it
in
four three two order right all right
all right yeah
yeah so why look because because i put
i take the out one out i'm the next one
will be
two right all right if i put a
two three four in if i put a two three
four in this order the next one take out
would be four right
which i don't want i want to take off
two so i need to push it two three
two three four in the reverse order so i
have one
stack dot extend
look this is the new keyword extent i
i'll show you and then children
it's children current children
in a reverse order how do you do this in
the reverse order
remember don't call it minus one
come on you know okay people see you
dancing all over the world okay so yes
great job yeah it's children color minus
one it's gonna be first order yeah
look it's children it's two three four
and in the reverse order watching
what's in the reverse order all right
all right
yeah what's in the reverse order is four
three two right yeah
and that's it so the next one look if i
put the four three two so the stack will
be look
four three two right
all right yeah so the next one where the
stack
and color is second pop what's common
color
will be what
yeah the two i take a two right and i
put a two here right answer plus equal
to
right and then it's kid kids i i put the
kids of two which is five
because only one element yeah i put it
five right
right and the next one which element to
take it
five five and there's no kids so i keep
pushing it so this doesn't have any kids
and then the next one is three right
and the next one is four yeah you see
one two five three four okay
one two five three four doesn't make
sense look
all right look here here
these this is the same plus equal
this is the same as answer dot append
right let's put that one element at the
end right
this is the same right this is the same
as this
stack dot extent what stack of extent
is the same as stat
don't append all the elements in in
these
right right yes so look every area
if yeah if the stack is book if stack
equals
one two three right and then and
eric equals four it was four
five four and then ryan
equals six and seven at least yeah so
i'm 13. listen up
i'm a teenager stack don't extend eric
so what happened after this
step
become stack will become one two
three and then what's eric four five and
you put a four and five right
that's why you mean extend yeah extend
the step with
new elements right because they're at
least all right
and extends doesn't have to be something
no no look you can do this class equal
if there's only only one element right
yeah you can do this way or you can do
this stack
plus equal current children
that's what you mean children column
color minus one yeah
look that's what it means extend is the
same thing as this one right
yeah you want to extend the reverse
of the children into the list does it
make sense
yeah right okay so
so i mean this is the not recursion and
this is the white loop eric while this
element in the stack i do this i pop one
element from the stack i add
append it to the answer and i extend its
children in the reverse order why is it
in reverse order
because we want to do the
first thing that's all that's why we
need to reverse it right because the
stack is first in that cell
if you push two three four then four
will be taken out first
if i push four three two and then two
will be taken out first does it make
sense
yeah does it make sense
okay okay there there are a few
two reasons they're gonna be united yeah
okay come on what
too much what what what is missing can
you tell me what's right
here if you don't know i don't don't
know how to do it
you tell me what to do somewhere
yeah you can do it with the follow and
here what's missing here
yeah and what's what's here what's
missing here there are two lines
there's no two lands there's only one
land really yeah there's only one land
there's two lines there's only one left
okay fine so what does it what what does
it do here
i mean can you tell me what do i do what
what's
need to be done here i take an element
from the top of the stack i think i push
yeah i need to can you explain forget
about the thing text you just tell me
what to do
i mean so i take an element out of the
stack
i push it into that answer and i need to
do what i need to
append each kid his children in the
reverse order to the
stack right yeah so hold on
yeah yeah i what's what's that
the children what's the children where's
the colonel's children yeah
so kyle and the children and reverse
order yeah
yeah that's why it is come on yeah this
is the
non-recursion because previously we
talked about a recursion according to
a pre-order yeah so which one is simpler
recursion one hour or this one
uh maybe looks like sorry maybe
what which one do you think is
easier to understand
[Music]
okay do you still remember the recursion
one all right
yeah okay that's it because you're right
let's come back to this recursion one
again this still remember
all right the first of all i need to put
a new downward here
yeah and then i need to travel its kids
yeah for i
in
children children i watch me
and then i need to attend it answer
equal okay you can write it in this way
answer yeah and then what's this what's
this recursion happening
it's easy come on what's good something
with pre-order
yeah i'm calling for you yes
[Music]
look at that d he's really vanishing
well
okay we're done with that why are you
listening today
that's good okay okay that's it that's
it for today
bye bye
wow