hey hello mr ryan
yeah remember yesterday we talked about
the energy tree
right so can you tell me what's an
animal tree
i know it's all a tree you know it's
just a tree okay
so you know we know the final retrieve
what's final three eric
a binary tree has uh
two two children yeah two two at least
one parent yeah two children
maximum one parent the lou does not have
parents right
the kid does not have any children right
if
if we remove the binary when it becomes
the energy so basically the tree
can have come up at most a few you know
you can have a many many children not
except
not necessarily limited to right right
so do you still remember how we define
the
energy trees right class
now all right can we leave that thing
later yes please
don't be cubed
[Music]
define in int
is the constructor and then we have a
value for the
note of the current value and the
children right
so you can have many children so these
children is the list of notes
yes yes
okay so look at the constructor self
stock value will be equal to value and
self stop children will be equal to
children right
yeah all right
okay so look if i have these
two three
four five
and possibly six and seven
okay sorry yeah yeah
so look everywhere listen
ryan listen so today you're given a list
of the notes
right you're given this one two three
four five six and then we
i want you to find out the route
one yeah of course this one is that
but how can we ask computer to find out
so you're just getting
you just check every night
look oh you just uh check the
very top notes but how do you know which
one is the
very top note that's the question so
each note you do
a breakfast set and the first one is the
root
the thing is we don't know the root
normally you're given a tree with the
root right
yeah but now the one that doesn't have a
parent
but how do you know it doesn't have a
pearl you can tell it has a children but
it doesn't have parents felon
so the thing is that you you for human
it's very easy to know okay this one is
the loot right but for computer it
doesn't know right because
you're given the root like you're given
a list of nouns like
2 one three four
six five seven okay so these are the
notes
and then you know for two you have
nothing no children but for three
you have you know it's what five here
and four four you know it's six and
seven right you have
children six and seven and then
six seven these are not right one you
know it's two
two three four right two three four
does it make sense normally you're given
a tree as a loot right you know one is
the loot and then you can
traverse the tree using the breakfast
search
or death versus right yes
but now i'm not giving you the loot i'm
giving you
a list of the notes in the tree i am
giving you all the notes in the tree
for each note you know their value and
you know their children
so how in this case how we going to find
out which note is the root
do you understand this problem
yes
yes so which now look here you're given
a list of notes
look at this so how do you know which
number is the root
uh don't tell me it's one because i
i mean yeah you know
you know from here you know the answer
is one but how do you know if here is
one
oh because like you know
so can it yeah can you think of a way
any single way like two
so it
and you see if that number is there
sorry can you repeat i guess because
this one issues the children
yeah and and they and and
uh rude is in the children so you find
the one which isn't there
okay quite close yes you find the note
which the children doesn't have
the no yeah yeah so how do you do it
efficiently
so you want to find out all the children
yeah if you want to find the basically
you want to find out that no
which isn't part of the the children of
any node right yeah
so what kind of data structure are we
using here
you're quite close so what kind of data
structure can we use to remember to
direct research data structure data
structure
what kind of data structure are we using
remember the one you use a lot
no set
why you said can you tell me are you
just guessing why is this yeah
so look every time
[Music]
put all the what all the children know
all the notes in the set
we want to find out if a noun is sent in
the children's section all
the children yeah so first of all we go
through this each note
right all right we go through each note
like this
and then we have a question all right
look at me everybody all right
look i look one is children it's two
three four yeah let me
this is the set i
i'm i i i'm visiting the note one what's
its kids
one two three four i push it here two
three four two doesn't have any kids
right three dozen
three have one kid five four here
four kids uh six
and seven yeah so five six seven it
doesn't have a kid yeah
yes so what's this two three four five
six seven so you go through this
which what's the set of these this set
is everything yeah one two three four
five six seven yeah
and which number doesn't appear in this
side yeah obviously right and you go to
this and you find out okay what is the
new
one is blue doesn't make sense yes so we
go through the notes and we know we push
the kids
into the chosen set right because we
know that
the root isn't definitely any
the children of any noun right
doesn't make sense yeah okay let me
drive this okay
this should be very easy
[Music]
yeah that's a very good job yeah that we
must be i didn't expect you to
remember that but you didn't remember
that yeah
minus one good job look all right
set okay let's say children
children equal set
right look click here another look
for and
in note
for i c or i
i
[Music]
how do you add elements no
and for let's set is apparently this is
a
false set is add for the list is a pen
okay
that's the different keywords
and
[Music]
so look this is children said we already
have it and how about we we know that
[Music]
right
or not let's do it all notes equals
equals one set we can do this
sensitive syntax x for
x in nodes right
so we are extra value for
x in nodes and then returning to the set
and then we oh we do
we have these orders yeah so what do we
do return
all nodes minus children right remember
remember
let's see let's sing a set and then you
want to
minus that this is a set this is b minus
that will be
outside yeah yeah you can do this set at
minus thing okay but this is a set yeah
this is the set then i want to convert
it to
a list i i think the list will be just
this yeah this
list of red and then the first element
because we know
there's only one element right okay so
you can use this
here set what we are converting
a list into the set what's that extra
value for x
in node right this is very fancy python
syntax but if you
not sure you can always for and
in note if m not if n
not in n children then we add we do we
know it's the
no that doesn't have any uh doesn't
belong to the children of any note then
it must be the root right what's the
time complexity
from number one
what's the space complexity
we want to add the word to the set
chosen
which one is that something to add
yeah f yes what ad
yes yeah bye
ryan you want to say bye bye bye to
people because
we're missing you every time you're
sitting there
right bye good job good job today okay
that's it
okay eric say bye see you tomorrow