[Applause]
yeah today we can't talk about a
string complex you know what's complex
complex complex compressed
and decompressed if you
press it and you not press it
kind of the compress is you make a big
thing into a smaller thing
yeah but you can always restore look
alright
from a bit to the small is complex yeah
complex
and then if you can restore it that's
the complex
yeah yeah in what cases we need a
complexion and decompression for example
like if you want to send a big
big thing yeah over internet you want to
send a picture
right to your friend but the picture is
very big
it takes time so in this case we can
complex the picture
yeah to a smaller size and then we send
it to your friend and your friend
when you when your friends get it you
will decompress so you can
see the original picture that's complex
compaction and decompression
complexities make this big thing small
become practices
restore it to to make the small things
you know big again yeah i'm
small yeah okay so this is the concept
so
today we want to complex the string but
not necessarily we can decompress it for
example like
look a a a b b
c b d e
e okay doesn't have to be an alphabet no
no it doesn't look
this one look there are three a yeah
three a
two b one c two d what two e yeah
two d okay look if i have a lot of e
here so how can you
complex this one we have one kind of
thing it's called run dance con
one dance okay one length what's one
lens
running runner is encoding look a a how
many a's
three three a then i took three how many
ones will be one thing let's even one
season let's just put c one two three
yeah
and how many five five so which one is
shorter which one is longer
five e no no one thing this is this this
string is longer or this string is
longer yeah
the same look how many characters one
two three four five
six seven eight nine ten eleven twelve
thirteen
smaller look this one is one two three
four five six seven eight nine
so i have nine characters this one is 13
characters
so what does it mean this one is shorter
right so
if i want to send this message to your
friend
right and i need to send it 13
characters
and which is better if i can send it
nine characters
which is better so for example your
friend
gets this message this is complex
message like he can
decompress it look he can decompress it
okay three a then
he knows three a two b okay two b
one c two d five e
you doesn't make sense yeah
does it make sense yeah yeah why we need
the compaction so look it because it's
too big
for example there are 100 e's here and
you want to write it 100 times that's
that's going to take time yes but i can
just run
change this to 100 counting right so you
will still
be 10 characters and you'll be faster
right and when your friends get it
then you can restore yeah yeah then your
friends can
decompress it yeah that's what it means
compression the compression doesn't make
sense
right yeah okay so today our job is
slightly simpler so look look
a a bbbc dddde and
you need to tell me the complex version
is a b
c d e that's it you see so
any consecutive any consecutive
characters
you just need one yeah they compress
into one
yeah doesn't make sense
how can we do it oh oh
uh uh
how do you use the notebook no you don't
need a notebook but how do you how to do
it
maybe you can use notebook i don't know
just tell me we can
maybe we come okay just tell me what
happened
just tell me how to do
[Music]
quite close erica so look can you
explain again please
okay so if it's the first one character
a
and then you put it in and then you try
if it's the same as the previous one
you don't put you skip skip right and
then the next one
you put it because it's different right
you put it and then it is the same
skip it different put it different put
it
this same different e
okay so yeah that's a very good approach
so listen
so so we just basically check if
the previous characters is the same and
the first one we definitely put it
because there's no previous character
right
yes i'm right okay can we write this so
today we'll be writing this
this is simple okay so look define
complex complex or complex s
and c okay let's say the answer your
answer will be
at the beginning is the empty string
right
and then look if four
four look if we want to have a previous
one here previous
previous equals num right because
beginning here
for i in s
right look if
if current string is not equal to
previous one
right right if it's not equal to
what should we do we we append it to the
current string right
all right all right and then previous
equals i right
right does it make sense yeah and then
return
answer right does it make sense eric
can you check does it make sense doesn't
make sense
yeah okay so look because this is the
string direct
you know we're manipulating the string
we are adding adding the
string uh append the string to it it
might be slow you have to
string my uh string
connect connect the string in the python
is quite slow so we can do this eric we
can do this at least
yeah we can put a list this is simple if
i
not equals previous one and answer would
be dot append
apparent we can append the i right and
then look
return answer because answer is a list
right so we need to
put it to make it alright look
remember a so you'll be like that a b
anytime i see answer i always say
written
yes yeah because that's the naming
convention okay a b c so how can we make
this a bishop do you really remember
this if this is answer and how do we
make this abc remember
oh we use a join
where you'll remember yeah
[Music]
what happened if you press dot john what
people are watching you
yeah people are watching your dance
okay so all right look look here we are
using the previous right
but we don't need to store the previous
if we iterate the index we don't need to
uh start it in previous right because
the previous is always is previous right
so we can remove this all right and then
we
iterate this range we turn the range
range length s
okay and then how how do we do this look
look then we can say if
i equals zero if the first one if it's
the first character
we put it right o or what
or s i not
equal to s i minus one right because
that's its previous one then
there was answer dot append
open what can you tell me i plan what
however
apparent what if it's the first
character all the current character is
not equal to the
previous character s i we want to append
the current character
and then we don't need this previous for
i right because we already know the
previous one is
it's minus one and this still works okay
doesn't make sense
what's the time complexity
slowly please
[Music]
okay so do you still remember look this
is the traditional way of implementing
it right
yeah we're using it let me explain it
again okay
this is the list we're going through the
index
yeah each character if it's the first
character or
its current character is not the same as
the previous character
right right then we probably put it
in the current in the list there and
then we return we join the list by
empty string so we join or make it a
string right yeah
does it make sense so do you still
remember we can use the group by
function yeah i talked about that
some time ago guru bank yeah
guru bar is exactly the same thing look
eric if you do this already hungry
all right all right so look group i
is the function from its tools right
iteration tools
if you use the glue guy what happened
all right you will return
remember you will return the a b and
then
there will be a iterator
of a a right and then
b iterator of bb right
this is the iterator if you want to get
it you need to change this to this
and see an iterator of c so let's see
easy all these can can be converted into
one line
again the join we want to join the list
yeah so look
at this yeah x 4
x comma y in group by
goodbye guru by s
island bracket that's it a single line
right
does it make sense all right guru by s
yeah remember blue by s the key will be
the
group the y value will be the list
of the its group right so x will be the
group right
and then i want to join the x doesn't
make sense right
yeah really does it make sense
yes okay so let
uh so this one look at this one
remember if it's a aabb what does it
mean you will return the tuper
yeah guru by this group by this will
return the trooper which is what
a a a and then
and then a tuper a second one will be
aaa right
so i just want to return to this first
one which is x axis here
and at least so you'll be drawing a list
of
a b c right
all right john abc returns abc doesn't
make sense all right
yeah what's the space complexity
does we do we need a space do we need a
space
this one is hard to say because we are
probably using the space here
right everyone
implementation do you still remember we
are not using any space right we you
don't count
one oh one we don't call it we we don't
call the answer as the space additional
space right
all right yeah okay so do you still
remember you fight
every eric if i'm i'm going to write it
and then you tell me what to do okay
look all right answer he was this
for i in range
range one and then if
what of s i
not equals what then
answer dot append
what okay and then return
join what okay
come on ready wait answer
okay good job and then this one
s-i s-i yes keep going yeah
it's what the first character what i
want
the first character what does it mean
i equals zero f
s i not equals the previous one
uh previous yeah previous one well
there's no previous li is the color
what's the previous one
s minus one s i minus one come on
range r uh s
pi what's the length of the s
what's the dental guys what's function
which function
is okay that's it yeah yeah
that's it for today well that's it for
today good job
say bye to people bye
look at that teddy say bye bye bye
bye okay okay come get see you tomorrow
bye