hello hello mr how are you doing today
good okay so today we talked about a
simple function
in python which is called accumulate
despite accumulation
what does this mean cumulate accumulate
how do you spell
accumulate what does it mean
eric accumulate what does it mean
accumulated accumulation accumulate so
early look
it means to accumulate to put the things
together yeah look at
one two three four five at least
right six seven eight nine ten all right
so when you accumulate this array
what happened i i then you tell me what
does it do yeah
1 3 6 10
15. okay so when it accumulates you'll
become this
what does it mean it's a generator
it's actually a generator
wait i think i'm yeah
actually i feel like
well add a zero add one two
quite close yes what does it mean zero
one three water why is this yellow
sorry
wait what what what's what's theo coming
from
i was like doing like one yeah
right there was like one plus one
yeah and i was like yeah you know yeah
yeah i know
how about this here what's the six
what's the six
six is double
look carefully what's 10
and what's 15 come on what's what's it
compared to the previous one
come on
come on you're quite close come on
what's what's between these two what's
between these two what's between these
two ones will be the next
four five yeah and why is that
well why is that
what is accumulate you don't understand
is what accumulates let's look up
in in a dictionary what does it mean if
you know this one you probably
understand what they mean yeah
baby accumulate
yeah accumulate what is it what is it uh
gala together yeah investigation
together together uh acquired an
increasing number of quantity of what is
it does
that mean a bear does not affair
okay all right look what's the sum up to
this point
one what's the sum up to this point
what's the sum up to this point
six do i need to continue
no so what what's the accumulation tell
me explain to me
one two one one
two one two one again one
three six ten fifteen
yeah one one one plus two one plus two
plus three
one plus two plus three plus four one
plus two plus three plus one from apply
yeah
this is accumulate yeah yeah because we
want to know
up to this point plus sum how many the
sum
of these points and until this point
right
doesn't make sense so this this function
look is from each tool so you want to
use it you can use this from
it to us yeah
uh literally to us import
please iterator yeah for it
it's really it is it's it's it's from
italy or it functions
actually i'm not quite sure what i mean
just double check
uh from eaton to us
from it to us iteration to us
import import accumulator
important we want to use this function
accumulate
do this this one
e2 remember we have used this from each
of the tool
import one remember
cache yeah is it cache cache remember
we're using this year so these two are
provides many many functions so this
this i think it's from here so look
so look if array is equal
in a circle okay so
like that and then look let's say
a equals equals what
equals accumulate
yeah and then you accumulated to take
and you want to print it print it you
can say print
it print but you need to turn this into
a list because this is a
iterator generator remember so if
this generator what does it give you it
gives you one element at a time right so
you can fall
i in accumulate do this then you'll
print it one
three four ten right so bring list
a then it will give me
one three 6 10 right
yeah all right how can we implement this
function
okay define yeah let's say we don't want
to use the
we want to reinvent the rear wheel okay
define let's just do call accumulator
accumulate i'll go q
mu later okay and then let's say a
is the number with the array right all
right
all right look so look
what so how can we do this
we can change the numbers in the uh
we can change this array if you want we
can change it we don't need to
we don't need to create a copy look we
can change it look for
i in range
range let's say one to length we start
from the first one right because the
first
well no we start from the second one the
first element is there's no change right
everything
look one two three four so how can we
change
this all right the first one doesn't
change right
the second one is equals to its number
plus the previous one is
three right now what's the next
is three plus its previous one three
which is six
and what's next is four plus the
previous one
yeah does it make sense
what did i just say
so what we start from the second number
so every time
this number we want to update it with
the sum
plus the next one the previous one come
on why is the next one
what what's previous one minus one
i minus one and then return a yeah
because when you return a that's at
least that's not generator
so how can we make it a generator
can you win yeah remember we
seen this keyword before yeah from a
that's it we because we want to yet one
element at a time we don't want to get
the same thing
so from a means that we want to eat one
element and the ten so it will give me
exactly so this is exactly the same
function as
from iterators input accumulate it's the
same thing yeah
we invent the wheel yeah we invent
the wheel what does it mean so it means
we already know have
uh we but we want to reinvent it right
we don't take it again
make it again yeah so while we're making
it we just i just want to
demonstrate how what's behind it right
the accumulated function that's why it
is yeah
yeah all right we are modifying this if
we want to
if we want to make a copy we can do we
can say like a new right
new array right equals deep copy
copy don't be copy right hey
all right we're gonna copy a one and
then we can do this
and then we can we can do this n equals
it's the same thing yeah
doesn't make sense yeah
oh we don't need we can do this all
right create a new array
but instead instead we can do this
and the append because our and
the first first element it needs to
contain the first element right
and then the second element will be and
append
up and what a i
ai is current element right
plus and minus one right
all right does it make sense so
it's the same thing so every time you
append the current element
and the previous element pretty
previous element of n look look eric
the a a is a is one one two
three four right and and at the
beginning i
set it to the first element which is one
okay
and then do this i will be two here
right
and apparent a i two plus
one right the last element of n is three
so i probably
one three here okay so next one
i equals three right i a i is three
three plus
the last element of n is three so six
right and the next one four plus the
last element of
n is 6 so that's 10 right
does it make sense yeah this is the
making a copy but we don't need to as i
said we can just directly
directly multiplying yeah a i plus equal
ai minus one so basically when you add
in this a i minus one it's already the
sum
of the previous field previous i minus
one item right yeah so we can reuse this
does it make sense
eric look here a i start with here yeah
okay so two two plus the previous item
is one right
yeah i raise it three
so now the next three plus the previous
item
yeah does it make sense and i call it
here four
plus the previous item ten does that
make sense
yeah yeah what's the time complexity
n yeah what's the space complexity
if we are modifying this what's the
space complexity
we are modifying it we don't we are not
using any additional array
we are not using any other things we are
all
we are this is input what's the term
why is that we are not using any space
what's the not using one oh what
constant
you say oh a what's oa i said that
before
okay you don't you say love you need to
be confident okay
um if we are you making a copy that's
our n right
yeah but we're not no that's that's
that's okay like yeah it is
what's here what's here
giving you one element in the tunnel
yeah so you can use it in a
it's a generator right so you can you
can
use it in a for loop you can say for i
in
accumulate and then it will give you one
element why is that look because if
if a contains a minion right
if a contains a minion
meaning elements then i don't want to
return
a minion at the same time right maybe i
just want to use one at a time right
so give me one give me one give me one
right
yeah if if we if you give me a hund a
million
elements i may not need it i just give
me one give me one right
for example like we can have
this may not be a very good example
because we are all we are
calculating the entire array at the same
time right
at once so look we do still remember the
prime numbers
how many prime numbers are there how
many prime numbers
up to what no i mean
we in react how many prime numbers are
there
there's no limit how many about how many
prime numbers
i know quiet loss is what it's limited
or
unlimited it's infinite finance or
infinite is it finite
or infinite
or unlimited which one
unlimited i didn't want any of those
you don't need this one i know i think
because there are as many as you want
right yeah
so which one pick one okay for
what what's fine finally is that maybe
20 you can count it with opposite of
counters
infinite remember infinity yeah
yeah yeah that's the positive infinity
minus
infinity right so which one
okay which one is no fish come on come
on give me the answer please
how many prime numbers i'll go for
unlimited i limited count these
infinite all these three are the same
thing it's okay right
yeah it's because it's as many as you
want why are we talking about that okay
let's say okay let's say
the if yes
if how can we prove it's unlimited
it's very hard but i i i assume look if
we must be saying
if we assume the prime numbers are
limited okay
yeah yeah let's say if it's p1
p2 until pn right yeah
if it is if it's finite right it's
it's and if there are only n prime
numbers yeah
yeah how about if i times it together
yeah times it together right that would
be not a prime number right because you
can find this right
yeah all right how about plus one
so if i plus one that becomes a point
number right because it
cannot be divided by any of these prime
numbers
right you cannot find any number so what
does it mean i find another one prime
number which is not p1 to pn
yeah all right our assumption is that
they are only
p n they are only n prime numbers but
if i multiply them together and plus one
i found a new prime number
so what does it tell us our assumption
is wrong right so what's our assumption
our assumption is there are only n prime
numbers
so it's wrong what does it mean the
prime numbers are quantities
all right is it elegant is it beautiful
proof
maybe it is yeah this is the opposite
yeah
you you you assume something is right
and then you you prove and then you
prove you
you come back to your approval and then
you say oh my my assumption is wrong
right so the opposite of the assumption
is that
from number of prime numbers are
unlimited doesn't make sense
yeah okay so why we talk about
polynomials i want to talk about because
it's unlimited
so if i have a function like define
get next prime right
okay next prime give me your next prime
number
so if it's two the next one will be
three
five right because it's unlimited the
list is always unlimited you can't
return a list
of unlimited right does it make sense do
you
say like if you if you go for two
and two is a prime number do you need to
give a
give a prime number so yeah this kind of
prime
so let i want to use this function yeah
get primed up get next random i want i
want to do this
i want to do this y
y uh let's say um maybe maybe i'll just
do this
uh print
yeah next next prime number
get next prime number okay that's it
i know now we have a loop right 4
i in range
might be 10 i want to print the first 10
prime numbers
right do this right you see so this
is the you will give me uh
it will give me a number every time
right
doesn't make sense you'll give me a
number every time
because the list at least
maybe maybe i can write it this way
maybe it's better
for i in in one
in in get prime
numbers and then i just print i'm going
to put in i
right yes yeah so look these scheduled
numbers is unlimited
they're unlimited number of prime
numbers but every time i want to i
i will return the i i will point the
point 3.20 so
here here no nothing
so here i was just saying i want to
yield
yet yeah uh a prime number right
yeah yeah here's the prime number right
i want to hear the problem number
instead of generating a list of the
because in this case it will not be very
good to generate a list of prime numbers
right
because it's unlimited does it make
sense
but i know the next point number yeah
i don't know how many more numbers i
need to fit it
give you because it's unlimited but i
i know the next one doesn't make sense
yeah so that's why the years from
okay got it okay let's see for today
we'll talk a little bit more okay
that's it say bye bye to people