oh hey hello mr everybody mr ryan how
are you today
good good okay so today we're going to
compute
the angles between the sec the minute
and the hour on the clock okay so what's
how do you draw
a three uh three o'clock
on the clock only the ten yeah three
o'clock
okay so let's yeah okay it's not let's
show them
something about this is
how do you draw 3 3 30
3 30 yeah 3 30.
3 30. you sure
the thing is that when when this minute
moves the
the hour will also move right it's not
straight
straightly does it make sense
it's half right because look it should
be half this is three
and then that's four here so when is 3
30.
yeah yeah i know so here will be yeah
so here does it make sense six all right
yeah seven eight so when when this
minute
moves when this mini moves the hour will
also move right
right doesn't make sense for one hour
okay so for one hour how many
angles does that one how many for one
hour
for 60 minutes how many
hours i mean the angles of our one hour
how many angles this angle right
yeah what's this
how many angles a circle here you go
like around
go around open it how many or angles
sorry
angles look this is 90 degrees right
90 degrees and what's this 300 and
degrees yeah this is this is a 180 yeah
and then you
go around the third that's that's 360
right
yes and how many hours on the clock
12 12 so how many angle for between one
hour
if i i like hours from go from one to
three thirty degrees
thirty degrees so look three hundred
sixty divided by two every thirty
degrees okay so we know
one hour equals 30 degrees and how many
minutes we have in one hour
uh okay so how many angles does one
minute have
how many hours does one minute the home
angle
angle like this 100 this is 360 and you
say 60 minutes so how many
if the minute moves one minute which end
this small angle which is
what what's this one degree
no of course not one degree what is one
degree
one minute how many minutes you just say
how many minutes
60 degrees or 60 minutes and how many
minutes how many engines
60 degrees 66 degrees right
yeah so minute moves one minute is 66
degrees right
yeah okay so we want to find out the
angle between the hour and minute the
smaller one right because it always has
two
the smaller one and the bigger one right
we want to know the smaller angle how
how can we
compute this
the small angle like 300 uh like 330
what's the angle between 330
330. look three thirty this is thirty
yeah
three ninety degrees no it's not ninety
degree
i i just said the hour move as well
right look this is
this is three this is four
so one hour will be okay that's it you
don't need to write
look this is 30 yeah this is this is 6
right
30 yeah so what's the degree is here not
here this is 90 degree
right all right look at me this is 90
degree
but we also need to count
constant angle 75 degrees
75 degrees why is it 75 degrees can you
explain to me
[Music]
yeah 75 why you why you saying 75
you know it is half yeah
15 and yeah exactly yeah that's that's
we're done good job be confident it's 75
because what the hour moved halfway
right so this is 15 degrees
we just said that this is 30 degrees
before move from three to four then it's
half
it's half that's 15 so so 90 minus 15 is
what 75 okay
okay so how are we approaching this
problem if if you
if it's h hour and m
minute what's the end between them if
it's hr
minute
so how we calculate this does it
can we calculate it as look can we
we know this is zero right here is
yellow yeah
can we calculate h angle first and now
we calculate
m angles minus that that will be the
answer right
doesn't make sense yeah
look like take this for example 3 30
right
okay what's the three hour degree three
hour but we need to catch
we need to count it for at least half so
30 minutes
how many hours divided by 60 right
yeah and plus h that's that's the
hour move right because hour is three
hours
three o'clock it moves every three yeah
but it also needs to move
half of the minutes so which is here so
it will be
h minus m divided by 30.
that's the total hour
it moves yeah i will just say it is what
it's 30 degrees right yeah right this is
the angle of
hour right what's the meaning of minimum
m times
what m times 1
6 yeah and if we minus these the
difference minus least that will be the
answer compared to
so this this is the angle angle a angle
yeah and we need to calculate
a hundred minus anger and an angle which
is smaller right
because we want a smaller one right does
it make sense
yeah doesn't make sense all right
okay so can you explain to me can you
explain to me what um
can you explain to me so this hour we
need to modulate by 12 as well because
if it's
more than if h is given from zero
uh to 12 okay we multiply by 12 okay so
it's between 0 to 11 okay
does it make sense all right yeah
okay let's buy the curve right it should
be easy this is a mathematic problem
define anger let's say
our meaning right
okay look we need to first of all
get h between 0 to 11 right because
sometimes you say
21 hours right yeah 21 o'clock
yeah 24 yeah so modular equals 1
20 sorry
we want to make this number between zero
to twelve eleven o'clock is
equal to twenty three eight o'clock is
equals to twenty
percent modular twelve yeah so this will
become
the actual becomes zero to eleven right
between zero to eleven right
yeah okay the angle look
mini angle let's say n
angle minute equals
we know it's minute times 6 right yeah
yeah six degrees right all right yeah
minute so this angle times six right
is the angle between minute and
this zero doesn't make sense if it's 30
if it's 30 minutes what's the degree
uh it is
[Music]
30 minutes where is that degree
your degree is kind of like hey
so what's the answer and come on
i enter m equal m times six so what's
when m
is 30 what's the degree um
yeah so it's 180 so it's basically like
that and what's the
30 what's 15 when m is
15 what's the degree um
look it's 90 yeah is it when it's 15
here right
yeah you see yeah okay so you understand
this angle
is is this yeah okay sorry
hour angle hour
angle hour equals
we know it's hour right yeah yeah
but we need to class with with m
with one time and times 30
all right plus what can you explain
what's here what's your point
m divided by five
thirty
another half right right and each hour
is 30 degrees right
yes all right okay and then look
so the difference difference so this is
an answer answer okay answer equals
abs there's a difference between
anger abs can you tell me what's abs
abs is american no no
a death
no no abs absolute value remember the
difference between zero and the number
if it's if it's minus three is three
it's three it will small yeah so the
difference between
right and doing understanding is abs
value zero here
one two and this is minus one that's
minus two
right right right this is the numbers on
the line
if you put these this is abs value
absolute value
it means the distance between the number
to the zero so abs minus two equals how
many
units here oh yeah how many units here
yeah right
abs minus two equals what
minus two equals two right and i'm
asking you right
abs minus two equals one
absolute value how many units one
distance between minus two to zero how
many
ten two okay abs one equals
equals what how many units between one
to zero
one yeah that's what you mean if it's a
negative number you take away the
negative if it's a positive number it
doesn't change
okay that's what it is so we want to
calculate the angle well the angle is
obvious to the positive yeah
all right yeah because sometimes the
sometimes the hour angle is bigger than
a minute but sometimes the mean
anger is bigger than an hour does it
make sense 3 30
3 30 the 30 minutes is bigger than the
hour right
3 15 the hour is bigger than a minute
all right
so we want to get the difference and
then we want to return the
retainer minima alright so what
mean answer and then
what we want to get a smaller angle not
a bigger angle so what's the
what's that answer
so in this this this is angle and what's
this angle
what's the this angle is
yeah that's what i'm asking for yeah
answer
what what
what
we have just given two numbers and then
we do some mathematic calculations
what's the space complexity i'm one yeah
that's it because we're only giving two
numbers we're just doing some
calculation we don't mean
it no matter how big is this number how
complex this number we always calculate
it
instantly right does it make sense yeah
all right okay so i'm going to
[Music]
erase this and then release this okay
what what come on
ryan everybody is watching you
ready huh come on
yes yeah maybe yes come on what's abs
mean can you tell me
ivy is what
[Music]
what's the angle of minute come on
that's the easiest part
what's the minute oh how many minutes
what's the minute
yeah what's the easy end yeah
one it's just the symbol m1
[Music]
yeah that's it okay let's say
bye bye