hey hello mr mr ryan how are you today
yes okay so can you tell me what's
vowels
oh f-a-e-i-o-u a-e-i-o
is y uh a vowel
sometimes sometimes like my yeah
my mind okay so okay so it's kind of
semi okay so
let's let's take this ai for uh
like uh all right yeah for the vowels
okay so
today's task is given a string and we
want to remove
all the valves in it for example like
a b e o
d i don't know what it is i mean you
given this function and to remove all
the vowels you should give me
b d d that's it
okay so what's the approach of doing
this oh you just
uh wait it's just what
just take away the a e i and you just
go through all of it and yeah you know
go to the all along
all the characters in s and then if it's
vowel what do we do if it's not about
what we do
keep it there keep it yes
yeah you you you do it tiffany
do the new okay so maybe maybe you can
write this
remote remove vowel
right as this empty string so how can we
iterate over the string for i and s
for i in s column and then look
what if one if each eye
is not in a vowel right so how can we
draw this
no
[Music]
actually this if it's a string you you
use the
answer plus equals i right and then
return
answer return answer oh you're three
what's the time complexity
what's n declarations
the number of characters in the string
what's the space complexity
okay
okay that's it and because we know that
the appending
a character over and over again to a
string is slow so we want to make this a
list yeah
so if i place at least what should i
change here
answer door putting a lump
element into the back of the
list
append
make it better but look i not in aeio
actually we need to
check how many times in the worst case
if we want to check if i
five times if it's a if it's e if i so
we can make this better
by using what kind of data structure set
yes notebook because the set lookup term
is com how quickly is this oh well one
constant
look at then we look we can do this
valve
set and then i i put a
what a e i o u yeah and then i can just
not
if uh if i'm not in
vowels right right and then answer the
opening and then it still should work
okay all right
yeah this makes sense yeah now this one
is a one constant a one constant look up
terms
extremely very very fast going through
the characters one time right
and we're using the answer to append the
characters that
are not in the vowels right it's only
four minutes that's okay that's okay
and we're going to use a few
few things yeah here so look one
another way of doing this is using the
replace function the string has a
replace function so you can say
look if you say a b c dot replace
g replace a
into b so can you tell me
what is this so i want to replace
abc this string with when the a
i want to replace a with b so what does
it give us
abc w replace a b so what's your what's
your show does
the b replace with a day no just a
replacement
yeah we're done yeah abc i play on your
tv
you too bbc you know what's bbc
uh something something sweet is from
chinese okay you are bbc youtube okay
bbc iplayer
on your tv you cannot read that now okay
okay
so look how can we use these functions
to remove all the vowels in the string
oh we just we need to replace all the
vowels with each one
with just nothing nothing yeah when you
place the vowels with nothing then
eventually that's that's removing it but
you so you can say return
s dot replace a nothing stop
yeah you keep doing that don't play b
it will take time to write yeah nothing
and detail
replace i nothing replace oh nothing
replace u nothing right
yeah okay then we can do this
we can do a loop right we can do this
for i
in a e i o u yeah right
s equals s dot replace
replace i with y
i with the
return s so look f i will be a
i o u yeah will iterate five times and i
want to replace with i with one
how do i replace it with with to remove
it
uh nothing nothing yeah nothing let that
be
return chinese character okay
so this is a replace yeah and we also
can
use the write it in a very nice uh way
of list look eric pretend
remember this join john alexia
then we can slowly see for c
in s if c
not in what
okay that's another way of doing it and
we also can use them
sorry what difference yeah yeah of
course i'm just yeah define
and then return this okay course and we
can use the filter filter function
theater is the function to
uh okay so read this theater what does
theater mean
either movie theater
no nothing theater you along the theater
something out of something
yeah right like yeah you want to filter
like uh
so look there's a there's a
something like that and it's a very
small hole and then if you give
put all the sand and the bigger sand
stays out
up right the smallest end goes through
so let's call the theater yeah
uh yeah it doesn't make sense so it's
like the whole string here are you under
the theater
only the noun vowels goes through the
vowels stay here right
all right yes so theater
there's a function function function and
then input right
input so let's s and it will give us a
a list of a list of
a generator of a list right so this
function look we can
do this join johnny's right
all right return journalists but this
function we can define what
define this function x we need to define
if it's not a vowel right x
return x not in one
right yeah that's it so we
return join theater
function s that's it and this function
is you need to give it this function
but we can also remove this function we
don't need to declare this we can use
the one line thing
called lambda yeah so instead only of
this we can do this
we can fit it with lambda
yeah you see so you
it's 1 9 return empty string dot join
theater lambda comma s and let
that level be linked to one line right
another way yeah another way so how many
there's so many ways how many ways you
remember so far
okay not really you know you're not
remembering any of this
anyone okay let's not define remove
that's that's why
right together remove vowels
s okay so which way you remember
anyway any any
can you can you finish once
can you write it diddy can you write it
okay answer equals yeah i need anyone
okay i'm this string yeah that's
good okay okay no no
no you don't need the color okay keep
going
four yeah wait we're done keep going for
i
in okay okay that's good keep going keep
going
too larry i don't know why okay okay
keep going all right foreign
okay okay if what if i
not in what
i um
okay i know okay writing okay okay
answer one sorry you need to have a
space piston yeah that's okay
wow this is a very clever one okay
yeah yeah yeah well done ryan wear them
look but one one thing you have to you
need to have a space
right when you go to when you have a
column you need to have a space
yeah this needs to shift in here right
doesn't make sense and this needs to
come with that yeah yeah
for c that's e is
um
that's it we're done today