go hey hello mr mr ryan how are you
today
okay so remind me what is final research
tree
[Music]
can you draw yeah draw quickly and
explain to
[Music]
i'll do a three here and draw here
okay well so what yeah you draw a binary
tree and it's finally says tree so what
makes it binary that's true
on the right right side is greater than
the parent and on the left side it's
uh smaller yeah yeah so smaller and then
look
this is this is on the right side of one
so it should be bigger right but it's on
the left side of the three so it's
smaller right
yeah so on which
order would give it a sorted list
which order remember we have the
pre-order in order for solder
yeah you know what in order yeah
so left no right right so it's never
known right you'll be zero one two three
four right
it's a sorted list and how about if it's
a
breakfast search what which order is it
it's
one zero three two four yes level by
level and how about pre-order
uh that would be one zero three two
four one zero three two four and how
about post order
okay that will be
zero uh like zero
two four yeah three
one we're done okay so you got it okay
so
how about if i give you a range like
let's say
uh 2 2
4 2 left equals to 4
and i i want you to find out the sum of
all the notes within this
range inclusive 10 yeah can t
be in it yeah that's right well i said
inclusive when you say increase
when it's inclusive you put a bracket
yeah this is inclusive
yeah there will be two three and four
yeah
and if it's inclusive if it's not
inclusive you put this
curly brace if this is right this
bracket
means two and four is not in it square
means in it okay okay yeah
so two three four right the sum would be
nine right yeah okay so hope yeah
today we're task is our task is given
the root of the binary switch
and then the left and the right which
means the inclusive range of the lower
bound and upper bound
we want to sum up the notes within the
range
so how can we do this
[Music]
well yeah you know
like something
oh yeah right yeah
in order yes in order
and then you know so in order notes you
will have
one two three four right zero one two
three four
that would be uh yeah
when you do in order what's the time
complexity of this
oh like ten
and n is the number of nodes yeah yeah
and then one thing you have all in order
so you you
you must store this in an array right
let's also take owen
space right yeah and then you want to
find out the two and four right
two and four for example you find these
two here and four here
and then you just sum it up yeah yeah
and if the two and four is not there you
find the one
between yeah you know okay so how do you
find the two and four
okay
[Music]
you are doing the linear search right
can we do better because it's already
sorted
so we can use what linear search is o n
right
you'll find another one term right yeah
so what
how can we do it better make it better
if it's just salted remember if it's
salted we want to find an element in the
sorted list
we can use you know cut in half
again yeah what's that name called
binary
binary what yeah we're done binary word
final research come on yeah you want
because this is
sorted and you want to find the number
it's finally searching okay
wait we're done right binary search
okay but and you'll find two two times
the binary search login right
yeah and then you sum it up right so
that complexity is still on because
you've got the o and
right at the beginning can we do better
yeah can we do better
do we actually need to perform this in
order
wait wait wait wait wait actually wait
you stop
you start from here and wait okay
you don't need to check this one because
because it's smaller
and and it's not in the regular table so
so previously uh you can actually
iterate all the nodes yeah proof of
all the nodes and check each node if
it's in a range yeah that's the proof of
thirds right
and if you want to prove us the uh
integrate
uh traversal the binary issue you've got
a lot of traversing
agreement like uh default search
breakfast search yeah pre-order in all
the
post order yeah as long as you can check
all the notes
in the range right and then you'll check
if it's the inner range you sum it up
right does it make sense
can we do better
wait then let me just implement this
okay and then you can tell me how can we
make it better
i think you've got the idea okay define
okay let's say
as f function we have a root
we have a left we have a right yeah but
we are not using
this at the moment so look if
not load yeah if the load is empty then
we return what
nothing zero right because we only find
the sum right
yeah then we can have answer equals
zero and now we can say if lu dot
value if it's bigger than
l smaller than r then i will i add the
answer it's in the range right yeah
lose the value right all right look if
current node is between this range
i answer i will definitely include no
right
yes and then i can say answer
plus equals f load the left
left right and then can you tell me
what's next answer plus equal one
f with the right yeah
yeah yeah okay so let's complex t what's
the term complexity for this one
oh and because we are we need to visit
all the nodes in the binary tree right
all right can we do better look at
you're right right look if this is one
zero three
two four yeah if we want to
find a between two and four
right look if it wants to find the
between two and four
if it's bigger than it is one
in this range oh no no right
because one is smaller than two right
if we go to the left you'll be also
you'll be even smaller so none of these
notes will be
inside this one right so i need to go to
the right all right that
makes sense yeah so so yeah
yeah i know i know you know so look so
all we have to do is when we're
traveling to the left
we don't need to look so so how how can
do this
so if if so we put it here here
if blue dot value
right if root of value
is is what is bigger than 2
is bigger than 2 bigger than r then we
do this right
then here
here what do we do with this if root of
value
is smaller than r right all right
look if this value is bigger bigger than
then we can go to the left if it's
smaller than 4
then we can go to the right right if
it's bigger than four
we don't need to go to the right because
it's always bigger it's always bigger
than this region right
doesn't make sense so all we have to do
is put two
if yeah without these two if
there will be o n no be blue forcing but
if we pull up
if what's the time complexity in the
best cases
i mean if if if b spine research tree is
balanced
what's the time complexity
square no
a logan where download or login
why is it all again i say it's balance
balance they are unknowns if it's
balanced
interesting you'll be something like
that right
and then you'll be hyped right because
every time you discuss
half of it abandon half of it right so
h is the height of the tree but in
balance
balance spanish surgery h is
approximately log n
right remember how many nodes are there
how many nodes are there seven seven
nodes what's the height
three yeah so log two seven is roughly
three right yeah all right it's all
actually all log two a
is 3. 2 to the power 3 equals 8 right
that's where it comes from okay
yeah does it make sense yeah mommy not
ok so now we this is recursion
yeah where is the recursion happening
where is the recursion
what's a good question oh wait wait wait
talking about itself
yeah it's calling itself and which part
is calling itself
yeah f f function right yeah right
down everywhere okay we can do it
without the recursion
yeah remember previously no no no
we use the stack right to remember that
the thingy
the left tree right three and then we
reverse it right there
a few days ago i show you oh yeah i
think i remember
that yeah you'll remember that okay so
let's do this
what root left
right
yeah just scale mommy a little bit
if not this is the same
it normally returns right yeah okay now
now we have a answer yeah we also have
an answer equals zero and now we have a
stack
we have a stack equals at the beginning
we put a load in it
right right and then
wire while this stack stack is less and
it's not empty while there's element
stack
we want to pop it current
equals stack how do we get the element
from the stack
oh we pop it yeah pop
okay now look if caroline
you currently look if
it's current and if
current of value is
in a range in the range we we add it to
the answer right
10 yeah answer i say it's a number yeah
current of value
level what and then here if current
value is bigger than left
right then we we put it in a stack stack
dot append
yeah okay we put it in a stack so we put
it in the stacks
current or left okay
and then if what current value
what smaller than one ah
on the right side then we do this stack
dot append
current one right right right turn and
right
on the stack and then return what answer
we can answer so you see we're using a
stack yeah you're using a state
let's do that example okay
one zero three
[Music]
okay let's take at the beginning is put
a one here right
yeah answer is zero answer is zero
so and the answer equals zero
we get an element from stack take it out
if if if this current value
is between two to 4 no
then i skip this if current value is
bigger than
2 no right
if current value is smaller than r yes
because
1 is r small r is 4 yeah y is smaller
than four right
then i put it right which is three
put it here in a stack here right okay
and then i go to the next
i take the element from three
if three is smaller than two uh is it
between two and four
yes then we put a three add it to the
answer so angle
plus three which is three if three
is bigger than one yeah
bigger than two yeah three
now we are three bigger than two yes so
we put the left
which is two on the stack right here
yeah
if three is smaller than four
yes we put the right on the stack which
is four
okay yeah okay the next one
we take it off take the four off
if 4 is smaller than between 2 and 4 yes
we add 4 here right
yeah all right it doesn't have anything
it doesn't have
because you put it left and right and
you'll be empty and it will be
you will not come in here again and then
another thing is two
take it out okay two is between two and
four yes plus two
so the answer is three plus four plus
two
nine yeah with an answer does it make
sense yeah
does it make sense okay what's the time
complexity as well
are you logging in
right this is the same as the previous
one including bracket
yeah it's the same what's a space
complexity
why is
thank you very much yes i want to do
some beatboxing people think
ryan you want to do something boxing
brian you want to do it no okay
okay that's it that's it for today see
you tomorrow bye