go hello hello mr
mr ryan how are you today good okay so
yeah today we talk about the maze
what is maze it's like you're in the
maze and you need to go
[Music]
yes okay so look need to be hard
not easy okay so given look
um let's just try this how can how can
we
draw a maze good good one okay
hey the zero zeros are the party cooker
and the ones are the wolves
that that's gonna be super easy
yeah so zeros and uh empty space you can
walk one
the wall okay one wall
and west engine engine is the top left
yeah yeah engine yeah
and when's the exit yeah the bottom
right
exit so here look you can go here
oh i can go here go here go ahead go
ahead go
go go yeah okay so
what's the shortest distance one two
three four five six seven eight okay
so eight steps the the shortest distance
is that
however however if i broke it
here there is no way now you need to
tell me it's minus one
right doesn't make sense if i block it
there's no path
yeah if if the
axis is one you always return minus one
or the entrance is my
one you'll return minus one as well
right because the ancient and uh
are blocked okay okay so is it clear
is it clear this problem is it clear yes
how do we solve this
okay with a matrix magic okay
so one over is shortest distance okay we
want the shortest distance
and it's uh it's you can you can expand
it as like a
search graph search problem right
how do you search your graph with the
shortest distance
uh
[Music]
yeah yeah
and then i'll give you a hint okay so at
this point
at any point i can go to four direction
right oh yeah i like
you you can be comfortable here okay
so so look if look look if
this entrance i can go to the four
directions right or two directions yeah
possibly four right even here okay so
look
you can expand it as the next four nodes
so what does it look like and i know
here you can have
another directions until we reach the
end
what does it look like every tree
yeah but how do we travel this look and
here you have
another four maybe or maybe three and
here you have another one four
and here you have another what what is
it and then go to the next level
the binary tree is actually like going
in quarters
so what does it look like no so what
does it look like if i
push this one and then the next step and
then the next step
and the next step an alien so look this
is step one
now this is a step one first step
two step what's this search come on
[Music]
because look here as i give you our
hinge
you will visit the next next step and
with next step
okay enough enough and whenever you
you visit let look the breakfast search
gives us the
guarantee of the shortest distance right
guarantees the shutting this time right
yeah yeah because look i reached the
step one
with the step two if but the first
first time if i meet i am an exit
it i can guarantee is the shortest am
right
yeah doesn't make sense okay so let's
break research so we can we can treat
this as a graph okay
this is what it's like yeah okay let's
go
[Music]
let's do this i'll give you already the
hint look a shortest distance square
graph and can we solve this using the
temperature yep
yes maybe but breakfast search is ideal
here because therefore search you always
go to the
right you always go as deep as you want
but you don't know if you let loads
these three exit right you might
spending time
trying uh impossible path i'm right yeah
doesn't make sense
this looks easy escape mix
rules is length of metric right and
column
is length on the you know the first
metric so it's
m0 right right okay
look okay okay look
if rows equals zero all columns equals
zero returns minus one if the mac
is empty i i just return okay i'm not
going to write here but it's good to
check if it rows equals zero or
column equals zero what does it mean it
means the main is empty
language times minus one okay and look
if maybe zero
zero the first top element is is one
minus t or minus three oh m minus
one minus one eric can you tell me what
this means n minus one minus n equals
one
what do we do we turn what we turn
false minus one minus one all four yeah
okay so look if m 0 so which element is
this
m 0.
yeah minus one the last element yeah so
if either of them
is one it means the entrance or the axis
is blocked when we do ten minus one
doesn't make sense yeah
how can you smash it okay
smash what kind of data structure we
need to use to implement
[Applause]
what kind what function i will use what
kind of class are we using to define the
queue
class solution
and it has a double end you can push and
pop in
okay okay now look so first of all we
need to
push the first element into the queue
right so which is the
look alright q q equals
d q okay
and i'll push the zero zero the first
first coordinate yeah
we are here right engine and we we need
one step right yeah there's a
tuber yeah one and then bracket
yeah right yeah we put the first step
okay ryan can you see that please
now
what do we do
[Music]
we are at this position r c and the
current
current distance okay current distance e
equals
q dot dot one to the one
we don't take
left because it's sticky it's problem
okay
can we focus on the drawing okay
look yeah look if
r equal equals rows
minus one right and
b equals columns minus one what does it
mean
[Music]
right so there are four possible
directions right
we are coming we are here so where can
we move
all right we are here so where can we
move next one
we're here this hair yes
and then this and this yeah but we need
to check if it's one yeah
level direction you can go four
direction right yeah
but if you want to do that you need hulk
smash
oh smash oh no we know he's gonna smack
okay
[Applause]
four d like now we look d
r b c in four direction now we can do
this look
zero one this is the offset yeah
zero one means that right right
one zero is what if zero one is y
one zero is one left no no no
zero one is right zero minus one is left
and one zero is one
one zero down the bottom
look because it's rows rows all right
this is rows this is columns yeah all
right
look zero one means what rows plus zero
columns plus one so it's on the right
right
yeah doesn't make sense
okay look and then nr equals
r plus dr can you tell me nc equals one
c c plus pc
dc
smaller than rose right and
and what
rows the new rows is between the size of
between 0 and rows and then
and then nc 0 smaller than
nc smaller than color right yeah
also also n and one
and m and r
and c is not the it's not the wall so
what what's your idea
if it a new the next picture is
not a wall so what should i put here
e m is n r and c is not
equal to one it's not equal to
and
so i'm here at an r on the current
position rc
and the next partition is n r and c try
to try these four directions
and if the next direction is still in
this maze not brought
not outside the maze and also it's not
a wall so what's the wall picture here
what's the wall picture
somewhere come on
look i'm here can i can i move here no
right no
no so i need to check it and not see not
equals what
one just one come on if it's not a wall
like what should i do i should
push it to like a pen yeah a pen all
right
put it into the key remember remember
the process remember to spill remember
the boyfriend
yeah take one element push all his kids
to the
to the kid to the queue right right so
what's your
appearance what should happen
d is the distance current distance is d
so what's the next distance
nd there's no nd what's the next
distance
n m now i'm here at t
i work stable what's the d i work one
step
one yeah d plus one come on
down okay return
if i hit return one return one
outside should finish we still can't
find the exit
here return minus one let's not answer
come on there's no
there's one problem this is the basic
basic of the breakfast search but that's
one
tiny problem
it's like look if i'm here all right
yeah
if i'm here i push it next step here
right but when i'm next step here
i also push it back the next step right
so it doesn't make sense so if i keep
working here left
right and i when i do this search i
expand and go to the left
i go back to the original place doesn't
make sense
do you understand so how can we solve
this problem because
thank you breakfast you look eric look
so
i'm here at this position uh my next
next step
include moving to one step to the left
right
but now when i'm visiting this step
popping it from the queue
and my next step including the right i
pop it to the right
so what does it happen i'll keep moving
here
you'll never find me exit am right yeah
doesn't make sense do you understand the
problem
do you understand the problem yeah okay
it's all kind of soft
we're using uh hulk smash
no no no we're using uh some kind of
thing
[Music]
the notebook is the data structure to
see
to re remember something right so here
look
we use we use the notebook scene okay
we have we've seen this before c equals
set right
all right yeah and then here what should
we put here
here here right here i i edit before
this
what did i edit if
ah c
sin right we have seen this before
right yeah i mean we have seen this
location before we continue
so we we don't want to continue right we
want to
continue to the next iteration and
otherwise what do we do
at one and what can can you tell
me
so if our scene is not is already seen
we have visited rc position we need to
continue
otherwise what would we do we should put
it in
so i append
and edward edward
we are done
[Music]
in the map like the normal thing is in
the llamas in the maze the pictures in
the base okay what's the space
complexity
why
[Music]
yeah okay let me see
if there's anything missing here no
today we get
now time for a breakdown okay wait
wait no yeah
shaking every time can you not shake
this okay please oh yes
[Music]
okay yep and now i got it
ryan yeah
uh yeah okay and what
and what so if the next pixel is not a
wall
the next pixel is not a one and what
bracket let's call it
have a square bracket yeah and
what you can use this is
nc no no no bracket you need to look at
this
[Music]
and then d plus one what's t plus one
space no no no what are you doing you
want to check
n r and see if it's not is that
not equals one right here right and
[Music]
c and then what did i say
here here what not equals one
not equals one column
and what do we do we should push it
append it to the queue
if the next fixer is yellow basically
we're saying that if the next pixel is
yellow
so we find a new step so we need to push
it into a queue right
[Music]
yep
yeah no no no another another bracket
two brackets two curly bra uh two
brackets are
points of this yes yes that's a tuple
right
yeah and then smart
yeah what are we pushing yeah i know
what
[Music]
yeah can you explain what what is d plus
one
because definitely a minute
can you not shake that's it
that's it bye bye bye bye
bye bye bye bye bye can you do the big
boxing