yeah hello hello
everyone hello ryan hello hello
yes uh remember yesterday we talked
about this bfs yes
this is jumping game okay
so let me just review it let us review
this
a little bit so
we have look we have a list of numbers
yes one
zero two 2
1 4
okay and then possibly let's do it um
yeah let's do it one here okay
so if if we start at this position
look yeah we can go this way two two
step
we can go backward two step
okay so
one way of jumping to this zero is
alright look at me
look is
to here
and i go back to these and go back to
two
then here or you can do this too
many ways here and and then jumping one
here right
yes so remember this bfs
we search the tree for if we are at the
two right we are at this position too
so now i can go to this partition
which is to the one or go to
this position this other one yeah
so this is the left one that's the right
one
that's right i'm just learning about the
bfs
no i'm just i i will introduce the
another
concept later left one okay and then now
if it's left one and then i can do this
yeah which is yellow or list which is
left one yeah you see so so the point is
that
every one every time i take a level i
take
the note in the tree and i expand it
expand the children which is
two right and i take this and i can
expand it are we today we're learning
dfs
yes yes great job because
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah okay so
let's
yeah dfs so yes today we are talking
about dfs so what's dfs
daniel dinosaur first
okay this right this is first
and that's the search right
bfs join my first search
breakfast search and these death that's
the
photo therefore search okay that's
only depth yep that's what's up
so so again using this look
so we're talking about this please right
so if we are two
so how does it reflect this to this
problem
okay ryan you need to be careful okay
pay attention
two then i can go to one
and then i search these to two again
and then two you see so it's
the different search is that i pick a
path
yeah and then i go as long as far as i
can right
you see yeah so
so so let's let's do it in
code okay so how do we do it
how
[Music]
so look here dfs
and stuff on the list this is the least
this is the map we have the list
the numbers we're talking about the
numbers
and s is the starting point right
so now we first of all we need to check
if the starting point is zero
then we say if the starting point
here is already zero it means we have
reached the destination right
so what what should we do now we return
can you guess here written what
because we already visited it right
okay so now if i'm at this position as
so how many choices can i do no no no
how many choices do i have
if i'm at one position how many choice
do i have
two two yeah because i'm jumping forward
or backward right
so now two choice so f4 i
in minus one one that's a list
minus one false not yet
minus one is jumping backward one is
jumping forward
then now we need to check we need to
check
if the partition has uh we need to
calculate the next position right next
will be equals s right currently is
s plus i
times n s right
yeah so what does this mean this means
that i'm
at this position and if this number is
one then n
square bracket s is one and then minus
one or times one
plus s now currently i will put this
position right
now we need to check if this position is
within the boundary
yeah if
next bigger than zero or
bigger equal than zero and next
smaller or equal the length
length and right not smaller than lens
you can't jump off out of the boundary
also we need to make sure the position
has not been visited before right so we
we can do this by passing a
notebook function right a notebook
dictionary which it will be
let's call it notebook and then that's
using a set right and then the column
here
so now and if this next position
is not in not in notebook
so it means we haven't visited the
partition before then what we do
we first of all we add a petition into
the notebook right so notebook
dot add next
now okay so now we we have the
blue no no no
do you still remember the question yeah
calling itself so now we need to call
the function very very very good
if dfs recording this function and
what should i be passing here next
position is
s now s is current partition what's the
next position
uh i now what's the
next next partition next right s
at i times n so next i pass on the next
and then what in the notebook if this
function return true then i return to
right
return two okay
if this returns now remember we need to
remove
remove this position remove this visited
so that the next step the next time
yeah next time because there are two
lateral partitions possible partitions
possible steps so i need to remove these
for the next move right if i jumping
backwards
which i didn't find a solution
then i have to jump forward
to try right okay so and then what's
what's next what's here what should i do
here return
false yes because after this if we can't
find it
we return first right okay so do you
see yeah i see i see it
yeah i see it
so look at this notebook when we add it
we need to remove it right
i yeah it's better you can also you can
put this here but i don't think it's
quite necessary because
look if this has to come come in pairs
if you add it to the notebook then some
somehow you need to take it
print yeah bfs huh what do you mean
um
[Music]
yeah it's optional okay for this one you
don't because
we already returned true so we don't
need to remove the remove the item from
the
platform but this one do you understand
why we need to remove it here
look suppose if i'm jumping backwards
right jumping backwards this is jumping
backwards
right and i put this number i put these
two in a notebook
i jumping backward and i found out i
can't get the solution i can
i can't find the path by jumping
backwards
then the next one i should be jumping
forward right
if we jumping forward and then you need
to unmark a mark at least position you
have been
visited because this belongs to the past
jumping backwards and then you'll need
to take it out
right so this is definitely search so do
you see
look if if i give an s i give it an
s i if i can find the path
yeah yeah yeah don't and and i i would
go through
i go i will go as deep as i can by
following the past until i found one
right
you see that's called different search
yeah
it's like it's like a maze yeah you see
a maze yeah
you are here entering you are entering
you are here
yeah and then here's it it's exit
exit and there are some there are some
parts here yeah
and then the first search is that okay
if you can find
a path you just go as steep as you can
as
the demands until you find it that's
cool
yeah yeah i know i've been tested how
what's best for research first version
is like no no no question search is like
that okay
okay what's the next step you can go
okay here
and then i can go here i can go here i
try to to go here and then i
pick the one here and i go pull up yeah
i know i know this is stiff fs
eat that versus preference is like that
yeah
and then you retreat and then you go
more you see
do you understand so it's like you you
are trying to expand your
territory until you find here do you see
it
yeah let's copy your vessel and dfs is
you find the path
you just try to go as much as deeper as
you can until you hit the
obstacles and all you are in you
you are in a place that you don't find
any more
exits right okay so do you get it this
is cfs and bss dfs okay so you need to
print
brackets bff that's just to test how we
the
uh how our solution is okay so
any questions no okay do you want to say
goodbye