hello hello mr mr ryan how are you today
good okay so today uh we talked about
the binary tree again so can you tell me
what's primary
uh binary tree what finally means what
is the dream
just finally tree okay so it's a tree
no yeah where's that numbers numbers or
values which one is the root yeah
and then we got the leaves right okay
okay can you put something on the left
side okay it's
smaller than the ring let's find a
research tree we're talking about final
tree it doesn't
necessarily have this kind of property
okay so finally what's finally
what's primarily mean t two
okay
so okay so seven okay so that's good
finance how many leaves are there four
four what are those seven three you got
nine okay so how about look
if i changing this to these and can you
tell me what did i do okay
wait okay wait wait
okay seven three one nine okay
and that will be 16
that will
[Music]
plus seven fifteen ten and is one plus
nine plus zero
ten and six and and sixteen
plus ten plus two equals
twenty eight we're done so basically a
note we are changing it to the sum
of the all the nodes in the current sub
tree right
all right so this node will become the
sum of
the subtree right so we call it
what all right we call it this one we
call it elephant tree
elephant tree because so big anything
yeah
okay shape of elephants
okay okay okay but look yeah we're
making this elephant okay so let's say
we want given the binary tree we want to
make it anything
how can we do this oh defined then we
say
elephant dream elephant okay elephant
elephant tweet
elephant okay
[Music]
how can we do this how can we do this
i'll give you a hint breakfast
deficit
but it's difficult to do it in a reverse
order right
definite search okay so the default
search is better suited in this case
and how can we do this when we we travel
a tree
yeah recursively and when we reach the
leaves
yeah so basically we can come up with a
function to return
remember return the sum do you still
remember we how how do we return the sum
of uh
three can we write that first okay so
then i tell you okay
look all right define let's say sum
okay so make sure you guys step out the
way okay
so how can we return the sound mary oh
if not loot
return what uh nothing yeah because
we're gonna sound right here okay
all right look uh answer equals
load of value right yeah
and answer plus equal one
value
length because look this is calculating
the sum of the left branch
this is calculated in the sum of the
rubrics
any time i see answers okay yeah because
i let me give you a name
answer okay look look here yeah
answer yeah answer is we take this
function return the sum
of the current tree right right
so all we have to do is what we're
changing this
root of value equals one
and make it in decrease what is missing
here what is missing here all right
it equals the trend value
yeah return value yeah yeah does it make
sense yes
yeah answer answer all right
why does doesn't make sense i know we
can just do this
um maybe we change it to dfs okay
definitely
okay and i will change this to default
search
does it make sense and then here
therefore
root okay and then return load yeah all
right
all right okay okay so this function
look at
this function
if i remove this bit yeah if i remove
this spit what happens
if i remove this bit this is just
getting return the sum
of the loads all right so you'll be all
right look
you'll be like that one two three
and that'll be four that'll be five
so dfs root if i don't have less thing
it will return what will return
one plus two plus three plus four plus
five right
yeah you'll be returning 15 right yeah
so all i have to do is do the value
equals one value equals the value
answer yeah so if i change leads
that what happened so leads will not be
doing anything right yeah this will not
do the only thing
six yeah then you become six
and you'll become eight and then you'll
become 15
right doesn't make sense yeah so look
if we don't if we do this if we can do
this
answer equals to the value
and then look if lou don't left
right he would do the left with release
and then here
if do the right right we can do this
if left right is that going to listen to
this right let's make sure what's the
time complexity
um
[Music]
okay so have we talked about getting the
sum of uh
using this final step for search before
do we i am not sure that's what i'm
asking i mean do i have
have you heard this but you understand
this yeah
the only difference is adding this yeah
you see this is
the only difference because we need to
when we
get when we can because this answer at
this point
is the sum of all the notes
at least loot and below yeah all right
and then all i have to do is change
leads
to answer right and you recursively
it make sense all right look here the
root of sum will be
six right before it's six and then i
change it to
six before it's two and i change it to
six doesn't make sense
that's the only tricky part here today
do you
see why we adding this because
previously you already know this
different search right
root dot equals current root right
if root of left equals left if root or
right but we have to make sure the root
is
not empty yeah so you yeah does it make
sense yes
yeah okay does it make sense
if i erase any these speed can you write
it
just this bit can you write it yeah it's
easier
do you understand you need to understand
that i can't really erase it
so i can help you okay bye okay
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah try
try your best okay don't worry about if
you make mistake okay
ryan you want to help girl
[Music]
so what are we doing in this functioning
okay
[Music]
is
we are going to answer yeah this is
answer the answer yeah
answer answer plus equal
on the plus equal yeah and the plus
equal one
because it will be dfs yeah
[Music]
okay
yeah because today will be 11. okay you
want to do some beatboxing
hey
that's not big boxing
okay