hello hello mr mr ryan how are you today
good good okay good good so remember
uh what is padding drum uh either way
that spell backwards is the same
perlinger
[Music]
can you write the pending drum egg
thingy like
check check palindrome okay i need a one
can you can you do it do you know how to
do it
yes okay so can you write it it should
be very easy remember is
[Music]
it's also the same as
yeah and then put it what
what is it outside or it's outside
almost there and then equal
it's a reverse version should be the
same as what come on you're quite close
yes yes yeah no no you don't mean the
column okay and that's
one way of doing this
can you think of another way of doing
that return reverse s
reverse equals yeah also also you have
two pointer remember i j and i'm moving
towards
each other right yeah okay okay
okay let's find this right okay so sorry
so today's our task is come on come on
enough
now what you do drawing ryan a computer
a computer
okay come on area
no no let's okay so how about if
today we want to check a string
we want to check the string if it's a
paragraph but you also can we only want
to
only check the lowercase so for example
like a
r one two a uh three
c d
e 2 c
question mark a r so you need to tell me
this is a
noisy padding drum why is that because
we only check ah the lowercase r a
c e c a r we ignore all other letters
does it make sense say r a
c e a
[Music]
does it make sense so this is called
noisy planing drum because we only
consider the lowercase we don't consider
uppercase letters the numbers the
question on the special characters
yeah so does it make sense so it has to
be passenger and
it is in there yeah yeah so
so basically the first step is to remove
all the characters
other than lowercase right and numbers
other other than the lowercase so all
the
non-lowercase letters yeah we don't
consider that right
so you take away all the numbers all of
the category letters
and all
characters other than lowercase we drop
it off
what do they look like then we check if
the remaining is the pending
okay so let's see what
what did it look like before before it
was just any
sometimes kind of you know you see i put
any letters
in between right so so just to mess it
up but you need to tell me this is the
noisy
noisy parallel correct noise
why is noise because we only consider
the lower case
all other characters are annoying okay
does it make sense can you tell me how
to do it
oh yeah take away all of it
[Music]
okay so
okay look before i
let's just go in front of your eyes okay
so how come how can we cut away can you
listen to me
don't draw listen to daddy okay can you
just
can you tell me how do you do it
we can construct a copy right yeah so
you tell me okay let's say
all right let's say the new string okay
new string
equals nothing right and then for
i in s if
if i is not a lowercase how do you check
if it's a
if if the character is clear lowercase
or no lowercase
how do we check if a character so if lee
c is a character and how do we cherry
with the
lowercase
all you can do is look because lowercase
remember this ascii is continuous right
from a to z right
so you can do this smaller equals
z bigger equals
a doesn't make sense yeah so c is
between a
and z so it's a lot right does that make
sense
yeah yeah can we do it can we do it this
way right
yeah oh this array
please it's the same as what eventually
c top
is lower that's
it doesn't make sense so this
will return true if it's a lowercase
yeah
and how about look c dot is upper
yeah then let's
and also this is digit make it yeah
so your digit is the same as what can
you tell me is digit
is equal to one it's digit equals
okay what doesn't that mean what's in
there
ascii 48 is asking yeah
asking this one how many a couple of a
uh who is 48
50 65
if i is is lower
so what should we put it here if i is
lower ns
bigger look ns is the new string we want
to
make it only add
what does it mean you want
now ns contains the characters not
only the lower case so we want to check
ns if it's a pending term right
so you just grade word at the beginning
okay
so it's return yeah return
okay and then what and i said
how do you check an assistant location
yeah
yeah okay okay man
wait yeah
that's it what's the term complexity
what's the term complexity
yeah you can say well what's your
special capacity
what's a space compression can you
listen to that
what's the space complexity
[Music]
as i said the string is very slow right
you just keep adding it so it's better
to do it
look leave it yeah you can do this a pen
yeah
open yeah okay i and ns is the list
now then you can you can do what you
want to check is that
you can also compare with the list with
this so it still works okay
so it's better to use the list okay so
how about we uh using the
how about array how about however we can
we can
what we can do we can use the two
pointer and skip the
skip to next lowercase right
hey oh
can we it's not drawing missing come on
guys
i don't want to do this again come on
okay
oh okay and equals l and
s right and then i i'm
j equals zero m minus one right
left and right yeah less than right wire
i smaller than j if two pointers not
meeting each other right lamba we need
to skip
we need to skip ryan can you sit there
please what we want to speak the long
none lowercase so how can we do this
while i are smaller than j again right
and if not
what s i dot
is lower right does it make sense
then i plus equals one doesn't make
sense so when
i kind of when i
current position that that character is
not the
lowercase we keep moving until it's it's
lowercase right
please a b c
[Music]
this this is j here right at the
beginning right
yeah why are you smaller than me
when i skip it look why i smaller than j
right i is here right
j is here and s i is lower is it lower
no right not little become true right
this is not lower right and i smaller
than j
i keep moving i plus one right yeah it's
still not
lower case right i move it so i will be
here
right then i plus 1 and then the same as
y is more than j and
not s j dot is lower right
then how what should i do here 31 minus
equal to 1 3 you'll come here right
right over here and i look then what
should we do
if s i not equal as sj what should we do
above okay and then i i need to
what i need to i plus equal one and then
one
so does it make sense yeah this is look
do you know all right
why is it noisy the only only special
part here is these two pins
right yeah if you take away these two
white loop is the same of checking if
the string is charged am i right
yeah because previously we have we know
that
if we if we without this bit that would
be the standard
equals one yeah yeah that would be if we
don't have this
part that will be checking if the
strings are present right
but now we need to add these because we
want to skip
non-lowercase characters right yeah we
don't want to speak
skip uppercase the of marker the
question mark
whatever integers right other than the
numbers yeah
okay so let's let's leave speed what's
the time complexity
what's a space compression a1 oh one
come on we're not using any space
right yeah i like i went yeah
okay okay can we come look at this is
this
this this is actually how we doing it
you need to understand how we're doing
but in python we can use the
simple syntax yeah i show you a couple
of functions to use in the
syntax all right look look alright look
a equal let's see at
out let's filter out the the the
long lowercase characters eric look you
can do this
c alright look for
c in s in s
and can you tell me what's right if what
if what c for c in
s is what c
[Music]
we want to keep the lowercase okay yeah
it's lower right
yeah and then and then you can just do
this return
a
yeah you see less easier yeah
or you can do is the what the y i is
smaller than j
thing it depends on how you like yeah
yeah right okay
yeah yeah we're done look and look
okay suppose we speed you can do this
eric this is a list yeah you can
do it as a generator and you put a list
here right
right this is the same thing eric a
equals list
this is the generator can you listen to
me i am c for c
is the same yeah oh you can do this
let's
you can do this already a
equals what
this i know we use the theater function
theater
what's theatre remember to filter out
something a theater language
function we can call it lambda i order f
first
and then s and what's f oh uh
let's call it g you can do it define
g c return
c dot is lower right that will be easier
and all you
you you move this you change this g to
lambda lambda
g g dot is lower
and then you gotta add return a and
return this is the same way return
a minus minus one equals equals a y
okay so this list using the field
function the fact remember we talked
about this a few days ago the field of
function
the function you can define it as a
separate function or a lambda function
you will go through the list go to the
string or list in the second parameter
and then check only only return
when the function return true right so
in this case it's the lowercase
right so your filter the string in s
characteristics and only keep
the lowercase right does it make sense
yeah
oh we also can do one okay
or we can do this s0
equals look yeah
c for c in
in s if c dot is lower right this is 5
you know right yeah and then s1
equals c for c
in reverse
reversed s if
c is lower right and then now s 0 and s
1 are
in the reverse or order right so it will
be a b
c d and then s 0
if i just do this if a b b
c a b b c the s zlo will be a b b c
if we filter all the other characters
right and s one will be c
b b a in a reverse order right because
this is reverse order and now
we just need to check if s zero equals
everyone right
all right yes doesn't make sense right
yeah then what we can just return
something because this is that we can
return
another function we can call all of it
all with
a equals b for
a b in
chip s c l o s one can you tell me what
it is
i say it's not a drawing lesson come on
can you listen to me
all function so the old function with
return true
if this condition holds so a equals b
if chip remember what's give function
array
look at the a is one two three
right b is four five
six so what's the g function of a b one
t
function of a b what does it what does
it remember
so you become one four
two five three six three six
yeah and then look if this is longer
if it's one is longer right hey
if one is longer the second one is
longer it doesn't take right
like seven it is still written left
right but we have a deep longest
remember
we have a deep longest yeah remember
yeah
all right does it make sense deep
longest
so you take the longest and typically
okay but anyway this looks
s1 right if it needs to be the noise
representation it has to be
a equals b for every kind of test right
yeah when the gpd has to be the same
right yeah
okay yeah okay so can we do other
things here no no no yeah
no yeah so
so any other method let me just double
check i think i think there's other ways
of doing that
is that you can directly do this yes
define fs
can you take it i'm going to test you
okay you need to at least remember one
method of doing that okay
we're not looking you can do this number
function here return
number
x x is x dot
x and x if it's the first version
equals the same right this is the lambda
function to check if a string
is if it's uh if it's uh
if what if it's a num if it's the
reverse uh if it's a parenthesis and
then we can fit it into the last thing
c for c for c in s
if s is lower right yeah this is the
biggest thing this is the function we
define and we're doing now this is the
fancy
syntax okay so can you i i have
presented you so many solutions can you
write simply buy one and we call it
for today okay okay
yeah no easy numbers go the simple one
come on before anyone remember i don't
know
you don't know i do how do you write it
anyway how do you how do you skip the
thingy
skip the uh now lowercase characters
we coded for today yeah remember can you
write it
you you're so close remember what
i think yeah take your time okay take
your time
yeah come on remember
what did i teach you what did i teach
you come on show it to me
yeah yeah that doesn't matter as long as
you remember one yeah
yeah come on write it ryan you wanna
have to have
write this one yeah come on
first of all you need to get filter out
the non-lowercase characters yes
yeah and how do you
how do you theater on the characters no
not
no in uh no no no no no
lowercase yeah big one which measure you
like
come on come on
race car okay
come on i teach you you're not listening
right come on
you want to return you want to figure
out the long lowercase
characters right you only want to keep
the lowercase characters and then
how do you check the how do you filter
out yeah
yeah keep going c in what
s yeah
for c in the s and then what happened
then we want to check if c
is uh lowercase right in
for c in s if if not in
it's c it is lower yeah bracket
the c dot is lower it's a function so
you need to uh
brackets to call it open bracket close
the bracket and i'm using my curly brace
on a square bracket no no no
yeah you're calling your function okay
okay
and then you can write it away 60 yeah
[Music]
is
you're missing something like a equals
what
a too small come on i can't see
okay
[Music]
yeah does it make sense right you say
you understand
yeah yeah okay okay you can do something
boxing