[Applause]
okay so today we talk about
some of four remember we have talked
about two sums three thumbs right
now we talk about four sums sum of four
but today because number four is one
plus three t
plus
[Music]
something like that okay so listen
summer fall is basically like uh
picking four numbers and you have a
target
wear them and we have a lot we have
different ways of doing that but today
we are going to talk about using um
you already know people network no fair
something
yeah kind of performing yeah
how come yeah yeah good question
so let's pick two pick uh four numbers
so let's say two
three four six seven
nine let's pick let's see if they these
any pick any numbers
can add it to uh let's say 21 okay we
want to find the 21
if they have any four numbers adding to
41.
yeah you just need to tell me if it's
two or four that's true
if you can find four numbers four
distinct distant
distinct unique number this thing yeah
you know listen
distinct unique numbers four unique
numbers you cannot pick one number twice
yeah you only pick four numbers we only
pick four numbers
let's sum up to target 21 so we
i give you a hint we can use the default
search of course we can have a two
pointer thing
but let's make it tomorrow or you know
in the future but today we're going to
focus using that research to solve this
problem
it's this one this one yeah and this is
this one
five yeah all 10 1 for 6.
i was thinking but again it's the same
with different answers yes
but we listen to it we only need to tear
we only need to tell if it's possible to
use the four numbers the sum of the 21
10 19 no that's only three numbers
yeah we're on the four numbers yeah so
10 one
four six or three seven yeah yeah
okay so for this so how can we use the
default search
i'll give you a hint that for this
number i can we we can go through these
we can search from the beginning
to the right yeah from the beginning to
the right for each number we can we how
many choice do we have
how many choices do we have number one
if look if i have a different search
function right
if i have a you know which number have
we picked
so far we have a left 10 and then we
have a count how many numbers we have a
pick so far
and then the remaining sum okay the
remaining sum
doesn't make sense so at the beginning
we can put this as
which the target right we want to pick
this number right the target
yeah all right and then this
card at the beginning will be zero all
right
and then we are we need to check if the
count equals four right
we only need the four numbers and left
will be beginning so for
each one let's go to the left to the
right for each one
for each left suppose left is here for
this ten
how many choices do we have for the
number ten
uh then i'm just talking about a 10
how many choices do we for this term
in the final answer like do we have a we
can pick it and not take it well
that's what i'm looking for for each
number we have two choice
pick it or not pick it for pick it if i
pick it what happened to this count
you add column will be valid
no the count will be how many numbers we
have picked so now so what happened to
the count if i pick it
[Music]
how many numbers do we need to pick how
many numbers have we picked so far
if we pick this number so how do i one
add one add one okay so target would be
what how many numbers do we need to
the sum will be minus ten yeah minus the
number right
yes yeah okay let's say minus ten and
then left
then we can go through the next one will
be left plus one right
yeah yeah this is if we pick and how
about if we don't pick
if we don't pick this one right and this
is the spear left plus one right because
we're considering the next number right
counter will be what will happen what
happened to discount if we don't pick
this what happened to this car
look at this if we don't pick this
number
so no no if we don't pick this number
what happens on the count
yes yeah yeah and then this target will
be
one the same person
so you see so the only two choice we
definitely search
if we pick top plus one cop
that plus one complex one target minus
this number
if we don't pick we just skip to left
past one right
and then when left reach the end we
determine first because we run up the
numbers
if count equals four
so look if car equals four what should
we do now if we have already picked four
numbers
but the target is not zero so what does
it mean
what what if we have to pick four
numbers
but the target the remaining sum is not
zero what does it mean
remaining sum remember if we pick 10 we
need to minus 10 right
if it's that if we already pick four
numbers and then current sum
the current remaining is not zero what
does it mean
it means that what's the target remember
we want to pick 21 at the beginning is
21 right
why not fit 21. and then you will pick
10 with 21 minus 10 and
we have a remaining 11 to pick right
if this cow equals four if we already
get four numbers but the remaining is
not zero what does it mean
it means four that means you can you
have to
try again yeah yeah that means that
fourth yeah because
that's what i mean if it's yellow it
means that one it's true yeah we found
the four numbers right
yeah so does it make sense this one okay
let's divide it
ryan do you understand
full time
how long we define the definitions here
right before seven
and we have a left yeah left and call
okay and then attack it yeah another
time yeah
okay look alex
if how all right
if count equals equals four we have
already picked four numbers
so what should we return it
so return t
equal equals zero right doesn't make
sense
if left bigger or equal than
grams what should we do now return one
if we have run out of numbers what
should we do if it lands
yeah return first okay
okay and now we have two choice yeah
we have two choices yeah let's say pick
pick equals what dfs
left plus one right and then what we
picked can you tell me what what should
i put here
left past one and then if we pick right
one count minus
one
if we pick a count how many numbers we
pick one one and then
target minus
skip this number and count one just now
yeah
and then t and then what retinoia
we can return what we have pick and not
pick so let's resize what pick
not pig so eat one of them is true then
it's two right
yeah written pick
or not not pick
remember this is not pig is the
available yeah it's not actually
not right okay and then here
i should i just call this one here right
return pfs
what should i give this number the l
the initial value will be what l is what
the first one is what uh
the first element yellow okay and then
uh
card is what at the beginning we haven't
picked anything and then
this one how many times do i put the pen
target
that's it does it make sense dfs
yeah let me define your inline bfs
function yeah
what's our time complexity uh and
we are picking four numbers so how many
kinds of solutions is it
no four oh and four oh four one
oh and one oh and
to the power four yeah yeah yeah that's
quite because look we have we we are
picking for
then for the next one stays
uh space complexity for why is it oh and
so
why is alpha because they're given n
numbers
we can iterate these n numbers for
in the four roof right yeah choosing
four numbers right
doesn't make sense all right so we can
change the four
i in length right for
j for first number in numbers for n for
second number in numbers for certain
numbers in numbers
and of course for false numbers in them
okay and then we can prove us it doesn't
make sense
yeah we can actually do using this kind
of solution therefore
first number is numb for second number
numbs
why the second number is not equal to
the first number yeah
so actually we can use the range for i
in zero to lunge for j
in i plus one to lungs to n for k
equals j plus 1 to n for
u equals k plus 1
to n and then if nums i plus num
z plus nums k plus lumps u equals t
return true right it also works does it
make sense
and then in that case how many how many
fours so what's the common gravity
what what's the time complexity of this
one
but this one is using the differences
here complexity
for this one it's a one because we're
not using any space this one is
om because we're using the recursion
yeah because you know you have the
left will be from zero to the n right
okay doesn't make sense eric yeah okay
so what should we do at the beginning we
want to check if what
if what we already pick four numbers
if we already pick four numbers we
should check what
we should check which which which
variable is
yellow written
we pick four numbers
yeah this is the same as if t equals
yellow return true ir split and false
yeah we can just put it in the same
thing all right okay you can do some
beatboxing
okay that's it