hey hello mr ryan how are you today
good okay so you know you got money yeah
you got a
1p 5p 10p 25p yeah
okay yeah how about nine no let's just
make it simpler we have a one p
one p coins five p coins
ten p coins twenty five p points
right twenty p coins okay let's
just make it 25 no no no no you're right
it's american it's not it's not uh it's
it's uh it's
it's not british okay it's america's
change okay american chance
in this program we're not american yeah
american
denominations okay so that's one sense
it's one sentence five cents
yes okay okay let's let's look at two
thanks okay
let's just make it these four numbers
one five ten twenty
twenty five yeah and you let's say
if you want to give people like
money like that let's say you want to
give us six what's the minimum
coins you need to that will come up with
six does it have to be exactly
yeah of course there are six one five
yeah one five yeah
two yeah you're all right and how about
five five
how many one okay how about
three uh
three ones yeah that's one one one three
okay so you get the meaning yeah if i
give you a number like uh
12 you need to tell me
yeah okay exactly okay so that's that's
how we make the change so we also know
how
the minimum the mean number of coins
they make up
the money the target money yeah does it
make sense
right yeah you understand the problem
yeah
so how can we do this how can we do it
remember look at this one is a very
special
case it means that the we can all make
it
one right yeah so you'll be less than
the number okay you give it a number n
yeah define how
how what's your approach of doing this
define
uh change making change make sure
like if a number is 12 like after you
said
the small the smallest coin which is
is 10. and then you have remaining of
two
and the tomorrow
okay so i understand your approach so
why not find
a largest largest coin that
is smaller than the target right and now
we use that coin and i will repeat this
yeah
subtract that right yeah yeah does it
make sense how about
uh okay
so answer we want the answer yeah
okay yeah answer and now
look for
the coins yeah eric look four coins in
how many coins there let's uh
we try the biggest one first 25 10
5 1 right yes
it doesn't have to be these ones no we
yeah we know
these four coins and we want to try the
coin let's say we're going to try to
have to beat these coins yes yeah that's
the given
given we know it's four points so he
doesn't have to have
1 5 10 25 no no no no yeah we are trying
so look we want to find out the largest
coin that is smaller than n
right
why is in reverse order do you
understand because we want to
try the largest one yeah yeah yeah yeah
but it is not always 1 5 10 25.
then you put it maybe you want 20 40 20
here or 22 here yeah
this makes sense look look so now
so what so so
how do we try the largest number that is
no
more than uh no more than a target
any idea how we're doing this oh i think
we start at the smallness
no we'll start with the black lives
matter
[Music]
okay so look so how many coins can can
we use the
c 25 so look now we are n right so this
coin
will be n divided by 25 right
doesn't make sense if it's more than 25
like 26 you will you need
125 right if you're less than 25 like 24
this will become zero right
yeah this coin okay then
how many how many of these answer plus
equally
right does it make sense yeah
why okay yeah does it make sense this is
the number of the coins
of the current actually not 25 is
divided by c
right all right yeah look
come on don't work here in there okay 26
okay
and divided by c this is the number of
coins
that this is a number least number of
c coins and with this answer we add it
to the answer and then now what
i do i need to remove it n minus equals
please comes one
i just at least comes with end coin now
we are
we want to make up n choice but now we
know you need
your time c and then what should we do
if it becomes
zero it becomes yellow so we do
we return it whether i'll break the loop
yeah break the loop
they break it will break this loop and
then return answer yeah
yep yeah or or you can just directly
return answer here it's the same yeah
return your written answer but you you
if you write an answer then you don't
need to write here but it'll be better
if you just return
because we want to beat an answer when
it's zero right it when it becomes zero
you want to return zero so
we just break break what's what does
break mean
break with double link yeah we just
normally being a
so break loop means that yeah we don't
want to continue with the loop
right we just we just skip
no skip we should exit let me determine
yeah it doesn't make sense
yeah yeah okay i'm going to do it
okay what's this i remove one thing here
um
yeah because we need least number of
coins yeah
okay okay what's the time complexity
oh one what what
i win
[Music]
yeah because we only tried four
iterations we already know it's four
integration this doesn't change
and look this calculation is this all
right
this calculation we can we can it's the
same thing as look look
this one this one yeah this is the four
iterations of calculations so basically
we want to know
we can determine look return and
how many nodes of 25 yeah how many coins
of 25 yeah
all right this number of 25 coins plus
and you remain 25 right and then
what and then 125 how many
20 how many how many 10 are there right
you remain 25
divided by 10 plus remain 25
and then we meant 10 how many five of
that
right and plus and remain 25
remain the 10 remain 5 how many one of
them that's
right no that's it doesn't make sense
the least can be turned
into one line
this is the number of 25 yeah plus
remaining of 25 is this big look
this bit is this speed yeah we speed and
now we need to
we divide it by 10 to compute how many
coins we need and then we we
this number keep dividing uh remaining
ten
and how many five of them yeah and then
the next is how many one of them
doesn't make sense so these can be
changed into these
yeah but this is more straightforward
approach yeah
we agreed we could easily try
the largest coin right right
we tried the largest comb 25 and then we
tried 10 we tried five we tried one
doesn't make sense yes all right
how about we can use the dynamic
programming in this case
remember we can use the dynamic
programming error you don't need
memorization
uh yes yes uh not top down button
he's in the cache maybe maybe we don't
another solution look you just remember
that the term convex is
a one for that and our space complexity
is also one right
because we're not uh allocating any more
space for that right
it's always this is very optimal
solution but look
if we use the dp function right
look if fn let's say
if n fm means that the number of
minimum coins to represent
to come up with the target n right yeah
and
you will be equal s
equals mean of all these f
m minus i
right look where
where what i
is one two
one 5 10 25 right
does it make sense yeah will
yeah look fn is the number of the coins
minimum coins to store to come up with
m and then we know we know we have four
choice
so it must be no you know
today and plus one sorry plus one
because we need
one one more right yes doesn't make
sense look
f12
the number of ways the number the
minimum coins
to come up with 12 is equal to
mean of all these yeah f 12
minus one no no f two plus minus one
f two l minus five f two l minus ten
and f two n minus twenty five okay and
then really
yeah because this is too small so yeah
this is too small plus one right
doesn't make sense so it means these
they're they're the previous we can have
f2 right
if we know f2 all right
if we know that f2 we know f2f is f2
plus one right
because f2l is two plus ten right
yeah and we have ten coins does it make
sense very
doesn't make sense this one kind
of yes
[Music]
can you tell me why why is this f12
f2l equals f2m f5
f7 class one can you tell me what's this
f equals
yeah i mean
yeah yeah mean okay so why why is mean
yeah you're right
this is mean why why is that
because we want to make up 12
right yeah and we know that f7 if we
because we have 5 so we know f7 that
the difference between this is that we
have seven and we just need
another five right yeah this is one
solution right
and then if we keep iterating this then
we can find the fn right
doesn't make sense let's try this okay
all right pay attention you you're
losing track you know define
fm what's missing good okay now look
dp let's do it dps dp course
at the beginning we set it to a maximum
value we have float
or max dot infinite
infinity yeah math
times n plus one yeah because of that we
want to
access fn right and dt zlo will be equal
to zero okay
the number of ways to come up with the
nothing
is nothing right yeah now look
for i in range
one m plus one right this is from f1 to
n
for coin in
yeah you all you can use this is the set
1 5
10 25 right yeah all right
look we don't try the coins and then we
want to calculate dp
i yeah dpi from one to n right so the
answer will be p p
one the tp1 the answer return tp1
what ppy well i'll get calculating here
see no no no dp1 no i just said
this is one sorry
f f n is the number of dpn is the number
of the coins
needed to make up the target end return
dpn come on oh dpm dp
minus one right yeah the last one right
now look we are currently targeting
the number i and then we have coin
c if i bigger than
or equal then c right yeah yeah we have
25 coins
if if 25 10 is bigger than one of these
number if
right and
and what dp i
minus c is not equals to maximum
to the infinite area to the inf
and then right because the dpi minus c
we know we haven't uh
we know how to make it up right
doesn't make sense yeah because the
beginning is
infinity if if this dp i'm if i minus c
amount we we don't know how to
make it up we don't know how to come up
with
i minus c then we don't continue
otherwise
dpi equals mean
error can you tell me what was here dpi
i minus c uh
bracket plus one dpi
right does that make sense
yeah we want to compute the dpi minimum
dpi value right does it make sense
is it is it
dp minus 1 the last letter dpn dpn
is the number okay let's do this again
dpn
is the number of coins the minimum
number of coins
if we want to make up n uh
money and amount of n right you want to
come up with the
give if i want to give you amount of end
coins
yeah then you will be stored in dpn
right
right db0 is 0
why is that because like at the
beginning it's nothing
right yeah then the first
iteration i want to compute the i dpi
from dp1 to dp2 to dp and my
n right yeah this is butter up
butter butter up water up
dynamic programming right yeah and then
for each one
i know we have four choice four coins
one five ten twenty five
if if current amount i is bigger than
the coins right
if it's if it's bigger than the coins if
it's smaller than the coin what does it
mean
you're given too much but if i want 10
10 coins
you'll give me 25 this doesn't make
sense right yeah
yeah if i is bigger than c if the number
the money is bigger than the coins the
total amount is bigger than the coins
and if i subtract the coins
yeah we know already if we already know
the number of coins
to make make up i minus the amount
then ppi is equal to
the mean minimum of this value dpi minus
e plus one can you tell me why we plus
one here
because what
why are we plus one what does it mean
can you explain to me
why is the last one oh
because i you know it's not that's
because we're using we
which coin are we using we're using
cornwall
base note i mean yes no no we which coin
are we using i mean
c c of course if because we use one c
then this
is the number of coins adding one more
coin c right doesn't make sense
yeah you get it right yeah we we
use one c coin and then the amount we
substitute
c right does it make sense this is the
amount
we are only making we want to make a
mouse i
and we can use one corner c but
then we substitute the amount from i now
we add one
coin because we use one currency right
that makes sense
now it's clear what's the time
complexity
why is the one
because look this is n yeah we're
iterating n times
but this one we're only eating it in
four times so it's actually
o four times n but we drop the
constant what's the space complexity
are we using the space here and here
we always use in space look why is the
bottom up because we're calculating the
tp1 dp2 db3 until we get the tpi
right ready
which one is better do you think this
this solution is better on the previous
one
previous previous why is that oh because
it's faster
why is that one is faster than this o n
right
yeah and time complexity is a one
compared to one here space complexity is
a one compared to space uh complexity oh
and yeah right
yeah so the previous one is optimum
you can't get better than that right one
is the farthest you can't get
partisan zero minus one right one is the
super fastest
am right yeah because you just give me a
number i just do some mess
and that's it but this one i have to
iterate
linear number of time right you give me
the number a minion
and i need to iterate a million times
that's very slow compared to one right
does it make sense
yeah this is butter up we can also do it
in
top down but not today okay we can also
do this in top down
yeah yeah doesn't make sense
all right how can we do this in top down
all right maybe i can write it down okay
hop down it's crash
yeah calm down
come on i put a catch in there yeah
catch yeah
again n if n
equals yellow return zero right
yeah all right it could be
different number of points is zero zero
four let's do this we want to get the
minimum right answer equals
answer equals the max infinity mass
infinity mass and then for
i in uh
you can do this curly brace or square
bracket doesn't matter okay one
one five ten twenty five right
but
n smaller than zero we return
return a maximum of max dot
[Music]
f m minus i right yeah
and then return after
wait min i don't know plus one i
remember yeah
yeah we we use the coin let's do this
if we use the coin c well then we need i
right yes that's what it says
okay look because if it's smaller than
zero
that will return low return infinity
plus one okay
that's a very special case yes yeah all
right
okay answer equals
z infinity okay let's let it what's the
term complexity space complexity for
this one
sorry all right and yeah it's the same
as
it's basically the same as the
dynamic programming yeah okay
you want to do some thick boxing
oh we're done okay i pulled it out oh
okay wait for the toothpick fairy okay
bye bye see you tomorrow
see you
bye bye bye bye be my pacman
pac-man