hey hello mr eric mr ryan how are you
today
remember a few days ago we talked about
the four some yeah four some
for some so given a list of numbers
one three five two
9 10 and 7
we want to find if they are number four
numbers
these are unique numbers okay if we want
to find
if there are four numbers adding to like
13 can you can you find it
no no no 16 16. can you find six num
four numbers adding to 16
16. can we be multiples
now you can only pick one number each
you know pick the number one each can
you find the four numbers adding those
yeah ten three two one two
[Applause]
but as long as you can find four numbers
that's not a 16. why is not sixteen
seven oh okay three five six okay sorry
okay
okay okay so remember a few days ago we
talked about the blue force
right remember and therefore search yeah
blue force and deficit remember
all right okay so for
the first number in range
let's say sorry
and right and for j
in range remember m plus one
n right four k in
range all right j plus one
and y and can you tell me what's next
four let's say u
in range what what
what k plus one and yeah very basically
we want to loop
four numbers that's the first number
let's set the number the third number is
the first number
each number is the
plus num j plus num k plus nums u equals
k
uh equals target yeah let's return two
right and
at last we can fall right this is the
pull force here what's the time
complexity for this one
n times four o n to the power four okay
not times four times four will be times
four right
to the power and we can use the
different search right remember for each
number
we can choose to pick on our pick
you still remember that definitely let's
do mine
right outside the depth of search
define let's say f udfs
look the left target
and what remain uh target
all the thumb and what
no no yeah that's one parameter missing
okay so we want to look we only pick the
numbers and
for each one we pick on an account right
right yeah so look if c equal equals
four then we return
this fear remember if we have quick four
numbers we want to check if the
target remaining zero right
yeah if left bigger than equal and
length of numbers
we return what if we have already run
out the numbers
yeah this left instance the number
yeah and then we can return return
dfs l plus one t
minus if we pick few numbers
numbers air right and then
count the plus one right you will pick
big numbers or
we not pick right we don't pick l plus
one t
and then c right doesn't make sense
therefore yeah this still remember this
okay there's a lot yeah
yeah what's a time conversion
oh
[Music]
because we we are returning when this
count equals
four right doesn't make sense yeah okay
do you still remember two sum three sum
and then we talked about the fourth sum
two sum three time and in order to do
this sum
we want we we need to have one sound
let's know one thumb okay
how come oh yeah one time yeah it's true
find the number which
equals the target in uh in the list then
we can do one
we can use the what kind of data
structure network
set we don't need to use the actually we
don't need to yeah we just go through
like this and find out okay if this is
the target
boom we'll find it right yeah we don't
even need to use that yeah for i
equals that in the target
find numbers if i equals target return
true
right yeah yeah doesn't make sense
oh look if it's one word about that
look what's the one you can use it says
notebook as well look you can say look
return
is the target target in set
set nums okay or you can just do these
numbers
you can type in num okay that's one sum
okay
one so
okay twosome define two songs
remember how do we to define two songs
yeah we can use the notebook here
remember yeah
or we can one well we can do what we can
sort the array
and then have two pointer remember when
they are equal we find it when they're
smaller
we increase the that point when they are
bigger
we reduce the right point remember
look look at one side give this sort
here
if we want to find if there are numbers
equals to
eight to sum yeah if i
this is the left pointer this is the
right point
left and right point add together one
eleven eleven is and compared to a one
bigger yeah you say you need to move
yeah okay now seven plus one eight okay
okay if it's smaller we move the level
yeah yeah can we apply this thing to the
fourth sound
you know in the three times we can use
this on the on the third number right
yeah alright two three five what's three
thumb
three times we make sure this uh array
is sorted and then we
iterate pull first the first number and
then follow
for example if i already pick the first
number is this one
and i can apply two sum in here right
yeah if i make if i choose the
first number here i can apply to some
doesn't make sense
and how about four thumb for somebody
all right what's further how about we
haven't done three
oh let's pick this one let's do some
okay
if i pick what's the times i pick two
numbers
and i apply two sum
from the on the remaining set okay
does it make sense all right you hear me
yeah doesn't make sense
how about fourth sum i pick three
numbers
and then i took and i can apply the two
some on the remaining and that's that
that's the that's the full song yeah
let's make scenary
so basically for this this kind of sum
problem
we can do what we can sort it the array
first make it sorted using o
and log n time right away
yeah and then we can pick the first
n minus numbers right
then let's owe a one
okay let's say i want to do this k sum
right
one one one strategy is to solve this
array using if this is this k sum
and an element the time complexity for
sorting is o one and what
log n right sorting yeah something
and then for this k sum i want to find
out
i want to blue force blue force k
minus one animals okay so what's k minus
if i want to k minus element so what's
this
n to the power of k minus one right
yeah um am i right
n square three sum is o
and uh
two sum is always square maybe it is
maybe not look if i uh if i
if i do this left and then
right right left and right
that will be that will be o n y or n
minus one so
three thumb three sum i would have all n
k minus one times n right yeah
so oh oh oh okay so three thumb is
basically
uh uh if i'm uh threesome so k equals
three
k equals three so o n
k minus two uh threesome i pick up two
one number pick the second number
and then apply these
no i don't pick the second number and
sorry mistake
so i pick the first number and i pick uh
i apply the
two some on the length so it's okay so
basically we're reducing the complexity
from okay
because we know uh o and k
we can do this k sum using k k times
loop
right so o and k uh this is time
complexity but you
applying these two sum on the negative
the rest two numbers we
we are reducing it to okay minus one
right doesn't make sense
yeah look threesome
let's do this reason for example okay
threesome
three sum if you have three lamps for i
in k range for j in
range and then for k in range that's o
and three i
i already but instead of doing that i
can do this one loop
uh i pick a number first that's n o n
and then i i can apply look two sum on
the rest
that's another n so it becomes o n
squared doesn't make sense
so we are improving the complexity from
o and cubic to o and
square
okay so can we do this on the fourth
song
can we do this on the fourth song
can you do it do this on the whole song
so how can we do this for something
defined for awesome
right lungs
target and equals
lens numbs okay now we don't we need to
solve the number how can we solve the
number
oh we're going to solve the numbers
what's the time complexity
what's the time when we talk about
sorting oh and logan come on
yeah okay okay now now
first time so we need to bluff off the
first two number
and apply the two sum on the rest right
yeah
so for the first number i in range
let's do this when n right
second number for j in range
i plus 1 n right right
right this is true number and now we
want to apply the
next two number a and b okay a b equals
one
so look here is number i i i pick the
first number here i pick the second
number here
and now where's the third and fourth
numbers at the beginning
here this b yeah so this is j plus one
and this is what
n minus one right yeah so a
b equals i
okay now this comma x equals
the sum equals nouns
i plus num j
plus one
plus nums what's your number
which number come one
i already have this a and b okay
okay so now this is the current fourth
sound okay yeah but this is sorted
remember we make sure these
two numbers are chosen and then we want
to try this
we want to apply the two sum on the this
one so if
x equals equal t great we found it
retaining y
wait if x bigger than t what should we
do
come on if this song is bigger than t so
we know we want to move
we want to move which is going down
[Music]
if this is bigger acting bigger than t
so what should we do
which i wish i should move this here or
move the a b minus one
and a has a lot a add one
yeah come on and then we turn away
[Music]
does it make sense that way ryan look
is it is it is it uh okay to you look
try the first number try the second
number
and then i i have picked two numbers so
how many numbers i left
i need two so i i pick the the certain
number is a
numbers at a the first number is numbers
b
and then right now i add all these four
numbers
yeah x you find the target grade will
return true if that sum
look here if the sum is bigger than t we
need to move the right pointer yeah
because there's no point in moving the
left pointer because it's
sorted already if you keep moving the
left what happened it's still bigger
right
so we'll move the b and if it's smaller
and one so look this is
o n o n square and then another one
o and q p compared to o and blue force
or definition right yeah does that make
sense
if i look two sum remember two sum
we just remove this hey yeah
two sum among the three songs sorry
threesome we remove this right
two somewhere to move this yeah you see
so this part is two sum
problem this part is two sum right
you see two sub uh not really
oh so we forgot something we focus on
uh we forgot why a smaller a smaller
than
equal it's going to be right okay all
right while the left pointer is not
smaller it's smaller than b pointer
yeah keep doing it right does it make
sense
yeah isn't it while a
smaller than b sugar
yeah yeah
okay okay so a and b and y a smaller
than b
to this right right now sorry this is
the
two sum right this is the two sum right
yeah
adding one will be three sum adding one
loop will be for some right
and five some whatever i don't wanna six
songs seven song
doesn't make sense so two sons
we we we left the two sum at the end two
numbers if you want to pick
four numbers let's make let's profiles
two numbers first
and then the rest i can apply to some
right
yeah what's the time convexity for this
one
and cubic wait what's a space complex
[Music]
uh
look we have a complexity here but this
is
smaller than o and cubic right yeah
this is smaller than our kingpin so we
we can disregard it
okay i eventually if we can disregard
this one no because this is so much
bigger than that right
doesn't make sense
[Music]
okay and then you say t
and then i remember there's return
there's no return come
on we are comparing
minus one in what case the t minus one
oh if t is small bigger
smaller bigger
again smaller
is the same as t smaller than
uh t smaller than x okay
yeah this is a four-some problem okay
okay that's it that's it that's it for
today