[Music]
so today we talk about
threesome again remember we talk about
three songs again but
it's a bit different three some less
than the target okay
what three songs less than the topic
what's three songs
i expect then it doesn't make even any
sense
but we hate it
two four six seven
one five nine okay so
target is let's let's say seven
no no no target is ten so you want to
find the triplets
three periods and one add it together
smaller than ten okay
two four one okay that's one and then
five anymore
we want to find we want to count how
many of them so that's one right
okay can you find anything less than ten
two nine no no no maybe maybe this is a
b
let's find a 12 okay okay
that'll be two fourths two four six
oh no no no no thirteen thirteen let's
say
two four six ten four one
so we have already got this okay two
six four six one four six one
it will be eleven okay and two six one
right
eight twenty a one two right
okay or two one a yeah it doesn't matter
okay as long as it's three
yeah these numbers are unique okay okay
so how many pairs one two three four
five five so you need to
tell me five is that oh i don't know
suppose is for all right
does it make sense or seven
no no this is too big seven four one
four seven one right
less than 30. okay so one two three four
five six seven seven right
okay okay so basically we want to find
the number of
triplets the sum of lambda triplets
strictly
smaller than the target and we want to
count how many of them
one nine three okay one nine two one so
any idea how we do this to this
performance where are the proof versions
so what's the true housing
takes what's attempted backstage um
[Music]
why is it because
because we need to have three numbers
and we and
we need to choose a three times so like
four
okay i'm not ready
okay and then answer equals zero okay
then four you tell me for i in
range but this is the index
the index and for
j in range one the second number
system what i
at one to n right and for
k equals in range one
in one j one
and one we because we wanted yeah
okay
[Music]
[Applause]
and come on okay can we do better
maybe we can yeah hey
we could use something else cool
no no no okay so
okay let's we can do certainly better
okay so
i'll show you how to how do we do this
okay and now you can tell me okay
let's first of all solve this number
four five seven nine
ten okay let's just try this and if we
only pick three numbers
less than 20
okay that would be a lot okay
that'll be easy okay so let's
let's first of all it would be like
similar like three times for some
problem first of all we fixed the
two numbers which is we improve forcing
these two numbers first number
and the second number okay right
the left this is the right okay
the first number the second number why
don't we have four pointers
no we if we fix two numbers we already
picked these two numbers and then we we
have
we want to apply have two of them
we uh
any of these to
my mistake my mistake i'm confused okay
so
first of all we pick the first number
all right look
pick the first number right and now
for this match i want to pick two
numbers here right and then this is the
left this is
right okay okay what what's what's the
one plus two plus nine oh twelve
twelve right it's it's smaller than
twenty right yeah
what the first number is one i already
fixed i approve of this and the second
number and the third number
right yeah and now look we know 12 is
stricter than 20 right so
now if i move this right pointer to the
left
does it still satisfy less than oh yeah
yeah
i move it moving more so how many of
them i need to add
four five yep and left
is left raises one two eyes index
zero one two three four five six i is
index six
i is index six left index
one so how many pairs are there if left
if the first number plus the numbers at
air the plus
numbers at r is strictly smaller than 20
so we how many numbers we can we add
how many how many two plates so we can
have one two four
one two five one two seven one two eight
one two nine how many of them
uh how many of them
five yeah and which is r
minus l yeah where that right got it
yeah this is the interesting part is the
middle because look we already know
these three numbers added together
smaller than target
and at this point if i keep moving the
right to the left
i still smaller right because it's salty
right
yeah this makes sense how come um
oh yeah yeah because it's smaller right
but look
if the target is what if like the target
is less than one two is eleven okay
right then if this target is eleven it's
eleven
twelve is bigger than eleven right so we
can't move it we want to
move the one
this one
isn't it if
no look 1 plus 2 plus 9 equals 12
is bigger than
is bigger than 11. so you mean right
to the right left yes okay okay
yeah and look before before is 20
so when it's 20 we we we add it and we
we want to move the left or right we
want to move that left to the one yeah
yeah all right okay doesn't make sense
yeah okay let me write it down so what
uh so you can tell me what's the term
complexity okay
define f num
t we first of all we need to solve how
we saw things
number
[Music]
um for i in range anyway
the second number and the second number
j and k
equals i plus one and one
j j is i plus one look i is the first
the number and then j and
plus j that's k what's j and k at the
beginning
oh it's this is one and k
is n minus one j is i plus one or the k
is n minus one right yeah why yeah let's
say we forgot to speak yeah j
smaller than k yeah yes if
noun numbers i plus
num j plus num k
if it's smaller than target now what
should we do with the answers
and add equals one ah equals one
remember remember what you guys should
say
[Music]
and what's out here
well there's no i thought okay
okay k minus j and then what should we
do with the pointers we should move the
left or right
we should move the left which is j plus
equal one one
okay so what should we do
one and then we can
answer what's the time complexity
n squared because this is o and log n
but this is more than
o n square this is the first loop this
is the second loop right left and time
that's the first time yeah what's expect
some questions
you see what daddy doing there
okay
[Music]
we
is
[Music]
is what j plus j one
plus equal one j plus equal one right
you will move the left to the
and the k k is the right y plus one
minus one okay minus equals one
[Music]
doesn't make sense
and we count already right so that's why
we move it
because we want to try if the next point
is bigger than that
am right does it make sense okay
okay that's it for today bye-bye you can
do some beatboxing
oh