hey hello mr mr ryan how are you today
good okay so uh i'm going to
write the two binary trees okay welcome
like like why just why
what do you mean why why why
you know you will know
okay so this is one well i don't know
one two
one three
why you are looking at that one
interesting that looks like a butt cheek
okay so i have two final cheese okay
remind me what
[Music]
speaking too fast okay we have a loot
one dude only one dude right
yeah there's only one little in the
final tree which doesn't have any
parents uh
and i have a leaves which doesn't have
any uh kids children okay
so look considering these two if i call
them similar
how do you know why they are similar
this one is super small okay okay
so given these two three if they are
little similar
they have the same leaves these
that's right yeah so basically if you
want to list all the leaves from left to
right these two trees are similar so
today's task is very simple given two
trees
return true if the leaves from the left
to the right
are similar okay so these could have at
least eight
and then here seven let's start similar
because three four seven
three four seven does that make sense it
doesn't have to be
exactly the same notes okay
got it because it's empty what do you
mean empty
empty tree i haven't did cheese that's
similar because they've got nothing no
no
yeah okay so any ideas
remember what
[Music]
and then we can
no no so it has to be in order so so
therefore search okay so we can have
these uh how many kinds of different
search
um is
pre-order i think okay pre-order note
left to right
okay so if we travel the tree it is not
left
right right and then we record the
leaves as long as
on the way right for example left down
right okay
one okay can you give the difference
pre-order of these
one two three four five
eight seven okay so which are number
three four seven right
so only three four seven okay yeah
these are the notes we are interested
and this one is
[Music]
five four seven okay so look three four
seven okay okay
i think so i think
so as well sorry i think the last one is
always
andy is it no
good question maybe maybe it is maybe
it's not right
maybe maybe it stays maybe it's not
good question can you leave the example
like it's not a
leaf what no one
seven is the last one three yeah always
the
the last one is always only right yeah
why is that yeah
this example that is not the case
can you can you release the example that
is not the case
you don't know okay yeah this is another
topic okay
so look we only we only interest in the
leave so which is three four seven and
we checked here it's three four seven
so if it's only the leave we we we push
it into a list right
right okay i know we checking that these
are the same right does it make sense
ryan are you following me maybe he
is baby all right
all right
leave leave
therefore search okay
yeah if
not loot we just return okay just return
and we have this answer here because we
want to have a list of the
we have we want to have a list of leaves
in this collection
list only right so look if
not what's leave not do the left
and not look that the left don't write
what does it mean
what does this mean if not lo dot left
and not blue dot right what does it mean
[Music]
the same as if rudolph left is none and
no right is now so what does it mean
if the one node is left now note is now
and right now is now what does it mean
anything not anything it is empty
no no no i'm saying if a loot doesn't
have if a note doesn't have
that tree and doesn't have righteous
what does it mean
folks what's bad is it a rude no it's a
parent no
is it a leave no print sorry if i know
it doesn't have
any kids wait if leaves
leaves come on if it doesn't have any
kids there is a leave and i want to push
it into a pen
open open a little value yeah right
yeah and then i'll definitely search the
left yeah
left equals definite search
[Music]
away
this is too much right because you want
to check yeah
how come because we are constructing the
list yeah look
all right look at me i released and if
you don't leave now
i added to this answer because this
function will return his answer right
yeah a list of the leaf
and then this is recursively checking
the left if the left has
and it's nothing that i don't want to
add and i
if not nothing then i i append two lists
together yeah append the left to the
left
and turn the right to do this right and
then return this answer yeah because in
the
definition right does it make sense we
can do it using the iterator
look okay look we don't need to generate
this we can just do this
if not and then i can to what
i can yeah power yeah remember this what
yeah blue u root of value
yeah generator
left i don't need this yeah and then
look
i don't need this yeah okay and then i
can do this i don't need
okay i do want to do lots of things i
can do this yeah
again from left
and then can you tell me what here use
from right yeah
right it's simpler yeah i want to hear
this here means that
okay i have this but if you need it i
will give it to you at that time
i'm not giving you right now it doesn't
make
make sense yeah so means okay on friday
mommy give you five pounds
years five pounds on friday when you're
in friday on friday
she will give you five pounds that's why
yay
[Music]
sorry it's true yeah i know and then
yeah from the left what does it mean
okay then i try
the left tree and i will keep earring
right when i found at least
yelling from the right okay but here we
go
we can't directly generate it because
this is a generator not a list
yeah so we cannot compare the generator
like this because it would
always return four so instead we will
convert a generator into a list
okay and i know this yeah
so it doesn't is a simplified and you
can also
look you don't need this you don't need
this you just do this ear from flat
and then you don't need that right here
right then here from
that so it's simple yeah if this is the
root note i yell the blue the
value yeah then i try to hear the left
recursive
and here the right tree because right
does it make sense
yeah the complexity is still this one
when comparing this
so this one is the generator alright so
this is a generator it doesn't return
anything
but when you're converting the list then
you will recursively
go through the list to get this new
value right doesn't make sense
yeah do you understand this year to me
yeah it's like a promise okay mommy is
going to promise to you that
she will give you 20 pounds this month
right
all right but she will not give you at
once and
unless you you do this this this thing
then we
convert the promise into that
100 pounds each day wow
that's greedy too much
okay i just went anything yeah okay
[Music]
okay
you need to convert it to a list
remember this is different
yeah can you see that no no
[Music]
another bracket this way this is the
this
part and equal equal confusion
no confusion breaking needs to come in
pair look
yeah and then you can write here at
least
and then compare the leaf right yeah
doesn't make sense
so what's here missing release and then
what that's my search okay yeah here
does it make sense
yeah yeah i forgot to do something
[Music]
bye bye bye bye bye
boxing