hello mr harry mr ryan are you okay
good good okay so today we'll talk about
uh
average levels of binary enough enough
okay so let's let's draw a final three
seven um
ten one one hundred two
[Music]
three okay then you need to tell me
it's seven and
nine and five
three can you tell me what what did i do
can you tell me using me
yeah yeah yeah average yeah so look how
many numbers
three three another average of the first
level is
the average is sum divided by count
right
how many numbers so sum is seven
one not seven say eight
three plus one is four plus two is six
divided by two
equals three no by three that's three
notes they're supposed to be
two okay sorry yeah you're all right
yeah that's a
that's the mistake yeah good job picking
it up yeah
yeah okay so what's how do we do this oh
okay so uh so the
route is definitely the same because
yeah you know
there's only one so but i'm talking
about which accurate references
[Music]
yeah actually can solve this problem
we'll talk about different search
tomorrow today about let's talk about
breakfast search
so when we're traveling that tree the
travels the level by level right yeah
when we travel a level by level
so look the key thing here is ryan eric
listen the key thing is that
we we do you still remember what's the
preference search oh it's my level 7
8 10 3 1 2. okay then what kind of data
structure do we need to use to implement
a preference search
what how do we take care of you first
thing last time yeah and how do we
no first thing first of all first thing
that's the last step
oh yeah first thing that last stop
remember the stack
you know we talked about oh a few days
ago we talked
talked about the seeing the sea on the
right yeah
that was one of the funny videos yeah
and then
you see that the thing that monotone is
decreasing right
a stack right but we talk about the the
queue here is first in first sound
and in python what do we what can how do
we declare a queue
what's the mean double ended key what
what does it mean
double ended oh you do it from the
uh double ended what is it
from the left yeah pop left and a pen
double ending means that you can have
push and pop from the both
both sides yeah both sides so my thing
is that
when i take a note when i pop a note
from the queue
and and i want to expand all the
children of the
of the of the notes current nodes in the
queue
so it means it's the next level right
so look do you still remember how do we
do this uh
but uh can can you tell me like let
let's kill yeah
let's keep so at the beginning what
should we put in the kill
oh we should play for read which is
seven okay seven okay now
okay okay now while the q is not empty
yeah
so we have this why there is any man in
the queue right why is that
send it here we what should we do we
push we first of all we
we see how many nodes in the queue
there's only one node yeah
right so we take this one node oh take
all the node so we first of all we know
how many
nodes in the queue we take this first of
all the notes out
yeah seven we push all the keys of it so
which is what
eight and ten eight and ten so look
so when i take it out it's a and ten
what does it mean a and 10 are
on the same level so we know the average
which is nine right
so we put a nine there but when we take
it out we know also know
it's seven so seven nine okay so take it
out and push the eight and nine
o and ten okay now there are two
elements in the queue right
yeah so add them together no no no no
i already add them together which is
nine divided by two i already know
now i want to take orders and then you
mix up
then then you stay in planet pieces
so 8 and 10 so what should we do next i
take all
nine out yeah yeah i take all of them
take 8 and 10 take it all and then
and then we shall put all the kids of it
it's three
one two three one two
because we know it's three one two so we
already know this v one two is the same
level you see
so every time there is notice every time
i take everything out
and i push the kids of it so the key
all the notes in the queue are there
only some level
yes or not uh yeah yeah okay this is the
important thing look
hey suppose there's anything there any
no here right
yeah look i take everything out i
pop everything out i push all the kids
up in it's always
on the same level so these notes are
almost a number yeah
does it make sense 10 11 12 13 14 15.
yeah 10 11 12 13
doesn't make sense yeah okay let's
let's buy this defined
yeah define average
average energy level
node
color
this
and then i have answered
what does what kill me
like the key it's not
evil empty whatever we can say while
they
knows in it yeah where they kill their
nose in the kill right
or it's the same as wire
it's the same as y or line q bigger than
zero yeah
this is the same eric look this is these
two thing is the same yeah
the same yeah yeah while line cube
bigger than zero is the same with y cube
okay in this case yeah
does it make sense okay so now
i have the notes in the queue which are
the same level so i want to know i want
to calculate the sum
so first of all i have some equals
equals zero right and how many nodes are
there
you know two so n equals then q right
yeah this is the node everything looks
like this is the nodes
in the queue right okay number of nodes
in the queue right
yeah yeah right
now look for and
stop in range let's do it repeat
how many times how many times how was
your appointment
[Music]
now i want to pop a element from the
cube so which is
current equals q dot y
pop one left yeah top left
now i have a no and i want to ask
acting to add a sum to it s e plus equal
or current or value right
this is the sum yeah i adding all the
notes and then i need to extend all the
kids
to the kill right so if car went
left okay if that note has left kids i
want to push it to kill
a pen no say the right one open one car
window left there
[Music]
okay now i have lee and i look hi
welcome
and then now what should i do
no append open what apparent
sn s divided
wow you're really getting it yeah
we're done with that what's the time
complexity
[Music]
what's the thumbnail okay
um
[Music]
what
for underscore in region
don't look at my notes
take this wrench
boxing
[Music]
is