hello hello mr mr ryan how are you today
good okay what did we talk about
yesterday
binary tree and the way to work
divided by everything
sum divided by the number that's the
average okay
and we use the breakfast search which
travel the tree level by level right
yeah that's a sum that's the mathematics
symbol
to represent the sum the sum sum okay
sum sum up the numbers how is that
sum that's the mathematics symbol okay
this level by level
right we use the breakfast search with
the help of which data structure
we should have done this that will be
the problem
so yeah no it has this
what kind of data structure are we using
the professor
oh
so if i want to travel the tree using
the
therefore search the pre-order what's
the pre-order of this one
oh it's one two seven three four five
three four okay okay so
if i want to travel a different search
uh
the binary is using different search
then i can pass on the levels yeah i
know which level
uh my current note is that when i
traverse
to the next to the left or right tree
we need to increment the level right
yeah and then we can use a
list to store the notes all right all
right
so what i mean is look everywhere look
at me don't play
so i have a list of look when i travel
here this is the level zero and i put a
zero here at the level level here okay
zero
and then i travel these two and three i
know that eleven
right is two and three so what do i do
this is level one and i put a two and
three here
right and then level two that would be
seven four five right as long as like i
know least least
right then i can calculate the average
right
because i know that i know the least
exactly
i think it's one sorry oh okay
one yeah so i know because i already
grouped them by levels so i know how to
calculate
the average yeah easily for this yeah
how do i calculate the average before
this my number this
list is ar right like one two three how
do you calculate this
uh average for this one oh that would be
easy
yeah there's three of them say one two
three that's six
divided by three how can you write a
can you write the aquarium the python to
calculate the sum of the the average of
ar
can you do it a let's say a
s equals zero for i
in what
[Music]
and then the energy is one s divided by
one
divided by the count which is
n which how can i get the range of
the number of these lengths how can i
get the number
of the elements in the ar
using which function
start with air wait look it's
lambda then
okay so this is the way but you can do
this
you can use what how can you do this sum
sum
a r divided by what some ai is actually
this one right
so ar what's a divided by what
divided by the sum of sum divided by r
sum divided by n which is what i just
told you
[Music]
this is ah sorry yeah okay
so this is average okay so the first
first step is to group the elements
to append the each note to each level
right all right doesn't make sense so as
long as we have a list of the
list of the notes for each level then we
can do this
easily right yeah okay i'm going to test
you okay just to make sure you
understand
how come because you look you look like
playing you're not
understanding okay define let's say
find average find average
load column
okay then i have to define a definition
here okay
therefore search first of all i have a
root and then i want to pass along the
level
level with zero one two can you stop
doing that
level and then i will have a result
result for the list of the notes okay on
each level
right there if not root if the
load is empty there's nothing we can do
we just return yeah
okay now i have a list which is uh
at the beginning is empty
now i need to find if
the level is bigger or equal than
length length is
okay so we found a new level i want to
push this
result so i stop
a pen a new route yeah which is a list
of the
we currently found finding a new level
so i want to push the level in it
right do the value right okay as
look this is the key thing
okay the lever dot append open one
and open what
and then what happened to the level if i
go down what happened to the level
level plus one result yeah
okay and then we don't write double
first one result
okay so can you explain to me what's
what's these two
yeah okay
um of uh like
getting a new level
yeah stuff like that
so when you go down you're passing the
level plus one right
yeah and then you're passing the left
okay
and then look if i call i need to call
this yeah therefore search
eric therefore search root and what
should i put at the beginning in the
second period
if i want to call it what's the
beginning of the level
what's the low value no this is the
front parameter
the loot is at level one
what's your happening and then i
s i need to declare is here yeah i
s equals mtv right at the beginning and
then return
now after ies i will have released what
what's is
here after this default search what will
be is
uh um no no
no no yeah i haven't calculated the
leverage what did i do here what did i
do these two
look if i go to the one level zero and i
put a put a zero here which is one
and a list of these yeah and the second
number is two and three right
and the third level is what so the level
is what can you tell me
three and four four just four okay so
this
this will be is okay after this call the
definition should be used to be based
right
and i want to return the average for
each level right
so i need to do this return
sum i just say sum x
divided by yeah but not yet i'm
talking about this okay i know what
divided by 1
sum x divided by 1
divided by the length length x
yeah and then for x
in result ah yes okay so let's
start with these these will become
erin these will turn these into
one can you tell me
what one one yeah and then
uh no it will be one and then what
t3 so
so this will be is and what will happen
here sum
x divided by length x for x in is so
what's what what's your order
2.5 yeah and then four yeah so
that will become this yeah does it make
sense yeah
what's the term complexity
the time complexity
what if n even
remember the complexity of breakfast
yeah uh
that was a
which one there are n numbers of notes
in
and notes in the binary tree so what's
the time
yeah what's up because we need to travel
each
visit is not exactly one right yeah
that's where one comes from does it make
sense
what's a space complexity
are using a deficit and also the right
result is this a list of a list yeah
this is the two-dimensionalist eric
a list of this so look this zero
is zero is this one is one is here okay
i s2 is here what you doing what's this
okay yeah good choice what's this
result yeah
yeah right okay
not quite exactly is look if there are
levels in here so which level i need to
append to
highest level what's this no yeah no
yeah
can you okay can you can you write it i
yes i yes which level of this because we
know
this never okay is level append
value okay come on you need to
understand okay
does it make sense oh yes yeah which
level is it
bracket level
bracket yeah bracket square
square bracket level and dot append yeah
because we are appending load of value
to least level
to this level doesn't make sense
come on it's quite simple why you still
not remembering
no there's no you don't need to append
the list you need you're appending the
value right the first time
is appending on this doesn't make sense
do the value
y right right and what's here we can
work
i have i yes how can i can convert it to
uh
i just remember something yeah
sum x divided by what what's this
oh yeah the sum yeah
[Music]
sum
when you're calling the function you
need a bracket remember you're not doing
that
yeah come on someone x
and then break it yeah and wow how do
you get the average
yep
i ask you to remember
for x for x in what in some
result is that
yeah yeah you see if i ask you to write
it you'll remember more right does it
make sense you understand more yeah
doesn't make sense all right can you
tell me what's this
why there's a if thingy it would be hard
to understand right
so if the level is
if we are rich we are going to the next
level and we need to append it to
next level then
[Music]
the result appends look
this is the result eric this is the
result
beginning is empty and then if i if i'm
reaching a new level the first time i
look okay this is one and here yeah if i
go to the two
all right go to the two but this list
doesn't have a
two level so what what do i do i go here
and i put a two here
right okay then this result will be here
right look
yeah and then when i visit three
yeah instead of putting it back because
it belongs to some level as too
yeah so what should i do this one is
level here which is here
apparent root of value so i i o does it
make sense that's what it means
yeah okay yeah
doesn't make sense larry you understand
a little bit okay and then i go
because we go to the left and go to the
right with the left
level plus one right yeah any questions
you don't understand
any questions
any questions asked
no are you gonna quiz us again
sorry are you gonna quiz us again please
ask
no no i'm just asking you do you
understand
i understand don't
just if you don't understand ask
questions okay i want you to understand
do i understand
do you understand
[Music]
okay dfs how do we call this function
therefore search how do you call your
function
yeah the first one is zero
level yeah yeah you passed the visa
yes we're done okay you can say bye bye
to people