hey hello mr mr ryan how are you today
good okay today is friday yeah okay okay
so today we talk about
uh finding two strings
special strings in a list of strings
like
i'm
okay so you mean i give you a list of
strings which has the same size you have
four same size yes no no it could be
five or six but they are all the same
size right
okay they all have four letters oh five
letters or whatever okay
so i want to tell me that if there are
two strings in the list that
only has one letter difference for
example a b
c d and a b c c has only one letter
difference
yeah so you need to tell me it's true
okay if i if i if this becomes b b
c c then you need to tell me fourth
because because you can't find
any string two strings in the in the
list
which only differ by one letter
one index okay doesn't make sense
or how can we do this oh
how can we do this the first thing to
think about
how do we perform checking every
possibility
checking every possibility how can you
be
specific how to check the possibilities
how do we check we want to find out if
there are two strings so how do we find
out if there are two strings
what oh we can we check and
we check every two strings yeah and if
there are any strings
these take the blue forcing of end
string checking every two pairs takes
how much time to pull for these pairs
what are those
oh and what the complexity of proof was
in the um
square yeah well n square that's my
favorite now
okay and then why do you have a space
using not yet
so we have we know o and square two blue
fours in
each player two pairs if they are in
string right
so how do you and square how do you
check
if there are two given two string if
their own they differ by one characters
oh you just go like this
go through here if it's different then
you'll return right
now if they're different you can't you
add one yeah and answer
the one and then you keep going right
they need a maximum it's one
it's not maximum the minimum the maximum
one
so it has to be exactly one difference
right
so you actually count the difference by
going through like
wait what if two are the same
then it's zero the difference is zero
and it's not the same
so correct so yeah first so basically we
want to
iterate each character compare character
by character
and increment the counter if they are
different right
yeah and then as i said if they are the
length of the each word is air
then it needs to take over a time right
yeah
doesn't make sense given to a string so
the overall complexity for these
is o n square times l does it make sense
yeah does it make sense yeah eh
is it clear quite slow yeah question
because but
at the beginning let me repeat at the
beginning we need to proof what's in
each pair
that will be on square and for each pair
we need to take
our time to check each character
yeah to check if character to find out
if they're only
one difference right let's overall
contact
oh and security can we do better
maybe we can yeah maybe we can yes we
can okay
of course so how can we how can we do
this
make it better we can use what
we're doing why why we want to use the
notebook the headset notebook or
hash test table yeah dot com
hash says okay
yeah dot co dot uk
okay so how can we do this eric so
look at the abc all right
notebook the notebook has two kinds
headshot has
[Music]
yeah you can say okay what's key value
pair
eric eight ryan seven
so if i want to look up the value eric i
can just
say look okay the 88.
all right look what has said let me okay
i said look a equals yeah
and then you can say a dot
add eric eric all right look look at
this and
eric hey
okay and you can say look mommy is mommy
in a they will return fourth right
because it's not in the mouth
you know in a hash set you can say eric
in
a then return to right because we just
added
yeah yeah so that's all one constant
look up time right
you have no book you just look it
instantly you can find if there are eric
or ryan on a
notebook doesn't make sense yeah i said
do you understand yeah
what's this key value pair then you'll
be like
wait i'm underground with
[Music]
you can say look a
a week equals a
and a e right look it has key this is
key
and that's the value seven and i can say
i can
i can look at this value a area where
you could return a
a writing will determine seven it
doesn't make sense so this is
a one constant it has key value pair but
this one is only have key it doesn't
have value it's a collection
collection it doesn't have all the it
has connections yeah
that's that's all called notebook yeah
because you can
you can have a key value pair on your
notebook or you can just write the name
on your notebook right this
these posts are okay
okay so coming back to this question how
can we
what do we need to put the in the
notebook the
first one eric look
we don't want to please speak this in a
notebook because it doesn't help right
okay we it doesn't have why is that
because we
if we find police in a notebook abcd we
can only check
if there are same string abcd in the
notebook right
but we want to find out if there are
string which differs by this by only one
difference so what does it mean
so can i how can we solve this problem
abcd how many variants different by one
character
what how many how many variants how many
possibilities
it differ by one character what what are
those
a b c d no what are the characters
can you leave the example which is
different than this one
okay so there can be multiple letters
of changing no no just one letter
difference
what are they one different thing can
you give me an example which is one
different
one letter difference b b c v well done
so
the first one is not it it's not it's
different right
yeah so basically you'll be b c d
something
b c d right or a something c d
right or a b something d right
or a b c something right all right
yeah how about if i make these different
bits
a comment letter like question mark and
if i
please in the notebook yeah
i'll put these four variants in a
notebook so the next time when i go to
the here
it has also four variants right then
these will become
a b c question mark right right
what's this abc question mark yeah abc
consumer
yeah we found the match what does mean
it means these two differs by only one
character
does it make sense yeah do you
understand what i'm talking about
yeah yeah this is very elegant man
yeah okay so can you explain to me why
oh
okay like okay so you
okay so you do like uh
if it's one that's a difference that
means
[Music]
a question mark cd
a b question mark d and a b
or a b c question and then you hop on
the next one
and this a b c c and that's
also match up with a b c crack your mark
okay so because we already put these
four variants in a notebook right
yeah and then we can look it up right
and you find it
we we follow one match right doesn't
make sense
yeah otherwise you'll put it there so
let that work okay let us do this
define uh let's just check
and we have these words okay and then
okay so now we have this data data which
is the set yeah we just need to store
these variants you have to remember the
variance
okay look for words
in yeah so these words will be
what would be abc something like that
this is the word w yeah
w will be okay so now we want to solve
the variance
we want to get the valence how do we get
the variance replace it with question
mark
every character yeah look how do we do
this for i
in range
length w
yeah so we index it and then we want to
look at the currently i will be
index for this one so we want to replace
this one
yeah so look the variance let's do it
variance okay
v equals w
yeah i want to get i okay
so i want to get the array i want to get
get the for example look here i is here
i want to get all the characters before
i which is
this part yeah at least b i want to
replace it with question mark yeah
question mark yeah yeah and then now i
want to get
all of the characters after so what's
this
plus what what's this
this is i and then what's this i plus 1
i plus 1 to the n yeah
this is beginning to the i not including
i yeah
then i have okay then if v
in theta return
wha v yeah
and then if not then we can p times
volts oh yeah no yeah why is it returned
false we want to put it in the
dictionary dictionary
data and edward dictionary
dictionary data
w w is becoming a b c d we want to add
the value with the equation
i i is a integer we want to add one
yeah we want to add v because next time
we want to check if it's in the data
and what's one one thing missing here
yeah if no there is nothing we can find
and return what
fox yeah do
it okay okay okay what's peaceful power
what's this what's this map
yeah to if what then do what yeah we
want to check
if v in data then done no no yeah
yeah then i think about a complexity
okay
if if what
we want to check if v is in data then
then return to right i just told you
come on
if v is in data
[Music]
we tend we can't rule
okay okay what's the time complexity
n okay l
hey i'm a koala oh n square that's the
previous blue force look
this is this is the end time right oven
here oh and
keep it and then this is air here the
length will be air right
now again i went again again
why is it plus this is together it's not
at
separate n yeah
what's a space complexity
who cares yeah they're using the data
okay
writing using the data if you see
something using something that's not a
one right
ryan doesn't make sense okay
that's it for today bye
look at this computer and look at these
stuff
okay that's it yes