[Music]
yes
hello and so today we're talking about
mathematics not coding today
yeah we're going to talk about these
messages
do you know what was introduction mean
instruction
no in the instruction induction
okay you don't understand that's fine
okay so
so this is a powerful tool to prove that
prove uh formula if it's correct or not
right
so for example like if i want to know
look if f is the function yeah
f n is the function of the sum
for the first and natural numbers you
know what's like natural numbers
two three four these
are natural numbers integers
so everything everything is is
non-negative right no no not actually
since
positive numbers yes so positive
positive integers positive integers
yeah please be quiet positivity
positive integers okay so can you tell
me
the the sum of the false first four
integers what was the sum of the first
one for individuals
one two three four yeah six seven eight
nine that's four
big brain f4 equals
what four equals one
the sum of this ten final five
million keep quiet
you're going to be on youtube okay don't
be so naughty
okay
you're making fun so let
if we know this this proposition
for perfection do you know this words
prepositions place
proposition is like you propose
something
yeah it's the now for the proposed yeah
proposition is if i yeah
if i tell you okay can you prove to me
that
the first sum the sum of the first few
integer venture number positive
integer is n times n plus one
divided by two yeah this is the form
what does that mean
look what did you say f equals 1
10 10 x y equals 15
okay 4 times 4 plus 1
divided by two equals four
four times four four to five equals
twenty
and divided by two ten okay
and how about five times five plus one
divided by two
times six fifty nine
so do you see listen
so if i tell you if i tell you
the first f 100 is what 50 50
yes you how do you know easy babe
look look the formula what did i just
tell you formula
equals 100 times a hundred plus one
divided by two right okay this is
fifty-fifty okay
okay yes yeah okay so this is the
formula for the
sum of the first no fifty fifty five
thousand
and fifty yeah yeah
some of them cosmetics some of the first
few
positive integers okay yeah yeah okay so
now
going back to the topics mass induction
okay so if i told you if i told you
that ryan ryan please
if i tell you that f n
is n times n plus one divided by two
yeah
okay so we need to do two steps to prove
that this is correct how do we do it so
first of all we ask
when n is one so what's the answer
one yes right
can you quite comfortable and one times
two two divided by two
one right yeah okay so when n
is one the base case we call it base
case because n equals minimum is
n is one then and the answer
is one right
okay so now if look
ryan are you okay ryan
good boy okay on tv okay now look
if n is look if if we talk
uh if we assume that
n is k right f k is equal to
just any any number okay k equals okay
did you say k equals a k plus one
divided by two okay
okay okay okay so if fk equals k plus
yeah
if k is the same as that yeah yeah now
then when you're in the end
what's kfk plus one what's the answer of
k-power
f k-power is it equals to f k
plus k plus 1 right am right because
now i got the sum of the first k numbers
i i just need to add one more right
yes yes you just had one not k at one
no k at one because this is look
f4 f5 is equal to f4
plus five right am right
at the yeah f5
yeah f5 is supposed to be x k
no k plus one look k is four then
k plus one is five that's what i mean
did you get
[Music]
why are they much shorter what do you
mean much shorter so this is the junior
case shorter than fk
why no i'm just saying this is an
example this is a general case
okay general case general case yes yeah
okay so now f k equals f k
f k plus one equals f k plus k plus one
right
okay so how do we do this so doing that
please
no
[Music]
math so look uh
let
fk plus one equals fk
plus k plus one right this is the k plus
one portion
yes
this is k k plus one divided by two
right
yeah yeah we know that right
so this is k plus one what can we do
about it we can do it is 2
2 k password is the same thing yeah all
right
yeah okay so now if we merge these two
how can we merge these two emergency two
loops that over twos right i was like 2
here
so k k plus 1 plus 2
k plus 1 right am right yes
look there this command here k plus 1
right
so it equals 2 k at two
k plus one and then k f two yes we're
done
okay yeah okay so look
at that look look wait wait so what's
next
look magic this is magic look why
look look this is magic look so this k
plus 2 equals k plus 1 plus 1 right
plus 1 yes yes
k plus
i know look k plus one k plus one
k plus one so if i
if i say t equals k plus one so i can do
f t equals t times
t plus one divided by two you see
do you see this it's the same i can't
see
it okay do you see so what what
so what does it mean what does it mean
what does it mean we we prove that the
base case
when k equals one
they form the proposition this formula
yeah
yeah is is correct right
we assume the kfk is correct
and then when we add one more item
yeah it will be the same yes
the formula is the same look so we prove
that this formula is correct this is
called
mass induction it always be this yeah do
you get it
yes i'm buying
[Music]
here is a more difficult one okay more
difficult
sum of a square like that if i saw fk
equals 1 squared plus 2 squared
plus 3 squared plus k square
okay i tell you let this sum equals
n n plus 1 2 n plus one
yeah this is the formula that means k
is bigger than three now look can we say
the base cases
when k is one one k is one what's the
sum
it's one right yeah the first item so
let's see if it's one okay so
n is one k is one so one times
one plus one times two
times one plus one divided by six you
see one
one times two plus three two times
one two plus one three right
one times two times three six divided by
six
why is it divided by six this is the
formula preposition
yeah i just told you it's that and i
want you to prove that it's correct
so we prove we first of all improve
so we sorry so we
we prove that the 1k is one the base
case is correct right
yeah okay now if you're not sure
let look that one k is two what's the
answer
k is two um the same
one one squared plus two squared
one squared plus t squared that's
five yes five okay look
put a two here two times
two plus one times two times two plus
one
divided by six two times three
six okay so this is gone yeah two times
two plus one
five yeah yes so look k equals two is
also correct okay
so now let's let's prove it so we just
prove when
k is one the base case is correct
now we need to assume when
fk is correct and i will add one more
so one more so one more item
what's that it's k plus one right
square right yeah all right
yes yes so look now this fk
okay let me just write it there okay so
easier
mud on your feet f k plus
k plus one square equals
six and six k
k plus one two k plus one
plus this item i also put a six
and i know becomes 6 k plus 1 square
right
yes all right so why i have 2
is because they are both over 6 so i can
merge these two items
so 6 and then now i have k
plus one k plus one here so i put a k
plus one
okay now this item will be k times
two k plus one right
plus is plus i take a plus
plus what six k plus one okay
all right why didn't you do a square
which one square that where
this one yeah because i take the k plus
one out
they both have this k plus one yeah this
is called uh
look if a b plus
a c one you can convert it is
a b plus c yeah all right
look because they have both a i can take
it out
and then these two just update it
yeah add it together all right for
example two times five
plus two times three equals two times
five plus three right that's ten that's
six
sixteen two times eight
sixteen you see yeah
still get it yeah okay so now
look sorry
so look this so
coming through that it's correct look
this is
this is a bit complicated yeah this is
2k
square plus k right plus 6k
plus 6 okay so look
uh look so this is 2k
square plus 7k plus 6
right so this thing
is equal to
it should be equal to what to uh
k plus 2
times 2k
plus 1 plus 1 okay so it should be this
way
so we prove is it we can do this 2
2 k plus 1 look it's k plus 2
2 k plus 2 plus 1
3 okay so it's it's it's the same
why is this the same
so here look yeah look
two k square plus three k
plus four k is seven k yeah seven k
plus one plus two and three plus six
so look these two items are equal so we
prove
that when k plus one because this is k
plus one we can
make it a t then you'll be the same as t
t plus one
two t plus one yeah easy
yeah i know i know so yeah okay
so this is called mass induction so to
sum up
we we need to do two steps
two steps first of all
first of all proof
through base case okay base case
remember
when one is sum yeah this sum of first
in
first n integers is when n is one
is the sum is one two
which is called induction step
so what does it mean so if we assume
when n
equals k the fn function
yeah fk function and then we need to add
one more
one more item f k plus k
plus one right this is one f k
plus one we can do this and then we need
to prove
this formula also
can be represented using this original
formula then we can approve this
formula instead do you get it okay
any questions so far no
bye bye bye-bye christmas toy
oh yeah