hey hello mr harry mr ryan how are you
today
so um today we're going to
design an agreement to check if there
are three consecutive
odds number or numbers in an array okay
what's
[Music]
can you write the function which is
check if a number is the odd number
if defined is off
if if if n
okay if if whatever the number is
if n uh divided
oh return
then fast yeah or you change this to one
and return to it
and air is returned two yeah all right
[Music]
oh you can see we don't need it because
when it's written it's returned
yeah you can put the errors return so
it's all
alternatively all right all right yeah
you can change this to one line yeah
what's this
return
or you can just do this return n
and one right it will be simpler yeah
remember that what end
binary is if it's an odd number in
binary the last bit
the rightmost bit is what one yeah if
it's zero
it's all even number yeah look this is
simple oh you can do this
using the lambda function yeah change
this to here
right are you okay you're listening yeah
it's all
reading captain on the pants it's all
look everything
these two lines can return can be made
into single line which is
r equals
you see you see the least two line can
can be
changed into these yeah doesn't make
sense
doesn't this need to decline no no no
that's what i mean if you
define you're defining a function it's
all you can
change this to is all which is a number
function lambda
n n is a parameter what does it return
and
and one and and one actually actually
because
actually there's a slightly mistake and
one is return one and zero so it's
better to
check if it's one okay yeah yeah
[Music]
yeah okay so let's return true or false
right
yeah okay okay so given a three number
uh
uh a few numbers in array one
five seven two six
you need to tell me it's four because
there's no consecutive three numbers
which
which is e doesn't need to be three
all right because i say so okay okay
i don't know okay there we go one if i
put a three here
then you need to tell me it's true
because 135
is a consecutive number it doesn't have
to be two two three
seven yeah yeah you can have uh eleven
that's still tens of three consecutive
numbers three yeah
i need three continuous continuous so
any three numbers hit like that
three number three number three number
this any of them is
we use the greedy uh
not exactly the greedy but how can you
check what's the anger anymore
oh okay sorry uh okay so you start from
the beginning is the odd number
he goes to the next one and there's
still our own
number and and then the next one is also
[Music]
so what do you do eric so you basically
you check
let's can three contains consecutive
numbers it is the
autumn right if it is written to
otherwise i move to the next conception
next one next one or i can do this
so look this can consecutive consecutive
consecutive consecutive
under the last one right okay so n
equals
if i want to find the length which is
how many is length down yeah
and if they are less than three numbers
we can't find it right yeah of course
then if and
smaller than there is three numbers all
of it
has to be uh false
okay and then look we can do this for i
we can start
look for i in range
we start with a two which is the second
of the third number
zero one two yeah and then to end and
we can do this if it's all okay suppose
we already have this is our function
noms i
and is odd
what should i put it here numbs what
and it's odd
left right numbs what what what do i do
here
three times one otherwise return one
to ten three return false return true
here i know what's
if we confirm any consecutive written
ones okay so i start with the second one
here so
if this number is e or lambda and
if this number is all number or is this
number all numbers so which
we where what's happening here this is i
this is what
i minus one this is what
i where i start with the second one i
i minus one and what's this i minus
zero y minus two i minus two okay
because we start with the second one
right alternative you want plus one and
plus two you can do this
start with zero and up to m minus
two right correctly yeah
this is all this is this also okay
because this n minus 2
up is n minus 1 up to n minus 1 and
minus 1 plus 1
minus 1 plus 2
n minus 1 plus 2 so uh
is it n minus 2 or minus 3
up to up to look i
will become 0 2
to m minus one maximum right because oh
no no n minus three maximum
right because n minus two is bigger than
minus three so
n minus three plus two is minus one the
last
index is the minus one that lets you
walk okay minus
[Music]
anything but look it's om but each
number
could be checked multiple times all
right
why is that because look
look at this 11 yeah is this even on all
them
oh number yeah check it and then move to
the next one
you see is this all number all i'm all
about let's check twice yeah
if i move another three is this all
number one
yeah so this number any number
between the third and the only below
yeah i know so every time because you
have a slight
sliding window of three and this number
the wind in the window will be three
times right
there will be three windows right one
two
three right all right so 11
has appeared in three windows what does
it mean it's all function needs to check
it three times
yeah does it make sense can we do better
without checking without checking
three times check the last one
we just check the first three then
we don't need to check these to eject
this one
yeah so first we check all of them and
and then
we just check the last one yeah and i'll
keep moving but how do you
yeah but how do you change this to make
this work
how do you make it work kind of similar
but
yeah because listen hey
how about we we have a counter we have
we remember the current
consecutive odd number count right so
look
yeah all right look look on all number
counter plus one all number
quarter plus one all number
counter plus one all number counter plus
one
even number we set it to zero
does that make sense yeah so we have
this number to cut to
to count how many consecutive num even
them
or number we haven't met so far we have
seen so far
and then at the meantime if it's more
than
we caught a maximum of it right
okay huh you still don't quite get there
not quite okay i i show you i assume
look
i show you okay let me write the example
one two three
five seven six
ten okay okay look at this yeah eric
we have this counter called odd
odd number and then we have this max max
max odd okay makes odds seem so far
is it odd number yeah
yeah one and the next one is one updated
to the next is it odd
no when i reset the author's yellow yeah
hey
and then here all right one
what should i put here one on the other
one yeah
oh number one what should i put
one and then one one yeah
what's the other a number is one or two
two two and then max off two
yeah whole number
uh three three
zero
and then at the end we check this next
part
if it's bigger or you go to three when
it's two right
yeah doesn't make sense and each number
we only check ones right
yeah okay let's light it you got it
[Music]
be fine check
numbs what what's missing
okay
uh odd equals zero right
and then max
bot equals zero as well look at it
for i in
nouns what's missing
e anyway is odd if it's odd
i what should i do here if it's all i
will do
oh we just implement one
and what means of all one
of the next o and what
for the point yeah we want to get
keep the maximum of the order and airs
as well
okay and then what did i do at the end
return max
max
what's the time complexity what's the
time
what's what's the space complexity
what's the space complexity
o n is the n is the number of numbers in
the array
what's the space compression are we
using any space i won
max
boom
okay