[Applause]
interesting okay maybe we can come back
to that later
today we talk about two sum who is the
investment that's happening we talk
about threesome less than that but
it's slightly different we want to find
out the largest to some
less less than a time for example like
doesn't have to be two some
one two three so the target is four
you get to school so can you find two
numbers
in the list which added together less
than four but i want to find the maximum
the largest one exactly four no
one two yeah one two yeah one two eight
if you didn't my question
look if i put a zero here
yeah zero here or zero three zero two
zero one that's all
less than four but i wanted the largest
sum that's less than four
so equals three yeah
zero one so any two numbers pick two
numbers
let's add it less than the these but i
want to find the largest one right
it could be three it could be two but i
want to find the largest one
what can we do we want to find the two
numbers
that added less than the sum less than
the target but i want to find out the
maximum the largest sum
that's less than the target so if you're
not sure what to do
say three thousand
yeah how can we prove what improvements
is the first idea coming to your mind so
what how can we prove us
we own the two numbers huh so what's the
term condensable if we prove us
all the two numbers pairs
ln squared oh n squared okay one square
so the time complexity will be always
good we just prove something and we
check if the sum
is less than target if it is we will
call the maximum right
yeah yeah okay can we can we just do
this just
just to give you an idea okay define
later you're going to say
can we do better less than
[Music]
let's say answer let's let's make it a
minimum negative
negative for infinity which is minus
max mass star infinity
isf we want to prove
it how can
for the second number j in range
so can you tell me what what should i
put here
the proof was in two numbers the first
number is
index i the second number index one j
j j star is what
you can start with i plus one als right
i plus one to n right or you can do this
you can start with t i yeah it also
works yeah
all right this means that i look at it
i j or o
i j or j i okay
which one is this can you tell me which
one is this i j ijlj1 the pairs
the index
which one is it so can you tell me i if
i i make sure the first index is i and
then
[Music]
the i j 2 a is bigger than i so which
one is it if
i excel from j yeah j i because j is
smaller than i right so it's here right
if
come on
[Music]
okay
how can we do better
what's that called sultan making
sorting and now we have two points yeah
remember yeah that's the comment
technique so
how about you we sorted binary search
numbers
what's the time complexity if i do this
[Music]
uh
do i need to minus one yeah
then why if two points are not met
right yeah okay now i want to get the
current sum would be num i
plus num j right all right
okay and now what should we do now if or
as you compare x with the target right
all right if x smaller than driving what
should i do
oh are we here answer equals the max of
the answer
[Music]
so look two pointer if the sound is
smaller than the target
we should move the left or similar to
the right
what i this is
sorted and if the top sum of these two
elements
is smaller than the target we should
move this also we move here ah we shall
move this
yeah one f1 i
plus at one okay and then what should we
do
what we do if it is if it's bigger or
equal to
t target what should we do oh we shall
move j
minus one j minus equals one right
[Music]
yeah what's
logan what's what's the time complexity
of this part eric
what's the tongue complexity on this
part
that's more funny what's the time
conversation oh
[Music]
and the overall complexity which one why
is that
oh because this one is very dominating
dominating this one yeah it makes sense
yeah okay
okay all right if x is smaller than t
two
two lines s two one nine okay
can you feel this for frank
oh that would be evp
um
i can explain to people what you're
doing okay
answer equals next one
[Music]
answer yeah
yeah we shall
i
[Music]
yeah so if it's smaller than t remember
what should we move to
if it is smaller than t once we more
[Music]
boys
okay say bye bye to
see you tomorrow
bye