okay so today we're going to talk about
come on come on so we talked about how
the accuracy to check if the binary is
the sun binary so what's combination
of the tree so if
any note except the leaves which doesn't
have any kids
if it's equal to
so if equals to to the kids right for
example they three
equals one plus two and two equals two
right except the leaf now that it's a
fine yeah yeah all two kids yeah if
then if at least if all the notes
except for this note equals to the
sum of its kids then it's a some binary
tree okay
so remind me how many ways can we travel
a
binary oh breakfast deficit okay so we
talk about preferences today okay but
what's breakfast search can you remind
me okay
three one two two zero okay so level
five level and what's the definition you
used to put on
one two two zero three one two two zero
yeah but it's different meaning yeah
level by level if i put
another uh nine the first search is
three
that would be some yeah yeah i know but
so in this case it will be four there it
will be three one two
nine two zero but the difference search
the pre-order will be
three one nine two two zero okay
it didn't have this one will it be the
same
you'll be the same you'll be let's say
okay so let's talk about first search
okay
in python what kind of data structure
are we used to to
implement the preference search
in python what what kill dk what's
speaking
that means that like uh you
you push you i get get
like you have one two uh
anyway and you you you get this one and
give a new one
so double ending means that you can you
push it
and then you can when you pop
it you can use the pop left on this one
right
you push to the end you will push a pen
yeah
yeah so basically but you apparent uh it
has
you can because it's double ended so you
basically can push and pop from both
sides
pop left and then you can pop and a pen
or you can append that right so it's a
double nd kill right
but in uh in breakfast you only
a pop left and a pen a pen which is a
pen right
right yeah but it doesn't have right
yeah you only have a pen and
a pen left it has pop and
pop left right doesn't make sense
okay define define
is so defined finally
is some fine and we three
what's the point read read bracket
column okay if not rude
bigger than zero yeah this is and you
also need to use
oh yeah yeah and current equals q over
pop left left okay
okay let's put the let's assume s is the
sum of the
it's keeping
left what should i do with this if they
are left kid if their left kid
f s e n plus equals
equal current
[Music]
left in the queue so how can i do this
because we take a kick take the kid out
of a kill and we want to push
its kids back to the queue right so
what's this
okay left right
left left
okay i'm not going to write it again
okay and then look and then if this note
is not uh let's know so what should i do
if what
if if however don't
[Music]
the while while loop okay after here
okay what's the time complexity
people won't listen to you okay you're
too loud okay
okay
[Music]
big boxing