hey hello hello hello
hello mr ryan how are you today good
i'm good good so yesterday we talked
about
some binary tree
so i'm going to draw a binary tree and
tell me if it's a sun balancer or not
okay
what is the sun binary tree
why is it no oh
so the parent needs to be equal to its
two kids
right two plus one plus five three
equals three
three yeah three equals three but not
except
the least no this note does not have any
kids so that's why this is
some binary tree okay got it right look
there you go on my hand
that's okay look at my new tattoo okay
okay okay
hello and yesterday we talked about a
breakfast search right
remember what's breakfast search
three which um a level by level level by
level
and impressive surgery what kind of data
structure are we using
okay okay come down
level by number and stuff instead is
uh one two three three which is uh
yeah um
let's do this so what's the what's that
therefore search order in pre-order
three three seven seven eight i think
three two three five three seven
and then three seven eight seven seven
a.m yeah that's what i said
seven seven eight nine guys okay so now
if we can travel a final to using
definition we can
check the notes when we're visiting the
node yeah to check if it's the sum of
its kids if it's
any if it's if it's at least now we
don't check right
define okay define
that first and we're passing the load
and if the empty tree what was what
entry yeah empty tree is a special case
okay let's keep when we visit the note
we want to store the we want to
store the number of the we want to
calculate the
x some of the kids yeah so let's say i
want to
do x any variable too so x
equals zero and then let's keep the
result here
answer equals at the beginning true and
if there are any violations
then we set it to fourth right if
if less the left note oh wait
left column what should we do next
answer and that research left
left
[Music]
and make sure that uh and we add it to
the
yeah and then yeah sorry
so x is the x is the stores the number
the sum right yeah so if there are left
keys or x
needs to plus equals one i'll be
uh x that's equal root
right x equal root what
we don't like the left
and then we want to because we check the
left tree right
yeah so answer equals
[Music]
the left sorry what what does this mean
oh okay so answer equals the answer of
death side okay say the definition of
the
reader of the left uh left children
so what does it mean what are we doing
what's this function
what what's this function do oh it's
it's
like this one is going and checking
on the left children so what's what are
we doing here what's this
search what's what's this doing what
what does it return
oh it returns if it says some binary
tree
okay what does it mean
oh uh you add up the left
right end of the left here look at the
left side
we want to check the boot if it's a
binary some binary right
and therefore search what
root therefore search
is the function to check if a given
binary
is a sum binary we are given root so
load
is here so we want to check the loop
this three is
the barrier tree now i'm passing it
a little left i'm only passing this bit
so what does it mean
we're checking the left we want to check
the left one
if if the left is what smaller
what left is uh it's
left it's smaller than the right it's a
sunburn
so come on yeah i got it
you got it now right why is that because
this is recursion
with passing the loser left it's a
smaller problem
yeah we already want to check the binary
tree with some binary
fss functions right and now
you want to check my leg all right and
then you breathe
right now breathe out
right now
slow down come
we're gonna on it okay the right
yeah okay you want it to do it
me do it okay okay
equal root
it's a bit small left
the left no right are you kidding me
observation yeah and
[Music]
deficit
that's okay basically you want to copy
this playstation change the left to the
right because we will do the same thing
for the right choice right so now at
this point
x if how can we check if it is not a
leaf note
oh it doesn't have any kills so if what
it doesn't matter because look this oh
what's this all mean
a or b right two of two one
two or two ah
don't guess okay what do you mean oh
one of them is two then it's two two or
four
five three one of them is two is true so
one eleven is true so what give me the
final answer
two of us i said
three fourths or two four so
three fourth or fourth four five
okay another one this is all remember
this is not new okay
i i get it dude
two and two
what does n mean in english uh two
things
two things a and b both needs to be true
in order to be true
two come on fourth and two rating fourth
and two
false why on this voice so low
fourth first and fourth
[Music]
needs to be both needs to be true in
order to be true otherwise it has to
it needs to be false right to get it
and o is the opposite
oh it's no opposite why not learn it's
true that it's true okay
yeah at least what you mean yeah at
least one and another one another one
okay which one are you gonna do now
exclusive oh remember i talked about
this before
two two and all
exclusive too what
what basically there are four kinds yeah
what's
exclusive or it's true only if it's
different
okay two exclusive two false
two exclusive fours two fourth exclusive
two
fourth first we're done exclusively
only two if it's different and
only two when both are true or
two when any one of it is true
is true right at least one of them is
true it's true right
yeah it doesn't make sense yeah can you
pass me
apple or orange i only want the apple
or orange it doesn't matter right does
it make sense
can you pass me the apple and orange i
want the both
right english okay
okay so where are we here if neutral
left or loot alright
what does it mean oh if if we gonna
we wanna check uh if it's uh children
it would even as a kid so if this is
true
what does it mean if luther left a
little y
it means that it's not a leaf now right
like if it's not this now we want to
check what we want to check the
column value if it's equal to the sum
right yeah so how can we do it if
x x is the sum of the kids right if x
not equals what if x
what's the current value what which
value
we do
[Music]
and then yeah what do we do oh we
should return
that first search return first because
now
we know already false right and
otherwise
we can
[Music]
now
written answer because already we
checked it
look at this end right and we want to
check the left
already check the left and check the
right will return answer doesn't make
sense
then return that
actually you could you you can save it
to answer
equals fourth right and then we can
answer it's the same thing yeah because
we determine answer here
okay i'm gonna rub one out no no no i'm
not going to drop it i mean
i'm not going to wrap it because it's
all there look it's all there
no no you're going to trick me no no
it's there look at that look at that
look at that look at that come on come
on
okay
what's the time complexity sorry
oh n o n what's n the number of
the number of the sounds
[Music]
binary tweet let's let's see
okay that's it for today