no hello mr eric mr ryan how are you
today
good good what's up everybody yeah
what's average oh okay so let me explain
so uh uh okay let me
like like we like one
two three four five
six yeah whatever yeah yeah okay
this is this
[Music]
because there's only one character is
one
and this one is uh
what this one is
so what's the average of two and three
uh
what's the average okay so there's
a 2.5 2.5 yes and then
what's average all these okay so it is
four plus five plus six is uh
divided by how many three yeah that's i
already so you just tell me
it's a sum yes it's a sum 15
divided by yeah it's a sum divided by
count okay let's average what simple as
that
yeah yeah yes okay so so given a number
like
like one two three a list of number ten
right
and i want you to tell me if it's
possible to
remove one number from the list
and the rest number the remember
that the rest numbers the average will
be
two that's the target will be
wait how many numbers can we use so they
have to be only
allowed to take one number so we remove
one of the numbers
and then the the remaining numbers have
everything
yeah because one two three the sum is
six divided by
how many two three yeah so the original
has four numbers but we take one out
so the remaining will be three numbers
okay so this is how to work it out
so you find how many numbers for this
example is
four and then if you take away one that
means
there have to be three and you do um
something
divided by three equals two and then you
need to find
then two times three equals six and then
you need to find a sum which
equals six okay interesting interesting
yeah i'm not
exactly following you but i kind of
understand what it means
but look so we given at least
at least a number yeah a number and now
we have a target
a target so you need to tell me if it's
possible to remove one
number to make the remaining numbers
have
average target return two or five right
so what what's your approach to check
this
okay okay say pray for them
yeah well done profession how to improve
work oh
taking every possibility and how many
possibilities of that
if there are any numbers i think it's
say so n because you need to take away
one
and then you know okay so how so
if we take away these numbers so what
should we do next
oh we shall say remaining is two
and three and ten and then okay
so then we add two and three and ten
and then divide it by a card and then we
choose three okay
i know yeah and we divided by n minus
one
we're done and minus one here m okay so
look if we take away this number
do we need to calculate the sum of these
they're the worse
but that's okay we worry about it later
alright
so in the cartons do you understand what
i'm talking about
if i take away these two how can i know
immediately what's the sum of the one
plus three plus ten
well i need to calculate that 1 plus 3
plus 10 if i take away 3
how do i know exactly what what the sum
of 1 plus 2 plus 10
think about it what's the sum of one
plus two plus three plus ten
oh uh uh sixteen okay
then if i take away two what's the sum
of one plus three
yeah if i take away three what's the sum
of one plus
yeah you got it the sum the minus the
number you take
right yeah okay so
so okay so you got it yeah okay
define define check okay define
numbers and target
okay sum equals s-u-m
number so this is the sum of all numbers
this takes o and time right because we
need to go through each number
and add it together this place over and
over right oh yes
and then now for ei
in nums we try each numbers right
okay then if i take away the number look
if
some take away the number i
and what is it equal if
s minus one i uh okay so
it's the sum if
some i might take away the number that's
a sum of the
remaining numbers yeah we take away and
what does z equal we
who is t oh we need to divide it by n
minus one
divided by n minus one so length right
num minus one right
and equals one what then what is the
equal
it equals the uh if it equals the target
okay this e equals t right so you can
transit you can move this to
the other side means to multiply right
yeah so it would
if t s minus i equals p times
length numbers
minus one right okay
and what's missing
now if the if everything is the
attention and what's
what should i return yeah
yeah oh yeah oh yeah what's the time
come next
square and square why is
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah okay
[Music]
all right look look
this is i right if we if we move
this to the other side right so we can
write it as
s minus t equals
i right yeah all right i equals
s if i equals s times
this t right all right yeah so if i
equals s
minus minus t times this right that
minus is the same right
yeah because eventually we want to find
out if i
is in one of these right if this number
is in one i right
all right does it make sense
so we want to find out look for i
numbers
if i equals something right yes
all right look it's least changing
s is not changing right we already know
it t is not changing right
this is no one right so these if i is
something
is something right it's already known
right
so what does it mean we can do this one
one nine thing return
sum we have three returns no i'm
i'm talking about these one none okay
you don't need this okay
some lamb these are s
right minus t
times l n numbs well that's gonna be so
long minus r1
yeah this is the number right this is
the number we want to find out if it's
in the dumps right
i can't see yeah so what should we do
in num
that's it so all these nines can be
replaced by this one
right doesn't make sense yeah it's
looking good look what's the
if num if noun equals one two three
four right okay so can you tell me five
in
numbers is it return true or false
it's what you're talking you mean yeah
five nums
nums
[Music]
so does it make sense it's the same
thing as for i
in numbs if i equals five
return true otherwise at the end within
four for i
in in terms if one in
one equals i i equals one potential
doesn't make sense anyway
are you so we this one
in in is means that we want to find out
if this number
is if this element is in the list right
what's this
complexity it's the same look it's the
same it's just
one noun if look does it make sense if
we we are finding we want to find out
in the numbers right in the lungs in the
numbers if
there anything equals to this right so
you can just do this if
this is enough right
it's the same thing yeah
you're gonna rub it out got it that
doesn't make sense
yeah yeah
are you kidding me it's easy today
okay do you need to write two no just
one of it
any any one of it we want to find
you want to return directly maybe this
is not mine
wait let me get right hand
return one land what
we can
yeah some is lowercase but it's okay
nouns yeah we want to get the numbers
here
awesome awesome korea
some numbs i know some people
won't understand you babe
some nouns yeah
and then it is
hey that looks like different it's all
it's similar
what are you known for i
know it looks different anyway do you
understand
if you understand try your best to write
it okay please hey
look it says s is
total yeah
it's it's similar but it yeah for i in
what in numbs yeah
[Music]
you need to understand right you
understand it before right
equals t
t t times
i don't know how they would do but i
could just do a dot
instead i know
numbs i'm not making you look at the
game right come on
minus one good can you explain i mean
it's easy
like that yeah minus 100 these
bracket here yeah
and if if i is in nums
return return to otherwise false
what do you put return is here okay
anyway
and then return falsity
okay okay
okay that's it that's it that's it
good job today good job
good job that's it