hello hello mr mr ryan how are you today
today we'll talk about cartesian product
okay no
addition is quotation okay product is
another word of multiply right
multiplication
okay it is called test okay okay can we
focus on the thing here okay
so this is another word of
multiplication multiple multiply
so look if i have a 18. that y is a bit
yeah yeah yeah okay this is
a a list of a is a b
and a list of b is let's say at least
okay
[Music]
okay you can even mix and match okay so
this is a match this square bracket
means a list yeah the list means you can
change it
it's mutable but if you do it if you do
this
right if you do this uh
what your parentheses yeah parenthesis
that's in math
parentheses these are called
racket yeah yeah or the difference
between cuba
and the list this is this is that
a tuper is immutable means after this
you can't change the elements
but here i can say b along
island too big yeah b 0 equals let's say
alex okay
what happened then it will replace these
two
errors yeah not a oh
look if c equals this two power and if
you say
c zero equals that
it's not po you're not allowed to do
that because
it's stupid you cannot change it right
that's the difference between two prime
and like this okay so here
uh condition product okay
look a
look this is this is mathematic
condition it's not the present one right
it's not i mean i'm just saying that in
mathematics cartesian it's not nothing
to do with the present right
you cannot do a multiplying present
using this way
condition product a b equals one you
take this
you will take each element of a
and try the combination with each
element of b so what does it equal
it'll become equal to that a list yeah
not a two part a two it will be a two
plus
two
and then a two
yeah and then
a three you're going and then b
b one got it b
two three three i got it
okay so what does it mean look it's just
a one a two a three this card this input
b one p two p three all these are
written in
two plus right doesn't make sense so
what can you tell me what's the
cartesian product
you're not understanding you're just
guessing okay so what's what's this
uh
doesn't make sense can you tell me oh
okay so this is car wait okay so this is
cheaper and this is this but you just
rub it out anyway
people is immutable i think
i think and this one is cuba is
immutable
at least it's mutable that's the
difference yeah yeah yeah i know where
you
multiply these two condition products
how do you
okay okay s
yeah i got it baby okay so it's
in par in prison we have this you know
you can do this you
you have an eta tool iterated to a dot
product to this exactly okay
okay so you can do this you can from
from eta to a
import product
and then we can use this product
function so you can say
look you can do this
a equals list all right because
this product returns a generator you
know the year thing it doesn't actually
give you a list
but you need to convert it to the list
or tutor yeah
list and then you can do this product
and you'll tell me what's the outcome
okay
product let's say
one two and then another one three
four like that so what's a
what does a become 21
what's a a is a list yeah yeah list of
products
one cartesian product a one two so a is
what
can you tell me a is
then tell me at least what 24
no cartesian product i just told you
remember that the thing you don't
understand now
yeah it should be a one three
and what's next two four oh one four
one four two three three four yeah i got
it
okay yeah got it so look it's this
product of these it will take
each element of one one three one four
and two
three two four yeah easy to understand
combination and then you become each one
is a two part
and then it returns a list of a
generator for this each tuber you can
convert it to a list okay that's what he
actually does i'm quick
so if i will i want to implement this
product okay
it's given two things and you can change
it to
to list to tuper it doesn't matter yeah
it still gives this result okay
this makes sense remember the curly
brace and uh another curly brace the
bracket
the punches and the square bracket okay
okay now we want the left angle is 24
two times it together yeah it's
factorial
okay so now look let's define if this is
a p function right
a b okay to restore cuba this could be
tilde only
and i cut that okay so how look
we can join
you want to go to the first element
which is a
and then second one for j
in b
and then yeah remember this q one u
okay here's the two of what can you tell
me yeah the cuber one
[Music]
a is an a one two b three four
and i is for the element in in the first
in a b j is for the element in b
so yeah come on it's very obvious
a a is a list i
does it make sense when you hear the one
this is the tuple yeah
looks weird okay it makes sense what's
the
if there are n elements in a m elements
in b what's the function
okay that's what i said yeah
remember this year thing what's the
earth thing can you tell me what
yes i promised me right now
like like uh mom mom mommy said
he's gonna he's gonna give us five
pounds on fridays
okay
[Music]
quiet okay so this project thing eric uh
actually italian product can support
more than two elements yeah all right
look you know what
you know this mean function yeah when
you take
mean from your one two now this is
mathematic
it's impossible different mean version
one two it returns one
one okay and then you can look you can
say one
three four or five you can keep as many
it's a
parameters it's not a list you have to
look at their four parameters they're
two parameters and then
this will still work right gives one so
the point is that if
the number of parameters yeah we call it
a number of parameters
it's not fixed remember in python if you
want to define
define mean a b
and you can say if a smaller than b
return
what a ass return b
yeah but here look
it's it's already fixed too so how does
this work
because look it supports more than two
right
and five six etcetera and the thing is
that you can use the
very uh variant argument so
you define it as this mean and then you
put a star here
star nums okay
i know how does it do so you can say
okay
star means that these nums you can give
as many
parameters as possible right it does not
have to be one two fixed number you can
give
two three five a hundred right yeah
you still work then how do you do it
look you can say
uh answer at the beginning we give a
very big number
yeah infinity right and i look for
i in nouns
i know how do i do with this answer
thing right
yes answer equals what what and then
answer can you tell me we want to try to
find the minimum of the
of of all the elements in numbers okay
it's not there come on you need to
understand follow me
uh okay so i want to get
okay let's define this as a f function
okay so this mean
is the anawa meanwhile
what i want to get the means of all
numbers
so what we know
is all the numbers in
i and then wha
why is the numbers i want to get the
answer come on answer
eric do you understand you understand
and then
i never really tend to answer okay
because the answer is the maximum at the
beginning
and then we want to get the minimum yeah
keep updating with the minimum right
yeah so the point here is we're using
these to
to denote the variance number of the
parameters got it
okay so the cartesian product coming
back to this interpolator
either to us dot product
you can take as many parameters as you
want
so remember we remember we we
have these the four only it doesn't work
right remember the first
iteration we have for for i in
a for j in b remember
yeah and yes
i say this wouldn't work because it will
make it
contain more than three elements yeah
you could pretend that a
b c okay it's still is there
this only works for two elements so how
do you
calculate the condition product for
three elements like three one two
and then three four
and then five six what's the condition
for that can you guess
uh
three five one three five
one three six
two three five two three six
two four five two
right one four five one four
six two four three five two three six
two four five two four six okay
okay yeah so how do we
write uh how to implement this product
supporting the variance
of the list abcd you know
how can we do this if we're not
supposing that we can do this
for i in a
for j in b and then for
k in c yeah if you are not already know
that three you can do this and then yeah
you know
yeah that's it but we are we are not
sure how many of them so how can we
define for that
look at this please what should i put
here
okay hey but we how many
we want to put a symbol here to know
that there could be many of them
oh the star sign starts and the value
so you can pass as many as you want okay
and now
we want to define the different search
yeah we're using this definition
remember the
fs the beginning will be left or the
left
and then the current i show you
what does it mean okay so look
a a will be you can convert
a will be passing like a list and you
look if you if
it's one two
three four five six yeah
i i actually is can be like can be
treated like a and a list
and then here left is the which
which uh we start from the first one
right
when we reach the last one we know we
have the answer so
for each one i can i can iterate the
possibility
of all the numbers here you'll be one
two right all right
doesn't make sense here look if
left equal equal length a
if we are reaching the end yeah we do it
reaching the end
right remember we talked about this kind
of algorithm before right it's quite
similar
for currency if we if the
left point array if the left pointer
reaching the end and we have a current
solution so we can
yield here yeah yeah we converted this
current to two power two plus current
and then return okay
now we are at left alright so how many
possibilities here in the a
left yeah so we want to
fall right for i
in a left right
all right does it make sense yeah
so look this is one two
left is here yeah another three four
okay very good left is here right
a left is this this this thing and a
left
i will be one will be two and then i
need to do
one yeah
from d f s
look at this ears no i want to years
from what dss
and left plus one
and currently if i choose i and i know
because
plus i
right and then here will be and then
at the beginning i will yeah it's from
is uh easy to understand or is not
yes no yeah it is uh there's lots of
views
yeah okay so so this is the dfs
the left thingy is at the beginning is
here right
at beginning i start with the first
element right first list
right when it gets to the end when it
gets to the end
and then i know i i found a combination
remember
which is current and then get yeah this
make it a tuple
right at this point currently it's at
least at making the tuber
otherwise i'm here i'm here right
and how many possibilities for the
current one it could be one or cookie
two right
so for i in eight left will delete and
then i try to i try to move it to next
one
because it will move it to the next one
right then i move it to next one because
i can try one or two here and then move
it to next one
which is the current plus i right if i
choose
the first one yeah yeah we can have
another phone
uh this is the local function right that
makes sense here
we we choose the i for
current element and then we try to try
to put the next one remember
we talked about this combination right
combination thingy
do you still remember three apples
picking two apples
yeah yeah yeah how many ways of putting
it right but we
it's the same thing for this one i can
pick
all the elements in the left i that's
the current choice
once i make sure the current choice i go
to the next one
right but i recorded the current options
which is plus i got it
yeah now this is a bit difficult but
that's okay you understand does it make
sense
which people understand
what it's fine it's fine yeah
okay how about can you write
can you write a three
a cartesian product with three elements
six easy huh
either right one product okay product
a b c okay so can you say can you write
a condition for that if there's three
anymore uh yeah three elements so it's
easy yeah
okay so for i
i mean four four thank you for i in
a yeah
okay does it make sense oh yeah
no i mean if
what does it mean
for me i promise i will give you this
but not yet
until you want it okay okay
[Music]
this is this this is the what's this
what does
this mean what's this here
if i i can make it as like this one that
will be uh
what will build the list okay got it
okay well what's the time complexity
[Music]
a times b times c yeah because look at y
one x
you're writing it too close to each
other you should be writing here
for i and then for j here yeah and for k
here yeah you have you need to have a
space yeah
that means that this one is belongs to
this right if you write it
here it means therefore doesn't make
sense
okay please don't do it okay
please