[Laughter]
okay
okay hello mr are you right yeah okay i
hope you don't scare
no people i just ruined my clothes at
them
okay
[Music]
you know what's magic oh yeah you taught
us before so what's magic
are you doing the maid thingy or
something yeah magic yeah
magic like on my bed so this magic
is like a two-dimensional list rows
columns yeah and we are given the binary
matrix
okay can i have your attention please
the final metric so what's fine
two so meaning that the magic can have
contains the elements zero and one
okay yeah unless one more thing for this
binary
metric particular is that each row
the zeros okay sorry like yellows always
come before the
ones so zero zero one one so it's sorted
yeah
okay okay yeah doesn't make sense
we have to return if it's true we want
to find out the
left most leftmost
column that contains the one so in this
case this
corner contains one so you return
one okay okay doesn't make sense
do you understand this problem so let's
see how do you return see what if there
isn't any
even like a good question if there's any
even all
zero yeah yeah return minus one okay
if they're all zero you can't find the
one there's no
such thing as leftmost one and this
isn't mine why do you return
one one because look that's yellow
column column zero column one has the
one okay
got it so how can we solve this problem
the
yeah how can we solve this
what kind of ideas have come to your
mind yeah
no we're done so we we kind of get this
the
before thing right yeah because why
can't we do this because
we can do this again scan from the left
to the right right
because we all know that the zeros comes
before the one
right all right so we can do this
right what's the term complexity for
this one if we do this
if there are r columns and c are all c
columns c sorry c
why is this thing they are times c r c
yes because
in the worst case it's all zeros you
have to scan of it right
yeah yeah okay so let's the best case
is this one yeah look alright
so look so for
column in range
magic yeah if magic
what r c equal
equal one then return what reason which
one returns rc
x matrix are c equals
equals one and with the title rc
no we want to return the column so which
one is the column
c yeah that's it otherwise with 10 minus
one yeah
all right all rc okay
we're done so can we do better
maybe we can wait that this need is fine
yeah of course yeah of course he needs
to be in different but i'm just writing
just to illustrate this idea how to
solve this you know i say well done this
is professing yeah we're checking that
out so how can i do
how can we do better okay how about if i
tell you remember previously if we have
uh
we want to find eric previously
something like that the rows are sorted
the columns are thought if you want to
find the number
in in the metric right we can start with
the right
top right corner right if it's smaller
we go down if it's bigger we go left
right
all right yeah
so look look
previously we have this yellow one two
three and then
and then four or five and then this
maybe
three two one okay something like that
if we want to find out
the let's say that we only find a
six maybe maybe four uh
maybe maybe let's say this is six here
right
and that's the if we want to find out
the six we start here
it's a bigger one it's bigger than three
go down you're bigger than remember if
it's smaller
go left right remember the thing is
the search a target in the binary
mat uh in in the sorted matrix right we
talked about this before
right so because this is sorted and this
is sorted
yeah so look if we were supposed to be
here
sorry i think four's supposed to be here
right
uh yeah kind of kind of look if if this
is this what zero one two three and then
three one two zero if you want to find
the six
yeah if we want to find six it's bigger
then we go down right
if we want to find two it's smaller we
go left right yeah so let's
think if this is one
if this is one do we need to go down
oh we need to go left that's right
because the already is one we need to
check left yeah if it's zero
we need to go down right yeah because
zero we're not sure right
all right and if we go down to the
bottom you go to the next one
if it's zero we go down let's see
because we can't find zero we cross the
boundary and let's say we can't find it
but we already update the answer right
so if it's one we go left we update the
answer because we already know the
the worst case is this one right we
already know there's
one as here right we need to find if
they are less
they are ones and here right
yeah okay so
so let's say answer at the beginning
equals minus minus one we assume it's
not there right okay
and let's ah let's see yeah then at the
beginning rc
equals
the first row next one with zero and c
minus one right
the peak is c minus one yeah so at the
beginning we are here right
yeah at the beginning we are here
wire r is smaller than
r and c
is bigger or equal
yeah because look you can this can
either
go down or go left right
all right all right what if
there was this zero and the zero this
day with one hand one hand
that's okay if it's one here you wanna
that's okay
so look
yeah yeah here yeah go down yeah
go left yeah go down yeah
i know what here what go left
automatic so we finally got it
so look why because it can go only go
left
or go down so ah needs to be smaller
than
real and c needs to be bigger than zero
right
yeah this is zero bigger than zero right
i'm right
it's magic
r c equals 1
if it's equals 1 then what
what what do i do what should we do if
you found the one oh we go to the left
well before that we need to set the
answer right answer equals 1.
what
[Music]
um
maximum where where is the maximum you
can go
guys wait where is
like where
it's start from here yeah so what's how
many steps here go
how many steps are there
three columns rows and what
those what columns previously all time
r and c and what's
[Music]
louder yeah because look no matter how
it goes it's always r plus c
right yeah yeah
here yeah yeah yeah still after i see
right
yeah okay so which one is better
this one okay why is it better because r
plus
is smaller than r minus
r times c right yeah got it
does it make sense there yeah
uh i think okay so let's
uh okay so can you wait in this stupid
are you kidding me
yes yes i'm not kidding yeah and then
it's done yeah let's start yeah
[Music]
weather that's it that's it for today