hello hello mr erin mr ryan how are you
today
so today we talked about an interesting
problem called the bottles
the mere buttons okay buttons
so look if you are given nine bottles of
milk why
just i don't like milk i did
okay meal small milk yoghurt okay
yeah okay so you have it you can
exchange
three empty bottles with a new one
right so the question is how many
can you drink wait what look
nine butters how many can you drink for
night butter nine right
yeah and nine butters
if i say you can exchange three empty
bottles nine butter will become
nine empty bottles and you can exchange
three three empty bottle with
another
[Music]
right so now it's three boots of string
and how many empty bottles of play
three right yeah and then three you can
exchange another one right
yeah doesn't make sense
does it make sense to you kind of
so look at the beginning you have night
butter so how many can you drink now
nine
right yes and after you drink my butters
you
the night butters become empty and you
can exchange nine
empty bottles one two three because
at each three empty bottle you can get a
new one a brand new one
so nine button you can have another
three
new bottles so maybe yeah you drink this
and then now drink this this
becomes empty right then three empty
bottles
you can get another one right
right and then now you have one empty
bottle but you can't exchange because
it's only one right
okay okay so that's today's question is
13. yeah today the question is easy give
it
very first what do you mean which one
would you mean
[Music]
and then you can drink 9 potatoes with 9
bottles you can
exchange to another three bottles right
why can't you
change empty butter what i'm saying is
empty butter you least
you know when you drink all of it before
it's full right you drink it you become
empty
and you're why is this me no i'm just
i'm just this is the question okay this
is the given question and three buttons
will
give you what another one all right
all right got it okay so
different n buttons how many can you
drink
question easy define
drink okay so and column yeah
so how many can you drink so any idea
how we're doing this
oh you need the answer yeah so
so uh right okay
if oh if we can divide it by three
recording uh not exactly it's like
we simulate the process okay we simulate
the process
so look every answer at the beginning we
can drink and butter right that's for
sure right
yeah yeah we want to calculate this
answer and return answer here
okay okay so why
why n n is the current buttons
right why
and is bigger than three
or equal three because when it's bigger
than three we can exchange right
all right i exchanged how exchange
equals
and then this exchange then we can we
can drink it right
so what should we do with the answer
plus equal
extend
because we have this exchange right
we're going to we can drink it
but now n equals
what and n is the number of the boxes
multiply three
look because we already use the divided
by three and then this is the remaining
right
this is the remaining empty button plus
plus one we have yeah we're done yeah
because we already drink this exchange
and this is the new
empty bottle right this is the previous
empty bottle
the new the the new empty buttons is and
then we go
closer let's see what's the time
complexity
you see every time we divide by three we
divide it right
too big and one uh
then no no it's quite cool it's not it's
the other way
you know it's the other way and
key you're nice what's owen
all right o and qp that's what ryan said
but i said this is
the opposite what's that oh
no no not the opposite log three base
annually
yeah why is that look every time we
divide
by three and then we yeah
okay look at why is that look nine
three one yeah how many threes can it
can you be
so every time you divide by three right
right three divided by
three equals one one divided by three
yeah so because that the thing is y
and bigger than three so every time we
divided by three divided by
every time we divided by two by divided
by two let's log n right
base two now is log three yeah doesn't
make sense er
yeah can you tell me can you tell me can
you explain to me
what is this yeah
yeah okay so well n bigger than three
then we can x
gain yeah we have that
exchange equals like x like if it was
nine
you divided by three which is three yeah
and then the answer cost three exchange
which
is three so nine plus three is
twelve okay and then n equals n
modulus three plus the exchange
and three divided by three equals one
and
and one is exchanged so nine plus three
plus one equals thirteen
okay so what's this why why we adding
this exchange
why if we can why can you explain to me
in words not the numbers
right because we answer plus exchange
this is the new bottle
we got right by exchange and then when
we drink it
when you drink it at least becomes empty
butter
right why are we moderate spicy because
we previously we have nine bottles
uh maybe we have tempers over here right
if we have 10 butters
we exchange
nine bottles to three new bottles right
and how many
left is one right yeah look
one one this is nine butters ten bottles
yeah
ten bottles right ten butters and here
we can exchange three right
yes how many left here
one left we can't exchange this is this
is one
and multiply by three right and plus
exchange what's the exchange we already
exchanged b
here here yeah and then this becomes
empty buttons again but remember we have
one more
previously so we have four empty buttons
yeah this is one plus three
and then one and four we go go to here
doesn't make sense yes
yeah yes are you sure
okay whatever you say okay come on the
last bit come on
i just raised in front of you return
answer
no yeah no yeah
i think the highest even yeah percentage
yes yes plus three exchange
exchange
i mean
[Music]
look at this guy look at this guy look
at me
look at this guy listening to the
greater than music own