[Music]
so what's the longest interval
we're given at least a list of
intervals we present with the start and
end
those are the integers okay start the
end for example like
1 3 1 3
this is a list of inner one three two
four three six maybe no no five
ten okay let's let's just do this three
intervals so if we
plot it in the line okay we plot it in
the line
this is yellow this is one this is two
this is three this is four this is five
and somewhere here is ten so one three
look once we start with the one
and the three is this one yeah i plotted
here
two and four is here two and four
you're just doing okay and then five and
ten
yeah okay so look when we combine the
intervals we have two parts these
one to four right and then five to ten
but this
the length here is five yeah the lens
here is three so you need to tell me
inside yes exactly so what if they're
both it doesn't matter because we return
the
longest length right
then we turn one of it which is also the
same right
it's like this length is three this
distance is like
eight yeah right i don't know three and
then you you need to tell me that's the
three
is the maximum the longest
okay so if we these are the integer it
can be negative so how we
solving this problem if we if we want to
look
at these are not particularly in order
right the intervals are i'm giving you
it's not from the left to the right
and how about if we want to visit it
from the left to the right how can we do
this
uh certain sorting yes so if the
interval given the interval so let's say
i went again interval
again complexity okay
so if we are sorting this and how are we
um solving this if we if this is the
same
uh how can we perform this one secondary
possibility
checking but not particularly in this
case how can we
oh anyway how can we do this
if we something something why why are we
sorting this uh
interval we want to visit in them in
from left to right order right
so if we visit the left right uh
how can we we can keep uh
what can we do with it look if this
current interval
we start from the second one the the
first one is interval
zero yeah we already know the star and n
here
right okay so even the next interval
what how many possibilities for the next
interval
it could be notes no no what i'm saying
is the positions
the style could be is bigger than the
star right so it could be
here this one it could be this way
or it could be this way right yeah all
right
there's three possibilities right
doesn't make sense no
not really this is a star and n and then
if we take in the next interval
it's on the right so it could be this
way this way or this way
but this is not connected to the
previous one right
yeah so for these two cases
for these two cases we don't change the
star right
because it will be connected to the next
interval right
yes but we we need to
we if if this is disjoint if the next
interval is not connected to the
previous one
so we need to change the start update
the start to this one
all right yeah and in all the cases
we need to update the n equals
the maximum of n current n and the new n
yeah and the new n right doesn't make
sense
yeah all right because the
end is uh if this this is the case look
if it is this case
the this new n is not bigger than the
old previous end so we don't update it
right but these two cases
are larger than the previous and am
right yeah
okay everything do you understand now
do you understand which part you don't
understand
[Music]
you're fine are you sure you're fine i'm
fine
okay so can you tell me how can we solve
this problem
oh uh okay so uh okay so
these are all the possibilities
and there's a start and we end yeah
while we're keeping me started
and and if then they're disconnected
yeah we extend it and yeah and then when
we have this start and
we want to we can calculate the length
yeah i'm right i'm right eric focus
i'm right yeah you're right okay so can
we write this problem
can we let it cool
um please focus okay focus everyone
likes funny things
longest interval
was let's say data okay let's keep it
data first
okay if we're not giving any data
what should we return
[Music]
right so what's data also the
complexities
where n is the length of the data right
now we have restart
and and current style and current
interval okay
equals because we want to get the first
one which one which is one
right yeah the first one okay all right
and then we start from the second one
yeah from let's say the
new star okay new star and then new n
right let's destroy it and in
we want to start with the second
interval to the end so what should i put
here
second interval to the end
column what what's second one
one column start from the second one
okay and then look
if the new star that we want to check
compared to that if
new star is bigger than the star what
should we do
this is the star this is the end
wait wait this is the new star here
just guessing okay new style okay
okay so that will be here and then end
and we want to update the end to the
maximum of
equals what max one or one and
okay we have this answer yeah answer
will be equals to
at the beginning will be equals m plus
the first one m plus star
n minus star plus one right yeah m minus
n
answer we we can we want to check if the
current time n is the max
is longer than the answer so how what
can we do here um
the next eagle max maxwell
and equal stuff i know what
equals the new new legend
what's the length what's that what's
this
dance it is
ah and minus and
minus start time
yeah it's always again because this part
is what this part is one or one
oh and which is bigger oh and logan okay
what's the
space complexity
what's the space complexity
and where are we using data
data data is given if we don't consider
that as the additional space
so what's the time what's the space
complexity
what i just said a one yeah okay
i said i won okay okay
hello hello
boogie if that's
if that look this is star this is n
and then if the new star is bigger than
n
right so what if start
and yeah you end and
new star cannot be bigger than you and
come on right
[Music]
i know well if new start bigger than and
we want to one
what
[Music]
on you you did you know it before and
then you
forgot right if
you start bigger than end what should we
do which what what should we do
[Music]
that
if it's if it's smaller than n what does
it mean
these two parts if mu star is smaller
than
n yeah this is n minus the new star
what does it mean we can connect this as
a combine yeah
am right away yeah
do you understand we don't understand
do we understand enough they can
if news dot
where's the pen yes
this pen is running out start
what equals
yeah that's it that's it bye bye bye
bye