hello mr eric mr ryan how are you today
good good okay so today we talk about uh
something about financially yeah even
look one two one four you didn't
sleep even leaves seven
and then two four okay so this is the
final three finally two mean what what's
binary mean
you got two two wait
okay so now how many rules are there
one which is two okay
we're going to delete evenly yeah so
first of all we want to delete these
which are even yeah what are the inside
even numbers
okay so if we did this yes we did this
we did
this and look what are the even numbers
now
two two two just two leaves two
two three okay so no okay so you need to
tell me it's two one
seven correct so
does it make sense so look at the
beginning look eric look here
at the beginning we remove the four but
now after we remove the four the two
becomes
leaf yeah yeah i know we don't move it
again all right
yeah okay so any idea how we open this
problem
yeah therefore you could do breakfast
maybe
yeah but we talked about deficits today
okay yeah okay so how are we solving
this look
oh we can't believe and if we're even
we are deleted
okay okay stop doing that yeah
so so eric everywhere so
we repeatedly travel the tree in
different search right and then
if we leave no we don't move it yeah
yeah and
leave and even now we'll be moving and
after that we need to repeat it
check right yes yeah
good all right okay so follow over
delete even
leave blood
okay if
not rude what's your widow uh
return nothing return nothing because if
it's empty it's not
it we just return it yeah if it's empty
thing yeah okay now loot
the left okay so what what does it mean
do the left
all right no don't left yeah i don't
care what's this yeah i don't care what
sleeve
so loot left i want to remove the leaf
nose from the left tree so how can we do
this
we want to remove the left tree believe
that even even this from the left tree
so
what should we do now we cushion yeah
so why should i put here what's it
happen here
what should i put here what's the name
of the function
yeah even
leaves and what should i put in here
we go left yeah
[Music]
but change the left to right
so what does it mean it means that all
right everything i will do it
all right what is everything what does
it mean it means that here is the loot
right
this is the look look at me look at here
yeah this is the loop now i'm calling
the recursion to do the job
yeah do the job for the left tree and
the right tree right
okay yeah and after that what should we
do next
and then if this dude becomes the leave
again
yeah so what does it mean look if canvas
how do we check if the root balloon is
the leaf now
now because i already did that
you know apply this function to the left
string and to the right tree
and it might be possible that these two
will be removed yeah because
yeah all right so and now if we check
the root is the difference so how can we
say it would do within the leaf now
how can we check if the low is the leaf
now if blue
what really does left
so what does it mean what does it mean
every the value what
[Music]
does not have any kid ali
yeah it's a leaf now now right yeah if
it's a leaf now
then if root of value you can't divide
by three
yeah or modular two or n one yeah equals
zero
and then what should we do if it's a
loop
return now because now if it's the leaf
now i will move it
otherwise here yeah yeah
because we need to go through
[Music]
2 you can also write it as n one right
equals zero it's the same thing yeah
yeah this is one
right and one this is binary yeah that
doesn't make sense
okay that's it for today