hello
hello hello guys
hello everyone ryan hello hello guys
okay so today
we'll talk about the something that's
very interesting
is called equilibrium
[Music]
complexity complexity algorithm
complexity complex yeah
why do we need this because that it's a
way
that we analyze how efficient an
equilibrium is
okay so yeah okay so for example like
if i have a number at least a number
like three
two one five seven
so this is the computer uh this is the
list of computer input
so if we want to know the maximum
in the in the in this in this case
how um what do you think how many times
the computer needs to
check like this is the numbers this is
the list of numbers what are we doing
so finding the maximum maximum
yeah i know the human can just look it's
seven right but the computer don't know
he has to check the first number okay it
has to keep a
maximum current maximum for example is
three
is two bigger than three no is one
bigger than three
no is five bigger than three yes let me
upload this
yes yeah is seven second and three yes
together five yes okay and then now he
found that
so the computer needs to scan once right
if there are any items and elements in
the list
he needs to check n times right
yeah so in so
you know how to do this yeah define yeah
max
n right yes yeah you can just do this uh
if this answer is a very small number
let's say uh let's say put in the first
number at the beginning
and zero okay and then those four i
in answer uh in n
what do we know if i bigger than
answer right then answer equals i all
right
you see chicken chicken is least
and if it's the number it's bigger than
the color maximum and i
update it right this is the method i
just told you right give me the maximum
so
if i update it and it kind of maximizes
right
updated is seven okay
okay so so look the computer needs the
in
needs to check and items so it turns
each time it needs to end right so this
leads to
our complexity we use the big o
which is n okay this is called linear
because the computer need
influence n if if that 100 items
yeah if n is 100 then computer needs to
check how many times
100 yes exactly how a thousand
a thousand yes you see the as this grows
and then the computer needs to check
that the number yeah so
basically this is n this is t and then
basically it needs to check this is
called initial yeah this is 100 and then
what it
corresponds is 100 here got it this is
called linear yeah
okay so this is convenient okay so
yeah yeah you remember okay so i put it
here
[Music]
and this is called linear yeah linear
so how about let's say if i remember
yesterday we talk about mathematic
induction right
remember can you remind me for the sum
of the first and positive numbers
what do you mean remember
one two three four over n remember
yes this equals n times m
plus one divided by two right yes
yes yes
yes okay so tell me if there are
if n is a thousand how many terms does
the computer need
no because the computer can just work
out by this mathematic formula
right you can just plug in the a
thousand here
right and then you can get the
equations you can turn the number
immediately right what
even it's ten million it's one time yeah
or one time yeah if it's one million
it's still
instant right computer can just work out
the formula basically
so it means that the complexity does not
grow
as the size of the input so what does it
mean is the
complexity is one o
one which is called constant
do you get it zero oh no
big big o oh oh like
oh
okay so this is another way okay
constant
remember remember the final research
yeah
yeah yes yes exactly so look yes
so tell me if if they are
looking if this is
zero this is a
okay if this is zero is eight how many
times
i need to for the computer needs to
check
if i want to look for the number like
seven how many times the
seven yeah the computer needs to find
the number seven here and
in final research remember how do we do
it
how do we do this final research do you
still remember how do we do the final
research
we change now we check in the middle
right the meter is four right yes
[Music]
it doesn't matter you just pick a
dominant number it doesn't have to be
exactly the meter you just have to be
around meter so it's seven bigger than
four
yes so it's it's definitely in this side
right
and then an a and four the middle
what four and eight six six okay so here
and is it six seven bigger than six yeah
okay so i don't need to consider this
yeah so the answer is here right
seven and six meter seven yeah we find
it you see so how many times
maximum it needs it needs two
three times right three three times so
what do we know is three times
is that two times two times two
bigger or equal than eight right there
only three twos right
yeah so this is called rock
so you probably don't i don't know the
function yeah that's equal
yeah so we can write this way look if if
2 times 2 times 2 equals
a right yeah 2 to the power of 3 equals
am right
yes yes so we can write it this way
3 look at this number look look it's
very
look this yes 3 equals log 2
this is log function so basically look
log
a b equals c what can we do that
a to the power of c equals b okay this
is
you basically can transform to each
other okay
do you understand so 2 to the power of 3
equals a so we can
write 3 equals log 2a okay so log
log 2 is a function it takes the n
x y equals log to x so we can transform
2 to the power of x
equals 1 okay so the complexity for this
is o log
n right we call it log
green okay i don't know how to spell
this
logarithm okay lottery so basically
basically is for final search if the
size
is if the size is 16
how many times the computer needs do you
mean
about yeah if this final these
footprints is 16 how many times did the
camera need
uh three no so he's eight sixteen
four four yes because it's one more step
yeah yeah
it's getting harder yeah wait wait five
[Music]
to k right we can write it this way log
2 128 equals a
so basically it's 2 to the power of a
equals
okay okay so this is optimal
okay so now moving next as you can see
this is the most efficient yeah i should
probably write this first
constant is the most efficient right and
then on linear
i don't know and then not log n faster
than
o n and what's next
[Music]
n square we call it n square or called
quadratic
okay quadratic how do you spell
code think yeah
don't understand this one conjected
yeah it basically means this you got a
square right
so look look look
if there are five numbers yes yeah
five numbers five numbers uh one
two three four five six seven
eight and nine ten eleven so can you
tell me how many pairs
can you if you pick two numbers for it
how many pairs can you do it
if there's there's a you know
sequence like you can pick one two
you can pick one too right yeah maybe
a few uh three just three numbers yes
one two
one three two three
one and then you can
do the other way two one three one three
two right
so six right yeah whoa
you can just times it by about two uh
number by two yeah yeah yeah um
yeah so look so how many how many
if i how many how many solutions would
that be
how many so if i uh if i pick
n here right so i can i need to
go to n minus one right n minus one
so basically the solution is left right
yes
divided we need to divide it three times
two six
right
always they're smaller to the biggest
one if you want to and
to one is the same then you probably
need to divide entire two
right so okay all right all right
all right so we haven't talked about
another one is called the
boundary no no no these look linear
first yeah
uh i just put it here for a while this
is n square right
n square like uh this is called
quadratic
okay so how about if a list
yeah and items if i want to search only
half of it
so uh these eggs if i told you i want to
just
to do half of it what's the complexity
is the anemia then you search
look there are n items but i want to i
only need to scan half of it
right previously it's linear yeah
because
this time the t is to end to that
oh well two right but still we we
if o n the the complexity is on y
because we drop the constant if it's
constant we drop it
yeah because the constant don't change
am i right
yeah so for like equilibrium analysis
if that evaluates a constant if even is
two times
and a hundred times n yeah if it needs
to go through a hundred times
this approach is tier me is still
scouting as
linear right am right
okay so the quadratic is uh let's go
back to the consensus okay
we haven't talked about that closer good
job
don't touch it okay uh because look eric
three numbers
three four two if you want to sort it
two three four yes i know but computer
look computer easily
n is three yeah and three numbers how do
we solve it computer here
and then another this is i this is j
yeah the two okay compare right
and then compare if two if if two is
smaller than three
okay i stop it okay and then j is here
yeah
this is three smaller than four
right okay so basically
basically if the i needs to go through n
step right
and for every i the j needs to go
through
n minus one and minus two step
right and etc so the complexity
is is the checking is around
n times n minus 1 divided by 2 okay so
this is still
quadratic right look because this is a
constant
all right this is constant this is
constant so this
this timing is still
approaching me to cons to project it
okay so we all know we all so
when the aggregate gets more complex we
also have these
yeah we call it cubic right cubic
and we have we have something
in between here yeah we call it o n log
n in the future we come
all this will not see in the future we
come across
some quick thoughts okay maybe i talk
about a quick sorting agreement
tomorrow and so look
one constant is the most efficient yeah
if you can solve a problem using a one
we prefer the one right
and then we and then this is the second
rotherland yeah and then
positive anemia linear than this one
and quadratic and cubic and then we have
also the exponential 2 to the power of n
and we also have n bacteria remember
bacteria yes
oh we also have l squared
square n what's this square root
square root remember we we want to check
if our number
we want to check if a number is a prime
number or not right we only need to go
through the square root of
integer to check if it's divided by that
right
divisible and uh
yeah so
can you give me an example of the
factorial remember so if if this one two
three okay one two three
so that you want to know how many
how many ways i can i can list those
three numbers
how many one two three how many how many
ways i can miss three numbers
one two three one three two right
two one three two three one
three one two eighteen three two one
what eighteen only six right is there
only six can you list
any almost communication we call it
permutation
permutation yeah permutation of n items
is n factorial do you do not
understand why if there are n numbers
how do we know is n factorial
how many away these three numbers three
factorial equals six
so there are six solutions do you know
why okay if i put n numbers
how many solutions i can put on the
first first first integer
first bit i can pick how many solutions
how many y is five there are only
three three slots six
no one chicken is how many there are n
there are three numbers how many numbers
can i put in the first one
do a fraction uh
one what is one there one two three what
is one how many numbers i can put on the
first stop
i just told you one two three how many
more months are gonna put
yes we yeah i can put one two three yeah
the first one yeah
if i pick one numbers how many numbers
can i put in the second place
yeah because i only put one right yeah
okay two and how many numbers i can put
for one
you see so if there are n numbers i can
do it this way
n times n times n minus 1
times 3 look at the n minus 2 right
and until 1 so this is exactly the n
factorial look at it
so if i tell you if the 4 numbers 1 2 3
4 how many permutations are there
uh
24 yes exactly you get it so this is
called
bacteria right
okay so
[Music]
yeah and then you put whatever number
here
i choose one and then two
and then okay
okay so so let's do the sorting now
for for this fully sorting okay so
look this is the first one yeah first
the fastest
thoughtful fact is to slow this constant
is the 40th
and then log n
second square root third
linear fourth factorial
and eight block and five i know what's
next
quadratic six cubic
seven right and
these two which one is first i don't
know i have to check maybe this is
next and this is yeah this is the slow
test
okay do you get it
what the is oh yeah contact
[Music]
we need to analyze the complexity okay
right
and another way this is called runtime
complexity and also we have
another similar approach similar
analysis called space complexity
space is we can also use leads to
analyze the space it means how many
space do you need right
if you if you need another n i'd
m items if you if the size is n and you
need
to allocate another n space for this
equilibrium
and the complexity is o n right the
first space okay
yes okay good job today
any questions okay
no shaking what do you just think