hi hello mr harry mr ryan are you okay
yeah okay so today we will talk about
uh digital okay
all right so given the integer positive
integer
only contains the number one two or
three
like two three three you need to tell me
if you can
flip one digit and tell me the maximum
number you can get
so what's the maximum number you can get
by changing one digit to three
three three two three three
three three three okay how about three
two one three three one
how about three one two three three two
how about one uh
how about two one one
three one okay hold on
oh about three three three three okay so
yeah you got it so what's the strategy
what's the angle
from this one and that's what the
biggest number
and if it's the uh
so you base basically you check you
check
you replace the first
from left to right first number first
stitches that is not three and then
change it to three if
it's not if releasing any then you just
return it right
all right that's what you use okay so
that's the greedy yeah so
we start greedy strategy we start from
the left
we go through the right we check we stop
and the first digit that is not three
and then we change it to three all right
okay
you can already
enough you can that's your strategy
yeah i said enough
okay
and what's the missing here column
okay now n is a number yeah n is a
number we want to convert it to
an array of digits yeah how how can we
do it all we can
i mean there are few ways we can do it
but what i'm saying is look if it's one
two three this is the
array yeah listen
this is the integer yeah if you want to
convert it to a
string we use this str right
yeah str and that will give me
a string which is one two three all
right
yes okay
convert the number to string and give me
a string this is a string this is a
number okay
it's different type okay okay
yeah and i'm having it now
you're not listening i am okay and then
now if i want to convert it
to to leave a list of
digits how can we do this all right
if you want to convert it to list three
three no i mean here this is a string
yeah this is a string type
and then i want to convert it to a list
a list of a list of digits
yeah a list and then look converted here
sprn okay okay and now we have a list
then it's easier we go through the list
from left to right and stop
if it's not three and we change it right
right
okay so look that was my way ar
equals list what what should i put here
here
list one uh
okay now now look and i i want to go
through the numbers eric
i want to close the list from left to
the right
and stop so do you still remember this
immunity
in the numerate
aorta
remember
this is the start with the index zero
one two and this is the very where j
will be the value like one two
three got it all right if you say for i
in a r then you will leave your i will
be one two or three here right
but if you put it as i j in illuminate
i will be zero what j will be
no no i'm talking about this so look i
is the index
right look when look if j
is not equals to what what am i
[Music]
we want to change it to three right yeah
so
look hey
and then when i change one number i want
to i don't want to change anymore right
break it
well don't break it then return
break it during hey wait i just said
stop it
it's okay okay break and then what
should i do with here
how can i convert this back we can no no
no how can i convert this back to the
number
look i just tell you the way to convert
it
to string yeah and then convert to the
list and how
how to convert it back
yeah john this is a string and how can
we convert it to integer
how can we convert it to integer
yeah in yeah well done look
if you convert a string to an integer
using function if you convert the
integer to a string use the
str stands for string function yeah if
you want to
convert it from string to a list of the
character you use the list function
yeah if you want to convert a list list
into a string you use the join
this is the delimiter okay and if you
want to convert
uh eric if you want to convert the a
look at a
space b space c
[Music]
if you want to convert these to abc
how what's the function
yeah look there's a space sorry
i joined up no no no this no this is the
other way i'm talking about
look if you're using a list you will
convert every digit but i won't i
yeah join is this way
i'm talking about this way what's the
opportunity
what's the opportunity of join
no break no join
the other way start with s string
the second letter is p
okay what the opposite of join what's
that
s p
yeah split so look at this one abc
dot split uh space
that you will split by space and abc
okay it's a
little bit different than at least okay
what do you do release
what happened eric when you do the list
what happened when you do a list of
these
what is that what what happened
this you have how many elements of list
abc space how many three
one two three three i mean look at that
space when you convert when you do the
list
you will have every letter every
character so there will be five
right yeah yeah but when you do the
split
the space now you only have three abc
got it that's the difference
does it make sense i said three no
three you say three is least is no
wrong split is three this is five okay
but do you know the difference major
difference
does it make sense what's the time
complexity
n is the number of the digits in the in
the
string okay what's the space complexity
n no one one
you need to be confident okay it doesn't
make sense
you forgot this yeah yeah a space
empty the dream dot john john
okay look at there's a bracket open
bracket open like a clothesline and you
need another one okay i'll do it
okay okay