hey hello mr mr rhino you alright
okay okay so today we talk about a
string
two string you know uh strings yeah
string the letters
eric ryan okay okay
a b c
[Music]
given two strings s1 and s2
can you tell me that if one string is
the rotation of vanilla so what what the
what does mean
rotate like airy yeah you rotate you'll
be
like that why
put it here you see nice right yeah
and and ah
you see that's rotating yeah
yeah got it so you basically you could
take one letter from the beginning
put it at the end or you take the take
the letter from the end
and put it on the beginning right right
doesn't make sense
okay so so if i give you okay if i give
you the
e-r-i-c small case and i i
see you need to tell me yes because e
right
yeah you can go look it
it can go what it can mean you see that
it can the front community yeah yeah
then it becomes
yeah it was rice and lyric
[Music]
that right so now so that's the rotating
version okay
so given two strings s1 and s2 can you
tell me how to do it
oh oh oh yeah
how can we do it think about it how can
we do it okay we just
move the first letter to the back
yeah just like yeah
so so what how can we try it
oh we need to first let it give it back
and then and then we'll keep moving it
right until until what
until it gets the same and
no maybe it's not the same until what
i'm asking you to check out from ryan
and then
and until it's and if you haven't got it
and it's king ryan again is
okay so so how many times we need to try
iteration s1
events yeah all right yeah
if that's if these two strings are of
different size do we need to try
if they're different no because that's
not possible right yeah
exactly not possible okay and if it's
the same size i can just
eat uh immune right yeah simulate fine
taking one letter from the beginning and
then put it at the end and check
if it's the same right yeah can we do
this
define
so first of all how can we check if the
size is different and it's not the same
how can we do it
can we do it all right yeah
let's say n m equals length
s1 length s2 right this is the length
and then what happened next
even if it's not the same size
[Music]
yeah and then we return false we're
there
okay now let's take s1 and put the one
together and so how many times four
i in range range i need any of them yeah
n or m right it's the same in this case
right yeah
yeah all right yeah so look s1
equals i want to take the
s1 from the second letter
to the to the last letter right
one is the second letter to the last
letter minus one right
yeah uh actually i can take
until the end as the first the second
letter so look at
a b c s one s one
s one one column is this right
yeah and then plus one can you tell me
plus one
s1 this is s1 abc
s1 one column is start from the second
letter to the end
with bc and then i need to plus one
plus one that one that one is what
s one yeah yeah okay then if
f1 what if
s one equals
[Music]
uh what's the time complexity
um
[Music]
this is o n but usually these you know
string
uh string operation yeah put taking the
string and putting that
rearrangement of the string takes on so
like over time
square one square okay what's the space
compressive
okay uh
it's hard to say because they look at
this is the additional space
right so oh and maybe not
because we look at this one
can we do better maybe we can
can we do better anyway okay look i
can show you a b c d f g
what's the rotation of what's the
rotation of it a b c a
and then
look at what abc bca
cab do you think what's the problem do
you see what what
how can we do this
a b c b c a c a b
wait wait let me get this straight let
me have it
like so
so we can just we need to see how many
lenses
and we just i might i think
yeah abc whatever abc
and then we go like here
yeah i got it almost there you don't
need to write the
third one just two one right because a b
c a b
c you just might say a minus one look s
one plus
s s1 that will contain all the rotation
of abc right
look abc abc look abc is here
bca is here cab is here right
yeah so i just put it se s1 plus s1
so if s2 is the rotation of s1 or s1 is
the rotation of s2 i just need to check
if s2 is in there right yes
yeah so look i don't need this
i don't need this and here you go v10
f2 in
x1 plus s1 well done let's see
you see simplified yeah
this is this and and two enchanters
finding in two encounters is usually
and the worst cases or n right but we
have better solution
than o and to search an index in the
string but you can
think of it as o for now right
yeah does it make sense yeah
[Applause]
nothing i'm having it this time
return is their s2 and
s1 plus s1 all s1 in
s2 plus s2 is the same right correct f
2 in s1 plus s1 in lowercase
um
[Music]
okay that's it for today bye bye i'm not
finished yet
okay does it make sense alright brian
yeah yeah okay