[Applause]
okay so today we talk about
the numbers again so we we're given a
list of numbers about target yeah we're
given a list of numbers we want to find
out the
sum of any two numbers that
that is bigger than the target but it's
the lowest
but has the lowest one like this one i
think
three three five seven
nine seven nine ten
no no no no no okay that's it once
you're eleven
okay i need eleven and the target is
let's say the top is eight so can you
find two numbers
that the sum of these are
bigger than eight but it's the smallest
remember we we we have a
three five sorry three and five
they're strictly bigger than that how
many numbers can we use
two numbers remember previously we have
these kind of similar questions
finding two numbers let's some less than
the target but the largest
three and seven three and seven are one
and nine
yeah three and seven or one and nine
yeah we're done
because one plus one plus nine is ten
three plus seven is ten it's bigger than
a but it's the smallest yeah you can't
find
any numbers two numbers the sum are
bigger than a
but it's the smallest right smallest
than 10 am right
how can we do it remember similarly
previously we talked about
sum of any two numbers that is smaller
that is smaller than the target and we
want to find the
largest now this is opposite we want to
find the lowest sum which is bigger than
the target previously we want to find
the
largest sum which is small
yeah okay so it's the same so can you
remind me how we're doing this
if you're not sure we can always pay for
us
okay so what kind of how can we put a
force
for us any pairs and if there are n
numbers what's the term complexity to
prove first thing the the pairs of two
uh
l square oh n square okay so we can find
any two number we sum up and if it's
that
if it's bigger than target we'll find a
minimum of it right
what okay let's do this
proof of thing okay
defy okay just f
nums target
okay and equals length
nums and now first of all the answer
will be equals to what a very big number
right we only french polish
infinity inf okay then
i in range redwater
the second number the index french
rejuva up to after i yes
then if this current equals
nums nums what the two numbers
how to place it together number
one column the index the first number
is i the second number index j so left
plus num's
[Music]
bigger
come on feel the blanks
i'll do this one of course that's easy
and then how about you
do that once no no police
if this sum is bigger than the target
and then we want to find the minimum
yeah max also
equals max minimum no max
yeah yeah be confident okay you can do
it you see
what's going on now all right all right
come on
come on please no
no i know
[Music]
zero to n minus one the index j
it starts from zero to i minus one okay
got it
yes that's mine can we do better
maybe we can
previously how can we solve this problem
how can we solve this problem
okay look at 1 3 5 7
9 10 eleven we want to find a cup of tea
okay okay so if this number is not salty
we sort it so and then we can use one
we can use one what's the t point there
yeah and how can we apply the two points
okay if this left this is
right we need to sort it first yeah
salty first okay what's the some
complexity to solve
again okay so left and right what's the
sum of numbers
and it's 12 and so 12.
okay that's good and then so we try to
make it smaller
to see if we can improve our score they
move it right
we're done what's your space what was
the sum 11 i know we improve and
we move we have to keep moving that's
ten
yeah yeah hey okay i know what happened
no it can't right now and then we have
to move the leg
well down wow are getting there and
seven seven
is ten and we can improve
then we move the left or right uh
left right right yeah okay that's it
what do i need okay good
two-pointer it's the same thing as the
finding the largest that
are smaller than the target right this
is basically opposite right
yeah this is a very good review okay
uh so first of all how can we solve
these numbers
break it okay and
left right left right equals
minus one okay
why the left and right no meat right
yeah all right and caroline
equals what
numbs left plus one that's right
yeah okay if
current bigger than target i have an
answer
on the equal minion answer this year we
forgot yeah i'm current what answer
is
we want to find the minimum yeah and now
and then here what should we do and
write minus one
and i have minus equal one else left
equals
one that's equal one return answer
answer what's the time complexity
what's the time complexity this is one
this is what this
i want to sound is on this one yeah and
oh and so which one is bigger what's the
thumbnail again
why is that no no no
because they're bigger this one is
bigger
okay
right minus equals one
okay and then what else you're missing
one
come on
[Music]
me of the current
answer the current okay
okay that's it that's it for today good
job
bye bye bye
hello and today we're gonna have a break