hello hello mr mr ryan how are you today
okay so today we talked about uh
a rocket examiner that's mass
yeah mass and we we are coming from the
earth
and then we have a robot we can move it
is what is a name
a special noun yeah what do you call
that a proper noun a proper noun yeah
the earth and we need a few spaceships
we don't need a
column okay we need we have a few
spaceships
rocket yeah and we have a list of people
like uh
the weight let's say 100 200.
that's gonna be a very heavy people yeah
four hundred
you know oh are you kidding me yeah yeah
okay
and let's say each each space each
market can carry the limit four hundred
yeah leave me
in four hundred and each spaceship can
only carry
at most two people right two people
so how many spaces the minimum number of
species do we need
uh to carry all those people if
if the maximum weight of each people
is less than the limit right three right
if
we place 500 we can't do this right
because 500 can't put into the spaceship
right
yeah so let's say if we know
all the people the maximum weight of the
people is less
or equal than the limit okay so how many
do we need how many
here three and take two tell me what
what are three
you can do one hundred two hundred two
hundred and four hundred
one hundred two hundred what and then
two hundred yeah another one
and four sorry so
yeah come on yeah and 200 and 400. yeah
let's see
what's the strategy of doing that
[Music]
i mean how can you all we can do is 200
and 100 and 400 right it's the same yeah
okay so let's say if i have another 200
here
no no if we have another 300 here so
what how do you do this
then you say a 300 because there isn't
any 300 people
sorry what does it mean you didn't say
another 300 because
okay okay 300 okay so there's a size 300
so
how how should we organize these 100 300
200 200 400.
yes
okay so what's the strategy oh wow
okay so you're trying to find
combinations
to the target so it's no limit
which is that
that but if there is no right if this
if this is 250 okay
so what if this is 180 okay so
[Music]
this dc
okay so what's what's your strategy in
this case
okay so
uh well
so what are you trying to do here
obviously those these are just
five numbers yes but it's easy to say we
only need
a only can have two
yeah because maximum yeah because only
one
spaceship can only carry two so so what
they must be very smooth very small
so what happens if i pick the most
heaviest
okay so for example this is 400 yeah the
spaceship
even the current maximum is 400 yeah
yeah oh maybe let's see let's say if
that
just left 300 yeah if the current
maximum is 300
this is the most service here i pick the
most harvest
one so because i only can pick one here
so do i pick the second heaviest
or the most light lightest lightest
why is that because heaviest heaviest uh
and not okay so heaviest and lightest
has my
nice chance of getting less than the
target
where the let's cook one okay so look
harry
if look if this lightest one
can go in the spaceship
right so it can only hit a rocket
it also what does it mean it means that
the slightest one can
also go with any other right
yeah why why does that oh oh oh yeah
okay this is the most heaviest yeah the
most heaviest so
lightest it must be smaller ah
smaller than 300 and
and uh because it can go with
any yeah this is because we got 100
yeah and 300 that makes 400
and then and then and then that's the
biggest
greatest and when you get smaller
definitely smaller than the target
okay so i kind of understand what you
mean look this enough listen now
the light is look listen now this is
most heaviest
if the lightest can go with the most
heaviest
that these lightest can go with any
other shape any other way
right right because any other way is
smaller than the most heavy i'm right
okay that's what i said okay if the
ladies cannot go
with the most heaviest what does it mean
it means it means we need to
check go with the lightest with the
second
biggest no no if this must have it
cannot go with the
lightest then what does it mean it tells
us that the most heaviest cannot go with
any other
weight right because even the lightest
cannot go
then all other all other weights are
bigger than the lightest
right oh yeah yeah yeah doesn't make
sense
so let's just make it go right yeah yeah
okay so what does so what's the strategy
here
what's the strategy here well if we saw
these numbers
that would be 100 180
200 250 300
okay if we saw this number does it what
did we
learn yesterday
remember that yesterday what did we
learn
oh two pointers can we apply it oh yeah
yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah it's the same thing
we saw this
every time we check the most harvest
right
and we have the lightest right
we check if these two can fit into 400
the limit
then we go we move it here if it's
bigger than the
most likely that one no we just let it
go right
got it so so it's like that
saying it's gone and then
[Music]
yeah because that what that's pretty
that greedy strategy why is that i just
told you because the only
one rocket can only have two people
right
yeah remember if the most have it can go
with the lymon societies it can go with
any other right
no no if the most if if normal service
can go with the lightest yeah
this ladies can go with any other right
it's what must have it cannot go with
the lightest what does it mean
it can only go by itself right because
it's only the
even the most lightest cannot go with
the most service
like the most heaviest will just go by
itself right yeah
okay that's very interesting yeah ryan
doesn't make sense ryan yeah
are you sure you're listening
are you sure
mommy said this is cleaner okay okay
define rock it
lock it and now we have this weight
weight and now we have this limit column
okay look let's say uh
count called column is equal to zero at
the beginning
and first of all we need to do what one
thing what would you do oh
no i'm still sort of waiting wait also
wherever it
is okay well what's the time template i
went again
oh i'm looking for this one hashtag
okay
so now we have this left right
equals left equals what oh
zero right and and minus one no no
length length weight minus one yeah yeah
okay so what what what's next what what
why are left
left and right what like left or
left what what left smaller
than my equal right because it can be
equal right
okay now how how what
possibly then all of them
must be the same if
l and r is the same it means there's
only one
yeah it's possible yeah there's only one
right it means that
all of them are the same no no no
left here a few weights and left here
right here right left and right can
point to the same one it means only one
right yeah oh yeah
okay look if left and right left is more
right so let's say weight yeah current
where
equals r that means you just go by
yourself
yeah yeah yeah you're right wait what's
the weight
what's the current weight oh it goes
left and right no no wait
wait wait what left and right left
and plus what wait's right can you
please yeah okay
okay now now what
now what what
oh no no no why why
what is left no because we are not sure
we on the tip
left right yeah
so it can only be right let's let's say
we pick on the right because the most
heaviest we go anyway right
yeah yeah the most heavies
will go anyway right and then ah
what ah what
when we pick the r what should we do
we add one i is on the right
uh minus one minus equal one okay and
then now
look if weight plus
what smaller or equal limit
can you tell me what well if the the
right
the most heaviest plus the most one
lightest
what's the most common air what's that
way to light
weight air right yeah if black then what
should we do
okay there we go and how can we
mean you will go how do we mean if we
will go
how do we mean if we go the left pointer
oh left and right left minus
left left add one and right minus
no we don't need to write already here
right
and then here when one goes so what do
we do with the count
it turns at one yeah
okay and then return return
wait return what limit
return how many ships yeah it's a call
yeah today i didn't name your answer
yeah
i want to test you if you understand it
if i put an answer here you know
return answer right yeah yeah
you got it what's your time complexity
yeah there is
what's the time capacity what's the time
to brexit what's time conversely on this
path
this is our end again and this part is
what i went
oh and so what's going on why is that i
got this one i have
uh
is dominated by uh by by this one right
yes bigger yeah okay
and then there's one more come on are
you kidding me yeah
it weighs two
what happened to the account if i choose
the oh yeah
i know if i did in my place
so is it go with the e4 is it goes with
y
i'm asking you if
what wait wow
wow yeah with this okay even
this is has a space yeah does it make
sense yeah
right look
if we we haven't used we haven't put all
the weight
in the in the spaceship right then we
pick the most heaviest
all right all right we pick the most
heaviest
ah minus equals one if the
common weight plus the most likely
can go with in the current ship
then we take that right
we take that let's believe that but
anyway
but anyway we will we go we have every
every iteration means that we let a
spaceship go am right
yes okay
that's it for today bye
bye bye