hello hello mr mr ryan how are you
hi today sorry it's good okay so
um we talked about uh making change
before yeah
and today is another problem of making
change
let's say we have a making chain one
one p one pin two two p
five p one twenty p let's say
okay okay and then twenty five you place
twenty five okay
just just make it up 25
okay maybe change five to uh change
change
1 10 20 25 and then i want to make 60 p
okay
okay so one question is that this is the
target we want to make the change and
then you can pick
you can suppose you have as many
unlimited number of each coin so you
have
you can have a number unlimited of one p
10 p twenty three
the minimum is three why is look
we can have 25 25 10 20 20 20
yeah okay so this is unlimited it's like
unbounded
unlimited for each one you have a list
of the
uh
this is the one example of i'm body net
sex you know knapsack
about it i'm body what's upbody
can form we can we can describe this
problem
in a very general way is that we are
given a
bank yeah we are given a back of
capacity
60 right about another 60
and we have a list of the different
items right right items and each
item has different weight right
and we want to minimize the number of
items
to put in the bag right so you can put
20 20 20 or
you can put 25 25 10
and in both cases it's the same you need
to tell me it's three
number three okay so
okay so we start from the now we saw
that first then we start from the
biggest okay so you saw the first you
from the greedy yeah and then and then
and
and then we did it again and
to see uh how many you can get right
yeah
so it's 50 and if you do again it will
be 75
so you can't get anything okay but this
may not work
right why is that if i don't have 10
then your greedy
is not working right you put the 25 you
start from the
you try you try to pick the most
heaviest right
but then you run out of choice right
yeah yeah so the greedy may not work i'm
right
target equals
25 and you only have
like one
okay 20
okay and like five yeah
four six okay then you need uh
six yeah because 20
um maybe no no no you can have four
four six and a one yeah so that would be
five
and then you can have 20 and another
one how about how about three seven
ten and the top eight okay hey
coming back to the question yeah you
pick the most heaviest you try 25 25 but
you're running
out of you don't have 10 and then you
can only make it up with
one right yeah so that may not be
optimal
[Music]
the greedy is not working here in this
case i'm just trying to prove that your
your solution may not work yeah i can
always find some input that
breaks your algorithm okay okay yeah
yeah okay so how can we do this
we can profiles we can search yeah yeah
yeah we can always search but
um
that's okay because we say that yeah
look at
that coins yeah we have coins and we
have a target
right attacking the maximum competition
so we can first
have to be p p yeah
yeah look 20
look this one so for each one we can
start from the scarring we can
pick these or we can pick the next one
right
yeah we can for each item we can pick
correct or we can pick next one so it's
a search yeah
yeah so this is going through the
default search yeah
yeah yeah that'll work okay so how about
if i tell you
you can solve this problem by dynamic
programming
do you still remember dynamic
programming what's dynamic programming
what's dynamite programming oh remember
minimization
me my motivation two down button up yeah
yeah remembering so the key point here
is remembering yeah memorization
so so if i tell you that f f function
f a is the num is the number of the
coins the number of coins
we need to make up change a right yeah
so what does it equal i have a list of
items or coins here
i have a list of coins here let's say
the coins
i have coins which is a list yeah and i
can say d
belongs to coins yeah this is belongs to
so it doesn't mean that i can always
pick the minimum
look alright eric look pick the animal
area what is
equal f a equals mean
of of what a
minus t plus one right
four four d in this
yeah all right what is it what does the
e
what does it mean look everything all
right
yeah what's what's that 1 5
20 25 and then we want to put a 60 right
we want to come up with 60 and what does
equal
f60 what is the equal equals
mean mean of what
of s60 minus 25
f 60 minus 20 f
60 minus five and as 16
what minus one one and all of these plus
one yeah because
last time yeah all right yeah i'm just
making up okay
so what does it mean look if i want to
com make up 60
right i know i can make up 25 right
if this is the coin
of making up 6 minus 25 and why why is
plus one because i need
one more turn one more coin right yeah
all right can you explain to me what is
what's this f sixty minus twenty plus
one what does that mean okay
so uh
so 16 minus 20 and 20 is a coin
yeah yeah and 60 is the target we want
to get
yeah and we add one uh because we need a
coin okay so what the f60 i know
the difference between f60 and f4t is
one right
but it's a 20 20 coin yeah i know
there's 20 here
all right all right suppose we know
already no effort here
yeah then we can use this value
because this value we already save it
yeah
so we don't need to compute this again
we know f60 because f60 equals f40 plus
a 20 pound coin
2020 coin right yeah and then these look
f40 what's f4t f4t equals f
mean of f20 minus 25 plus one f40 minus
plus one after 15 plus one and f19 plus
one yeah yeah
you see so in this case i updated all
the values between
one zero to a right
right i don't need to calculate again
again doesn't make sense
yeah and if dynamic programming we can
always use
implement in you know in
how many ways are top down and bottom up
right
let let's implement the button up first
look eric define
f and then that's the amount
right amount and the coins yeah coins
column okay look eric
so first of all we need to we need to
have this array at least to store the f
s right f 0 is what
is f yellow if the zero
nothing how many ways can you make it
nothing
it's nothing yeah so look
let's say uh let's
change this to dp okay and let's f
equals
look at zero this is f zero yeah
[Music]
plus at the beginning look eric
so in the beginning we maybe they
it's not possible to make up the money
right if you want to make a 60 and
you only have uh like uh you only have
13 there's no way to make up 60 using 13
right
yes all right
doesn't make sense so so if
if f let's say if
look for example f 60 equals f
14 uh 16
minus 60 minus 14 plus 1 yeah all right
but if this one we cannot make it let's
say we
we make it a very big number
right infinity right if this is infinity
right they'll be possible because
there's no way to make up f 60 minus 14
yeah
for a certain so so that initial value
is
very messed up infinity
times amount right hey what
what what's the y like that this is look
so f is the least the first list is zero
and then
the layer a or a times
of the mass of infinity so what's f f
it will be like this eric look at this
look at here
so what's f value it will be zero the
second one
second value will be what
infinity so you'll be infinity and then
infinity and then how many of these
how many of these this is at least f of
uh the these minus one no a
come on times a here this is look that's
what it means
the first one zero plus a times
of least okay so that's the least of f
f equals that yeah okay
and then what's next and what's next
and look for what
for i in
range what's i
a very rare for i in range
start from what from one
to a mouth plus one yeah we want to
calculate we want to calculate the f i
value right
and then fro for coin c
in coins yeah we have now we are coming
all right
let's see yeah
look if if current
coin if the current amount is bigger or
equal than
c right all right yeah
if the amount is smaller than the coin
it means it's not possible yeah if you
yeah it has to be bigger yeah yeah
and at least one of them and what
and f f1 i
minus c right what did i say f i minus c
not equals mass dot infinity yeah if we
can make up this yeah
so what what should we do f
i we are calculating the fy value yeah
equals mean
f i minus c
plus one and f i right we want to keep
the
minimum all right all right does it make
sense
okay ryan are you okay all right
all right explain it again okay fi is
the value we only calculate the amount
right
we start from the y
which four is from the bottom to the top
there are two four pick one which one is
the from the bottom to the top
this one yeah because f i f i start from
one
one right f yellow is yellow we already
know
f1 to a so
the i will start from one two three
until a right
yeah for each four and i choose the
coins and then you i
bigger than c and i might what's this
area
what's this i know what does it mean
here what does it mean here
i just tell you i explained two times if
uh the f
is see okay so f
uh we have a valley
minus the coin yeah it's not
equal to infinity is initial what does
it mean
i mean it can be yeah you know it can be
we can we know already how to make up
the money right
for example 60 and we already know how
to make up
40. if we there is no way to make a 40
and it's we we don't need to calculate
this right all right
yeah yeah okay and then what should we
return
the last value return which one
what are we calculating here a a or f
minus one yeah the last value yeah all
right yes
okay look if s minus one is a mass
infinity it means there's no way to
calculate it right
yes am i yeah yeah it could be possible
that we can't make
anything up to that f amount right like
16.
uh if you only have 13 about uh
13 10 you can't make 60 using the 13 10
right
yeah doesn't make sense because
60 cannot be divided by 13 right you can
only use one two three four
and you can't make up 60 all right
all right doesn't make sense nothing
no i'm still going to talk about the uh
top down
remember what's top down
a new memorization we start from the top
and we know we have i watch the time
complexity for for that one
i forgot to ask oh what if the amount is
a
and if there are n numbers of coins
what's the term complexity
[Music]
yeah why is that because we have a for
loop for the first form
we have nine that's amount yeah and for
the second
four when the coins then what what's the
what's the time complexity of the second
loop
the four coins
uh a n
yes and then times together you'll be oa
right
what's the space complexity remember is
the f function
what's the base from complexity
why is no
remember the space complexity for the
bottom up dynamic programming
what space are we using
[Music]
the f function f function f function is
is what
we are calculating f 0 f 1
f 2 to f a so how many of these
f a o l a okay that's basic complexity
because we just
need a list of f functions yeah
yeah to a right okay
okay now butter up or top down sorry
come down
define cash let's say
s cash okay we put a cash here
cash and a okay let's create
if a equal equals zero
what we need to define the base base
condition which is if a equals zero
return y
it returns one
wait return zero yeah remember let's
think dp
equals zero plus plus times infinity
right
yeah a times infinity remember the
previous one but
basically it's the same it's the same
implementation same idea but different
implementation yeah
okay now now
i have this a i want to calculate a and
i have let's say answer
equals mass stock infinity yeah
all right at the beginning i'm not sure
which one is it
ryan right this is a lot yeah
yeah and then i need to iterate over the
coins
yeah all right
i look it's the same if
right
if
coin is smaller than equal one
if the coin is smaller than equal one
it's smaller than an equal
in the coin yeah if that
coin is smaller than a right then we can
check
and let's say let's say x x
equals f a
minus a minus one
a minus
now the coin is smaller than a and i
want to try
a minus c yes and if
x is not equal mass to infinity
if we can make it yeah all right
and answer equals what can you tell me
answer equal one and return
oh yeah okay
yeah that's very obvious yeah can you
need that one
no no no this is the key point what's
good
yeah minimal yeah you know what i'm
talking about because we want to
calculate the minimum of what
the minimum
answer yes we want to keep updating the
minimum
and then what and what
what a a is the constant
we are what are we calculating x yes
that's one mistake there's one problem
you're so close to it
mass infinity there's a
no infinity
x is f a minus c if we use the coin c
then how many f a what's the f a and
f minus a minus c what's the difference
between
f a and f a minus c
c minus c 16
and we have 40p we have 20p
so what's how many coins different the
60p and 40p
20p is how many coins are these how many
coins the number of coins
i have a 6p 60b is the target
and i have a point 20 p
yeah and we want to know the number of
the
coins the minimum number of coins to
make up 60.
yeah so f 60 equals
f 60 minus 20
plus what how many coins
plus one yes and what's here
plus one yeah x plus one doesn't make
sense because we already have
coin c we know we calculate f a minus c
we use the coin c
so we need to add it back plus one all
right
yeah what what's the time conductor
before this one
i swear what's the time complexity
and this is n and that's a what's the
sample message
f-a-n oh yeah it's the same yeah what's
the space complexity
a yeah yeah but for this one is
recursion
with minimization but but if this a
is a minion what does it mean you need
to call this function many many times
which is not good
right so it's better to in this case the
bottom up is
preferred we prefer the butter up right
because we
we don't we we don't call the function
over and over again right because
there's overhead
let's overhead to call this function
right look the computer needs to call a
function all right
yeah so in general
so in general advantage of top down
right advantage of top now is that it's
very
i mean human readable all right because
look i just defined if a equals zero
deletes otherwise do this call
calling this application is human
readable
you human you friendly but butter up is
more like
computer friendly because the computer
don't need to
you tell the computer more efficiently
to save other
values right yes they're both equivalent
but it uh they both the in terms of the
agreement
your term complexity in theory that they
are equivalent
but but in practice
we prefer the butter up right all right
okay and uh
yeah yeah what
what we have used the coin we have tried
to put this
yeah come on
equals something about c yeah yeah look
we we are currently we want to array we
are currently making of the a
and then we want to try the c c value so
what s
s we want to call the value f1
f1 f1 a
f what yeah calling the decretion right
this is because you say with cushion and
what currently
a is called is smaller than a so
what do we need to do if this is a
this is c come on it's right here
here right this is the dynamic
programming okay we talked about this
before
okay that's it for today