hello guys and today we're gonna do
coding
yeah that's my dad he's gonna be the
teacher
miss terry how how are you mr white how
are you good
you're talking about the target yeah
today i'm giving a number okay so
let's say given the number five and then
we want to convert it to nine
how do we do it every time yeah it's
four
right try okay so you can you can do
what
you can find that nine no no no you can
plus one or you can times two
none of them work no you can minus one
or you can times two
minus one all you can times two multiply
two that doesn't make any sense
so look how can you oh you times t and
minus one
yes so let's you need a two right okay
let's try another number 26 to
48 how many operations do you need
yeah 22 26
to 48 yeah minus two
and times two where the minus one minus
one and then times two you need a three
operation yeah does it doesn't make
sense
oh yeah okay 26 minus
t equals 24 times we're done because you
can oh you can choose to minus one
and you need two and it becomes 24 and
the times two where down ryan you got it
yeah
yeah dude that's make sense yeah okay so
given the number
star star and then can you write the
algorithm to
to tell me how the minimum number of
operations to in order to change from
the start to the end
or in any thoughts me show
how how can we solve this problem
okay so can you tell me that if the
number the
target is smaller than the star will
happen
if like we want to convert from
10 to 5 so how can we do this
all we need to do is minus one
minus
what did i say about not doing that yeah
that's right even the target is smaller
than
uh
[Music]
we can't we can't do this yeah right
yeah okay
so i give you a hint what
i'll give you the hint
if the target is smaller than the star
we can only mine
minimum the difference might substrate
the difference see this is
so trapped in this this makes it smaller
does make it
bigger that's right yes yay
okay so look if we want to convert 40
from a
to 26
it has 22 different yeah i know so look
if we consider the opposite if we if we
converting the n to the star if we
reverse the direction
if it's an even number if it's all
number
we subtract one right oh
yeah no no we add one or always
substitute one we add one
right because the opposite we add 1 to
10 and if it's
even number we what
we divided by 2. all right yeah
so 48 it's a even number so what do we
do we
divided by two okay 24
look now 24 is smaller than 26 so what
should we do
add one that one but we don't need to
it's already smaller so we just
calculate the difference right
yeah just add it that would be two all
right
yeah can we do this
does it make sense so we we reverse the
operation we reverse the operation
define f star
s for star evo n okay
column if
n is smaller or equals
star what should we be ten
reason why if it's smaller yeah yeah
for first 10 if we if we don't want to
convert into
five we want to start from ten
converting to five what's your favorite
we get
we just do s e minus s
s minus z yeah okay then
if e
is n1 what is mean and one what does it
mean e
and one and one and one what does it
mean
is e and one what does it mean it's
all number or even a number uh even
oh yeah and one if it's one then it's
all number so this is
all number so if it's all number what
should we do
we should look look one
add one whether so return if we're doing
the recursive
one plus f
[Music]
yeah and if it's even number what should
we do
yeah so one plus f
s e divided by two divided by two
yeah so that that's the question so how
many locations are there
how many locations are there can you
tell me
how many of the questions are i call in
itself okay how many are you cussing can
you tell me you haven't
seen yep you know one of
these how many questions two
two yeah yeah yeah yeah what's the time
complex
what's the term complexity
it's hard yeah i win no because
every time we harven it haven't it and
then you feed this in the cage
oh look log n yeah roughly log n
lovely and again n is the
difference okay but if it's smaller then
we can directly return it that would be
01 right
but if if this number is always
right always bigger and then always the
even number then we can we can always
divide by two right
okay so we can do this iterate not using
the recursion this
is like because in calling this function
itself but in
recursion the good advantage of
allocation is what
we can focus trying to solve one
pro situation at a time and then if this
is all number
we can turn it to as another sub
another problem right right calling
itself to solve it
yeah if it's all number if it's either
even number
until we know if e is smaller than x
because we already know if x minus e
right
yes okay so let's do it in
recursion so with the recur
not the normal equation sorry so we have
to define the answer answer at the
beginning equals one
z right okay so why
because while if the s
is smaller or equals n right
column is it smaller or equals like if
it's n
is smaller than uh when the star
is smaller than that
[Music]
okay so if if the star is smaller than
the
end what does it mean
if e4
the
[Music]
is
what one because if it's all number we
can only
add one right look look at every five to
nine
else if n is all numbers yes
we add one yeah nine will become ten
right
yeah as it is
what's else here it's a it's
all number one
and divided by equals two and then we
have this
answer plus equals one because we
already
make one and then when this ends when
the
breaks uh what's the y loop why the y
loop
ends what does it mean it means that s
is bigger or equal than n right
yeah so return return
also plus s
and here minus e s minus e whether yeah
all right because y is after the while
loop
this is s become bigger or equal than n
then we need to add the difference right
look remember 26
to 1 48 right
all right so when this divide substitute
one is is 48 first of all you need to
divide it by
2 which is 24 right now the star is
bigger than the n
right yeah what does it mean it takes
it takes 26 minus 24 two operations
to subtract 26 to 24 right
yeah that's what it means here s minus e
is 26 minus 24 right
the answer is one right so it is three
operations doesn't make sense
yeah does it make sense no does it make
sense
yeah okay what's this
okay that's it for today thank you it's
a bit easy today yeah
it's a mess problem okay bye bye see you
tomorrow
see you tomorrow