oh hello hello mr mr ryan how are you
today
good day okay okay so
we talked uh we want to talk about
longest prefix
what's prefix like what
the opposite of free speech is suffix
whether on surface so prefix can you
tell me how many prefixes are there in
each word
five okay what are
right okay so now i've given the list
of the guys in three things
okay so today we're going to talk about
the longest prefix
longest common prefix
or lcp okay lcp longest common prefix
so given a list of words like
one word
what and what
wonder and
i wonder okay so what what's the longest
common prefix
wa w o right because w o n
is not right and we we want to check
when you were just saying it yeah i hear
the beginning with w so i don't need
stuff from w
okay so what's the any thoughts how we
tackle this program how are we going to
solve this problem yeah oh we're going
to solve this problem
what does it mean what does it mean how
we solving this problem
eric any idea how we solving this
problem
ryan how are we solving this problem
so
this one this one is not the same look n
and i
okay so your approach is checking
characters by characters and right
and here we found out this mismatch yeah
right yeah so how many characters are we
need to
checking how many characters do we need
to check
all of them oh man are you sure look
this is the shortest one
do we need to check four three yeah the
minimum right
because there's no point to check four
characters the first one only has
three characters so the first of all we
need to check the
shortest to kill the shorties right yeah
yeah
yeah yeah yeah ryan right
and then we go through these characters
by character kung fu
okay okay that's it so let's let's
implement this
okay
this word is a list of strings
so at the beginning what we need to do
is to find out the shortest
person yeah the shortest first shortest
the shortest length of all the strings
in the list right
and yeah right look so let's say
this k the shortest length is k
and k let's say is equals to the very
big
big number with net stock infinity and
for w in one word
in what and k equals one
k equals we want to
update the shortest one right yeah so
what's the
mean right okay okay of what what's the
length of the word
i word lens of dublin
yeah all right okay so
look these three lines we can turn into
one line
which is k equals
mean of length lens
i know what what should we do four
four w in words well done
okay so that's just one man okay this is
one note okay i don't have space here
so k equals infinity the very very big
number and i try to
iterate all the string in the words
and then for each string of words i want
to get the length of each word
and then update to locate hey after that
k will be
equal to three for the one yeah
and then now what do we do next what
should we do next
we shall we should do what we
let's say i i equals
okay so let's say we have three three
strings so i
at the beginning points to the first
character which is i equals zero
and then if if all these are the same
it's all the same and we point to the
next one we want to check oh oh
it's not same and and and r is not the
same then we break then we return
the first two letters right wa yeah
okay so now i need to i start from the
first one and
why excuse me okay
why why what why
is smaller than k yeah because k is the
minimum which is three yeah
there's no point to checking beyond the
chase character right
color and now look if we want to find
out
if these all the characters
at index i is the same we can use the
set
which is that set is the data structure
only stores
unique numbers unique characters yeah
if you put two ryans in a set there's
only one lion
that's me if you put the ryan and eric
in a set there will be two elements
arrogant right if you put a hundred
eric's and a hundred lions in the center
what happened
you will only have one ryan on one eric
because
the set is kind of hash table uh a
notebook but only yeah
only stores the unique elements
so why are we so what what we our idea
is that to to put
all the characters at index i for
words in in the set right and in the
event
yeah if there's only one element in a
cell what does it mean
what does it mean if there's only one
every man in us
in a set what does it mean it means
that's the prefix that's the character
is
and that position is also if it's more
than one what does it mean
what does it mean and and ah what does
it mean
then there will be enema yeah yeah now
what does it mean
it means it it means you break
yeah you break it because we found more
and then you do your previous prefix
which is w y i know what you mean yeah
okay c
equals set now what
w i because we want to get the ice index
the character index i
and then 401 for our
force for w
in words
for w inverse okay so this is the same
as
c equals set then for w inverse
c dot at w i okay you can turn into
uh three lines like this but we're using
one nine okay
length is length c
not equals one right yeah because we now
found a more than one character not all
the previous
i plus equals one yeah then we check the
next character and
and the last the i i
we will break and i equals two right so
we want to get the
character up to i equals two so return
return
we tell any words because
any word what the let's say we can
return the
first one zero zero column i
and then column i wait because i is two
and then we now we want to we take all
the characters up to two so which is w
and you can pick any of them for
convenience we can put
what's i what's zero is this first one
right
yeah one zero is w o i n
and then you want to column i which is
with return w
ou all right yeah all right yeah
what what's this part let's study what's
the point this part of complexity time
least complex if there are n numbers of
words
in string in the world what's this part
complex i went
where where down this is one yeah this
is he
got no head ryan eric look
and okay
and what's the what's the time
complexity if
for this part this bit check the k times
right
yeah then what's this complexity
because we need to check here characters
and then for this one
for each for this one we need to check
we need to iterate
and string right so actually okay comes
n because we need to check check the k
strings yeah
and strings right yeah okay yeah i'm
making it again
okay in okay n so the overall time
convexity is
o n plus k times m
okay what's the space complexity
i one
we are using a set here come on oh oh n
o n yeah because this is n right
and yeah in in uh in the worst case
maybe
in the worst case each character will be
different right
maybe maybe they're totally different
like a b c d e f
right g h i and then o
you the set will contain three letters a
d
and g so this is the set and then the
space complexity is
o-n okay and now we are getting that
uh thingy right never give up
okay then let's say uh
what what what's here what's here
what's here why wha why oh
well come on i
and k why why what why are you
i smaller than k
that's it for today good job good job
good job bye
bye bye
in my panties okay that's it for today