hello hello mr mr ryan how are you today
good okay and we're gonna do stuff on
this one
uh okay pentagram penguin penguin
pine green whatever that is do you know
this penguin we talk about penguin today
penguin okay so if a sentence is a pan
that is a gram
okay sentence it's a sentence that if
each even a sentence contains 26
letters in alphabet in the penguin like
what does that mean
okay
quick brown
jump over the
lazy dog jumps over
the lady dog lazy
dogs okay so look where's a
a b
e f f g
h is this h i
j
k l m
n o
w x x
x y y z z
yeah you see so each letter in alphabet
appears
at least once okay it can appear more
than once but it at least it needs to
appear once
so this sentence is a penguin
doesn't make sense okay so our class is
like giving a string a sentence this
might be we want to find out if it's a
penguin okay
any ideas oh we just check
if there's a a and this is a b
and if there's a c and if there's a d
and it does
oh no one level one
no work no work okay so we can
as you can see see we can do this yeah
so
how let's do this okay
define check okay that's a sentence okay
so you're saying that
for in our current character is
in in you just do this a
b and here here z yeah you write it that
way
yeah and then if if not
alright not c in s right
return
and if we all check it abcd to z and
then we return true right
number one right yeah know what what's
the time capacity
what's the complexity of checking a
letter in that o
one o n o n come on because my n
o n and then you what you want to check
26 times so it's all 26 times n
okay yeah that's pretty slow
because you're 26 times right yeah it's
36 seconds
stop doing that okay yours is wet yeah i
know
okay so one
one way of simplifying this is that you
know this c
is if you don't like this you write
range
26 yeah and then 8 is that
okay then this letter let's say a then
you say what's a
a equals remember this this chr what's
the
lowercase letter of the ascii of the
lowercase 48 that's zero
48 is zero 65. so yeah
no 65 is uppercase 97 is lowercase
oh okay okay
if recent letter every sentence only
lowercase we talk about lowercase okay
okay chr 97 plus
c okay converting these two
c is from 0 to 26 right to 25 so
97 plus 6 6. now you can write it this
way so you don't need to write
abcd yeah the thing is checking a letter
in a string it takes o n n is the number
of
characters in a sentence right all right
uh this work this work and how what's
any other idea
all right what's the other idea how
we're doing this
any idea any idea how to how do you
listen how about with you
how about we use kind of data structure
all right
what kind of data structure can we use
set yes
notebook so yeah eric
yeah he said yeah ryan because he said
sex like okay let's say we see
equal uh set okay
yeah i know we can say what for
i in s
c dot at
i right yeah i
if i tell you if i tell you all the
letters
in the s is lowercase after this how
many letters
are we looking for how many letters in
the set are we looking for
if it's a penguin 26 okay so then we can
yeah let's see if this is the low case
yeah it's all a lowercase okay
yeah okay so
using the set we can also use what we
can also use this
called counter remember yeah c equals
counter we want to
check counter s right right therefore
i know we can all we can now check those
return
a return length c
equals one 26 yeah
if if there's s well
if s contains contains the space
uppercase lowercase this does not work
because we have that
it has more other characters yeah so how
can we do this
we can do this every c and then we can
do this for
i in range
26 okay then we say
if ch if
okay what if uh
not chr
i plus 97 in
c right then return what
if you return five yeah return tree
yeah we are checking every letters yeah
that will work as well right
yeah what's the time complexity of this
one right
what do you say oh
this is 26 this is one
okay 26 plus n right so actually you can
drop the constant oh n
because the most time consuming part is
this b
the space complexity is our that's what
i said
first okay what's the terms what's the
space complexity
what's the space complexity
we are using one what are we using
uh what's that the counter yeah without
accept
okay so is that clear is it clear
you're gonna rub it out uh
no no no what's the ask ascii
of uppercase b
s-e-i-o uh
66. what's the opposite of
what's the lowercase c rpg
what
[Music]
will give us 97 uppercase
65. yeah i let all of the
one give us one
um and then look chr
50 give us one let me
think and give us what
what chr 50 48 is yellow 49 is
three fifties one two yeah two
uh string okay that's what it is okay
so let's look i is zero plus ninety
seven you'll be
lowercase a if not in c or actually you
can do this
you can also do this look if we are
looking for the key
index c c we want to know the c
counter of c c h r 97
plus i if it
equal zero yeah
if this num if this character does not
appear in the
sentences with return false got it
okay that's it for today