yeah okay okay so today we talk about
your life string yeah ss0 and s1
we want to check if s1 can be obtained
by
deleting or removing one character from
s0
for example s0 is a b c and and
s1 is ac then you need to tell me is
true
all right because if we remove the b
from s zero array
yeah now we can obtain ac right
okay yeah this is easy easy okay
and how about it look if it's a b c d
and if can you be removed as a b
you need to tell me no why is that
because you're relieving t
yeah because the difference yes so first
of all we need to check the difference
if we it's
one right yeah if the length of the
difference
is more than one certainly we can't
right
this makes sense over this
a b c d and then you tell me if it's a
b c
[Music]
f no why is that i can't see
because that isn't coin
every good possibility
idea so so first of all we can
remove any of these and then we check if
it is the same as the other one right
yes all right but first of all we need
to check
if the length is the length is the
uh if the length is the difference than
one right
i'm right yeah okay now let's try the
fruitful thing first okay
how can we blow first hurry let's just
tell you
if i check if this is s0
uh s1 if you want to check if s removing
one from the
s0 can become s1 okay so let's say
a b l l
let's say the lens okay lens 0
lens 1 equals lens s0
lens s1 why okay so
can you tell me how can i write this if
if
if what if we remove one character from
s zero
so we need to check if the difference so
s0 is now
i just take put it here as you know
advanced
so if n 0 not equals
l 1 what minus 1
which one is bigger s0 is bigger
okay then we return what we tend
yeah first okay so you said saying i
want to
check removing every character uh how
many possibilities of removing one
character from seo
zero zero yeah okay yeah four
i in range
l zero okay and zero i want to remove
the index at i
right so let's say this new character
new new string
s equals s zero
how how can i write it up to
i want to remove the index look eric
a b c b okay so look i will be
zero if i want to remove remove the a so
that
the index will be one i
plus s i
plus one right so when s is i
zero you become this b c d when i is one
will become y y i is one it would be
a c d okay then
if x equal equal one
i remove one character from
the s yellow and i want to check if it's
the same as what
if it's the same as which can which
string
which which is string come on
[Music]
okay and after this we return
what's the term complexity area
this is if this the length is n yeah
this is o n here and here
no no no why is it cube n squared oh n
squared here's always exactly what i
said
yeah look at o n times o n right the
chicken is exactly what i did
yes okay
does it make sense here yeah does it
make sense
look if i equals two zero one two
alright
s0 2 plus
s3 what does it mean s02
all right look at me i am
what's s 0 after 2 if s 0 is a b
c d 0 1 2 s
s 0 up to 2 what does it mean
it means it's a b c i think a b
up to c not including c plus s three is
what
zero one two three s three is what b c d
three start from three a b c d e a b c d
start from three characters three what's
what's three
cd zero one two three
what's s3 start from three
zero one two three what's three yeah b
and start from t which is what b
so you add it together is a b d that's
what it means by
deleting character c got it yeah
that's why it means i and i it's away
from zero to
the length of seo let's let's
let's hope we're removing one character
blue forcing removing one character from
from s0 and we check if it's the same as
another one right
got it this makes sense
you sure okay are you sure
you're sure really i need anything
else no no this is o n square so i'm
going to introduce you
to the o and o
right okay remember a few weeks ago we
talked about the subsequence
and subsequent what's the subsequence
that's like a bit of thing you know
like you know a b c d
e island
a c e
is ac a subsequent of abcde oh no it's
not
it is subsequent so basically you
removed
one or more eric you remove zero or more
characters from this string and it
becomes a sunscreen okay
look a ce but is it
c e a a subsequence or least no why is
that
oh because they're in the wrong order
you know
okay so another one another one
lucky it's 268 of sequence
2 3 4 6 7
7 8. is this a subsequence of them
why is that yeah so okay so
it's uh yeah so how we checking this if
s 0 is subsequent of s1
all right do you still remember how do
we check is
is the subsequent of s1 so
we move both if not the same we only
move one yeah right
oh you still remember this wow all right
to my surprise okay okay let's let's
quickly right here look
look it goes like evening all right
can i ask you to be quiet
as cll s1 column yeah
all right you tell me how to dwell in
ireland 0 a1 equals length
0 length s1 okay then if
the length s0 is bigger than s1 will
happen
yeah well what does it mean it means
that
impossible we're done if air 0 bigger
than
l1 return both
okay now i
j equals right
zero zero okay we start from two area
look at abc this is
a b c e
a c okay look s 0 is here
s 1 is here right and i at the beginning
is
spawning the first one j is pointing the
first one of
this one right all right yeah so
why are i smaller than
what l a and zero and
one and what and j smaller than
l1 yeah okay now look
if if s s 0
i equals equals s1
what if this is the same what happened
j i know what happened yeah
i i plus equals one right
yes
we need to increment which character if
it is not the same
let's say if this is bcd we only
[Music]
equals if
if i points into the last one then we
follow the match right
yeah so return i equals equal
zero okay so while this is the
review of the subsequence why i'm
talking about this
all right so if we know
this we it is more more chance of
it'll be much easier to understand v uh
you know one before that's what i said
so in first of all we check the length
right they need to be
still need to be one letter more than s1
right
if it's one letter more then we check if
s zero
is the subsequence of f1 right yeah
does it make sense so yeah here
then we look so suppose we have this
angle yeah
yeah all right
so how how do we implement this check
x0 x1 right
if length is 0
minus one not equals length
as one right retirement
follow okay now we just have to return
two three no no no no
yes yeah remove
[Music]
this is s zero continuous move
you remain this is s zero i learn less
as one
okay one one way of doing this is to
compare character by character
is a equals a of course yeah it's
okay so in this case what we need to
check
if this one is bigger so what does it
mean it means that
this part should be equal to this part
right okay
right am i right
does it make sense look because we know
this this string is one more one
character than that right
so if this is a mismatch c is not equal
to d
what is
yeah so the one after c should be equals
to
to this part right yeah okay so that
should be easy look
this this p is the same right
look we start with the s yeah okay let's
try
yes no no because yellow is bigger than
s1 so let's start with
s1 okay all right okay right look
e s yellow
we have a mismatch at here that means
all of you always need to be used
okay so then we turn return what s 0 is
more right so
s c l i
plus 1 1 column equals
why is it true because we it's too wide
because if if this is all match what
does it mean
immediately if this is that means
it means can you give me an example when
we
reach this point everywhere
can you give me an example one code we
will be executed here
okay so let me do the job okay
and you do the rest and i'll do e
i i say
okay can you do the right and then the
one um
sorry now what i mean is that
when when the when will be here
the code will be xq here because look at
cll
when there is a mismatch all right right
when i
mean mismatch the code will return
immediately right
the code will immediately return here
right yeah
okay so if the code is not here what
does it mean there is no mismatch
between
people
okay you say e-r-i-c-a-e-i-c right
[Music]
no that's not because look you will find
a mismatch in the second
character and he will return here p o p
l p
p o p p my god p o y
p p sorry uh
anything right if we e-i-c and e-i-c-a
for example does it make sense
yeah why is that can you explain to me
why eic and eica
would be here because
s1 because this is this is one
because this is bigger than that yeah
and
and this little thing and just have one
last bit well last bit because this is
checking the smaller lens right
so all these are match so you won't go
here here right
you won't go in here this is miss man
this is the shorter one
so what does it mean only there's only
one character
at last then we have a match right all
right
that's what we mean because if you find
a mismatch here you will
immediately return here got it when it's
returned
it's returned the function the function
will exit
right we yeah
the function we need to return your exit
will not come here
correct yeah okay
okay so can you tell me um okay so can
you
can you tell me which which which part
is
what's the term complexity of this one
yeah yeah mostly o and yes the previous
one the subsequence n squared
no no no it's still one come on before
that
is good yeah the subsequence remember we
check the
length is one and we check if one is
another one actually it's
all m plus n if
okay please everyone can see that can
you guys
come on come on
[Music]
s 0 is the longer one so
i i plus one right we want to check it's
next calendar i plus one column
bracket bracket exactly it should be
equal to one
double equal double equal as
s i forgot is one
i yeah i yeah
yeah column bracket yes okay that's it
yes okay that's it for today thank you