hello hello
i'm here are there enough enough
enough enough okay
okay so yesterday we talked about the
algorithm complexity right oh god
yeah so let let's um
let's just review a little bit okay as a
quiz
okay so i have two games i have a
number yes a list of numbers
and i want to compute the sum okay so i
have two problems what do you have to do
look don't shake i mean you don't check
so i have the
laser function f1 here right
look look and this is number n
okay and i have a function for
s equals zero i in s
s plus equals i return
okay
okay maybe make it this way okay make it
this way n is a number
n is a number like 10 so then i want to
calculate 1 plus 2 plus 3
plus tier 10 okay so let's one way of
doing it
is is this yeah
range m plus one
and plus i okay return s
yeah this is one way or two you need the
other way i'll do unit
f2 and i
return n
times m plus 1 divided by 2
okay so so this can you tell me which
one is
better there are two both can computer
sum of the first and positive numbers so
which one is better
just take a guess the equivalent
complexity remember
we talk about that so this is just
looping the n numbers
and then adding each number into the sum
and this is just using the mathematic
equation so which one is faster which
one is better
which one yeah you know the answer yeah
which one is better
remember we talked about the linear yeah
linear complexity
hmm what do you think come on come on
give me this
interesting okay okay come on come on
what's
which one is better just just guess if
if
n is a minion and what this does is
it needs to iterate the numbers between
zero to a minion
and adding each number and this one i'm
just putting a minion there
one million yeah yeah yeah i know and
putting a minion and computer sum so
which one is faster what do you think
in terms of computers
yeah you know a hundred times a hundred
plus one
divided by two which is gives you 50 50.
right
okay this one is faster
you don't need to repeat yeah yeah
you're all right yeah
yeah this is
this one is a one constant right and if
you
draw it on the ball look if you drop
joy on here yeah this is n this is t
so what does it look like this line
all right look at this line water is
okay this is one so the complexity will
be just like that
yeah yeah that would be just like that
it doesn't matter if it's 1 million or
10 million right it's always one right
but this one is if it's one million it's
very high 10 million is even higher do
you get it
this is okay well done that's very good
okay so today
going back to this topic we are going to
given two list
a like one
three five seven nine
and b another list two
for a okay just like that
so a and b are two two least but they
are sorted
yeah look they're sorted so meaning
each of these is already in order so
look two is smallest two
is in order right yes one three four
is increasing and this is increasing
yeah so the task
is to merge these two you know much
much to salty list
okay so our task is to merge it so
what's the answer here can you tell me
what's the answer
so look this is one three four five nine
yeah
increasing this is two four eight and i
want to merge it together and
it will be uh sorted so what does that
mean
so look one two three four five
seven eight nine yes
six okay okay yeah yeah okay
so the answer would be one
two three four five
six seven eight nine okay okay so
you basically take every element from
both and then make it salty do you
understand yes
okay okay so so
any source how we do it
any thoughts how to resolve it if they
are both of these
we take yeah we want to take both
elements
elements from both leaves and we want to
make it sorted
needs to be sorted as well in order okay
so one
one easy way will be if i put these this
on to the end or this list onto the end
yeah
and then it becomes this but it's not up
in order right
and then however i saw this entire list
yeah it worked right
yeah so how do we do it using the
define merge okay
much a yeah look comma b
what's this column
and then look if i see yeah c is at
least if i do it a plus b
then you please list here this list will
become 13579
right and then two four six a yeah
i know we need to solve this list right
so eric
can you remind me what do we do to sort
it
c dot source yeah
and that's it return c i can't see
okay this is one way or two here it's
quick right
yeah a balancing will become this yeah
one three five seven nine and 2 4 6 8.
this a big this c would become this list
and i sort it and it will become this
another return c yes yes okay but this
is
so this if all right
yes if the size of this is big a the
size of this is big
eight big b so let's in high c
yeah the c the size of c is what
a plus b so the c is a plus b
yes exactly and the sorting algorithm
generally takes
big o remember we talk about we go this
the complexity of this is
o and log n right if there are any
elements if we want to sort this with
an element this is complexity so this
will be oc
log c where c is a plus b okay
this is the one way of doing now we can
we have a better way of doing it because
these two leaves are slotted okay
these two lists are sorted
so how about look how about
i want to see here yeah i want to see
here how about i have
i
i have two hand left hand here right
hand here okay
okay so i compare is one smaller than
two
uh yes okay i'll put a smaller one
that's one here right
yeah yeah and i move this left hand
there okay
yeah is three smaller than two no
it's two smaller than three right yes i
always put a smaller one
here or two and i'll move this to here
right two hands yeah
three and four three smaller yes we have
smaller so i put a three here
and i move the three to five do you get
it
yeah and then five and four
four is small four is smaller right so i
put a four here and i'm moving
do you see it so i have two hands which
hand is smaller i always put a smaller
hand and move that thing
until it reaches the end yeah this is it
because it's already sorted and i can do
this
yeah there you see it because every time
i left hand and right hand
they're both pointing to the smallest
element in their list
am right do you get it if one is the
smallest of this
b is not small a two is smallest in this
right
yes then i compare one and two
one is smaller than two so means that
the next number should be one right
so the length could be in order yeah
yeah it should be in order yes
okay so we can do this
define what happens if they're the same
number
what do you miss a number in each list
if oh there are two numbers the same
yeah if i fall here
it doesn't matter if it's not smaller
you can pick any one if it's the same
you pick any one yeah and you move it
it also works right define
good question by the way that's a very
good question
merge a b y
okay so now we we we have a c
c equals the empty at the beginning
right
okay now we need to i j
l a l b these four variables i j
will be the beginning 0 0 0 0 means the
first animal yeah
is length a
and means b so i want to get the size of
both yeah
and then i need what i need to do y
i smaller than air a
and j smaller than
air b so when these two pointers are not
going to the end right and i need to
compare if
a i look if a i defend
is smaller than b j right
then i need to put put this number
c dot append
or we can do it do this c plus equals
plus a i right so we put this
one there and then i plus equals one
and move this left otherwise
otherwise you'll be a i will be bigger
than bj
now we need to to put these b
numbers bj number there and then j
plus equals one okay now but
do you have any return no yeah no yeah
no yeah so
the problem is that look this is n so if
the length one is bigger
one is longer the other is smaller right
so this
j will apparently may reach here faster
than this blue will end right so we need
to check
we need to check if there are remaining
items in both lists so we can do this by
we can do this by y
go go this way okay y whatever
why i smaller than aira if it's still
there anymore there then i need to
continue pushing this
pushing these elements to the end
and i plus one equals one and the same
as
the lp yeah j smaller b
and c plus equals b j
and j plus equals one right and what's
next what's the
what's the the last bit
you can guess which number is it
what we are doing here what do we do
what are we doing in order to return the
list which number which
which element which list we need to
return
take a guess
look what what we are doing here what
are we doing here
we are trying to put the element put the
next
smallest element
which is that l
or c why
why why i smaller y c
c yeah yeah because it's c yeah
yeah you see so uh just
take so this complexity will be just
n plus a plus b yeah you see this
complexity is a plus b
why because i have two two pointers my
job is movement to the end
and just one scan that will be a plus b
right yeah so it's faster yeah
it's a bit faster than than previously
it's oc right it's basically on c
remember remember the previous one is
one
[Music]
so which is faster which is faster
yeah which one this one yeah of course
so uh yeah of course the oc
is faster yeah because only uh
oc oc is
oc is this one and o oc local c
is yeah okay
so so any questions
yes any questions
no really okay so i'm going to
test it okay so what's the this bit
doing this is kevin
can you say what does it mean what's
this bit doing
like if if one is smaller you do
the smaller one and put a smaller one in
the list
and then move more the corresponding
pointer forward yeah yeah and here you
reach the end right l a and lb
this is the lens of b well done good job
today okay
okay bye oh yeah
yeah okay