hello babies hello mr mr ryan how are
you today okay
[Music]
yeah so okay so given a list of numbers
integer non-negative non-negative
integer
means that the the the smallest number
is zero
non-negative like five
three oh nine that's zero
number okay so you're given a list of
numbers non-negative what's next
non-negative what's negative oh means
uh you know like below zero
not below zero so it's bigger or equal
to zero okay yeah
okay so they i if i tell you that there
are k
numbers in here right the k
numbers which are greater or equal
than k okay so k numbers here which are
greater or equal than k
yes sorry what's four there are 4k
no no no no there are four numbers but
i'm telling you k
is a num a number there are k numbers
here uh which are bigger than k
so find out k so you need to tell me
what is
k find out k and if k
doesn't exist then you need to tell me k
equals minus one okay
so for example how many k will be here
yellow
three one two three right
three four much or bigger or equal
yeah look what's what's possibility of k
uh okay
yeah it could be zero one
two three four yeah yeah
okay so zero is zero numbers here bigger
or equal to zero
yes or no why is that because that's
zero no no no one k
is zero what does it mean can you find
any number here which
are bigger or equal than zero there are
four yes the output is four okay
say one right and four another thing not
the same yes
and one how about k equal one one number
is bigger than one no because they look
yeah there's no one okay no no no look
three five nine are bigger than one
right
so you see it's not the same
look two two three
five nine two again not the same three
three five nine yeah three five nine and
three is the same so yes okay so got it
so find out okay
any ideas any ideas oh we just
do the thing what you did whoa
yeah you're sexy this is very clever yes
what's
what's the call what's their car what's
the call
blue thing come on that's the most
straightforward
intuitive way okay so we blew first so
we
proof was all okay and we check we count
how many numbers here are bigger than k
right yeah
okay three three
okay can i write it yeah can i write it
maybe you can look at
maybe you so first of all we need to we
need to come up with a function
to count how many numbers that are
bigger or equal than k
right how can we do this if the numbers
let's make it count count
bigger or
equal right equal length
k right and if i have numbers here yeah
numbers here okay can i have your
attention please
can i have one can i have one of these
three um
how can we implement this function this
is supposed to be very easy right
all right yeah count bigger or equal
than k
how can we keep counting okay okay so we
start from
zero no no no i'm saying no now it's the
simple version which is i already tell
you i want to count the numbers
in the numbers in this array how many
numbers
are bigger or equal than k can we just
do it with a for loop
okay does it make sense all right
can you write the for loop all right
look
answer equals zero okay
and then certainly here you you need to
return
answer right yeah all right yeah
so i want to go through the numbers in
numbs
how can i do it all right
everybody do you know how can i get
close to the number
for something okay for something yeah
something yeah
it's available for something in what
okay
okay then how we want to count how many
numbers are bigger or equal than k
so what's next here
next yeah if k is if what
if noun if what if something is
something
what is something uh
that's not difficult right you got it
right what's the time complexity of this
part
what's the time complexity of this one
if there are n numbers and numbers here
he can fill in this part
all right what's the time complexity
what's the time
oh and yeah can i have your attention
otherwise you write it okay
numbs you have to get your
do you want to write it or not can i
have it okay
fight oh
oh n yeah
okay so we have this function okay
remember we have this something can we
do it better
let's see we can let's always improve
so every time every time we we
every time we we need to
use this function this function will be
used a lot right because
if we do the proof of thing we just do
this for
k in range all right look
ranger range one two
two uh to length yeah how many numbers
yeah
num that's the last one
let's call this uh just so okay you know
what it means if
fk equal
okay we know the other one i don't know
yeah it's k yeah we want to blue force k
if fk fk means the number of elements
which are bigger of
equal than k if fk equals k return
return k come on and the hours we ten
minus one yeah
minus one what's the time complexity
here
what's the time frame
here is what here is one oh n yeah
here's our one
and here is what oh n so what's that
what's that somewhere that's more worse
oh it's good so it's very bad right
yeah so look you shouldn't tell us that
one
as a comparison look at me do you
understand yeah
yeah blue four thing yeah that's what i
did at the beginning right
yeah yeah so if
if we can improve this function then we
can input the overall complexity right
so there are two ways to speed up right
all right either
we improve these this function
or we improve this right right
because this algorithm consists of two
parts you want to iterate
over k elements k k possibilities
uh the n yeah k from zero to numbers the
numbers yeah
and then for each one you want to try
but this function it takes away right
yes doesn't make sense
got it okay dmss okay
what's okay okay
okay if you say okay i'm going to ask
you
okay can you explain to me what's the
best part i i
need david handle yeah he got the pen
what's this okay
[Music]
that how many are bigger yeah
and then this is
yeah yeah the number
that is compared to
i didn't have this that that if it's the
same yeah if they are k numbers that
uh if they are k numbers which are
bigger than k
then we return k if we confirm any k how
many k possibilities
will be n plus one possibility from zero
to n right
and otherwise return minus one correct
now okay so
we can improve two two bits first of all
we can improve this function or we can
improve how we search this k
value i'm right okay so first of all
let's improve this f function okay how
can we improve it all right how can we
improve this f function
all right
listening can i have your attention
please this is lesson
no playing okay laughing
ryan
[Music]
do you do you want me to do it again
okay three three
four two four one okay
so if i want you to this is the list of
numbers if i want you to tell me
how many numbers are bigger or equal
than two
so how do you do it
yeah but imagine this is a very big
number you have to check from the
beginning to the end right
yeah all right this is all n right can
we do better
oh can we make it better we're done
yeah i got it baby yeah okay look wait
something is talking is what i can look
at
oh and okay but you only need to do it
once right you only need to do requests
and after so that you will be one you'll
be what eric
it'll be much easier you'll be what
one two three four five right
right all right then if i want you
to find out how many numbers are bigger
than equal than two so
how how would you do it overly sorted
array okay
how would you do it if you're looking at
you split in half
uh
[Music]
that's very advanced okay i was going to
explain to that
later but but you got it straight first
of all if it's
sorted it's better than i can just do
this yeah i can just search from the
beginning yeah when i found these two
oh i can search here from the other
opposite what i found is
when i saw a number which is bigger
okay let's do this side which which is
bigger than two
right yeah and i don't need to continue
right
why is that because all the rest number
will be bigger than two i'm right
so i can exit the check earlier
yeah but the time complexity for this is
still on why is that
why oh because
yeah it might be the end right you still
need to go through the end right
way down okay but the other thing is we
can finally search for this one
so as you say i want to find a two yeah
and i
i can do this number with with finding
the number in
o log of k log n right yeah
that's much faster right in
in python we can use this function
so look it okay let me go ahead and say
if array is one two three four
five six okay it's sorted
and i want to find i want to find
how many numbers let's say i want to
find the
three okay i want to find the three so i
can use this function
bisection bisect by set what's it for
the binary in
i don't know if i said top bicep left
but this is the package
name packaging don't make no sense
okay so i like it so eric
from you can do this wrong buy set
this is a package five import
import two functions bisect
bicep underscore
biceps right
numbers this the first parameter is this
yeah actually it can take up to four
parameters
the third and fourth parameter will be
the range lower to higher but
let's forget about it now the first
parameter is lumps
it's the array already sorted and you
want to find the x
let's say target yeah target so what's
the difference i tell you if i want to
find the three
where the final three all right
if i want to find the three in the
sorted array it it takes
o log n right yeah n is the number of
elements in this here right
yes three
is the position that is that if i want
to put the number
which is
so i find this number here right and
then you tell me the position to put it
is here
so that's zero one two right
so you start from the left so yeah yeah
so and by saying right you will return
what it will be here
yeah yeah exactly so what how does that
help
if this number is not not in the target
like if i want to find
three point five three point five
yeah look
if it's 3.5 it's not in the sorted array
so
can you tell me can you point me to
where it is
interesting interesting you will be what
where you will be pointing 3.5 waist
again
let's say one is left yeah yeah yeah
yeah
so you can think of that way you find
the petition to put 3.5
in and it's still sorted where it's
going to put
where are you going to put 3.5 3.5
you have to be here yeah we're done so
here you
can't find this but you can still find a
position
for 3.5 to e so that will be 0 1 2
right two zero
one two uh
actually you will be return three here
yeah because that three
index is going to play uh you want to
put a 3.5 in
index three and if it's bisect right
what does it mean you'll be here right
yeah all right yeah
3.5 you'll be putting pretty after right
got it
so how does that help if we we found
this number bicep
left okay aaron okay that's okay
if by say numbers k right
yeah all right what does it mean
k is spicy number okay if i put it here
so what does this mean how many numbers
that are bigger or less equal than k
can you tell me
number is x yeah if this example is x so
how many numbers are bigger or
equal than k
is this speed only speed
the same no no in this case it's the
same i'm
talking about if if x equals by bisect
that's k
it means that i i can put a put a k
in a sorted array at the x position
so can you tell me
there are x numbers bigger than k
x x number here bigger than k all they
are
n minus x number bigger than k which one
pick one if this is sorted
right just pick one come on you've got
15 percent
yeah x look
x is the number of positions to put the
k in this software array
none of that i mean they're x numbers
bigger than equal and k all they are
m plus n minus x number bigger or equal
to k
and the numbers the numbers of elements
in this array
so i'm actually asking you is this bit
bigger than equal then k or is this bit
bigger or equal than k if i put the
if i find the position to put the k in
if it says salty come on it's very
obvious which bit
let's supply the water come on why
right yeah of course why this big is
bigger i put a 3.5 here so how many
numbers are bigger
than equal than k of course here 0.56 is
bigger than k come out
yeah it's quite quite easier easily
significant okay so remember this
f function we can improve the time
complexity to what
with this function we can improve the
term complex to uh
f
[Music]
but remember we need to solve this uh
array
only once yeah we which it will take
oh
wait for something okay now good
so what's the second part we can we can
optimize
what's the second part we can optimize
remember we can we
iterate blue force from for the k from
zero to
n right yes but we can finally search it
am right yes
yeah am i we can finally research it all
right
so um
actually wait wait should we actually
can you pay attention actually the k the
upper bound of k
is what it's not the number of elements
i made a mistake earlier
right look five three
zero nine what's the maximum k you are
talking about here no
it's not four it's nine right yeah i
said knowing
yeah okay right because the k
k the maximum is nine is the maximum of
numbers
right all right it's not actually the
length of numbers right this is the
upper bound right
yeah so let's negotiate before the
truthful thing is
is what o max k
o max o max n times
n right then the beginning it's not o n
squared right
it's omax n times n could be could be
bigger than o n squared all right
yeah so now we can finally search this
bit
instead of linear search that's what i'm
saying the lowest will be n the biggest
one is the
next n and then we can finally search
this one
and then this will be o o
log max n right no of
max n and then times
what's the f function times 1 what
what's that yeah
it could be great if we can reduce it to
0 1 but
it's not possible
oh log what the
number of elements right o log n so the
overtime complexity will be this one
o log max n times low log n right
so hold on yeah yeah how can we finally
search this okay i'll show you
okay i'm almost finished yeah almost me
look at me right
now
the left left equals zero
okay the smallest k will be zero right
the maximum k would be what
tell me
max or nums i just tell you maximum
number right
all right now how do you write the
binary search
wire left smaller or equal than right
okay
yeah here numbers it's already salted
already sorted listen
why left smaller than r what's the
middle how do we get the middle
what's the number left right divided by
two
here middle equal left right right
divided by 2.
divided by 2. you need to divide the
random yeah i just said that bit
i don't have a divided by 2 bit okay
okay all right
okay k equals actually
this meter is k k uh equals one
f mid middle i
yeah okay okay if k
equals middle if k equals neither
yeah we found it right before the answer
yeah return k
right yeah this is the number we're
looking for right
then if if this
k is smaller than
middle
[Music]
is right
minus equals right equals
middle minus one else left
equals middle plus one
and we turn in here
okay so can you explain to me why is
this if k
is smaller than middle so
if if this if they are less if they are
less number than meat which is
is smaller or equal than
the meat number we need to
reduce the number of k right so it will
make it bigger you will be bought more
right
all right can you this is a bit tricky
to understand look eric
if the meat if the meat
equals k great we found it but if k
is smaller than the meter what does it
mean
what does it mean anyway k is here k is
here
if they um okay if they are k
numbers which are bigger or equal
than k which is smaller than expected
right which is smaller than expected so
we want to
if k is smaller than the expected
k is the answer if there are number of
numbers which are smaller
k is is smaller than expected so what do
we do
we need to increa reduce the meat right
we need to
search in the lower half here right so
the k will be bigger
right all right
if k is bigger on the other hand if k
is bigger we want to increase that we
want to search in this bit
so that next time k will be smaller
right
click and we can finally search this bit
so l these this angle will be o
log max
nums yeah and times here this function
this function is all what's this
what's this
log n this motion login
okay oh look maxon logan what's the
space complexity
uh one oh one yes okay just respect easy
to understand what's here how do you
calculate the middle
middle yeah
yeah it's been 27 minutes
yes thank you for counting i already
know that
i didn't know that without looking
yeah 27 yeah left one
how do you calculate the meter from the
left and right add
right and then divide by two
but you need to break it right otherwise
the these will calculate first left plus
y
bracket do you understand yeah whatever
you say
yes bye okay bye bye bye bye