hello hi hi hello mr erin mr ryan how
are you today
good okay so what's binary search tree
it's a tree with numbers and on the left
side
is smaller than the roots and on the
right side is bigger
you need to be apparent what you need to
be
preparing not just
it's not just
is basically the value tree but the
numbers the notes on the left hand side
is strictly smaller than the parent
and the right hand side is strictly
bigger than right so
in in the final research tree they are
not
they are unique numbers so it means that
there can't be any
uh duplicate numbers right all right
yeah so for example if you have four
another four you can't put it in the
binary okay
yeah so how many can you put a four
here and here four sorry four
no no no that's what i'm saying they are
all unique numbers
so you can imagine you have given a list
of
given three numbers for example one two
three how many kinds of how many
different ways of the
binary search three one two three
it's not unique right you're gonna put a
two here all right this is one
three yeah yeah or you can put a one
two three yeah
oh you can put a three here can you put
a three
two one right yeah
so as you can see there are three ways
right maybe more i don't know
could there be more two one three yeah
or yeah so they're basically
three okay
because the pre-order right pre-order
pre-order is the sorting right for
example pre-order is one two three
pre-orders one two three
two dollars traversal okay all right
does it make sense
put all the services what what's with
the other terminator
i like build it like definite search way
yeah but which is the left tree and the
note and the right right
left left right right left
blue and right if there's right
let's read right left
note right pre-order the pre-order of a
question
i think that's in order oh
yeah you are right you know yeah we got
[Music]
so it's actually uh pre-order is 2
one two it's not what we are looking for
is what it should be
left no right in order okay let's know
so in order of
binary search tree is give a circuit at
least
am right okay okay so today's task is
very simple
given a new number like for example yeah
let's say i just leave this point this
is true okay
give a new number four
insert it into a binary search tree
okay we'll just make it for the same
you just i you just please note here
somewhere and make it a
new binary search tree it has to be a
new binary
okay any idea how we're doing this
how do we insert it so for example if i
want to put the four here where where
are you going
see there can be lots of boxes yeah
that's our answer but
look at the easy way pick the easy way
let's fall this is the brightness
tree yeah of course if you want to put
that it could be
if you change the root you it could be
what
it could be if i three four
two one right right if i
give you a four this is original tree
right
you can tell me it's this one that's
okay but it's too complicated you're
changing the loot right
so all i want to do is what you put
these four
somewhere here without changing the
existing
binary search tree yeah
so if you get it if i tell you if
it's what if i tell you you want to put
a zero
yeah so where do we put it without
changing these three numbers
where down yeah you see so so how are we
doing this
oh one point five oh one point five i
wanted to put this
one point five where to put this
why don't we put it without changing
only three
yeah you got it yeah so easy
what's the approach you're going to take
1.5
is it bigger or smaller than can what if
we
cannot do it without changing it that's
not possible because we can always
change it
right why is that look 1.5 is
bigger or smaller than 2.
so it should be on the left hand three
right so i go here
is one is it bigger or smaller bigger
bigger so i put it here easy
got it yeah okay so
so that will be easier define what you
know that
because you just did two yeah
[Music]
that's okay what was your question if
it's another two right
no that's what i said at the beginning
there's no duplicate you make
your duplicate okay okay look eric
define insert
into pst what's bst
finally okay then this is the loot and
that's a very
so what happened if we just return
a new loot return
pretend a three now three now
[Music]
okay then what if the value in this
value
is bigger than current load yeah so
where are we gonna put it
this is this is the root like a 2 if the
value i'm going to put is 3
so if 3 is bigger than 2 what should i
put what should i put
we shall go to the i'll go to the right
yeah go to the right but i'm not sure
what what happened if i would call the
recursive yeah
so insert so it should be inside in pstu
and then can you tell me what's the
parameter i put here
right on right right and then with the
value yeah
yeah yeah it should be put in on the
right hand right tree right
right all right else but i need to
give these to root.y right root of right
will be
these right got it all right
okay can you tell me what areas oh
read the left inside bst
reader left valley
and then return wow we're going to
return here
we turn left
you turn the tree which tree or what
tree is it
three nights
written one wait what's the term
complexity
if there are n numbers notes in the tree
and
again uh okay maybe o
h the height of the tree right because
if it's a highly balanced
final tree the h will be equals to
log n right and it's not normal okay
yeah i said logan
yeah but look if it's look why is logan
if he's the highly better
half of the tree yeah yeah yeah highly
balanced look if there
there are eight seven notes yeah so the
height is roughly blocked
three seven is roughly three three yeah
not seven
three okay it's highly balanced and can
you give me an example
yeah yeah one more thing can you tell me
this
if it's unbalanced okay
can you give me draw a very very
unbalanced final research tree
you wonder yeah like one
two is like this there so there's no
advantage
of searching in this right all right
do you get it why we wanted it why
why we prefer the balance instead of
unbalanced because because when you
start you abandon
half of it yeah and for this one i'm
balanced we cannot abandon half right we
if we only fight four
we always go one direction there's only
one possibility right
so if there are n notes in the worst
cases
yeah and if there are n notes the
complexity
of unbalanced fighting unbalanced
finding a number in the
unbalanced surgery is what
and if it's highly balanced finding the
number again
yeah that's why we want the highly
balanced
okay let's do it okay does it make sense
yes yeah okay
okay what even what
if that note is what then we want to go
to the right
i don't know what what what why in what
cases we are going to the
we're going to insert in on the left
tree
or the right three
come on
if the value and then loads of value
three
sorry three one three
what in what cases we want to insert you
know on the right tree
or the right tree in what cases
which is uh bigger yeah we can write it
if
one one is this one which is bigger
yeah come on you need to understand it
first value yeah
yeah bigger bigger one
no no no not equal there is no equal
thing and then
[Music]
yeah that's it
okay that's it for today thank you
bye