go hello mr mr ryan how are you today
good okay consider this a
b c d e
f g h i j a
zero one two three four
five six seven eight nine okay so this
mapping for the first
ten letters in alphabet we have
mapping to zero okay and then look if
this is
a c b
so you'll be become zero two
one right okay one
c b a what's that
two one zero if you pass this together
that'll be two hundred
and thirty one yeah and what's that 231
is
cbd cbd
so today's task is very easy given two
words
first word second was
three words you need to tell me if they
added together is the same
all right then you need to tell me true
okay because you
give me acb and cba
and cbd and you need to tell me yes
because acb plus cba
equals cbt according to lease
correct are we here
yeah okay any idea
thing yeah how are we improving every
possibility what possibilities
well there's only one possibility it's
not performing yeah it's just
okay straight forward yeah you figure
out this one
you figure out this one and then you sum
up them
and see if
okay so we need the functions to convert
these to this right
yes if this is function f if
if f a c b
if it is a function f acp you can tell
me if it's 0 21
right then i can say f this is if
a this is b this c and i can say i can
check f a
plus f b is equals to f c right
easy pc yeah so the most important
thing is this f function right right
so how can we implement this function
bottom up what bottom what's out of
bottom remember how do we convert these
the numbers to the
binary to remember no no no no
no remember this one one one one one in
binary is what
how and how are we converting
111 to 15. one
two four eight exactly so every time we
comes two plus the
yeah so for example one times two and if
it's zero we skip it
yeah so so look at it so how do we
calculate one two three in decimal is
like one
and then here is one times ten plus two
okay
then the note becomes 12. and then 12
plus 10 times 10 plus 3
equals 123 exactly so yeah
so if we know the mapping which is times
10 plus
it's the same yeah we the only
difference is that we need to convert
this a
to zero b to one c to two right
okay yeah this is one way of doing okay
so let's implement this function define
f s f column
so let's say answer equals zero
right that's the beginning yeah
therefore we want to go through how do
we go through this number in
s for i in s
right right now i is the character a
a b c this kind of thing
and if we want to convert it to 0
what we can get what can we do
we can have this if if i equals a
then then answer
times answer plus 10 times 10 plus
a plus zero but now you need to have
10 if so look remember long
time yeah what's this in
asia remember
65 97 65 is uppercase uppercase you
always mistakenly from there yeah
yeah okay so look answer
equals answer is ninety seven times what
can you say times what
product equal m times what plus
or d o r d i what's our d function
it returns which number order
97 minus y equals zero 98 minus one
equals
one 97 yes i need to minus 97 right yeah
yeah remember when this is a this
this function returns 97 minus 97
0. yeah all right
when is 98 b minus 97 is one
and answer equals answer times what
answer times times what what's the
what's the base
0 what 1 2 3 one equals one
now answer is one and then i
have these two here so answer equals
answer times one
times one plus two times one five
right answer equals answer times what i
need to times one
then plus two plus two and then i need
to times what plus
three in binary times two
yeah yeah that's what i'm saying times
ten okay and now this is answer value
and
i just need to return what it cannot
yeah what's the time complexity
what's the space complexity
and then i just need to return here
return f
a plus f b equals equal fc right
let's say yeah if there's a function
defined
uh leave this g function a b c yeah
given three words okay
yeah okay another way of doing this is
that we have a mapping like
mapping mapping equals okay curly brace
this is additional error curly brace and
you have one
you have lowercase a and then you will
return
zero and then keep writing lowercase b
array
lowercase p column one
right and then you can keep writing and
here
g no and j equals
what j equals
three mapping two uh nine okay
and then here i have a value right i
have i can have a string here
so instead of here i can say look s
uh all right please n equals
empty string and for i in
s m plus equals
mapping mapping i right
mapping i i will be abcd
[Music]
how can we convert it return can we
if i want to convert one to three string
into an integer one two three oh how can
i
impress them in
no no no integer right
and then n and because this is one
string rook eric marking yeah and
mapping
eric what this making what is it
i mean what's the inside what this key
value pair what's that
dictionary right dictionary and unless i
is the key and mi what does it return
if i is a what is the difference zero
zero okay and then add all these
together so
if it's uh if it's a c then it will be
clo 2 1 right then it will be 0 to 1
right this l will be 0 to 1 and convert
to in that will be 21
right okay yeah so
what's the time complexity for this one
yeah what's the space complexity
and why someone
i'm thinking
this is the additional array alright
this could grow this is the same size as
right right so it's all n right now
previously that one does not why why is
that because it's a number
right we're converting to the number
only right got it
yeah that times 10 plus that thing yeah
correct does it make sense yeah
[Music]
i i got it baby
and equals is something about
um okay
good job today that's it good job say
bye bye
bye