oh hello hello mr mr ryan how are you
today
okay today we'll talk about intervals
again yeah we talked about some internal
problems before and then we talked about
another interval problem okay
right that's funny okay so let's say we
have two
uh intervals they are sorted remember
first of all it's sorted
what i mean sorted is that the intervals
are given from the left
right in in the numbers yeah look here
this is the number
number line right number zero here
one so each each number i mark it here
yeah one two
zero one two five yeah
so i have a look here i have one three
one three okay and one three here this
is the interval
[Music]
right okay so that's three three
intervals
one three five six seven nine it's
inclusive so the emperor
yeah separate look this is star and star
and star n so this is the
interval and another b what i mean the
given
sorted is that look we are given from
left to the right okay
and the b interval will be something
like one four
one four here yeah and
maybe five seven
okay ryan
don't think yeah i'm not singing okay so
look
so you now need to tell me the combine
okay let's connect it so it's uh
intercept
so which is one four no one
one three here and
five but again we have a seven here yeah
look at this point yeah yeah so you need
to tell me
yeah seven seven we're done so does it
make
is it clear yeah is it clear got it
[Music]
so how do we know first of all in order
to solve this problem how do we know
the two intervals are connected or not i
have this
intersection point or not if this is a b
and then infinity is cb
how many kinds of relations does it have
how many kinds of relations
between a b how many possibilities for a
b and c b
quite a lot right yeah look eight b
one two yeah this one one
this one yeah one yeah
or smaller one yeah
and of course if it's disjoint yeah
please join
okay yeah correct yes
right six six maybe maybe they are quite
similar look lazy
if you can swap a and b these two are
the same
and maybe they can be like
oh yeah okay yeah yeah this is similar
to this one it's the same
okay so we oh of course for this kind of
uh we can check right for example
for this one we can check if a a
this is a b if c if c is between a
and b right right yeah or
or for example this one uh
this one then we can say if a is between
c and d
yeah yeah but we have a better one which
is to do what
looks look if we get the maximum of the
starting point
the maximum of starting point a b and
the minimum of the ending point right
yeah doesn't make sense minimum ending
point
right look the intersection of these a b
and c d
is what which bar is this far right
so this is max a and c right and this is
the mean of
b and d right that's the end yeah right
so we want to get the maximum of star
and the minimum of the n
right so if star is smaller than n we
have an intersection
right can you draw a one which it does
not have intersection
okay so look at abcd what's the maximum
of a
anc starting point
what's the meaning of
the star is bigger than the end then
let's notice
uh connection all right there's no it's
disjoint right all right
yeah okay so we this is the basic of
checking the two intervals
if that to see if we we have this
intersection between them
so for now we can have two pointers
right eric
to scale from the left to the right okay
and if they are this if they are
already okay
if the star is smaller than n then we
push the star and end
this interval to it right right
and then look look eric here
all right yeah one three point four
what's the interval between what's the
intersection between these two
one three one three okay one three then
we we know we have an answer one three
and should i move the which one
to now because look at this end we need
to check this end
three three is smaller than four so we
move move the smaller end
next one right right got it
does it make sense
this ending point now we check the
ending point which is smaller
we move the smaller one doesn't make
sense
oh yeah yeah why we can't move the
bigger one because the bigger one
we don't want to check we want to just
move the smaller one to check next one
is
spear smaller than this one right so we
need to move this one here
five six and one four yeah
one one four and five six doesn't have
an intersection no right
no now which one is big the end point is
bigger four and six which one is bigger
four nine six now we move this bit yeah
yeah
okay five six on five seven five six
five six we push the result five six
here and six and seven which is smaller
six six now we'll move here yeah seven
nine and five seven
seven seven seven and then we move to
the end okay so you see we got the
intersection yeah
gonna make sense okay so let's try this
that's a b colon
okay then the lens okay let's say the
answer answer equals at least
at the beginning at least okay at least
yeah and how can we lead next
what do we know we have two pointer i
equals z equals one i equals z equals
one
i equal equals
at the beginning of the index the first
index is one
zero zero yeah okay
okay then why are i smaller than
lens a and
j
hey
[Music]
and then we push it to this answer yeah
then we push
answer a pen
stop star end
okay now we need to check the end part
yeah if
a i one one
smaller than b j1
if if a i1 is smaller than bj1 we need
to increment i or j
i i plus e plus
because we're scanning yeah i needs to
go and step
and j needs to go and step a mouse yeah
uh what's the space complexity
what's the space complexity if we don't
consider this as an
additional space what's the size and
what's the haha
nine okay what's that what's that
i plus equals if
ow
i plus equals one else j
plus equals one okay
yeah a i one ay
something just went the end we don't
want to check it
closing this bracket square bracket no
no that's okay if a
i i one
is smaller than
b j one a is here b is here we want to
check
any point which is which is smaller
right one
the break is square bigger yeah one yeah
okay one
one one networks i plus equals one else
j plus
equals one i plus equals
else j plus equal one you want a smaller
one
else j plus equals one
column
yeah j plus equals one j
plus equals one j plus equal one
james equals one okay that's it let's
see for today
thank you yeah yeah thank you see you
say bye bye