hello hello mr ryan how are you today
okay remember what is substring oh it
just like you know
a bit yeah you know what so
let's say a b c d e f what's the
substring
a a b a b c or b
c d yes to be continuous right abc
how many sub strings of size three how
many
how many of these size three one two
three four okay so a b c b c d
c d e d f okay let's try that's fine
yeah yeah yeah size three uh substring
of size three okay and
if i give you a string and i want you to
count how many sub strings
of size 3 and each substring contains
only unique characters so these are
unique characters but aab
is not unique characters okay for
example a b c
d e you need to tell me is what
this is does not have has like a
duplicate calculator so this is
on top abc comes bcd comes city council
three
okay got it yeah
yeah i'll argue with this problem okay
so any idea how we're doing is giving a
string
given a string of size n
so how how do we know
[Music]
like so first of all i think it's good
like the set
content is unique yeah yeah yeah okay a
good point set
so first of all if a string has has
n characters a b c d how many
how many sides a substrate of size three
how many times how many
uh t okay so what what is this
a b c b okay then if it's the end
character if
n equals four then you say they are two
and n equals five
how many one two three
three yeah so what's the n equals six
equals one
i mean n equals six how many sub strings
of size three
let's see come on two three and what's
next
four yeah so so if you subtract two yeah
so
n minus two okay so they are n minus two
substrings of size three and we just
need to check
proof of this n minus two
right and how do we check if there are
if the size
substrings or size 3 contains only
duplicate
unique characters if this string is abc
how do we know is it's
unique in the size if it's the same
so if this is equal to this if release
is not equal to that and this is not
equal to that and this is
no input right okay good
what's the time complexity
define let's say check
string column okay
like even if the length is less than
three now what do we do
we just return zero right yeah you can
optionally please if len s
smaller than three what does it mean we
can't find any substring of size three
right
yeah if a b you can't find any
substrings
and we can nothing zero
nothing okay answer equals zero okay
right four
index in range
let's start with the third one yeah two
and you can tell me one then x s
if what if i want to compare what s i
s i minus one no no yeah no yeah
if s minus two i minus two yeah i want
to compare these three all right
what's i i look
i start from two right so i will be two
minus two look two one zero right
all right all right no a b c c e f
what does it need to mean i will start
from this here i right
i want to compare i with the previous
one and previous two
i minus i was right yeah so if
s i not equal s i
minus 1
not equals s i minus two
and s i minus one not equal
s i minus two
and we want to count incrementally
one line yeah yeah
[Music]
yeah look look these are unique
characters yeah we can we can also do
this look we can also do this
what's the letter from i minus two
i minus so this is i minus two yeah i
mean and i want to
from start from a two to two three yeah
to here
yeah up to this point i plus one so if
lens i will i put a set put it in a set
eric set
s i minus two column i minus two here
and then i want to include three
characters so what's next
what's what's next i minus two column
[Music]
one no no no i minus two and three
columns from this is from and to what
this is hey look this is i minus two
and i want to to include after this or
at least
not including this what's this uh
[Music]
two what up i minus two plus one
i minus two plus three what is what
plus one plus two plus three
three i minus two plus three is what
i plus one i plus one not including i
plus one yeah so it's abc i want to take
three characters so it's
i plus one right if this
put it in the set all right put in a set
if it's equal to what
if it equals 2 to what
if this is said it does not store the
duplicate numbers
duplicate characters and if they are
unique
so what's the harmonic elements should
be in the set
unique numbers how many unique numbers
this is a set three yeah
okay it's the same yeah and we can
please remember put
previously we can put this into a
one-nine thing okay this is just to
do this i can i i don't need to write
okay i can tell you return
return what okay yeah we can answer here
this is one line okay i can do this
return and i have a array yeah
all right wait what is that right uh
return these
and remember s
i i not equal s y
minus y and s i minus
[Music]
well i in two left
s count true true f
culture so we will call the two two
values
there this is also one let's say yeah
don't look at my notes okay
you clever boy no no no
you don't need to remember this it's too
complicated but but i'm going to erase
this bit just to
let you know what s whatever i'm just
raising our income from you
i i hear
what's here
you don't need to write so hard minus
one too
and at this point i want to get a turtle
soon
and five elemental
one last question if there are n numbers
of characters
how many how many substrings of size
three
divided by three
[Music]
and minus two yes and minus two of
course am i so that's it