yo hello hello mr mr ryan how are you
today
okay so today we're going to talk about
uh
one interesting problem which is called
what's what's look you know the chest
yeah chest above looks
yeah um
[Music]
and rings yeah yeah yeah everybody look
look come on come on listen
on the chest on the chest okay for
example
one two three four five one two three
four five
six maybe one more okay so this is six
times six chessboard
it looks is it's like a looks i don't
know how to draw it and i really think
there's such thing as a six times fifth
chest
yeah it's eight times a right yeah okay
so for example
right that looks like a person okay so
let's put in a person a person can
attack
each other if if they are on the same
rows or columns that's it have a
diagonal no no just looks and colors so
if
how much does it have to kill
a person every time no no no i'm just
saying that
okay so what if they they can't
kill anybody on that turn how would they
move
good question okay we are not thinking
that far yet but today here
i am i'm asking you to play sixth place
six looks here because six times six and
there's six loops
and you can place it some other way here
like that so none of them can attach
each other
okay
how how can i place it here
here yeah but when you press here yeah
and then you can press here
you see so none of them can attach each
other right
yeah yeah now why do you have to have
six weeks
that's the question you are given six
books on six times
oh that would be easy
[Music]
that's why yeah that's one possibility
so the question
is the given given n
looks on n times and n chair how many
possibilities how many ways we can put
them
if you're not sure we can always solve
like think about it you
already know this before right remember
it's a very simple question if you're
not sure
think about one times one how many ways
are we putting one
is one right you can only put it here
one right
two times or two how many ways you can
put it here
put it here right or you can put it
put it here here right all right two
two and n times three how many ways
they are low right so one two three
that's the way you say you're always in
technology yeah yeah and
it always works yeah you always walk
yeah and what
are they doing here two yeah
any other way yeah
wait you i think you'll get it get this
answer soon yeah
wait let me check it out
okay i think it's something
how many ways after you imagine
uh okay
so how many ways let's be right yeah i
think
it's something nine eight eight eight
six i think about this bit and
what do you mean i think there's
something about
this line and this one yeah
yeah one two three three three three
think about it
how many ways i can put here what
wait one two three
one okay okay so
first of all the looks cannot be in the
same row okay
right yeah okay so let's put then how
many rows are in
n terms and just prompt
how many rows yeah okay so let's put it
let's try putting first here and i'm
putting seven
seconds here yeah row by row yeah yeah
if i put it here
how many ways i can put i can choose
from
in factorial where down yeah yeah
so you put the first one on n and then
the second choice is you have n minus
one right
and the third one you have one and minus
one
oh and here one so that's m that's it
you see easy yeah okay so let's review
this we talked about this on the first
day every question remember
yeah day one recursion yeah that was
like
that was like 190 days ago right
okay so how about we implement this
location f
f n if n
equals one
okay if n zero factorial is also one
okay
if n equals zero return
factory one then what return what
factorial n times n
times what can i connect factorial and
how to implement this one
n factorial equals n times what
n times i
times n minus one
minus one times a minus two
t one okay so what's this bit what's
this bit this is
like i think it's like one no no
this bit is what m minus one factorial
right
yeah so n returns n times one
and minus one factorial okay which is
one
there's no vector that f n is n
factorial so e equals n times
f and minus one right okay okay
we can do this with uh iterator really
okay so look
answer equals 1 4 i
in range return returns
start with 2 2 and n o n plus 1 can you
tell me n
plus 1 right
answer
n times what's this
time times equal
where's n come on n times what i from 2
[Music]
no i'm like talking about this you can
return
we don't need to reinvent the wheel we
can return math
factorial factor and
that's it okay so we have already have a
function to calculate m
zero using this function next of a clear
and easy
okay okay can you write this uh
can you write the previous one okay
answer equals one and then for
something for something something and
then do this return answer okay
let me do this return another thingy
okay
i yeah and in what
[Music]
okay in one
you want to i want to go from 2 to n
right so what's that function
you forgot the range come on run
range
[Music]
you're missing something where the
that's it
that was already there okay okay good
job that's it for the day
bye bye see you later see you tomorrow
bye