hello hello yeah that's my eric hello
eric mister everybody
how are you today good yeah okay so
today we'll talk about the binary tree
again okay by the tree
the numbers nose all right so finally
what's fine we mean
two okay so if i have these notes
a loot doesn't have any parents
and any notes it can have left or right
you have maximum two kids right
and then the leaf doesn't have any kids
so if
if the if we say that the left triad
is angular 45 degree and the right tries
and
45 degree to the right so we want to
find out how many lines vertical lines
are these you know the minimum number of
vertical lines that
cross all those notes for example this
one it will cross 1
two three four okay
so look these these and
the loot and is the same line on the
slice on the center of the root of right
or left okay and also root on left or
right
if i have another note here like five
okay okay so we want to know that
complete
vertical line in this case is one two
three four
got it is clear
how can we do this well first of all how
many ways we travel
the binary tree how many
breakfast such differences what
preferences what does this stand for
level yeah breath first search okay and
the different search is
dfs therefore search so for the
breakfast search is
one one two three
[Music]
left no right okay in order
no resume so what what's that one two by
three one two five
three two four okay yeah one two five
three two four yeah
three five one two five one
two or another two three four yeah okay
yeah because now this is in the middle
okay so
in this case if we go today we're going
to use this preference to solve this
problem
[Music]
and how we solving this just do
breakfast
sideways breakfast sideways so what do
you mean sideways
turn it around turn it around
how so
what determines the number of the lines
they're all 45 degrees yeah if we i if
i said this if the loot is and the
horizontal
zero can i delete the offset
and if i go to the left what happens
minus
minus one if i go to the right one
yeah yeah you see three total ones yeah
i go another one that would be mine
right there yeah two yeah or two okay
so when we go to the left we
push the kids and the
the horizontal offset right minus one
and i'll go to the right we push the kit
and then increment the horizontal offset
and in order to keep to count how many
how many offsets in the unique
i mean how many unique offsets uh
where should we what kind of data
structure are we using
to store the unique elements
set set has said yeah notebook set
okay so then we know how to do this okay
that's why the code right in the cup
we know we find let's say number of
number of vertical lines okay what's
your lens
root or we're given a root column
column if the root is empty if not load
what happens
what should we return 0 because there's
no
lines right and in order to implement a
preferred search
what kind of data structure we need to
use
q q and in python
dk what's pq mean where the
q equals dq dqe
and
okay so we need to push the load and at
the beginning the offset
is one zero okay
wireless element in the queue while
there's an
element in the queue we pop it current
and offset offset
[Music]
equals q dot one pop it
pop forward left yeah because
at the beginning we're going to talk
this is the cube we push
at the rear we take the things out yeah
we take thing out from the left
from the beginning we append to the
right
okay that's the cube first thing
this is q we have q fine
okay okay so we
okay so in order we we also need to keep
a
headshot okay let's say data let's call
it data equal
set okay this is the headset now i got
the offset
i can push it data dot
offset right yeah i know this offset i
put it here
the unique it will only keep the unique
offset
and look if karen
if the left is not empty
queue dot append open one
open what are we
right anything current or left
this is the tuber yeah turn the left and
the offset what happens on the offset
what's that offset one
go to the left what happened to the
offset minus
we go to the right we plus one and
return what we return return the number
of the elements in the set so what
should i do
here
[Music]
data this data is the same we want to
count how many numbers in that so what
what's the function to call length
data data
you see that's it so if current the left
we push it to the left
we uh minus one bye-bye
okay okay
okay so what should we do how do we pop
it pop it from the left
how do you write it pop two things
two things yeah current yeah cactus just
one line
yeah current yeah current comma
comma is a tuber that offset yeah
equals q equal oh that's a nice writing
equal
yeah that's it well done today good job
good job very well done today okay