hello hello mr eric mr ryan how are you
today
good what is the five good okay so
yesterday we talked about the number of
vertical lines
right there the preferences yeah
[Music]
three
and then when we expand the notes we
kind of use
we need to pass down the what how do we
know which
which line it is how do we oh
we say the root line is zero
yeah this is yellow and we go to the
right
[Music]
we push all these this horizontal offset
into
into a what no no no no no notebook
headshot and we call the lens of the
headset right yeah
and we use a q in breakfast search to
implement this professor
in python we used
okay what's the other way of traversing
the financing
[Music]
so look if this is one this is two this
is three
that's that's how many ways we can
travel a
tree using the different search three
in order pre-order we order will be no
visit the no first and left to right
in order to be visited
in the middle and what's this what's
this oh a post order
and then there's some something like
reversed
in reverse in order all right reverse in
order could be
uh what r and l okay right
reverse you know okay yes because it's
reversed so look if this is the
preorder this one we order what's the
pre-order sequence of the
service the binary
this one
[Music]
one this one one
okay one two three yeah one two three
okay
so one two one three
and two three
one
uh yeah one two okay
if it's the primary research tree right
the left node are smaller than the
parents the rhinos are bigger than the
parent which order gives the sorted list
[Music]
no this this is not viruses three yeah
the left tree is
less smaller this would be this one yeah
this is the final okay
this one this one no the left right
no left right wait wait wait like this
this one no no no no
[Music]
so if we use the pre-order to travel the
partnership so
how can we remember so what should we
pass down our
will we do the different search
define before search
load right all right and then look at
that
now we have at least therefore search uh
what
uh let's say the vertical number number
uh yeah
we can have another function inside of a
number of vertical nones yeah
and another function is
yeah okay and then we have released the
first search another defined
do you define it
what should we pass the the second
parameter
uh if we want to travel let's go to the
left which we should what
plus one yeah yeah we should have at
least x variable two
horizontal variable yeah why is it x or
any variable
you can name it oh you could x because
look usually
usually in a mathematic this is x this
is y right
this is the horizontal y right
why is this one horizontal but we're
going to left left left
right this is x right all right
so in order to do this all right we have
a
line to which stored unique data which
what's your opinion eagles
set said yeah yeah and
we want to we want to manipulate the
land inside this fashion so we need to
decorate
non-local okay none of the land not like
and then we should do this one if
not if not those
yeah because if it's empty we don't
return and then we need to put the
lines in to add x
yeah what does it mean what does that
mean
the x is current horizontal horizontal
uh okay the lines uh
you know the horizontal yeah i mean
yeah uh yeah so so look what this is one
two three so we push this is zero yeah
at the beginning you know push it into
the lens and then we need to do it
definitely
[Music]
one
with the load zero
yeah and then we need to return
where how many numbers are in the length
so we can work
length well done okay so let's stay for
search what's the time complexity
what's n
[Music]
the numbers in the pine
tree okay what's the space complexity
hey
come on come on come on
yeah okay done okay that's it for today
good job
bye bye bye bye