hey hello mr mr ryan how are you today
good okay let's define a sine function
first define
sine what are we talking about
yeah yeah but we started s g n sign a
number
okay okay let's divide it look if
what what equals zero will be times zero
uh i'm defining a function yeah
if n bigger than zero we return
one and s will be return
zero minus one for negative here is
negative right
yeah that's the sign function right
negative numbers
so for example sgn 100 what does it
return
sgn 100 you put it here so what does it
return if it's a positive number you
should return one
one one sg and minus two
return one once one sgn
technically
[Music]
so only three possibilities values come
out of this function
if it's a positive number written one if
it's the negative number
within minus one yeah if it is yellow
yeah look if it's yellow if it's bigger
than yellow we can one and
else what else if it's smaller yeah it's
smaller than zero this is the only
possibility okay
okay so this is the simple stem function
so yes telling if you
if it's like uh
yeah yeah okay so given a list of
numbers like one two
zero three minus a hundred
uh i have a few numbers i want you to
find out the sign
value of all the products you multiply
yeah yeah okay so look if i want to
i want you to find out the sum function
of the value this value comes out from
for all the products you know that
multiplied together yeah 1 times 2 times
0 times 8 times 100
so what's the sign value of the product
of these if you times 0
yes yeah okay so that will be zero yeah
if i tell you that is one and what's the
exam value
i can remember this what's the sum value
of these values
this
no first of all times all these values
and then five dollars one times two
times one is two two times eight is
sixteen sixteen times minus 100
yeah so if you want to find out
come on it's easy right i need the
calculator
do you need to actually need this one
yeah because
this is so you don't actually need to
find out the value right
yeah yeah because we just want to know
if it's positive
negative or yellow right yeah
it's negative not quite sure if i put
another negative here
what happened double negative makes
positive right yeah
minus one number yeah
yeah okay so we want to find out how
many first of all we want to find out
if less zero if there is zero the sine
function will definitely return zero
right
no matter how big or how small the value
is the product is
if there's no zero and we want to find
out
how many negative signs right yeah
and if it's an even number of negative
sound
it is one if it's odd number of negative
signs
minus one where okay let's see but
obviously you can times it together and
then return it yeah
let's write this house i think this is
like one two
sixteen i think this is the one times
okay look fifteen times minus one okay
let's
let's say put that sign okay put that
sound let's fix
[Music]
the first approach is we want to find
out the actual value okay let's
say let's say uh product plus p equals
one and then for
i in nums right
we can know right about we can do this
and how can i find some product
p y p
p p
[Music]
all right look so this these these the
complexities are n right n is the number
of
numbers it has four okay we can do this
using fancy syntax yeah
all right all right
yeah we can do this reduce function
reduce reduce is from it
to us or function i can't remember it
reduce
reduce all right reduce the function f
and then numb that's it
function we need to define it as what
define this as
uh i put it here define f a
b column return
return a times b right right yeah
return this is one thing just two times
together with you i want to reduce
can you hear me please one two three how
do we reduce with this one so it's one
times two
[Music]
so i can reduce i can please add using
the lambda function number
a short shorthand for
[Music]
a b a okay so the initial value
is one okay for the reduce and we can
use this
but here we want to count how many how
many
negative yeah so look look here
negative let's say negative count okay
negative
equals zero okay yeah four
i in nums so far as i went
yeah if what what should i check first
if i equal equals zero which will return
i say right greater than zero
if i smaller than zero what should we
return
no no no no we should what should we do
will come
if i is more than there is we shall
count how many
yeah yeah
yeah what should we do with the negative
equals
we have no and this i is a smaller
number so
we want to what negative
[Music]
no and i is a negative number so we want
to count
put it hold up one come on let's say and
then look
return one
if negative
how do i check if it's either one or two
two more okay there is two oh and one
more
equal zero
yeah that's it so in this case we are
not
multiplying okay we're just checking
this will be faster because much
multiplying is slow and we're just
checking the sun
it will be faster right got it
yeah okay i'm gonna erase this okay
[Music]
one what places negative
equals plus equal what you okay if yeah
if i
i i
i if i was smaller than yellow
write it properly anyway okay and then
what
negative one
yeah we're counting you counting
equals yeah
okay that's it for today thank you very
much see you tomorrow
bye