[Music]
so today
we're going to talk about the
important the most known salting
eggplant which is called
quick salt algorithm yeah quick stop so
can you tell me what it does
quick thought
[Music]
yes yeah
what does it mean i mean quick sauce sit
down it
means i think it means sorting
salting quickly exactly so
look look if we're given the number
[Music]
one two five six one two
five six okay
okay so that's the sorting saltine
agreement okay
so so how do we this quick saw how how
does it work i mean
look if given uh like two five
six nine six three okay
uh maybe one more number one okay
so first of all how it works is that we
need to pick a number
this number can be any any number random
number
or the first number or you can pick them
in the number or you pick the last
number any number
okay so can you pick can you pick a
number
just any number two all right
okay two so okay i pick two right
okay so now find the elements which are
smaller than two
one one okay
you find the one yes okay one
um what find the elements which are
bigger than two
three five six
okay okay yeah three five six or maybe
in the order yeah five six uh which is
five six three yeah
and find the number uh maybe i put a one
more zero here okay
so let's become zero one okay yeah
and if i put another two here okay yeah
so
how many twos are there there are two
right two so two
two solely so now
we got a smaller part the
equal part and the bigger part
and the answer is to add at least
calling itself solving this using the
quick sort
and solving this using the quick sort
and then put these together
so this quick saw would become zero one
yeah if it's sorted
and this is two two right and then hit
this one after sorted
you can pick any number from here again
like three yeah
and then put a smaller one before three
uh
bigger one after three yeah and then
this become one
three five six so you see after salting
and i put all the pieces together do you
see it
now it's insulted do you understand so
so the
the how it works is that i pick a number
yeah and i separate this into three bits
the ones which are smaller strictly
smaller the one which are
equal and the one which is a bigger yes
yes we know this this small
equal is in the middle but this may not
be in order right
then we're calling itself recursively
remember to determine
we call a recursive quick sort function
to solve these two parts am i right yeah
okay so now can you tell me how how
should i pick this number
i want to pick the number that as the
smaller part and the bigger parts are as
e
is equal right as as many as equal right
yeah do you understand if i pick a
number which is zero
then what happens if you pick the number
zero then there's no number smaller than
zero right
and so this bit will be like nothing
right and then all the elements are on
the right hand side this is not
efficient right every time you just
soft sort uh thought one element that's
very slow but these
every time i partition it into three
parts
yeah so it's quicker so i want to pick a
pivot number which
we call this preview pivot yeah pv
number give me like
pivot yeah you can one stretch it you
can pick a
pivot number which is the random
speaker any random yeah or you can pick
the one which is
in the medium remember in a medium
remember we talk about the medium yeah
like one two two one two three four
eight one two three four what's the
medium
what the medium is these these two
divided by two yeah so two point five
but there's no medium right
very close to medium so we can pick two
or three right
but this requires another processing so
normally it's not very
practical so we just pick a random
number right
okay so now i'm going to implement this
quick thought okay
so can you tell helping help me if you
can okay
define quicksort let's call it numbers
okay so now what do we check we need to
check we need to check if
first of all if the length of the event
even the size of the
number we want to sort if it's smaller
and or equaler than one what do we do
if it's just one number or if it's
nothing what do we do we just return it
right
if the number is already sorted if one
number is already sorted
right yes yes so return
return one and because the size is
smaller than one then we return one okay
now now yeah now we need to find the
parts which is the smaller bigger or
equal right so we have three three bits
now
we first of all try the number or pivot
number so pivot
which yield a pivot don't do that nobody
will see enough pv number
we can pick the first one last one or
or the random one yeah if you want to
pick the first one is and
zero right yeah but if you want to pick
a random one i i i told you
i i i picked random which is random
and then you can say choice okay this is
interesting choice
and so what does it mean is that given a
list of choice
and very yes and like london to give me
one okay just one random number okay
yeah okay so now i want to have three
parts equal equal part yeah
and then small
smaller part
and then bigger path okay
yes yes yes
okay now what's now we need to loop in
this end right
for i in
n yes yes
i know what what should we do now if
i is equals to pv
then we we push this pivot append
okay a pen or a pen equals a point i
asked if look as if we can short as air
if
okay air if yeah else if
i is bigger than pivot
then what was that bigger
bigger a pen
i and can you tell me what's next
s right smaller
yeah a pen
i why yes yes
now we have the equal part smaller and
bigger part now the
the last bit so how how can we do this
the last bit
the last bit okay the last bit return
calling the save look quick so return
what quick sauce
smaller right
plus equal right we don't need to slow
that equal right
because it's already equal right yeah
because that
if there are three twos and we don't
need to solve it because it
is already in order right and then and
plus
quick sort
what should i do here
smaller equal and what's this what's
here we need to solve bigger
bigger yeah you see this is recursively
recursively
recursively as sorting the smaller parts
and the bigger path am right
yes look this is a bit
area look for i in n we're looking each
number
in a in a list if it's equal
if it's equal to pivot then we'll push
it to the equal
if it's bigger than pv it'll push it
into the bigger if it's else it should
be smaller right it pushes to the
smaller and when you're calling that
recursively quick saw the smaller power
plus equal plus the
plus quicksilver bigger and now look at
this one
we can we can replace this bit yeah
this bit is we can replace this bit by
using a simple syntax here
we can do this look okay here yeah
i'm going to write this and then you let
you you can tell me
x for x what's x for x in n
yeah the x now is x right
but what is that x is in n every number
in n
right if x equals
pivot okay
so what should i do the smaller here
x for x in n if
x smaller than pivot okay
and what's bigger than pi here x for x
x pivot okay
this is the same thing as this yeah and
we don't need this
and then return quick saw smaller plus
equal parts bigger right
yes do you understand it they do have to
put
quick start
smaller part plus the equal parts past
the bigger parts
this is calling the smaller part every
time so
what it does is look look three
three two one five okay
so for example if i choose the previous
three so what what
is on the left hand side yeah and one
five for example like if i say six five
okay it's on the other side six
right so this is sorted yeah this is
here
yeah two is this part smaller
six y is this part a six five is not in
order so i call this
chord itself to divide and conquer yeah
so i solve this problem
i call in the same algorithm to solve
the smaller parts
which is six five do you get it and
after calling that it will be in five
six
then i put it together that would be two
three three five six so let's get it
now it's in all insulted do you get it
yeah yeah so the accurate uh complexity
for this one can you make a guess
it's a bit difficult can you make a
guess is it
o n is it o n log
n or is it o n square
which one pick one just guess
just just guess which one
which one don't worry don't don't worry
uh if you make mistakes just pick a pick
one and i'll tell you if it's right or
not
one in three the chance what do you mean
there are three choices just tell me
which one
oh i don't get it the complexity i mean
how how many times the computer even
have n
elements in the array how many times the
computer
how much time the computer needs to
spend on sorting
three what three i mean these if it's n
elements
how much time the computer needs to
spend
there are three parts i mean calling if
they're n elements how many times
does it only scan one time uh once like
alignment or does it need to
scan multiple times
you're not sure that's fine you're not
sure
wait you want to guess
[Music]
yeah yeah so definitely not this one
right yeah okay so is it this one
yeah probably okay yeah
this is practically is always n but but
only
if you pick the favorite correctly
remember what i told you if we always
pick the smaller smallest one or big
largest one yeah then the complexity
will be o
and square right do you get it because
every time
you just saw the one element right and
then you need to end iterations
you know for each you saw it takes on
to solve one element and you need to
sort n elements so that would be n
square right
yeah but but if you pick the pivot
very cleverly you know if you pick
something in the middle you always
separate into half right
remember the binary search yeah very
similar yeah
remember binary search all right every
time you cut in half yeah
and then that will be locked in right so
that will be n log
n okay yes yeah i come back tonight uh
to this that
in the future you know don't worry if
you don't get it but this is
a very important agreement okay
okay say bye-bye okay