hello hello mr ryan how are you today
good and today is about rotating images
rotating images yes the me means 2d
magic okay
rotate
one two three that's the magic yeah
yeah we want to rotate clockwise
clockwise
yeah anticlockwise we can talk about
antifungals tomorrow okay today just
clockwise
so here two clockwise you become
what you become you'll become one it
will become
one two three one four
seven two five eight three no so you can
turn these uh away so that will be these
will be seven
four one eight five two nine six three
eight five four eight five two
eight eighty-five to six nine three okay
so you turn this string
okay yeah so before we
come up the solution for the rotating uh
do you still remember
what's the transpose one for seventeen
like like that one two three four five
six seven eight nine how can we write
the transfers can you one four
seven one four seven two
five eight two five eight
three six nine three six to nine okay so
what's
what's big transposing mean what does it
mean
how do you how do you transfer the
what magic do you do it how do you come
up with leaf
i mean what what you turn it around
and you click and you reverse the
columns
but okay but most intuitively how to do
this
you know about how do you look one two
three four and how do you
what's this transpose one three two four
one three four yes and what's this
how do you know it's one three two four
come on it's very old three two four one
ah okay so yeah what i'm saying is this
the diagonal is mapping so look
it's wrapped with diamond two and four
swap it
seven and three swap it anything along
there
eight and six working right that's how
you go to transpose
correct yeah makes sense and
the transpose this is n times n
mental it can be any size for example
one two
three four five six this is this is
three row times two columns right when
you transpose it you'll become two rows
and three columns
okay so how do you transpose these
this is another number how do you
transfer this one three five
four six so one three five two four six
right you see three rows two columns
becomes two rows three columns
okay yeah and you transpose it here
here at the beginning you'll be column
three row number three
zero one two two rows and zero column
and then now you become
zero and two column so which is zero
and two column five yeah look right
right
you see yeah
so the transpose
let's review this transfers first and
then we can talk about it a transpose
okay
define transpose
transpose a metric a what's missing
every time if not a okay then we return
nothing okay we can or nothing between
nine
okay because if it's an empty you can't
transpose it
yeah okay and then we need to find the
rows first rows and columns
so look rows right
and columns equals length a
that's the rows yeah and columns what's
the length how do you write the columns
length a y a
0 the first row right come
so now we've got these we call this
we call the rows and columns and then
now
because the transpose one it will be
the columns will become rows the rows
will become columns right
yeah so let's say the target the answer
okay the target t
equals at the beginning okay zero
for in range
at the beginning will be rows rows will
be the columns and rows
and then for underscore in
range when you
so what this means is that at the
beginning is two times three and then
you
i will allocate a t which is three times
two right
right and then i can just go through
this original
metric for r in range
range one rows right column
for column in range
columns okay so this is interesting
eric ryan t t
what what equals the original matrix is
a
a r c and here
what should i put brian
this is rc from the arushina and here
will be uh
this transpose one will be what
the where then well got it you already
got it
ci the opposite that's why i said two
times three becomes three times two
so this is the choice
which one will be returning
t yeah we want to return the transfer
okay now this is the transpose
so suppose we know these principles
already the time complexity for this one
is o
n what's n or you can say o
right rows times y columns yeah because
there are those times columns of
elements in this magic okay space
complexity is all the same because we
are allocating
a new metric to retain okay
now if we know this transposing and we
want to rotate it
we can combine the transpose the first
step right one two three
four five six you look at me okay
when i transfer it will be one four
seven
one and one two five
eight three six nine
five three six nine okay the first three
numbers in the three time tables
yeah okay so now this is transpose and
then how can we make it here
okay i'm going to write it reversed
oh right
so this is the b from here to here is
rotate 90 degree right
yeah from here to here is what from here
to here
is from the second to the third one what
was the transformation
how do you get from here to here
universe
yeah okay good good job so this is
transpose this is reverse issue
and then we go we can do it and it also
works for
this is end time yeah it also works for
what for like this one two three four
five six yeah this is three times uh
three row two column and when we
transpose it
we become one two rows three columns
yeah
one three four eighteen one three five
two four six and then we reverse it
reverse each row is it five three
one six fourteen
is it look is it yeah
yeah when you rotate this 90 degree
you'll become that so it also works for
these
and when the rows and columns are not
the same okay
okay so now we can write this okay good
job
d5 rotate right this is rotate 90 degree
clockwise okay
we'll talk about anti-coca-wice tomorrow
okay
rotate magic first of all
metric let's let's
transpose let's say we already know
trends how to transport
okay please this means i want to replace
the original content of
m because i pass this metric here so
transpose is return of new magic
and i want to replace the m right so
it's
square it means i want to replace m and
this is
already transposed and now
for row in range
the rows what's the rows length
length m okay less than m
i want to reverse this how to reverse it
remember
how do we reverse the number uh mr
rn three two one for that yeah yeah look
sweet one how can we
release even the least housing will be
worth it do you still remember
we can use the two pointer thing yeah
exchange three and one logo let's say
one two three four
exchange is four and one right
then move it together exchange two and
three
until the math right correct yeah but in
person we can also use this thing
column column minus one right remember
so m
r equals m r
column column minus one that means i
want to reverse space
okay and return
and that's it matrix yeah magic okay so
look this is all let's say there are
n elements in the uh n elements in the
metric oh
and and here
[Music]
okay here is another on so yeah so
o2n which is of the one and
that's the way how we do you do in two
two places
the first step transpose it the second
step
reverse israel okay okay
okay i'm going to okay how can i do this
i'm going to
[Music]
can write it down here that's easy
so we want to return we want to yeah
yeah and
no bracket is the function
bracket not a square bracket okay lambda
means the number of
rows for the matrix right and length
look
m0 is the number of the columns
yeah all right right look here one two
three
because in the metric it will be like
that right you'll be
like that a list of these basically a
matrix is a list of these
lens m there are two this which is the
row
length m0 is this one and how many
numbers in m0
ryan how many z how many numbers in m0
one two three three then that's three
columns okay
three columns two rows okay that's where
we get the m0 okay good job today
good job good job bye bye mateys
bye bye