hello hello mr all right
yeah okay so yesterday
we talked about uh rotating the
magic 90 degree okay let's take a review
okay
like one two three four five
six seven eight nine and half seven
eight nine
how i i i want to rotate at least 90
degrees
yeah there'll be seven four one
so how can we say this eight four
[Music]
how do we transpose please what's let's
let's do the transfer first
what does it become
what does it become you remember the
transposing
yeah through this
[Music]
then look four and two seven and
three six and eight right
yeah and then you reverse this bit
reverse
each row right so that'll be seven
four one eight five two
nine six three okay
is that a i think yeah look this is
rotate ninety degrees there
right yeah transpose transpose
what's transport swapping right
swapping something along the time
[Music]
clockwise
clockwise okay
uh does it make sense how can we do this
[Music]
place anti-clockwise me one easy way
i mean you can think about it how did i
say so
let me think
yours yep three six nine
so you turn this way so it's three six
nine
two five eight one four seven
okay it turns out uh this way doesn't
make sense
okay yeah i think you just do this one
and just do
the line this way instead of this way
when you do the line
how do you know how do you know it's
land here
because this is the answer
and then it's like you put it on you did
a line here
so you just swap it
okay yeah you so you mean swap the road
yeah
well yeah observation yes yes
so we we instead of swapping each row we
swap
rose yeah so this throws super yeah yeah
oh another easy way i was going to to
tell you that you can
clockwise how many times i make it
anticlockwise
huh but this
is clockwise uh you you want to turn
this thing
anti-clockwise here and then if you i
want you to make it clockwise how many
times it needs to be
to become one cup yeah whatever
so it's the same right you
anti-clockwise three times you'll become
clockwise
you clockwise three times you become
what anti-clockwise right
yeah that's another way if you really
can't figure out that way right
okay so let's do let's review this code
the transpose let's do the transpose
thing okay
let's do the transposing
define transpose
let's call it a metric m and
column if not metric if it is empty we
just return okay
and now we return uh we want to create a
new metric which we call it t
uh okay let's do the rows first okay the
rows
and column equals the length of m
and what's the column length of m0 okay
yeah so that's the number of rows let's
the columns right
and then i want to create a new eric
look
one two three four five six if i
transpose this
you this is three color three rows and
two columns right yeah
if i transpose it and what what do i get
look what do i get with this if i
transpose
[Music]
i look at what
i transpose this one what do i get
the rows will become the
the new metric the rows will become
original columns the columns will become
rows so it will be one three five
two four six right and this is two rows
and three columns yeah
the dimension has changed look yeah look
this dimension has changed to here right
right yes here look at this one
this one is 2 1
1 right 1 1 the index is one one the
original is also one
and this one is original this one two
one and then here you become one two
right
yeah one zero one one two
three so the num so for example this one
the index if
it's i j right and then when it goes to
the transpose it will become y
the index will become what
j i right that's what i mean swap the
rows and columns
so here why why would we need to know
this because
the rc and then i need to create the
metric t equals
at the beginning i put it
0 for underscore in
range ah okay that's the columns
and then for underscore
in range what
let's the rose will become y r c
c c r c
the original is r times c right and then
after i create this this becomes c
times r okay this is the metric for c
times up
r columns are columns and then
zeros okay correct
right yeah
okay so now i'll look then i can do this
for ah
range i i want to assign r in range
r for c
in red c
right look at the original this t
can you tell me what do i put here the
index equals the original is
m right m r c
so what do your happen here c
c i yeah return
which which magic which measure
m is the input what's the output
come on it's very obvious what are we
doing here we're talking
target thinking this is the transfer
okay we are creating a new metric
so the space complexities of rc the time
complexity
is what come on
very obvious what
sorry why is that one come on
we are transposing we we need to visit
each element
yeah i i mean i want you to represent
the complexity using r and c what's r
and c
oh
look here is two that's very obvious r
and c come on why is it a one right
a space complexity here this is creating
a new metric
yeah yeah time conversion this is time
complexity and let's space complexity
here right
we're allocating the space for the new
metric yeah
it makes sense oh yeah
got it okay now
so remember yesterday we talked about
reversing yeah
yeah let's say clockwise okay let's just
do this clockwise first
clockwise and m equals
okay we use this to say i want to replay
uh i want to erase i want to replace the
content of magic
by transpose transpose
and then and then row equals
length of the new matrix
[Music]
okay and then look at everything
transfer okay
four row in range
this is yesterday's con common yeah m
m y and r each row i want to to reverse
this
how do i reverse this
clockwise yeah and then if i can do
repeat these three times that'd be
anticlockwise that's one method
of doing right yeah you can say
anti-clockwise
i think this is my favorite time uh
that's fine
look if we're changing this because
anti-clockwise
clockwise and we can just do this
clockwise
tongue three and
yeah and clockwise and calculate
and yeah that's it yeah yeah you can set
it to
my and okay so that's one way of doing
the app
okay one thing i want to mention is that
this is not in place what is in place is
changing the
changing the numbers without allocating
a new one
this is we are allocating a new one
right okay
but if we i tell you the dimension is n
times n
it means that it's a square metric right
it's a square metric
right yeah three times three four times
three
it's a square magic then we can do this
in in in place
in no time in place what's what's in
place
so in place let's look for a second
and equals length m right arrogance
is in python n equals length
m that's the rows and the less columns
for i
in range n
right and then for j in
range what anyone
range f no it's quite easy to make a
mistake when
i because look one two three four five
six seven eight nine oh i want to change
okay look i want to change i want to
swap
along the diamond room right yeah all
right
so all i need to itera is the these half
all these are right the top half of
bottom half right
you don't need to iterate always right
am right
yeah look if i swap here look
look i it right here four yeah you i
don't need to if i go to the four
i slow for you two right right if if i
go here again and
look if i swap it that will be two and
four right
and then if i go here again if i iterate
this again what happens
i swap it back right does it make sense
you stop it twice
that's not only one we just want to swap
it uh
butter half yeah i'm right doesn't make
sense yeah
so look how can i do this look uh m
i j m
j i equals what
looks q
[Music]
a b equals b a yeah i also to where are
we to ryan equals lion eric
elizabeth stroke yeah okay
so now this is this is
in place and now we all will transpose
it how we want to reverse it each row
yeah this is the same yeah 12
in range
and and i want to swap i want to swap
the
the color the rows the rows one two
three i want to swap
one two three i remember we can use what
how do we swap two points oh we can just
go through to the half yeah
so four j in
range and divided by two
and then look m r this is the row
mrj
[Music]
um
this this index will be m minus one
minus ray basically i want to swap these
two color
elements right look alright j here
this is zero i want to swap it with this
what's this
zero one two two right the index right
how how do you get the 2 it's 3 minus 0
minus 1
3 is the number of elements in a row
yeah for example 1 2 3 4
5 6. i want to swap with these and this
right yes this is index one
and i want to calculate this index this
index equals what
six elements yeah six
six minus zero minus one
one minus one right so that's four
zero one two three four you see four is
it so it's
number of elements minus one minus j
that would be and i need to swap it okay
yeah okay so now if i i want to make it
anti-clockwise
instead of swapping the each row
one two three four five six seven eight
nine
instead of swapping that's sick so every
time
instead of swapping this yeah i want to
swap
here right yeah all right and right
so look what should i do look this is
yeah
all right this is the same so i just
have to go through
the first half right the number of rows
have every look at this one
yeah and i want to swap one all right
minus r minus one right all right
yeah this is the number of rows mi is
here
and and minus r and r is here so i want
to swap it with these two so
m and minus equals what
how what should i put here
easy mr m and minus
r minus one equals n and minus r minus
one is
n
okay so you see let's let's swap him
when we stop him you'll be
anti-clockwise yeah yeah
yeah return return and
no we don't need to swap it in the
middle right because you swap the middle
to the middle it doesn't change
yeah look you want to swap
one two three four five no i mean do you
need to pick
one space look you swap
one to five two to four three you can
swap with
itself or you don't need to do anything
even you do
it it's the same right yeah okay so
let's let's just swap in
okay any questions
any questions any questions um
it's basically can you tell me why this
is
n minus two and divided by two okay no i
don't need you to write the curve
i just need you to explain to me why
this is n divided by two
n is the number of rows one two
three four five six seven eight okay
so you technically just needed it and
divided by two yeah
because that's technically what do we do
here what do we do here
what do we do here
we what are we trying to solve here
it's trying to solve the anticlockwise
yeah i mean here this bit after we
transpose
what are we doing here we want uh
until the middle yeah
what do i mean and swap it
so with this one to each one
yeah and this one will do that yeah
right now
i know we just need to go through the
half that's what i mean divided by two
yeah half right and then mr will be here
right three that will be here right
let's like call
let i want to swap with mr and this one
this one n minus r minus one is this one
right
okay yeah
okay that's it for today good job
goodbye