oh hello hello mr mr ryan how are you
today
good good okay you play the chinese
chest right
yeah you know the chest in the ball yeah
the chest
and the whole tiny chest because they
not chinese okay okay let's try
you know that the toast yeah on the
night in
in the chest yeah wait wait let me do it
the horse or horse in chinese chest all
the night
yeah night what night
a night a night could is a soldier
a soldier on a soldier
on a horse wow
that's what i'm saying yeah you you jump
always
one uh one offset and change
three so how many even an infinitive
unlimited unbounded chessboard yeah with
the grid
okay yeah and the knight for example if
it's here
how many ways can you jump how many
how many ways eight eight ways
it could be here yeah ryan
look it could be here and here
here here here
here and here right yeah all right
yeah right okay
you know what you mean okay so keep
giving infinity
ball and if this is if this
if this if this is zero
zero right and i give you
uh the ninth position saying here
that's uh rc right rc
here is r here here is c
yeah and this is minus okay so it's a
it's a axis and i want you to tell me
that
how many the minimum number of moves
for it to return to the center
right yeah maybe i can draw a little bit
do you get it you'll get it yeah
okay so for example let's let's draw
okay so for example here is zero zero
okay let's do this
wait
do another one
it's not equal that's okay that's okay
so here
this is original position this is a
target
we're attacking and if if the
soldier is here so how many
moves can it jump from to this point
two huh oh is it two
you can try yeah
what okay
right yeah
right let me get it straight
three yeah so here here here right
three yeah yeah and how about here
okay so we get it so look if it's
unbounded
unbounded unlimited there's no boundary
of the chest i give you a number like
like here if i give you the answer
one zero so one
zero is this one you need to tell me is
three
and two zero you need to tell me it's
two
zero two okay here
yeah look if this is what zero
one two and here is zero one two
axis right yeah you go okay so it
doesn't make sense
the rose columns okay okay
do you understand this problem yeah you
understand how can we do this
okay so for example
here as you just said yeah okay
yeah so you're just gonna work
backwards
[Music]
yeah so any idea how we're solving
and this how how do we solve this
problem
just any sort of random source will be
fine it doesn't have to be correct
excuse me
how do you solve this problem how do we
ask computer to solve this problem
given uh
[Music]
infinity by its infinity how do we
perform him
i mean yeah obviously performing you can
check the next partition right
obviously they are unlimited here okay
look at the two pointers
no look look the horse here and it has
a position next right yeah and from each
location it has another a position right
right so you could blue force
each other each position until it falls
this right
right all right yeah but it takes time
right
because look a the move the number
a possibility for the first step is a
and another second two steps if the
knight makes two steps a times a
another at three step so a to the n
right yeah to the power m
and if this end this position is very
very far
and he could never find it but for
example yeah it could
because you're trying this position and
randomly you don't know where you
you want to go right when i don't know
where to go am i right yeah
so and the other thing is that it could
repeat
if you jump it here and the next time
you don't want to jump it back right you
need to remember where you already
jumped right all right
and how can we solve this problem we can
use the
what notebook yeah the head shapes
remember the the moves we have
we have visited but the thing is this
board is
unlimited so it doesn't make sense i
mean it's not feasible to
to use the search right because you
you're going to try to remember all
those
moves eric we have visited and that's
going to be very inefficient right
because if
if r and c if if this initial location
is a minion
all right a minion a minion step far
away
from the original so you're just
randomly
walking in eight directions for example
here you're here right all right look
look at me
don't don't don't like you need to
answer here right
you don't you're going to expand your
search here
and then search here yeah it's going to
take time and time and time until you
find this right
right you can use the preferred search
or definite search right
all right yeah breakfast searching that
first search am right
yeah but that's going to take forever am
i
all right yeah okay so can we do this
mathematically
all right stop drawing harry
can we do this uh in a better way any
idea
do you know what i'm talking about why
this is not
okay this is this approach is not very
efficient yeah
if if i tell you okay
if i tell you if this board is limited
if like it's a hundred times a hundred
right you want to place the knight in a
board with a hundred and hundred and
then you
tell me how many what's the mean number
of moves
from this position back to the original
to left
top top left corner right
then we can do the pressure search in
the first and right
side side yeah if it's like this far
yeah we want to move closer to it
yeah whether yes yes exactly we want to
move closer
okay so what i'm saying like if the
search space
i'm saying why this data search
preferences
doesn't work because the search space is
unlimited
do you get it if the search space is
the search these are the search
agreements eric
breakfast search search deficit search
blue for search
search uh and it are inefficient
yeah because you've got the unlimited
search space it's unlimited how can you
search in the unlimited
thing right but if i tell you that this
board is limited like 100 times 100.
yeah i know maybe 10 times 10 of 100
positions yeah 10 times 10 yeah
then you can do this there for such
preferences because here
you know you you don't need to check
here because it's out of boundary right
right all right and then you know it's a
hundred times
a hundred possible partitions
the maximum and you can do you can do
the breakfast search you have different
first
yeah until you find the path to the
shortest path between
any point to here all right doesn't make
sense
okay so now yeah you mentioned a very
good point is that
we're here yeah if if look
at the beginning this position can be
negative yeah because it's unlimited
alright
look all right look at this axis yes x
yes y
right yeah it could be negative yeah
these are the negative
space am i right negative
but if we turn look we want to find the
position all right look we want to find
the
closest position here
is it the same as here right you can
always mirror it right
all right the distance between this
point
to this is the same as the distance
between
here to here right it's the minor right
here yeah
we can turn the negative into positive
right
all right because look the distance
between this point
to the origin is the same as here
doesn't make sense it's the same right
you can mirror it
so let's think about the positive cases
only now we can turn the negative to the
positive using which function
the mathematic what's infinity what's
this one here
remember what's this one here
a abs abs absolute value yeah
okay so look here
if we are here okay and we want to move
close to that so how many positions can
you can you
the previous one yeah
yeah eight no no yeah it's a
but but which two positions are closer
to this
and yes exactly we don't need to check
here because it's true
away right drifting away and this bit
it's further away
you can try that no no no this is far
it's it's fun so only these two
positions
but we are not sure which way the best
right all right
but we can do eliminate these two this
another six right
because it it's it has bigger distance
right it's jumping the the opposite
direction it's not the
thing we want we want to move closer
right yeah so it should be this way or
this way
and that's it look now what we can do is
what
let's say f function ah
x y then we can say what it's equals to
mean what
f x minus one y
minus two or f
one f one x
minus two why what y
minus what come on
one yeah minus one yeah one is two minus
and what what we need to do is plus one
mean of these two functions plus one
plus one from here if if these two
positions can
no we already know we already know the
distance between
this these and this we pick the smallest
one
and we want to jump from how many steps
from these two to here
so if we are we know the distance
between uh
the cost the answer from to jump from
this partition to this
and is this f x minus one y minus and
here is f
x minus two one minus one so in order to
reach this point we need to plus one
plus one
yeah yeah and this is what because we
already know this we don't need to
calculate it over and over again what
does this call
recursion with uh
is here right it's here all right if
it's zero and zero is zero right
if it's the release in
in this position
uh in this position in this position or
here
is what is two right here
here here
how do you jump from this to here
[Music]
you can go here and then here right
remember it's an immediate ball right
yeah all right so two
no no no how can you go left
here go here and go here right yeah
okay so let's say top-down dynamic
programming mathematic
okay let's write this very quickly
there we go
define f
f r wait cash
define f x y
are supposed to be different colors look
if
x equal zero and
y equals zero its original return one
right zero okay
if x y look at x y is in what
it's all positive yeah in in what cases
in these cases
we can say in this case one
one zero two
three zero two zero
return one two then two because he's the
biggest
yes we have the number all right
let's return minimum
of f x minus
one what y minus one
t two and f x minus two
y plus one huh
first one minus one minus one
and that's one first one outside okay
yeah that's it and forgot one thing
yeah because if you're not doing the
cash
it'll be explanational yeah because you
call
the calculating over and over again it's
like a
remember the fibonacci number all right
all right look
yeah look fibonacci number f3 f4
f4 equals one f1
f3 plus s2
and f3 equals one f2 and f1
afterwards
okay okay look look look at f
f2 f2 here f2 here
yeah f1 here f1 yeah even we if we don't
catch it y pad
this value will be calculated over and
over again right the same thing here
because look f x minus one f y minus two
yeah
eventually if you're not catching it
this value will be
calculating over and over again and this
will make the
time complexity exponential right right
am right but now we we're doing this
uh using cash and at the beginning if
you
you need to pass this x and y which is
absolute value right
all right if this is a function what we
need to call is what
what what we need to call is f absolute
value
of x and absolute value of y right
yeah all right and
because of the value this could go to
the minimum
right all right so this needs to
absolute value as well
there's one string here it's abs you
need to put this abs value to all of it
why is that eric do you know why why why
we need to do this
because like x minus one
y minus two x minus two minus minus
one mm-hmm it could be this bit
so what i'm saying is the x the x minus
one y minus two x minus two y minus one
has to be
like the way yeah yeah
we need to put a absolute value of it
yeah yeah together whatever
absolute or minus three equals one three
yeah absolutely a hundred it was one
hundred yeah well absolute zero equals
[Music]
yeah okay you're right computer you can
put minus
zero is actually let's say zero
can you tell everybody in the world what
have you learned so far
as short as possible okay we learned
about
the chest yes and we're gonna
play it in the kitchen yes yes boys
and we're gonna do the hats i'm
gonna leave the target yeah so what are
you trying to solve here
i'm i just want to know what have you
learned what's the
the menu of night moves yeah what's the
the problem and how are we solving this
just answer these two questions
what's what's our problem what's the
problem here and how
minimum moves yeah not the greatest
they're minimal yeah because great is
there's no answer right you can always
find a bigger move right right
yeah you can always jump further right
i'm right there's no
such thing as the maximum number of
moves but there's a
minimum move yeah yeah okay
okay and how are we solving this
uh dynamic programming yeah and
top down and how are we implementing it
recursion with minimization remember the
cash
flow down okay okay okay that's it for
today good job