hello hello mr mr ryan how are you today
okay so today it's very easy today we
have number
like one two three or minus three to
five and this is bigger
yeah i want you to tell me that if i
give you one letter
five inserting five into any places and
find the maximum number it can be
five five one two three and then this
one
the maximum three minus three to
five five yeah minus three two five five
yes
okay another example like
three six uh
uh six three six
okay what's the back what's the biggest
number you can be
by putting a fight six five don't need
to be big
need to be next to the biggest number
okay so what's your strategy
if you are allowed to put the five in
any letters
what's your approach what's your
approach
yeah you're right what's the approach
[Music]
five so how how can we do this
if you're not sure what can we do three
fourths
yeah how can we improve something
yeah well
interesting so what's your approach why
why you choose to why are you she
put it yeah this one why you choose to
put it in the front what for this one
why you choose after
it because for this one because
we print because all of it
all of the numbers are smaller than five
so we put it
[Music]
the five after we don't need this one
because this six is bigger than this one
this greater
than 600 and this is just six
okay okay interesting yes and
so you try to find for the positive
cases you try to
from the left to the right you're trying
to find
but find uh
if there's five here what should we do
if we trying to find the number which is
less than the digit which is less than
five
right yeah if if this is five what
happens
if you put it in front or put it at the
back right
it's the other side for this one minus
we put it at the end because because
instead of in front because
the smaller digits there are
[Music]
yeah okay
yeah the opposite obviously yeah that's
very good
very good uh how i mean
given these three digits in the worst
case we have to try
right every every one so we can just
try to inserting the digit in every
position and then we try to convert that
into integer i'm right yes yes
yeah i'm all right so all right so
five for example like one two five
five one two how many positions can we
put the five in
how many positions five yes one two
three four five yeah but for the minus
one two three how many positions can we
put
one one two three
three four right because you can't put a
whole five here it doesn't make sense
right
five minus one yeah it's not a very
number
okay okay is
uh okay minus
minus minus 17 minus 25
minus minus 18
minus 119
and so what do we do now this n is an
integer we want to convert it to one
string
yeah we want to convert it to a string
alright so how do we do this
let's what's the function if we want to
convert it to string
remember s equals
that's what the string string
yeah how what's the function to call to
convert a number into string
what's the first three letter of a
string str
yeah sdr okay yeah all right
look then then the answer
let's at the beginning the answer will
be what
if we want to get the maximum what's the
what's the initial value of the answer
no you could be negative so you could be
we should put on
what minus what math infinity
well done yeah so because we want to get
a maximum
right and now look if n
is greater than zero if it is bigger or
it's very smaller right
yeah so let's say the flag like f equal
if n goes zero let's start from
right because if it's negative cases i i
don't want to put it in
here i want to start it from putting the
partition
let's what the one comes comes from yeah
offset
f for i equals
for i in range
tau is the f and then ends with the
length
the length of the m plus one yeah
because
because we can put it one two three we
can put it at the end at the
end right yeah yeah
yeah stop jumping okay then now the
color number will be what
c equals
s right hey put it at the beginning
i i'm gonna pass the five here
and i need to plus s i right
what does it mean look all right look
one two three if i want to put it here
if i want to put it here what does this
mean s i
mean it's this particular position and
then 5
i put a 5 here and s i column is this
bit yeah anything after
and then i need to com check the maximum
so how to write the answer equals 1.
maximum yeah maximum or what answer
yeah and then what let's see what should
we do we see
c is the integer is the string we want
to convert it
back to string back to integer integer
what's the time complexity what's the
time commentary
what's n a number of
numbers plus one the number of digits
yeah we're talking about the digits
[Music]
so what's the space complexity
so this is for i and let's see
okay what's this what's this big what's
this okay
what's this bit okay
like it okay we want to split the string
and put the five in so what's the string
here
yeah column yeah yeah column i
don't know this one column
plus five yeah that's right i put the f5
here and i want to put anything
why are you clicking it don't write it
so hard okay don't waste the
pen okay i iowa column
okay can you tell me why this is if n
equals zero bigger than zero f
is zero what does it mean if it's a
positive number and if it's a negative
number why the negative number is one
because we don't want to do this minus
yeah
we don't want to put aside before right
right i the index where to put a plus
plus right yeah got it oh yeah baby
okay okay what's the function to convert
a string into an integer
what's that what's the function to
convert a string into integers
function to convert the string into the
integer
uh which one
yeah what's that functions to convert an
integer practice string
str yeah okay this one okay okay that's
it for today good job
bye bye
[Music]
yes