hello hello mr mr ryan how are you today
today's friday yeah okay so remember a
few while ago
we talked about max maximum product of
three numbers yeah given uh
any number like two minus three five
six one zero and you want to find the
next product of three numbers yeah
what's our approach to do that
do you still remember still remember
no two points salty yes we salted and
then what
if we salted this will become minus
three
zero one two five six
okay so what's the next three numbers
you can pick
to get the maximum three five six yeah
and how do you totally check it
is the negative numbers so they
we want to check the maximum three
numbers and
all the maximum the the maximum
and then two numbers if there's a one
minus a hundred here
so what's the maximum three numbers you
can get
make kanji
[Music]
that's right yes so you pick these two
at the maximum
so in in short term if in short term we
also saw these numbers
and then we find we find we compute the
product the multiple
of the next three numbers or the
minimum two numbers we and the maximum
right yeah we need to pick okay so
about today is the simplified version we
want to find out
the next product of two numbers just
pick two numbers
that would be easy so what's that
so if you want to pick two products and
then
to find out the maximum product can you
tell me how how do we do this
these two equals your times together is
oh okay okay so what's your approach
first we check if there are even
numbers we do we need to add actually
if it's if it's bigger than one sorry
what's the picking one
right if there's more than one negative
okay yeah and we don't need to actually
check we just need to compare
two cases the next two numbers
and a negative one a negative one
negative
negative which how many numbers we need
to check negative
uh two yeah we want to check the
negative two numbers
and if they and we want to find out the
maximum
of these two right yeah a little bit uh
what's the time complexity
yeah yeah what's the term complexity
what if i would
end again yeah because we need to start
starting yes we're
like done and what would you
it's 300 it's the maximum for that you
can pick this one on that one yeah
okay so for to do this we need to solve
this
and then we find out all right yeah okay
let's do this
define max
product of two right and then numbs
and then we need to return the maximum
of what the nums
sorted will be slower to the maximum so
numbers can you tell me
this is the smallest number right time
times
what one yeah and
between nouns the
the biggest number which is one
the biggest number on the right hand
side if we sort it zero one two
three four this minus one yeah numbers
minus one times one
this is zero this is one and you're
saying this is minus one
and this is what
[Music]
two what two zero one this is the
smallest this is the
second smaller this is minus one is the
largest and second larger what's this
no no there could be any numbers here
minus one this is syntax minus one
what's this
minus dot what minus two comma i just
said two
it's minus two okay half right you're
fifty percent right okay
okay uh
so why are we starting here why are we
starting here
oh because we want to get very big
we want to get the two biggest and the
two smallest right
yeah all right if we know
the biggest the most largest two and the
most smallest two do we need to solve
yeah we just need to find out the two
largest and two smallest right
all right yeah can we do that look
look if we do this this is the number
yeah
0 minus 5
6 2 1
minus 100 okay for the for example we
want to find out the maximum two numbers
yeah just just just uh maximum two
number let's say the maximum
the the biggest number one okay let's
say the biggest
biggest okay and then
the second biggest yeah right
i know biggest and second biggest
initially you would be
equals minus negative infinity yeah
yeah so because i want to keep it there
okay now i go through this okay i don't
need to sort it
is 0 is 0
bigger than the biggest now
yeah this is the initial value yeah yeah
all right so if it's bigger than that
first of all
if it's bigger than that then i set it
to zero
no no no not yet not if i send it to the
piggies
right so what happened to the second
biggest
it would have to be smoother
look for example if current begins is
nine and seven okay yeah yeah
this is the biggies and then this is
second piece if i have a card number
which is 10
so what's the biggest 10 what's the
second biggest
yeah so here we have a new one
the biggest will be the second biggest
ever
and the new one will be the biggest yeah
it kind of yeah
you're right yes so look look then first
of all we need to replace the
we need to save the second biggest now
right because it will be the second
biggest all right this will become
second bit and you raise this
right nine and then i put the 10 here
it's the same yeah got it okay another
another case is
another cases uh
if it's seven and if it's ten here right
the biggest second bit
if a comes in will happen
yeah so you need to rip because it's
bigger than my biggest no no
[Music]
yeah you got it yeah so if we close the
left follow this strategy
we can get the biggest and second
biggest right yeah so
and the same thing the smallest and the
second smallest
all right yeah so if we keep
four variables and following this
strategy
then the time complexity is one
we're down away yeah good job right
right you're listening yeah good job
oh and because we just go into once yeah
according to once i'm right
okay oh n okay so it's which one is
faster
can you tell me this one why is that
because
and the other one the first one is what
you need
and what the investment for that oh and
again yeah
yeah so this is better than this is
better than
than the second one right okay let's try
this
what's this
girl okay
that's right
no yeah no yeah we know not return
okay look let's say the piggies the
biggest one and the biggest two
biggest one because two equals minus
negative at the beginning right yeah
and then smallest one equally small is
two equals one
if we want to keep the peak is what
the initial value for the smaller small
value
yeah the max dot infinity so we can get
a
thing yeah so for the number
yeah i in numbers following the lines
again
all right all right can you tell me
look is the current number right
if i is bigger or equal than b1
which is the biggest one so what should
we do now we
shall now p1 is the biggest q2 b2 equal
b1
two equals one yeah and then b one
equals one
i right b yeah okay then a
s is a if if i
is bigger or equal b two b three then
what
and then we need to do this for the for
the small one and small two yeah
if i is smaller or equal than
small one yeah if
this is a small one this is small two
okay we can say we can say s2 equals
s1 s1 equals
if i is smaller equals
s2 equals one
okay and that's it after this we have
the b1 b2 which is the biggest
small s1 s4 2 is the smallest and what
should we do 10
return 1
b1 b2 x1 s2
b1 times 12. b1 times
yeah because we want to find out the
product between the next two
maximum largest two numbers or the
smallest
can you tell me why we need to find the
product of the smallest
number it's easy question
because the smallest might be yeah if
double negative makes positive yeah
if minus a hundred times minus 200 maybe
bigger than five times six right
easy as that right yes okay that's it
that's very good okay that's very good
okay i'm just going to erase this can
you tell me what happened here
b one times b2 s1 times
s okay you want to write it
b y
yeah you can just write terms yeah oh
you don't need to write okay okay
okay see there are space here
okay comma
s one times
yeah that's it good job today good job
very well done good job
bye-bye bye-bye
are you okay
what's that eric okay good job bye