[Music]
each now has how many notes how many
kids
okay and how many loots are there
one okay and
the notes without the kick without the
children what we call them
okay so given about the tree we want to
find out
the left most left bottom corner
left bottom corner bottom
leaf okay so which is the this one the
last row
so basically it's the last the left most
note of
of the last last leaf last steps
okay okay any idea
okay so we do what you
and how do we go to the bottom one how
many ways of traversing the binary
error right how many weighs two what are
those
okay so which way which method do you
think it's appropriate in this case i
want to find the logo
sorry that's how do you know that was
sorry
[Music]
oh sorry ah and you go to the bottom
yeah but how do you know i'm
how how do you know it's the left button
yes but when you scroll to here
you definitely you you you need to
rewind right
and then come here here or how do you
know
yeah we can use the default search but
we can use
that we can solve this problem tomorrow
using different steps today
wait for search we just do the last row
yeah point for search what's the
preference search
okay so level by learning easy
everything so
here here here here okay every time we
explain the notes we
remember which note we
remember the first the first note and
then we
after this breakfast search the first
note is the
which node
yeah you will be the last one right yeah
okay can we do this it should be very
easy
defy search
root column
if not load and every time we need to
check
if not return num okay because
if it's a rule it's empty we don't have
the first node
in the last row all right yes can we
focus
it's not drawing listen okay
in python in impossible search what kind
of data structure do we need to use
stack or
skew which one kilo
so in python which which how can i tell
you
thank you thank you
and then at the beginning what should i
need to put in a queue
can we focus no drawing here can i have
your pen please
[Music]
okay okay so here what's right how how
should i perform a breakfast search
if i have a kill at the beginning
here is the queue and at the beginning i
have a route here
so at the beginning what should i write
when there is what y
queue right wireless animate in the
queue and what should i do now
yeah but i want to pop all the left
nodes in the same level at once right
so how many nodes in the layer in the
in the same level in the next level how
many nodes for the first
level yeah well s z equals what
yeah but how can i get the number of nan
nodes in the queue
[Music]
yeah how many what's the function the
the thing is
[Music]
and then these notes i want to pop these
number of notes right but here i have i
will have an
answer answer at the beginning you'll be
long right this is the
let's say answer is the first note of
the
first note of these level okay and then
when we update it
and you'll be the one we exit the
function actually breakfast such it will
be the first note of the which row
of which row this this answer is the
let's say it stores the first note of
the level whenever and if i exit this
while loop
and which first node it will be
okay so now i need to do what four
and then and here answer equals
equals one
yeah and then i need to pop these number
of notes yeah so four
underscore in range red one
right zero what which number how many
number of nodes we need to pop
up when we all the length is
five yes size yes come on
and then if if
and then look then we need to probably
current equals q
downwards pop one
left top left yeah
and then if carol and top left
what should i do if there if this no has
the left kids what should we do
if
on that yeah um
current uh if e current dot if current
dot right
what q dot append
current dot
yeah so we check the left note and
right now yeah yeah you
got it and then we turn which one
answer is the first note of the last row
first note of the last row yeah
yeah i'm right okay uh what's the time
complexity
i went what's n the number nine in the
binary tree yeah what's the space
complexity
i end because we're using okay
we're using the queue yeah okay
[Music]
okay uh what's that where's the eraser
please nowhere
where's the eraser can i have the eraser
[Applause]
what's missing yeah what's missing here
what's missing here what's missing here
we need to pop how many number of nouns
in that in a tree how
size equals
okay i have a good one
okay that's it thank you bye