what did we talk about yesterday
um what
something about the binary tree yeah
left bottom
finally three value right yeah
one two three to talk about the right
talk
okay so okay today
so we want to find out the first note
the left most note of the last row
okay yeah and yesterday we talked about
the pressure search
right left by level
and every time we expand the notes on
the next level we
store the answer as the first note all
right and when the breakfast search axis
the answer will be the first note
the left most note of the last row right
all right
yeah and today we're going to talk about
definition right
that's research so what's the idea about
that first search
you can ideas how do we know how do we
how how does it work if we use the
deficit to solve this problem how does
it work
i think i think you go deeper as you can
so you go
to two and then yeah
so do we need kind of some kind of data
structure to store
what kind of data and then we can use it
later to get the
leftmost node of the level
the maximum level all right
yeah but we don't actually need to use
the step because we can use the
recursion right
right so here all right let's stop doing
that
so here all right what kind of data
structures do we need to
use to store the mapping the the level
we need uh to store the lever and
which that's most know right that's most
note
all right are we right
so here we can go as deep as you want
right as we want and then when we visit
each level
we check if a node
has been visited if this level has been
visited
or not right if we go to the left left
first but note eric diff
definite search if we travel visit the
loot the note left to right what was
this
note note left to right what's this
order
yeah we pre-order yeah if we follow the
pre-order
pre-order the first note
in each level will be the left-most note
if we visit it first right so we kind of
kind of
need to remember that if we have visited
the
level before right for example if we
visited one
have we reached level one yes no
no okay level zero have you reached the
level zero
no we haven't got anything in the what
kind of data structure then we put b
yes said or notebook map we put it
we can make it okay okay the level is
yellow we have a node one
okay then we go to what two right
yeah have we visited the level one
no we put out the level one to note the
two
okay and then what's next have we
visited
note any note in level one yeah
yeah so we don't stop with no update
have we visited the node in level two
no okay so we visited we said two equal
the node is have we visited the node in
number two
have we visited the node in red number
two yes
then we stopped okay now we have this
mapping
hash map level yellow the left most is
one level one and then most is two
number two the leftmost is four so what
should we do now
the last one why is the last one we find
out
that's the bottom
and then
[Music]
it has the largest key right largest
level and we find out the value
which has the largest key right yeah
yeah so what so this makes sense we use
the recursion visit the left node
uh the node the current node and then
the left node and then right now
that is the pre-order and let's
implement it in recursion
yeah which in which which uses the step
by default right location
and now we kind of need to use a hash
map to start the mapping
the keys are the levels the node the
value of the note of the left most
leftmost note and then at the other last
week
we need to find out the note
which has the largest key which will be
the left most note in the largest level
right
does it make it does it make sense yeah
okay
can we write it please can we write it
define okay let's say this function is
uh find left
left left most
okay the root if
not root again we need to check the
spatial corner case return what
if the load is empty if there is the if
tree is empty
do we have the left mouse node in uh
now we return that or actually we don't
need to put alarm
if we just return it means now right you
can
you can also say return number or you
you can just
return it means return now okay and now
i need to i need a hashmap to store the
mapping so
let's say uh data let's call it data
okay data equals the dictionary okay
that's the
dictionary that's the hashmap okay curly
brace okay
and then now we have uh phrases define
a definite search okay and then i how
many parameters i need
braces how many parameters do i need to
provide in the default search
[Music]
we need to pass what kind of parameters
in this function recursion
if we go down to the next level we need
to pass what
what the value what
eric what's the parameters what's the
thing
load yes and then we need to also
need to pass which which thing which no
we uh what kind of information do we
need to pass
into it when we visit the left node left
right now
what are we trying to do here
the what what happened to the
if we go down to the left node what
happened
yeah what happened if we go down the
level never know what happened
this is level zero what happened
yeah we just we just return yeah we just
we can
okay then i even here i want to access
this so i need to put a landlord
keyword to say okay i want to visit i
want to update a value in here
data and then look
if i need to check in this level
okay so all right what do i need to
check i i know
this is level and then i want to check
if the level is in what in which one
each level has been visited right
so what should i do here
yeah level in data if level
not in data if level not in data then
theta bracket
this is this is what square bracket
level
yes the level so we have the mapping
level and the root
the note okay the root okay then now we
need to
visit the left or right first all right
therefore search one
and therefore search one yeah right
okay lose the left arrow and
and then what's the second parameter
we go down what happened level
level one plus one
and yeah
yeah because we go to the left the level
class right we'll go to the right
level okay and then here we go to dfs
we call this function load
yes and okay that's an interesting thing
after this bit the data is the
dictionary
we have the keys and the values and we
know to
find out the keys what are the maximum
keys
return okay look at data
dot keys that's the key there
and if i put the maximum what does it
mean i got a maximum level right
all right maximum data keys is the list
of the keys so which will be zero one
two right all right
after this okay for example here
so what happened here what happened
after this can you
if this is the binary tree so what's in
data after this
at this point what's data in in here
can can you provide me uh data what's in
data
it's in the like level and okay 0
is one one one and then
one is two okay and then
two is four okay okay data
keys returns one we turn the last
what are the keys of this one or this
one
what are keys key value which are the
keys
that's the value that's the key key
value pair so keys will be
zero one two like this yeah and maximum
returns
which one two okay and then
i want to get the two of the four how
can i write it
no no no no this is the max this this
value is
max data keys so i want to reference the
value of these
so what should i do
i can just do this data and then break
it remember that dictionary
the dictionary if additionally i can do
this theta
alright okay theta 1 equals 1 what's
theta 1
theta 1 e equals
2 2 yeah look this is the key and then
return the value that's the dictionary
okay that's the hashmap
okay we can just return this one yeah
return this one
and the value yeah if we if you want to
return the very top value if you want to
return a no you can just do it okay does
it make sense
yeah i'm going to erase something okay
no
okay i'm going to erase this thing what
what should i do here
okay what should i do here what should i
check if that no
if what if yeah
you don't need to write so hard okay
either
[Music]
if what the current level is not in the
digi
in the data right level which is what is
whatever
level yeah
not in yeah
okay that's it yeah theta or theta dot
keys
it's okay it's both okay you can just
write data okay a little bit no b
yeah okay what's the time complexity
what's the time complexity
[Music]
what's the space complexity what's
n
yeah it's the same n is the number of
nodes in the binary and then we are
using
an additional uh data yeah hash map
yeah what in the worst case
how many items can be in the data
how many engines no no no if like n
numbers knows independently how
what's the maximum in worst case what's
the
n why is that can you draw a tree which
is has n
thingy
yeah you see one level one note right so
in this case data will contain endnote
okay
very good very good okay see you bye bye
bye bye