oh hey hi
hello me sorry mr ryan how are you today
okay so we talk about the binary tree
and we have a different
uh traversal algorithm okay
so let's say one two
three four this is about three yeah
five six seven
what's the pre-order one two three five
four
and then one two three four five six
seven so preorder is
not left right
four five six seven yeah what's in order
now three two four
one six five
okay what's the point for such order
one two five three four six seven
[Music]
level by level okay okay so today we
were interested in these the in order
okay so in order yeah
it's one way to remember that is that
the node
is visited in the middle yeah yeah i
knew that another one is air
is ah and air what's what does it call
it
over like reverse in order so can you
tell me what's reversed in order
we're back in order yeah that
is okay
so i solved the problem
[Music]
yeah yeah okay
what okay so let's let's talk about
in order in order to define in order
let's put it in the answer in the list
okay let's try versus
and put it in a list
and we also need a definition a function
we can recursively travel the left tree
and the right tree
load here so what should i do here if
root is numb what should we do
in order okay so we need to definitely
the left yeah i know what should we do
here
visit the left tree and what happened
what happened then and then we
visited me no no not right with the left
tree
look what's in order left no
right we visited the left tree then we
visited the night
alright
depending if you want to return the list
of notes or the list of
values and now should we do next yeah
[Music]
and then we return what
[Applause]
n
recursion and let's just stack yeah we
use the stack okay so
we're going back anywhere that's that's
good question yeah
because the recursion the computer
maintain a stack for you but we can also
we can we can implement these
using iterator of course by using a
stack okay so how do we do this
okay all right look let's let's see
let's put this
three here okay okay let's put these
three here
three here and three there are two
everywhere
this is
[Applause]
[Music]
it's like uh what if we we just put one
in
first is burst out okay
so what if you just put one in the
segment
and then you take it out until we first
get it
okay okay come on listen
how do we use the stack to solve this
problem uh uh
in order okay so stack okay so
we have a stack and we have a current
current thingy okay current variable you
have to keep the current node the node
we are visiting
so what do we do we put that current
equals load
now current equals root okay so we put a
one here
yeah and then we keep put putting the
left
if possible what's left what's on left
keep going no no no too far five is not
on the left we keep going okay so we put
a two here we
put a four four here okay and
and then what should we do now we should
read it we should take it out take this
four out
okay we take this for us so the answer
is
four here yeah take a four hours and
then we
and we what do we do
right go to the right okay
what should we do now we go to we we
take these four out
yeah i'm putting me on so we put in the
answer
and what uh what's next what's next
should we do
on right left when you push this one
uh we push this one two four
and then we take these four out we take
this four out what's that
next what what's the what's the fall
fourth one isn't the answer yeah four is
really nice but
four doesn't have a right right doesn't
have a right
yeah so again we take these two out
two out and then the one out
take this two out and then we uh
no no no we put it nice and we take them
it's right
which is what right is one five five
five yeah and then five
but five easy has a left left note
it doesn't have so i i don't put i i
don't
i don't i skip this and i put i put this
five out
and then what's next we we shall
we take one out yeah it will make three
we take one out and we go to the right
yeah
so basically go to the right three yeah
we go to the
three and then we push it's left in
there
okay yeah yeah
and then we what uh uh actually we need
to push the three in
right we turn the three in and and
put the six we take the six we take the
three we go to the right
and then which is seven okay you forgot
to pick six
yeah in the list four
uh no no six three seven yeah six
three seven okay six three seven
uh so
so the the thing is that if we
have the left we we keep pushing the
left
now if we can if
okay four two five one hundred and sixty
three seven
okay so listen listen
listen the approach is that we keep
pushing the left
note if possible
[Music]
yeah then we go to the right okay that's
a bit of we push the left nose
as many as we want and then if we can't
push the left we
pocket one we pop one from the
stack we pop one that's from the stack
we put it in the answer yeah
and then we go to the right
okay we go to the right okay does that
make sense
let me write a code okay so so you
understand because it's better to
explain with the code
define fine in order
and then now we have a step step in a
cell in python
what kind of data structure are we used
to implement a step
first search no no no array yeah at
least yeah so okay
i stack
[Music]
i will set it to the beginning of route
and answer
i will have equals to the empty days
yeah
okay now why okay while your current
is not empty or the stack is
then i push it i put a stack put a left
into the stack okay so s t
dot append a pen
and then we go to the right go to the
left current equals current
left we go to the left okay and then
after this
look this big is trying to obtain the
the a bit complicated or try to append
the notes in let's note in a step
we try to append the left note in a
stack right like one
two four we try to put that next note in
a
in a in a state can you listen to me
please
one two four so it's one two
yeah one two four right okay we try to
put the
try to go to the left as much as steep
as we want to put it in the stack
all right this makes sense yeah yeah and
then we now we currently
we equal the pop we take one
we take one from the top right
yeah this is four and i put it into the
answer answer don't append one
open one
i take four out of three one
[Music]
because in the next time next time
i take current is what color is now
so it doesn't do this and then you go
pop again which is two
right and then two's right it will be
five everybody
that makes sense and then we turn we can
watch that
right now i mean current
[Music]
i give you one minute to to understand
this i'm going to ask you questions okay
so can you explain to me how how this
works this one
is all the roots yeah
[Music]
okay so okay so and then if
blue is
so what does this bit here doing here
what's this bit doing here
going to oh we're trying to go to the
left every time
i'm pushing the nose if if the left in
the current node
look if a camera now is not empty we try
to go to the left and push it into the
stack and after that we take one from
the top of stack
to the bottom and then this is the uh
the
answer will put uh i will put this
append
the current note into the answer that's
and then we go to the right yeah why we
need to go to the right
oh because we can't be going to the left
anymore
because the left already in the stack
right
we push the left tree in a step we take
it out
we take it out and then this node will
be the root
note and then we we visit the right tree
yeah
this is the right thing got it okay
i'm going to ask you to write the
differences one okay
that would be easy to understand can you
write it
the question the first search one the
first episode
okay answer answer equals one
empty this and then define therefore
search
rules can you already speak here
and then i i root
and then return return what
are you kidding me
[Music]
think about it think about it okay i'm
thinking about it
okay well if loot is empty i show you
now and then what we return return okay
and then what should we do here
there are three statements here huh
foreign
yeah come on that's it okay good job
today
good job bye bye let's see what she is
yeah