okay so remember we talked about the
parentheses what's parentheses
uh it's just like a bracket bracket okay
bracket print this is
open bracket open parenthesis closing
practices
so so
if do we still remember how do we check
if a string
if a string contains only these two
parentheses how do we check if it match
if it's a valid
well what i mean values it comes with
pairs
and this is a very penises
this is a variable this is not
this is not right
this is uh um
these this is not
right okay okay you just need to find
out i think you're just doing like a
matching petal
yeah how do we find if we are given a
string how do we know if it's a very
print decision
uh we just like doing the id and
specifically so how do we check if the
it's a very kind of seasonal for example
yeah i'm gonna do one
[Music]
and then so we start from zero
okay so we have a counter if we have
one like this yeah open parenthesis add
one and if we have one like this
and equals minus one okay so we have a
counter when we meet the opening bracket
we increment the counter by one right
when we meet the closing bracket we
decrement by one
right and then what happened if if the
counter fall below zero what does it
mean
it's not it's not a very parenthesis and
at the end if the balance if the counter
is not zero what happened what does it
mean
it's not right for example like that
yeah what's the balance of the piece
minus one one yeah
what's the what uh what's the
balance minus two minus two one
here minus one we immediately know it's
not very very positive right
okay let's go use that what's the time
complexity of this one
oh oh oh
n okay
okay so today's task is something
similar so given the integer and we want
to
find out that uh how many ways we can
generate a variable contains
n pairs remember it's n pairs so what
does it mean
a pair and one n equals one a pair
is this this is the very parenthesis
right
so given m pairs what does it mean
what's the length of the string
in the n times two n times two yeah
because
each pair contains two they are n pairs
the total length is
n times n times two okay
okay so for example n equals one
easy right when n equals 2
can you write the answer to n equals to
2 pairs how many possibilities of the
two pairs
any other options
mean i think so um yeah i think you're
right yes that's only
good uh players yeah and players of
valley princesses
okay so how do we do this how to what
are we what can we do
if we don't we can
what can we do listed proof of thing can
we do fashion
how can we prove first the proof was
also called exorcistic
exhaustive yeah exhausting exhaustive
search
meaning that i try
every possibility right so how many n
equals two so n pairs we know is n times
two
length strings so for each string for
each character in these
pairs how many possibilities for each
one if this is
n times two okay this is n times two
that's the string yeah so n times two so
for each one
for each one what's the
how many possibilities two right what
are those two
they
what are those two strings we need to
try here
the uh wait wait
what was it again don't know what but in
the bracket
right sorry so the bracket how many
possibilities for each
each character it's two two yeah only
two
okay opening bracket and small closing
bracket okay opening
opening parenthesis or closing
parentheses yeah yeah
each one is two two possibilities so if
they are n times two slots
what's the how many possibilities of all
these uh
the string if if there are n times two
slots
and each slot contains two possibilities
so what's the overall
and well
how do we do
[Music]
sorry n equals one two n equals two
how many possibilities here are two here
are two
yeah and how many three how many
possibilities six
two four one what's next come on eight
eight yes and so
of two of t two to the power of two
times
n yeah that's the length yeah definitely
kind of bigger
yeah and remember we take enemies n
o n time all right to check if it's the
uh a string is the very
parenthesis right yeah it's i know we
need to times what
two times n because the length is two
times n
right so but we can drop the constant
right
look we can drop this constant so o the
overall complexity is o
n times two to the power of two times n
right
okay that's a lot yeah yes that's a lot
okay so so what's the problem of this
one
it is two why is this low because
we know the beginning the beginning
can it be a closing bracket
if it if it's if it's start with a
closing bracket
it's definitely not that's the problem
yeah so we know in some cases we already
know that no matter
what kind of the possibilities come
afterwards
it's still uh invalid
parentheses right yeah so there's no way
look how many possibilities are these
there are a lot right
but once we have we know it's a closing
parenthesis do we need to generate all
of those and check again again no right
so we are because we are wasting time
here let's put for thing right
so we can use the backtracking which is
the default search
definite search and then we don't
continue
exploring the path if
we found out that the current
current settings do not lead to a valid
configurations right
do not need uh configure to current
configuration do not need
to not lead to valid solutions
right now we don't spend time doing that
now we're just backtracking yeah
backtracking what's backtracking
backtracking um backtracking
yeah so in order to do this
we can define the function yeah okay
let's do this define
define what let's say uh let's
let's call it therefore search right
search okay then we obviously outside we
have this answer
we answer equals the bracket thing
the list of empty solutions and now we
need to
remember we need to remember the current
the current solution the current color
string current
current part of the valid parenthesis
string so we call it current right and
then
open the current number of opening
processes
and then closing parentheses yes closing
okay okay so look
so at the beginning
and at the beginning we want to call
this function with empty
yeah because currently we uh at the
beginning we don't
know we don't generate any parenthesis
at all right
and now we shall pass with the second
parameter answer parameters
and closing what's the what's the number
of the opening and closing
opening at the beginning do we have any
no so what's the number what you put
here is it right yes yellow opening and
zero closing okay
okay now if the length of current
okay if this string yeah alright look at
me
no the length if the current length is
equals n times
n plus n what does it mean
[Music]
is that technically yeah n times two
then
this is the value parenthesis right yeah
then we can answer a pen a pen
current right yeah does it make sense
the default search if we if if we
already
know uh
actually actually there is something
here if
if the current string has to
has has the length of left
to n we still need to check
if what then we can append it
answer the append
current can you tell me what it is is
what
between closing opening and closing
one opening work closing
for a very princesses opening
opening and closing what are the smaller
what
for a very apprenticeship i'm saying for
ready parentheses what's the relation
number of the parentheses yeah equal
right yeah if the length
is is the final length right
yeah if we want to generate three three
pairs
three pairs of very premises and the
length
is six right that's what it means the
length is six
now we need to check if they are three
yeah if it's there three opening or
three closing right and three closing
another way of doing this is if opening
equals
n n and what
and what closing equal as well
if opening equals ends closing equals
one come on opening
sorry opening equals closing another way
of writing this is if opening equals m
and currency equals one
come on opening n
n come on open the equal sign and
closing percent right
it's the same thing as opening equals
closing because the
length is n plus n right right corner
okay column good job okay so now
if not like we have we can we need to
return here right because the length is
already
maximum length yeah there's no point to
continue
look if what this is the condition
if in what cases i can search for
current plus uh opening bracket
and then open plus one and closing
in what cases okay so this means i want
to try
next one with the opening bracket
right so in what cases yeah yeah i know
but for in what cases i can try the next
one as open and bracket
if if if
if the opening is smaller than the
closing
why no no in what cases i can put an
opening
no okay another one here
you think about if what and i can try
the closing
current plus clothing closing
open i know what you're gonna put here
closing
closing one and
one yeah okay oh yeah
okay so in what cases i i can pull
let's try this if this here
there are two openings and two is
closing here right can i put the
clothing here
[Music]
why is that white
and can i put a closing here you need to
put uh
opening right yeah but i cannot follow
closing when
i cannot put the closing when the number
the opening is what is smaller or equal
than closing them right does it make
sense
then how can you just compare it
[Music]
no no what i'm saying is the current is
equal left
and i can put a cup opening that's for
sure yeah in any cases i can always
start with the opening there's only one
condition i cannot start with the
opening why is that
how many max how many what's the maximum
number of opening can we
can we generate in this particular case
all of them
what what's the maximum
the number no n yeah yeah
okay so if opening one
if opening is a smaller end
yeah if opening is smaller than
obviously i can do this right it's
nothing to do with the closing right
because at any point i can start with
the opening all right
yes can you find an example that i
cannot start with the opening
yeah right now all right are you all
right
okay for this closing how can we do this
closing
i mean if the opening
what
i think what it's not closing
yeah so in what cases we can start with
the closing er
if if open and close
what condition is open
bigger yes y is bigger if open is bigger
than
closing then we can do the closing here
yeah look if there are two open
and one closing i can start with the
closing yeah
all right yes yeah oh
if if they look if open is close equal
to the club
then i cannot start with the club right
because as long as i start with the
clothes but
the balance will fall below yellow
you'll be negative so you ready right
correct yeah okay so in this case we can
just do this
so it will be a lot faster than the
proof of thing yeah
the time complexity for this one is a
bit tricky okay you don't need to
it's out of scope right it's huge is
uh yeah it's very complex it's
4 to the power n divided by square n
yeah it's quite complicated it's
mathematic
is the it's roughly the
the catalan number c2n
yeah so it's quite from there i can talk
about this the other day okay
but this is far better than far better
than
than than what then what's the beginning
to the power of two n times n right yeah
this
is far better than this one okay because
this one
yeah times is exponential look this is
exponential yeah
yeah why this is better can you can you
explain
daddy like why this is better because
the time
complexity yeah and why this has a
better time complexity
i will have faster time contexting
because
because if it begins with a
closing bracket it you know immediately
if it's not valid then we don't need to
try right
so for this one is that we don't
generate all possibilities but for the
first approach a proof of thing
how how does it work we generate all
possibilities and we check each
possibility right
let's take forever right that's going to
take a much much longer time
then we generate only generate the
parenthesis when there's a potential to
be a valid parenthesis
when we start when we start with these
closing
parenthesis there's no way to generate
all kinds of
possibilities here right because no
matter what kind of
configuration here this setting
does not d does not give you a very
parenthesis right
i'm right so you save lots of time here
right
it's like it's like a final tree right
it's like a binary so what does it mean
look
at the beginning at the beginning here
nothing here
you can generate uh open parenthesis
you can generate a closing practices but
here we don't need to do this right
because
basically these branches we don't need
to explore but here opening
bracket can we generate the opening okay
yes
can we generate a closing bracket yes
and here do we can we generally open
bracket yes can we generate closing
bracket
no right right look at this this branch
this
literally subtree yeah we just don't
visit it
yeah we save time here right you see
let's
the therefore search proof was in
definition is try to visit
every branch right and the black
tracking
is what it's a definite search but i
don't
visit those useless branch all right
let's go back
at uh backtracking okay all right
yeah yeah because i i just found out
it's usually visiting here and then why
should i keep visiting here right
i can just go to the very branches all
right
okay so that's it for today thank you
see you
bye bye oh bye bye