okay you can say hello
i'm bad so today we're going to talk uh
another
remember yesterday we talked about this
quick quick start right
and today i talked about something else
yeah yeah that's okay it's okay
we talked today we're going to learn
about merchandise
like important random this is it yeah
can you tell me what happened what is
do you still remember a few days ago we
talked about how to merge two salted
leaves remember
yeah look at it look at here yeah
and at least one two yeah
another list maybe one three another is
two four
one emergent so what we get
one two three four yeah that's easy
easy remember we talked if these two
are salted yeah both both these things
yeah both leaves are salted then we can
compare right the smallest
yeah now that's only smallest one yeah
and i move here
it's two smaller than three yes than my
two here and then move here
three four you see i don't understand
yeah you get
it yeah okay so this is how you get it
okay what the monster
[Music]
if it's the number one three five right
another is two four six
these two lists are sorted they are in
order right one smaller than three five
yeah one
and two four six are increasing yeah so
what we do is that
left hand right hand when we compare the
value
of what left hand and right hand is one
smaller than two
yeah okay so if smaller one and two then
i
i picked one i push it into the pull of
one here yeah
and i move it here move the left hand
here i need
two and smaller than three yes
yes two smaller than three now we push
the two here
right right yes yes
do you get it can you go to the left
please do you get it
two and three two smaller right and i
put it two here then i move here
and three and four three smaller right
yes then i put a three here and then
move the three
move the left one here and the five and
four four is smaller
yeah and then move here yeah five and
six
yeah 26 and then that's 5 and then 96 do
you get it so
if there are two subsidies i can do this
by oh
oh uh o and m right this is rap
right if this is a this is b and the
complexities of a plus b
okay and this is the review of the
merging two sausages
can we sit down please please what do we
talk about
how to be a good boy during the class
doing
lessons
[Music]
listen to me so what how does that help
look if if we know two lists are
already sorted then we can do this this
way right how
then we can we can so our task is to
divide the list and all the lists
into a small pieces and then logic back
look if these are this like look
if two four five
six one and
three okay you will have six numbers all
right
ryan sit down if you have six numbers
away yes i am you are looking you're not
looking okay
if you have six months okay now we want
to solve this make this saudi
yeah so how do we do this we first
seventy
three four five six yes my computer we
can do this look
we can divide this into two right
we have two equal parts yeah yeah two
equal parts
then we we saw this if we can make this
sort
and make this sorted then we can use
remember the merge
function yeah remember with the merge
function
yeah to merge these two parts right yeah
yes so in order to solve this we again
we
stop we partition this into half right
okay do you get it okay
we position this into half
so it could yeah yeah i know it could be
you can put it this way it doesn't
have to because three numbers you can
equally be two parts but
how about it let's do it this way okay
do this way
okay now this one number it's already
sauteed yeah we don't need to saute it
now we want to make this sauteed yeah
already salted
but we don't but we have to put it into
two pieces
now two is salty four is started all
right
so then i use these to merge this into
two
right eleven two four fourteen and two
four
seven and five magic
sorry sausage do you
and three are understand salted
don't worry when is salted when this
when this bit salted is one three six
yeah
right and one one three six and two four
five
merge it remember remember the
multifunction
yes remember we talked about left leg
and we can merge it
do you see the point yeah okay another
example another example
ryan are you listening ellen
that's enough okay that is talking okay
please
ryan whoa
okay look look
so the first so so look
three two one
six how do we solve these four numbers
easy what do three things i know how do
we solve a computer look
first of all divide it into two two
pieces two pieces yeah
and then these two pieces
put it into half so these four pieces
are already sorted by their own right if
we merge these two
we have two three if we merge these two
there will be one
six and how about we merge two three and
one six then will become one
two three six so so
you see how we get it we divide
and solve each part yeah divide and
solidify
divide and conquer right
okay so let's try to write a
code okay so let's try to go
the code is important
let's skip the first plate which is the
much tooth to list okay
or we can come up later like
if we want to merge merge to list a and
b
yeah a and b what am i missing here
column
okay yeah babe okay now
if you are taking a parameter much merge
and ray
we imagine array okay so let's start
with this bit first
if we merge this array uh much saw this
array okay
to make it simpler so much salt to salt
multi sauce
merge thought okay
so now we need to check if the lens
yeah if it's smaller than even what
if it's nothing if the element is
nothing empty or it's one element it's
already sorted right all right
it's already sorted
array all right
so we return return array right if it's
already one element we return it right
okay so now we need to find the middle
path right
look we need we need to find the middle
part to
to split to the least
into too hard right yes so now we take
the middle half equals length
this is length length
and divided by two right yeah
divided by two okay now the first half
the left
the left half look now we have an array
this is array yeah
and we have calculated the middle part
yeah and then
we want to solve this anyway can you
look at daddy please
but you know what you're walking can you
sit down and look at me okay
okay you already know the left part and
the right part okay
what am i writing now you already know
okay so left left now the left part
equals this ar we are we are doing it
until the meat right yeah
so now this is the left is this one yeah
this is that right so
what what so right right
mid column it means
start some meat and then this part okay
and now
we have the right arrow left hand what
what we are doing now
we call it sort much so functions to
solve these two parts right
so so we are calling these two functions
right
left equals that right equals that then
we need to sort
much salt
merge salt arr left
because we are sorting the left bit and
we assign it to
we can assign it to left as well and
right
equals multi-thought
right so now these two bits are already
in order
now what we need to do
left and right right
okay so you you get it did you get it
yes yeah do you get it that's one do you
get it
look so uh
there's an array right it's a list a
number a few numbers
like that yeah no no no
look at daddy
listen ryan listen okay i am
okay listen do you don't get me look
and at least
so i want to sort at least a few numbers
so first step divide it into half yeah
and then my soul is stupid once these
are thoughts
so so i'm here and we do recursively and
dividing partitioning this array into
smaller b smaller smaller and here it
becomes only one element of nothing yeah
one is only one element it's already
sorted right i give you a number i say
it's salty
am i right it is right yes if i give you
a number of three
i said is it sauteed yes yes of course
it's not one number it's not it's in the
right place
if we started and then if we have two
otherwise when we have this uh
already sorted part if that this one
number is sorted there
and this number is sort uh is
sorted then what we do we merge it
remember we have mu
we know how to merge two sorted list
right
we know this i'm matching yes
so when you merge it you can merge it
merge it
to into a bigger path all right
okay so now okay let's review how to
how to i know right now look
we we are calling the merge here which
is not implemented here right
yeah but this is the important part
merge
one two into one two right yes
okay let's buy this merge let's like
review it
we we know how to do this a few days ago
right let's write it again okay
look and you correct me if i'm wrong
very much
a b column yeah i didn't did that
yeah merge a b 9 1 we need to get the i
three pointing to the beginning of both
yeah what are we doing
most two searches remember no
i don't certainly i
j l a l b equals
zero zero length air a
length b right so this is just two
two or two solid list you have to sort
this
one three five two four six and we're
gonna
put this into one two three four five
six yes
okay now why
i smaller than what y smaller than y
is
[Music]
why these two pointers are the end now
we need to compare if
a i is smaller than b
b j right
it's okay if a if one element is smaller
than the other one
yeah then i picked the smaller one right
yeah so another one
uh let's put a result here with
results here then
result append
a i ask
reserve dot append
bj right and you need to
plus equals one move the pointer to the
forward yeah move the smaller pointer to
to the bigger one okay and then what's
next
and then and what's that when we when
one reaches the end the other may not
finish
right so we need to compare the size if
i
smaller than aira then we
append we can plus equals
plus equals the next
yeah which is a
i it means from the current position to
the end
as i s plus equal b
j yeah and then return with desire
got it all right yeah
you see this is beautiful aquarium right
so the complexity is o and longer and
similar to quicksort remember we talked
about quick saw yesterday yeah
it's the similar complexity okay any
questions
okay so do you want to say goodbye