[Music]
today we'll talk about binary the weight
the weight maximum weight maximum risk
okay so by number three you already know
by mystery yeah the notes
final three is one of the graphs yes
graph
like how many notes can how many
children can the note have
two maximum yeah maximum yeah what
exactly what are you about to say okay
so the
let's define it look at that okay let's
do it
so it is nothing let's define the width
the next the width is the lever
for level is the distance between
the left left mouse note and the right
most note
okay and we're going to find the maximum
width which is the maximum
width of all levels yeah so for example
how many
how many the distance between one
leftmost no one and one is zero right
because
it's just one note right for the first
level yeah all right
that is the level two the number one
what's the distance
uh two two right because
there are two yeah two yeah and how many
notes can you
the distance between the notes in level
three
so you can put the one now here and the
most for yeah one two three four yeah
okay and
okay so if i have another note here so
what's the difference between this and
this
interesting yeah
[Music]
what's the difference between this and
this
three that's right yeah
so it's like that yeah you see
here another two yeah okay
so one one two three four
five six seven
yeah so you can squeeze all the nose
there
but then i know we want to calculate the
distance
needs to be including the the leftmost
note and the rightmost note okay
so given these how do we calculate it i
mean
what's that how many ways of invisible
knives yeah yeah how many ways
are we going to uh can we do to
traverse the binary
and how do we actually break through the
preferences
[Music]
level by level and what kind of data
structure are we going to use to
implement weapon search
we want to use the
what kind of data structure do we need
to implement the process search
queue what's q
i like a thingy
first out first thing okay fifa and
in python uh we are using what kind of
the
data structure i mean what kind of the
function class are we going to use
to improve to declare a queue what is
this dq okay what's that landed
[Music]
yeah because i asked that question a lot
yeah so let me answer thank you
so it was a and over again
just to test you okay come on guys uh
so let's uh how can we use the breakfast
search to
calculate the distance uh okay
so how can we do this we in order to
find the distance we
one way of doing this is that we need to
have a way to calculate that
coordinate yeah let's say that
coordinate
of the left most and the right mode
right all right
and we can find out that the right most
for a note
if this is this is parent
that the closing difference between its
left and right
is what is what
how many notes are i mean right next to
it right
yeah okay so if we define the way of
these
then we know that the right note is plus
one of the left note right yeah
so one way of doing this is if we go to
the
left what do we do
we can multiply by two yeah if this is
zero
we can times zero here right it's still
zero right here is one
and you times two here is two all right
does it make sense okay let's take an
example like uh let's say
easy one okay let's say if we want to
if you want to calculate the distance
between five and four
okay if we want to find the difference
right and i alright yeah look this is
zero
this is what this times two
times t zero zero zero and here is zero
right times too much of at one this is
what
one okay if i turn if what's the value
of this
i mean if i times two this is times two
if i have no here that would be two
right
times two here will be two right and
then here
what was that times 2 plus 1
3 3 okay so i know this is 3
and this is 0 so the distance is what 3
minus zero plus one
so like can we verify it yeah
okay yeah so look you can have four
right
so this initial value doesn't matter can
we do use the one here
one here okay let's do this one
times two is two right two times two
is four right two times four
four plus one right five right one times
two
plus one is for three yeah
yeah three times two six
and that's seven so seven
minus four plus one equals one
okay so it's it's okay yeah the initial
value so look yeah if
it goes to the left you multiply by two
if it goes to the right
you multiply by two plus one right does
it make sense
okay so in this case in this case
we we can do this uh buffer search
and then exploring the nodes of the same
level
at once yeah and each one
at each level we can we can know the
distance between the leftmost node and
the rightmost and when we expanding the
uh children into the next level we if
it's the left node we multiply by two if
it's a right node we multiply by two
and one and one
plus one and plus one yeah that's it
okay let's do this
let's do this coding
define max with
me good okay
if it's an empty tree what's the answer
of the
what's the answer yeah
okay and then q equals
dq and at the beginning we need to put a
root
in and then the initial value let's put
a one okay or zero
okay let's put it one okay i could be
better
okay okay all right
[Music]
so can you tell me how do we implement
how to implement the breakfast search we
need to check
when there are notes when
how do we check how do we implement the
breakfast search we are the beginning of
the room
yeah so at what condition we how how do
we do this
how how do we usually implement a
perfect search here
yeah i know so we put the root in and
then
and then what's next then
we take a luna out and we'll put the
kids in right
okay so here what should we like here
what we do
at the beginning when are we asked uh
when are we terminating the brexit
search when do we
stop doing the process search when do we
stop doing the process search
okay why kill what does the wire kill me
well the key keeps on while q
is is what it's not what why there's no
in the queue what q is not empty right
yeah okay and then how many
y cube is not empty so count the note
common notes in the queue
uh belongs to the same level yeah yeah
so how many notes are there in the cube
at the moment
one yeah i know but how can we do this s
z
equals one what so for is
or any variable equals one what cube
a function length of key yeah the length
of q
and then here at the beginning we need
to say that make
the lesson right let's say l and r at
the beginning the left
is the negative infinity right
negative infinity and number
i is one r is one
the primer is what the bible is what
uh even here
i minus math okay so
so we have the left boundary right
boundary set to infinity at the
beginning
and then what should we do four we need
to
because they're currently okay okay
let's do this that's pretty
end okay they are currently n nodes in
the current level yeah for
underscore in range let's repeat anytime
right right
okay and then let's call it current
let's call it c
c and then this this is what this is the
value yeah value
equal as one let's pop it c and v c
is the root v is the value so what
should i do q dot one
pop one top left yeah because we are
taking the note from the beginning of
the q
it's popular right if the evil is pop
what does it mean
if it's just pop what does it mean
taking notes from which side
pop leg is from the left side and pop is
along which side
right what's dq mean
okay then pop left is taking notes from
the left side and you'll
take it from the right side yeah
that's what i mean yeah okay so we take
the notes from the left side
and then what should we do
what do we do we should update the l and
i yeah air
equals one the left hand side is what
mean of l and v right and can you tell
me
i equals one i equals one
now max max
what
we want to update that yeah yeah yeah
you're right yeah
and then now if c dot left
then let's know so what should we do q
dot
append option one
and the value so what should we do
q dot one no no rule the common number
is c
okay and then here is c c to the right
okay so c to the left and then what
see the left what's this value kyoda
appen
see the right and what
come on the value if we go to the left
what happened what happened to the value
v
times t v times two and if you go to the
right what happens
is three plus one times two plus one
okay and after this we have updated the
f and right
and the answer let's call it our answer
answer here equals zero okay
so answer equals next
answer and what what
and then return what come on
yeah we we we now
okay so at this level we know the l and
r
the left and right so what's the width
of that
level with which this level so here are
a node and here is
air here's r uh what's the level what's
the distance
all right mine plus one you need to
transfer that
yeah okay because look if two and three
what's the distance is three plus minus
two plus one is
two right it's not one right got it
i'm right yeah okay so r minus
r minus a plus one and then we want to
we want to keep record the maximum
right of the whis answer and return one
awesome
written answer okay so look lr
at the beginning is the infinity and now
we're expanding the endnote of the
current level right
by expanding the nodes we up we use this
v
right we use the v to update the l and
right right all right yes all right
mean equal
yes actually
this is opposite right this is opposite
right because the left left you want to
be the maximum
and right you want to be the minimum so
air will be the
minimum of error right yeah i equals
maximum of e
right am right because ah the r boundary
right boundary at the beginning is
negative infinity so any number will be
bigger than negative infinity yeah so
these these two statements are
going to update the left and right
boundaries yeah
and then if they are the left nodes we
explain the node we insert the nodes
into the back of the key which is a pen
right yeah
what's the what's the if i want to
you know this is dq a pen is append this
this direction at the back i want to put
it at the beginning
what's that apparent what depending the
left
yeah open left okay that's why it means
double ndq
and then we it's following the left
notes and right now
at the back of the back of the queue
and then we after these four we are
finishing
expanding the nodes in the same level
and then now we know the r
and l air are in there and we can
compute
the width of that level and then we keep
answer is the
maximum level of maximum weight of
all levels this is the answer we're
looking for right what's the time
complexity
what's n number
yeah because we're using the kiwi okay
yeah times convexity because we need to
visit
each node once right yeah all right if
we have n nodes in the
final tree we need to visit each node
once am right
yes does it make sense yeah
okay
[Music]
what's these two come on you see it
what's this i did not
so we we are expanding like we are
popping that
the key uh the element from q we need to
update l and r
yeah a air equals what
yes the left equals one
you we want to update the l the left
boundary of the
v okay that equals one
yeah i mean mean we want to get the mean
value
mean of what and that one is the max
yeah
yeah wow yes
yeah we want to update the add we
which two values come on think about it
it's easy
v yeah v and
it's not that bad okay it's easy okay
okay that's it for today
say bye bye bye bye bye
that's it