hello hello
hello miss lorraine how are you today
good what did we talk about yesterday
oh we talked about the win we were
baptized we use our binary tree and we
use the questions
yeah we we when we're exploring the
notes
in the next level yeah the notes are in
the queue
we is exploring all the notes in the
queue
as the next level we we can compute the
distance between the leftmost node and
rightmost now how do we compute the
distance if we go to the left node what
happens
we times two and to the right we time t
and plus one yeah so oh yeah we go to
the left we double it
we go to the right we add one double
edged one
good
so today we're going to use the
different search okay definitely using
the stack
people search stack usually
okay we're using that as usually
so in order to do this surface search
we need to visit the nodes right within
a node
and when when we visit the nodes we need
to store the level
as the keys and the values the value
will be the v
and we update the v in the dictionary
right
so we have a data like data
the keys keys of the data will be
the level right and the values will be
a list of two values which has the
what the left and right okay and we keep
updating these two values
all right so can you tell me what
defines define let's do the define let's
implement define therefore search what
kind of parameters do we need
second minute what what kind of
parameters do we read
when we go to the left tree
when we go to the left tree what
happened to the
times so if we go to the next tree
what what can what three values do i
need to give
if we go to the left lu will become one
we go to the become one yeah and then v
will become one the v will be times
two yeah a level will become what that
will become
uh plus one plus one okay and we go to
the right do
do do one right
and what happened to the v v times t
plus one
and what happened to a level level plus
one where that
and then we know least then we can we
can say
if if the level if the first time
the if the key the level key is not
existent in the data dictionary what
happened what does it mean it means that
we all we visited the this note on the
first time on
this level then we
[Music]
how would we get to the same character
again
what do you think saying i is
not same note okay why do we need to go
back to the same note again
yeah no this is the one no at once
that's the definition
yeah okay so the first time
if the level is not in the in the data
what does it mean
we visit this the first time now we need
to set up key
data level equals what lr
equals vv okay
if if the lever is in
level in do uh in data level what does
it mean
we already seen the level before then we
need to update the level with the
compared to column v yeah right okay and
at the end at the end at the end this
data will
contain something like okay levels
yellow level zero
the left will be zero the light will be
zero level one the left will be maybe
glo y will be two right level two maybe
the left will be zero
right will be five so we want to
calculate
the maximum of this yeah y minus r
is if always go to the left because if
you put a zero here it goes to the left
it will be zero times two will be zero
right
oh yeah and then we want to find out
that maximum distance between
the values yeah so we can say return
next r
minus air plus one for l r in
theta dot one theta dot one
keys of values keys keys is this one
come on
various values is this one okay i keep
saying
key yeah data key key key is that
the level right the level can you stop
moving
okay let's try this
please
[Music]
if not good if not
return zero yeah
yellow yeah okay
okay listen like we have this data
as i said how do you define a dictionary
can you tell me how do you define the
teaching
decision right how do you differentiate
curly brace yeah or you can do this all
you can do
this this also works all d4
okay but the easiest way is to do this
curly brace it means that
it's addition what's this key value
pairs okay
key value pairs yeah like like theta
area equals eight theta ryan equals
seven okay we talked about this before
and then
what did define
therefore search what what's what's the
what's the parameters
how many parameters uh root value
and level
column okay if not root
if not no means that if rule is empty or
if you look
just return you is to leave empty when
we can
okay now we've got this level here
so if level as i said if level
in data what does it mean if we have
visited this before right
right then then what theta
the level right look this is the key
value
zero let's say yellow is the left
right one is the main uh the right okay
equals what the max zero zero
would be the left you could be mean
right mean
data level
zero and what's the second parameters
[Music]
v v and then theta
level what one
one yeah equals max theta
level one and one
v yeah because we are updating the left
and right okay
okay if else what does it mean if it
goes to here else what does it mean
it means that we have not visited the
first term right so we have to set it
data
level every l
equals the thing equals one we put a
value
two values two values what are those
values
value value and one
what if the first time we visited what's
the left and right
we have this v what's the difference
yeah very very good
okay and now we got this value and then
we want to go to the left yeah
definitely
[Music]
and what happened to the v time stay
what happened to the liver plus one
that was actually the right v times t
plus one level
first one ah times two one plus one
four one plus one that's why i said
okay okay and then now after we call
this yeah versus at the beginning what's
the we call it with the loot
what's the v at the beginning it doesn't
matter yeah zero one yeah remember zero
okay and what's the level zero yes you
know what actually it doesn't matter you
can put a one one right
return okay this is the best part yeah
we ten one
maximum i want to put an r
minus l plus one yeah
four l r in
in one theta theta dot one
eight other one values yeah the keys are
what are the keys what what are the keys
first thing what are keys here what are
the keys here
come on one lucky flavor the values are
two
and a list of two elements yeah the left
and right okay
the left and right are missing it here
okay so
so um does it make sense
you got two rubbers
so um okay yeah
come on come on what happened this is
the first time we visited so what should
we do with that
what's your assignment yeah
[Music]
no no theta is the dictionary but which
level is it you need to give a key
yeah data breaking bracket what
what the first term look at
the two lines above data level zero
equal what one
never yeah level and the first time
what's the left
and right value bracket equals what
because equals
and look because here data is defined in
the scope of this
in the scope of this function and inside
we have another in
inside function in inline function which
is going to use the data so as here
we need to say a keyword what's this we
in order to use these
inside this function we have to give it
a qr can you tell me where it is
if you're not spacing this keyword the
data you will say okay
the computer will think this data is
inside this function but which is we
haven't declared
we want to tell the computer this data
we actually mean
it's the data here right so we need to
give it a
keyword which is non legal
yeah yeah because this date we said this
third data is non-local and if we do not
know the way it is
it's here right that's what it means
okay
okay that's good job today good job
today say bye bye
bye bye