[Music]
me okay
what's factor if f i f
i is a factorial number okay so for
example one factorial equals
one factor exclamation mark one
two factorial three three four six
four factorial twenty-four five bacteria
one hundred and twenty
okay so what are we doing here why why
is this we just
times it one and then one time two then
one time two then three then one
okay so f i equals i times
i minus one times what i minus two
and two another
one yeah and we can say f i equals
i times f y
remember in the first step we talk about
this equation f i equals i times one
f1 i subtract
one yeah so the f1 the
terminal condition is f1 equals one
right yeah
and f0 is also what the zero factorial
is also one okay this is a special case
yeah
yeah okay and zero factorial is one one
factor okay
look this is very important okay
okay so now if i wanted to take
uh okay so i raised a little bit too
fast so look
the first for you is 1 2
6 24 120
720 okay so
can you notice that if i have a
factorial
like 720 200 720 it's
always bigger than the previous
factorial sum right
right look it's always bigger than 100
20 plus 24 plus six percent
and 24 is always bigger than the
previous number
120 is always bigger than the previous
factorial sum all right
two is bigger than previous time six is
bigger than one plus two am right
yeah okay okay why why is that look
we can prove this okay we can prove this
f i f
i plus one equals
i plus 1 times f
i right yeah we already know that right
yeah and this is b bigger than
i times f i right yeah
look f i is a positive number
times i plus one times it's always
bigger than times i times i'm right
yeah okay this one okay so i
comes fi what does it mean is equals to
they are how many times of f i
uh how many i times f i
how many times are f i i yeah so that
will be
f i plus f i plus
f i plus f so there are
i terms of this i comes this right
yeah item solids
okay so this look if i write it another
way look the sum
of the first first i minus one
um okay so the sum okay so let's say
here we have this f i
plus f i minus 1 right
look at plus f i minus 2 plus
2i so listing this thing equals what
this is the sum of the first i items
right
all right so what we can use this yeah
this is the sum sum f
j j equals y side
yeah yeah area so this symbol is j
equals 1 to i
okay so you can play you can think of it
as a 4
4 j equals 1
to i inclusion and i will i want to sum
f j
so it's equal to f i f i minus 1
plus f minus 2 right
yeah so that
i times of what actually this is f
i okay yeah
this is f5 fj was like sum of fi so
which one is bigger
these and this which one is bigger which
one which one is bigger
these are these which one is bigger
yeah these items and this one yeah of
course look
this is equal but this is bigger than
that this is bigger than that so it's
bigger
and so what does it mean so f i plus 1
is always bigger
this is bigger than the sum of its
previous
right we just prove it yeah cut it
yeah yeah okay so remember this okay
remember
this is very important then in in the
thing we're going to talk
now okay so now
okay let's try this first few again okay
one two
six twelve uh
no six one twenty four
a hundred twenty and seven hundred sixty
seven hundred and twenty okay okay so if
i give you a number
like 31 can you represent as a sum of
the distinct what's this thing
this thing this thing this thing or
unique yeah it's distinct
this thing like dinosaurs
31 can you represent as the sum
of the factorial number but each number
you can only use one that's what i mean
this thing
and most one 24 6 one
wow okay oh yeah so yeah you can
in this case you can tell me yes okay
how about four
nine why is that you can't use two twice
or use one four times well done so
at least it's not yeah because two we
are using twice okay another one
is uh 144.
120 and 24. oh yeah
okay okay so how can you tell me so
quickly
how can you tell me so quickly what's
your approach to tourism
so yeah you know what
how can you tell me so quickly what's
your approach to
so which one you which number you need
to try first
the biggest the biggest yeah yeah and
then you always take the biggest one
if possible yeah yeah okay okay
can we do it from the smallest can we
just take it from the smallest
[Music]
look why look take this 31 for example
can you do it from the smallest
one two
and what's next six six and what's next
twenty-four you can't put the terminal
yeah so you know you
so you in this case it doesn't work you
risk
the chance of using the the bigger
number bigger factor
right that's what it means yeah so we
always take the
biggest one because if we can take this
one
it means that we can we cannot
if we take this one means unique because
the
this sum is bigger this is bigger than
the previous yeah
okay yeah got it so that works yeah
because i take 24 i know
the previous numbers cannot sum up to 24
yeah
all right but if you take this morning
this number
like this you reach the chance of using
the 24 right
because you already use the smaller
numbers am i right okay
okay
we can also use the default search right
because look
this is a a kind of nasa problem and
that's it what's next
now yeah nap stack
is a type of like sack that you snap in
neptune
okay so these are the options candidates
the numbers
i know we can each one we can choose
pick or not pick right
yeah if we pick it we go to the next one
we've saw this problem before yeah
so we want to example we want to take
each item
at most one so we can for each item we
can choose pick or not pick
pick pick and not until we get a
uh 31 okay this is one approach we can
talk about this tomorrow okay but today
we're going to implement this one
yeah and this one okay yeah
so in order to do this what do we need
to do
at the beginning in in order to do this
again what do we need to do
we do what do we need to do what are we
doing here
we need to do what what do we need to do
here
we need to uh stay the ones which are
smaller
but yeah what's smaller
than we can subtract okay so but in
order to do that
at the very beginning what do we need to
do we need to
calculate the saturn right right and
obviously we need to put it in at least
there and we can try from the
largest if we if we don't calculate it
it'll be hard right
we need to know these numbers but that
will be easier
let's do this
let's say define a sum
of factorial okay fact okay
at the beginning what what is the eagle
at the beginning
the numbers is this the right
i mean list list bracket yeah at least
okay at the beginning third at the
beginning is the first one is one
and and
okay and then we want to multiply by x x
equals one okay so y
fact is smaller or equal n
times times equals x and now what should
we do with the fact
what should we do with the fact uh
we put it in the list yeah yeah
so what can you tell me what's like uh
append
nam start a pen come on numbs open
okay and what's next we have final fact
and what what's next
what happened to x x equals x plus one x
plus one okay
let's equal one yeah x equals 1
3 times 1 is 1 and we put 1 in the list
and then x equals 2
and we times f x equals
2 right put the 2 in the list and 2
times x
plus equals one is three two times three
yeah you got it i don't put it in the
list alarms
okay now i want to start from the
beginning uh
the largest one so for
i a in range
what should i put here there are three
parameters
start from the beginning the right
monster the rightmost
element is what -1
yeah but what are we trying to do here
the numbers the numbers here
the numbers is 1 2
6 24 120. yeah look
that's numbs nums always will be here
will be this one and what what are we
trying to do here
what should we try first we shall try
the biggest
120 so what what's the index of these
what's the index of these minus one
what number why what minus one length
length function num
minus one and then at the end we want to
go here right
right we want to reach here yeah but we
need to give the
one position to the left what's what's
the end minus one
i know what's the step if you go to the
left what's this one
yeah one column
okay okay if n is
bigger or equal
what should we do if this number 120 is
bigger than 120
what should we do what should we do what
should we do
if we look if look before it is 144
right
if it now is 120 what should we do with
that like this number
n minus m
minus equals nums i
i okay that's it and then and then at
the end if you come to if it goes
through these
already and what should we check if the
number is one
if n equals yeah okay
okay okay what's the time complexity
it's very tricky this one
what's the time conversion what's the
time complex
you can say oh anything of anything
oh let's say oh let's say oh ammo okay
what's emu
[Music]
yeah so this bit what's the animal here
what's
what's these numbers here yeah what's
these numbers
factories the number of factorial that
are small or bigger than n
yeah small bigger than n smaller yeah
okay so m
is the number of factorial that are
smaller that is smaller than
n right right yeah if it's in this range
like 2 to the power of 31 right
if this 32 bit integer if it's a sun
it's the up to these minus one yeah so
it's
it's almost 12 12 actually
distinct bacteria yeah we are excluding
the zero factor
there are 12 distinct factors that are
smaller
than this number yeah okay so if it is
the case
we know it's the number is fixed that
the time and space complexity is what
one come on
one or one yeah because i just told you
if that there only 12.
so here at most 12 iteration and here
almost 12 12 iteration okay that's a one
in both space and complex times space
complexity but if i tell you n
is absolutely large number then you need
to tell me o
m where m is the number of the bacterias
that is smaller yeah
that is smaller than n okay all right
that's it for today oh that's it for
today you can say bye bye
goodbye bye bye bye