go hello hello mr mr ryan how are you
today
good day what have we talked about
yesterday remember
we taught about uh the
lower the factorial oh yeah we talked
about the factorial thing
okay so can you remind me okay so what
is the factorial sum
one zero factorial equals one i one one
factorial
one factorial equal one two factorial
two
if i keep your number like 31 can you
tell me what
it's possible to use the issue possible
what's this thing mean a unique unique
okay this thing unique uh
so for the 31 can we use this thing
yes and what are those uh
uh one six twenty four
one plus six plus twenty five and how
how are we
what's our price okay so we just uh uh
uh replacing and so we are doing
we are showing the one yeah you like
that which which
that 31 can subtract by
and then we are subtracting the biggest
as possible
so okay 31. 24. and then okay so
we took minus 34 which would give us
seven
and then and minus six yeah six and then
one we have one okay yeah okay but not
not here
because there are two ones we just need
one okay
and so what's the term complexity of
this agreement
let me try this one what's the term
complexity for this one
i don't think it's the you called it
and what's um your thing but
like this bit yes the number of
factorials
that distinct factors that are smaller
or equal
than n right okay okay
so look if we if we have this
distinct in fisting the factorial number
saying okay this is the list of the
numbers we have 1 2 6 624 120
and 720 okay and
we have uh we we know we are given the
number like
144. 144.
so so literally this is
not like a knife problem okay so these
are the items these are the weight of
each item
and then yes one yeah i know i know
but yeah too heavy yeah you are right
too heavy so this is the capacity of the
back
yeah and this is the item for each uh
this is the item the weight of the items
yeah so
the the question becomes that can we
find
can we fill the bag the nutsack which
we with some of the items yes
and we want to exactly feel the bag
right okay
yeah so for for example
so if we list the uh items here eric
1 2 6 24 120
and then for each item how many choice
do we have
we have uh five
no no for example i want to this is item
one
it is weight uh it's weight
one kilo for example and how many choice
can we put
can we have if we by deciding to put
into the nut step to what i lost either
take it or not pick it yeah pick it or
not pick it and then we can use this
strategy right to try each possibility
so for
for m items what's the time complexity
of this argument
[Music]
yeah so 2 times 2 times 2 times 2 this
is the multiplication
okay okay so let's let's run this step
for search okay
let's play this strategy
look at my new tattoo okay enough enough
define define
uh let's say a
distinct sum okay some bacteria let's
say bacteria
factorial sum and then we are given this
end
now the first thing is to do what the
first thing
is to uh to what
we are given this number n so the first
thing we need
to find the fact
the fact the factorial let uh smaller
than or equal to n right
and where we're going to put it in
fact and what's the fact
it's the thing we uh what's the fact
what's the what's the data structure we
are going to use to store the
number of bacteria i uh we
are going to put it in like
a fact yeah what is that
what is this what is this a list a list
yeah a list of numbers or we can use the
including in the double ndq yeah dq we
can also put it in double nkq
okay so look factorial
equals let's put it in the dq yeah dq
dt double ended k double and cube we can
put it in
both sides okay if we put it on the left
then there'll be a descending order yeah
the biggest
factor will be on the beginning yeah if
we put it at the end
the biggest factor number will be at the
end right
okay x equals 1 why
why what uh let's say
let's do this uh k
okay k equals one y
k smaller equal n
what what do we do now y k smaller
equals n
what k times equals
x and what should we do now with k k is
the factor
yeah let's put it in the left so the
left most the big the first one will be
the
largest factory apparent left
okay and now what should we do with the
x what should we do with the x
b what should we do one
yeah yes
x add equals one okay so now the
factorial will be the
list of the factors factories these are
factorial lesser smaller than n
right okay then now we do this dfs dfdfs
and then so what kind of parameters we
do we have here
so the following for each item so if we
have this
array bacteria this is the factorial
yeah
for example like like 144 right
that would be 1 2
6 24 120 yeah that's
it yeah effectively will be uh actually
you'll be
the opposite right because we append
left so you'll be
you'll be what you'll be the opposite so
you'll be
120 24
6 2 we didn't need to change six
oh yeah yeah okay so
n equals 144 right so at the beginning
at the beginning so we need a index
to point out to which value we are using
right
okay so let's call it index index finger
and then the second parameter will be
n no no no the second parameter will be
n right
and right this is the number of the
capacity
left in the back i'm right yeah so when
it's reduced to zero what does it mean
uh it's true yeah it should means that
we have uh
we have found a way to fill the bag with
all right with items yeah
yeah so look if n equal
zero return one try
okay and then if n smaller than zero
what should we do
if it's smaller than zero what does it
mean return one
yeah because it's not possible yeah okay
and then
if index if index
equal bigger or equal equal length
length uh effect what does it mean
return one if the index here if it's run
out of index if it's indexed here what
does this mean
let's zero one two three four if it's
equal to five what does it mean
yeah because we have tried every
possibility i will try have each item
here
and then can you tell me what's what's
this return
return
so how many choice for this index
how many choice do we have 10 if n
equals zero no no no what what's the
energy or is that therefore such one
for the index current index i try the
next index try the next index right
so x plus one index plus one okay so
the next item i want to try is index
plus one and so for this item what can
we do with this
do we pick it or not pick it right we
can pick it or not pick it okay
for pick it what should we do with n if
we pick it what should we do we shall
subtract and subtract
index thing yeah so what factorial
index right and then what should i put o
or n
what this is
yeah and the other one is not pick so
one of them is two is true or one person
is two are what's your opinion of
lobbies i think
you're doing something like oh oh yeah
because yeah you can pick or not pick
this right
so that's all oh what oh what i put it
here that's what such
index plus one okay
and then no p if not p what happened
with this n
no no it's not pick what happened to
this end if i don't pick with this and
how many items do
what's the weight left the weight
is it's worth it needs to be zero
no no no no colony is n if i
pick one item let me subtract these
if i don't pick these do i need to
subtract no so what's what's happened
here
n and it will be n right and then
and then i just need to return and
calling this one return dfs index will
be zero and then passing the
n right pressing the n look yeah
okay so this is kick this is not p and
one of them is true
it means that we found a way right i'm
right yeah
uh no rubbing out no rubbing
no not being on so um
does it make sense does it make sense
does it make sense here so okay i'm
going to erase the last bit can you
write it
oh god return what you can just write it
here
yeah all right return uh
return return
yeah listen we are calling the location
calling yourself yeah
index yeah index interest means that
that one means i want to try the next
one
yeah and then if pick or not pick
n minus f a c t
what yeah
no no no bracket bracket not curly uh
this is
a square bracket yeah square bracket to
if we want to visit you if you want to
get a value yeah and then
index index one
okay yeah the next one is oh
zero n return bracket
a new zero column and
clothing bracket no no why you write
that return again
return these this is to pick and then
what's the other option
uh you can not pick right yeah
so oh yeah
yeah zero end
he's not finished here index plus one
and then and that's it yeah
and then we are calling with p as what
what's the value of
index at the beginning what's the thing
there
0 0 and what's the value of n
what's the value of n the value of
n is the sum
it's the it's on it's n y it's the same
yeah passing the s
right n
yeah yeah this is this n that's so
obvious
yeah that's not so obvious yeah because
we we are we want to find out if
we can sum up to n right and that's the
that's the weight of the knapsack right
that's the maximum capacity of nam sec
okay okay that's it for today
so lastly which one is more uh
efficient the one we talked about today
or the one
we talked about yesterday using that
using the try the maximum thing which
one what happened
yesterday the complexities work and
today's complexity is over
come on we've talked about this before
each one has two options
yeah two to the power
okay so which one is better this one
yeah of course this one is far better
than this one yeah look om is the
omg here and what's out to the power of
n
2 to the power of 0 is what 1
2 to the power of 1 is 2 so it will be
like that okay so this is m this is the
complexity o
m okay o o m
is this this line okay om
and o to m is this listener so one m is
a hundred
yeah m is hundred oh o two to the power
of hundred that's a very big number
right
got it yeah you see so in this case we
can see
yesterday's approach is far better than
this one today we're using a recursion
definition why is the recursion
happening
yeah can you tell me recursion happening
what's great recursion recursion is like
uh what's the recursion come on
we talked about it first day okay so
recursion is like a thing that is
uh how can i explain what
what's the question can you give me a so
can you point to me with which
advertising course
come on free question
wait what's the question the question
definitely says come on
yes we question look this is a function
name we declare here
recursion is calling itself okay yeah
calling itself yeah yeah do you still
remember how can we write a location
function to calculate the factorial
that's just give a quick review yeah
come on
that's the very basic you shouldn't
forget about it okay
okay okay then tell me factorial
okay f zero equals one
f one equals one f two equals
one t equals
um two okay s
three equals six okay s n equals what
equals n times what times
f times f1 f n
minus 1 yeah that's it so let's be
question look
cos fn and minus one and we know the
initial
condition right so if we implement this
using the equation how can we
write it just a little preview okay
leave it okay define
f and if
n equals zero or
n equals one return y
return
if n equals zero n equals one
taiwan what's the factor
what's the value of factorial f zero
factorial and one factorial
what what's the return written integer
what's that
the integer is what's what's the value
of zero factorial in one factorial come
on
how high is that return we know what
return
i just tell you come on that's recursion
i want to call this f yeah f1
[Music]
subtract one
yeah okay so where is lubrication
this bit yeah because that's because
including itself okay
that's it and you can put a cash here if
you want okay
yeah cash okay doesn't make sense
[Music]
okay see you that's it all right
bye bye