go hello hello mr eric
are you all right i get it okay so today
we talk about
a string problem okay given two strings
okay for for example i have
a b and then ba
and you are allowed to take one
character one letter
in the first string and then swap it
with another letter in the second string
and then
the question is that we if we can do
this if we can do this unlimited number
of times
limited unlimited yeah as many as you
want and can we make two strings
do it forever and can we do can we make
two strings equal
right a b to b a a b
and b a uh we want to make it streaming
please
okay
[Music]
faster you don't need to ride so heavy
hurry hurry look am i having a heathen
say yes no i mean no
no a
and b yeah
hurry up and then b
yeah and a yeah
then it becomes bb and aaa right bibi
and a.a island what's going to stop
yeah swap tire knock yeah you can slowly
no let's b become b oh you can swap
these two and then you'll become a b
and i like to swap these two okay so you
become b a
okay got it okay
okay so you you nail it okay so how
about if i if i
give you a nailed it yeah nailed it
a b c and then
okay let's say d e d e f can you do it
or is these two
[Music]
come on it should be quite easy to check
right
wait
wait oh come on why is that
yeah we can use it in two places yeah
and we have one f as well okay so how
about
if i give you more c
okay no why is that they told us
there's um three and three kind of
three and half okay so how can we get
even number so we can't we need to count
the number of frequencies
for these uh the frequency for each
character and if it's a
odd number then certainly we can't right
and if it's an
even number certainly we can with
unlimited number of times stop stopping
there
yeah okay so in order to count the
frequency uh
what kind of how how can we do this what
kind of data structure are we using
um notebook notebook or headset or
in in python we use kind of how can we
count a number of the
frequency for for a string or
list do you still remember last thing
start with the c
yes okay okay so that's kind of look at
this
animal come on come on okay let's see
okay
these these are two these two are the
same size okay answer
no so no book yes
[Music]
i was thinking the binary tree okay no
okay
what should we buy this for
i in what range
in c top value we can do this value
and if what how can we write it
can you write it here here what and
here there are three things missing
one come on write it so we are either
wait it's
iterating the values which are the
frequency if it's even number
uh if it's uh all number what happened
can you not write it so hard okay
written one
huh
[Music]
divided by two i yeah
i if i i okay i divided by two
all modules yeah okay
can you write it faster people are
watching you you don't want to be slow
slow
okay come on it's more to us okay
okay okay and then
if it's even number or if it's all
number
uh even if it's
what number you want to do what
you got equal equal equal equals
no no no not here modulus 2
0 are you sure it's easier equal
to become even number and one time if
you want to be
even not equal okay what happened you
can imagine
to what to what
possible values
what does this mean it's an odd number
yeah
column and then what if it's all number
what happened
return false yeah and then we turn true
yeah we got it
oh yeah look at me okay okay return
return two
okay okay that's it that's it
you can also write it is i and one right
yeah it's the same yeah okay yeah
yeah i and one actually you can just
draw the
modulus too if it's equal to one you can
just do this
you can you can omit that module equal
one okay
[Music]
if there are s numbers in
the size of s it says the size of t is t
what's the total sorry
sorry
[Music]
t s plus yeah
what's the space complexity
well where are we using the space here
come on yeah
and what's the space what's like the way
look we we are adding the string here
yeah we can do this look
we can use this we can count it one
s right and then we can add one here
c dot update yeah
update t this is the same thing yeah
does it make sense alright so we we use
the s
object to construct the character c and
then we can update t
means that we take another object we
can't frequency and
update c so you can do this it's the
same
yeah yeah okay and then look these
you can return what these i can write it
in one line
all right look return
or look oh oh one
or what i
models to equal equal 0
4 i in what
yeah is it clear written all is
everything in here is everything
this condition satisfied
yeah for i in c the values i divided by
modulus 2 by 0 or anything
is even number okay okay so another way
of doing this
another way of doing this um
because look because these
frequents and this character needs to
come in pairs right
yeah that's the thing we're looking for
if it comes in pairs
what does it mean if a number comes
twice what does it mean
um if it comes twice um
in one one or in one age
one remember what's exclusive oh
this is exclusive or is like
one exclusive or one equals one
zero exclusive or one equals one
one exclusive here it's the same
yeah zero exclusive oh zero equals one
can you feel the value
zero yeah one one yes
yeah we're done okay okay so what
happened look
if they're same it's zero
so if the numbers abc and abc
if you if exclusive or all these what
happened to the value
what happened to the value it was
zero it would be zero yeah because look
it has it comes
in pair yeah so if we exclusive
everything
will become zero and if it is yellow it
means okay
if it's not in zero it means not okay
right
yeah yeah okay so we can try this look
define check
s t okay look
x equals zero for
i in right we take in
s plus t yeah or we can do it in two
loops yeah let's do it in one loop
s plus t x square
exclusive
you have to press the shift key yeah
press
shift and six then you give this okay
okay exclusive or equal you go up
exclusive oh what i go through
all the characters in s plus t
and what
x exclusive oh i want to exclusive
everything in the x plus t so what
should i put here
should i put here for what in s plastic
come on you can guess
for say this bit yeah
come on
what's this plastic come on what's
can you tell me what's follow before
there is i
in f t yeah okay so and i want to do
what
x i yeah but this i
is a character yeah how do you convert
the eye
into the uh ascii remember this ascii
thing
yeah what's this in ascii
wait wait what's this huh
97 65 48 can you
feel dinner one
i know one of these is one of the a's
wait i'm guessing
[Music]
yeah exactly okay so how do we convert
these to this
how how can we release to this are we um
i have a two choice for you okay c-h-r
and o-r-d which way is convert
the function i'm telling you
one function is to convert convert these
to here and the other one is the
opposite
can you guess from the name character
order okay which one is from the
from the character to to the number
which one is from the
ascii to the character can you guess
from the name from the function
so this direction for the character to
number which one which
function we will do order yeah because
the other one is from the order to the
character yeah that's what you mean yeah
order gives you an order yeah
character gives you a character yeah
okay so here what should i do with this
eye
what should i do with this eye
we shall
[Music]
what's the term complexity it's a sum
yeah
what's a space complexity um
a one a one yeah okay that's a tricky
yeah i saw you're gonna say oh it's
the same it's all one yeah because
you're not using this place good job
okay
yeah and we we can use the
look if we can we can do this we can we
can
if i if i remove this for i you know
previously is s plus t and if i remove
the plus t so what should we
what should we do now we shall we should
do
what if we move we're just going to
s then what's next
yeah okay so can you write it
for i n t yeah it's just ready you need
to practice
yeah come on you shouldn't ask me this
question okay for
why because it's so obvious for i
yeah okay come on come on all right
yeah can you follow me oh yeah
right properly oh yeah come on okay and
then what then
oh yeah on come on right faster come on
can you write it properly otherwise i'm
going to erase it and let you write it
again
and you'll write it properly okay and
what's next
i know what's next what's the last bit
return
this is how quick i can do it
[Music]
you must keep kidding me what's written
for us and written two
what's the previous one why why are you
saying between two and within first come
on
why are you writing this bit why really
speak why is
that should be okay that's it thank you
bye-bye