go hi
[Music]
matey hello mr ryan miss mary are you
right here
okay so today we talk about counting the
odd numbers
between a range what's all numbers
on tables so can you give me a few
sometimes
well if we pass it in for nine okay 11
13 15 79
and what's the even number one is the
one that could go in the two-time
table and has a flat top what's flat top
sorry
flat top if you're building blocks
oh okay okay a lumber block yeah
okay so it's two
okay so if i give you a range like three
to five
three to seven and remember here
square bracket means inclusive yeah
the answer is so how many numbers
between these
three seven yeah three five seven yeah
three five seven
because the seven is inclusive how about
this
how many numbers are all number between
this range five
yeah just fine yeah you got it yeah this
is called uh this is
parentheses on exclusive okay so
yeah you understand this three seven and
how about you've got
if i tell you like it's three like a
thousand
how many can you count no yeah it's too
hard to count yeah
yeah but how about three seven and two
a thousand you see the answer is the
same right
is it the same you see the same yes or
no
yeah why is that two is not an
odd number yeah and it's the next odd
number is three yeah
so these two answer the same so if this
lower case
if this lower bound is even number
so it's the same as this right
yeah it's the same as this if if this is
the
if error is even number the answer will
be the same as
l plus one r right so we we can actually
ask computer to
count the numbers between this range
okay let's quickly divide that again
okay
define curve
odd lr
column okay let's say answer equal
zero and then now if air
it's even number right how do we say how
do we check if it's an even number
we you know divided by two if
it's zero right if divided by two
is 0 look like if it divided by 2 equals
0 it's an even number
and in this case we can do one
l plus equal one we can make it
up one yeah the weather okay then
look and wire air smaller or equal
r and then i can count it
yeah count the all number yeah and what
happened to air
l plus equal
one like two two yeah two because three
five every time you jump two right and
here you
are bigger than r right yeah okay return
turn off what's the time complexity for
this one i win
what's n what's n
[Music]
what's the n what's the what's uh what
are we looking for here
what's n number yeah the odd numbers
between this range
yeah also n is roughly r minus l divided
by 2.
but yeah but we dropped a constant yeah
so you can say oh n which
n is the number of numbers between this
range okay wear them
but apparently if r is a minion
right then it's going to take forever
yeah i'm right all right
it's going to take forever yeah you're
nothing yeah nothing
going to take forever is that possible
we can just do a mathematic calculation
yeah we can of course of course we can
okay so
remember we have a range function we
have a range function and we can
actually cheat a little bit ask computer
to do that
math for us range so we can say
uh define count and let's define count
odd
lr okay so look it's the same
if air
modulus 2 equal equal
1 if it's if it's odd number then we can
directly return
length depends on what range
right we generally iterate the range
will be air
and what's the second parameter but
actually you'll be r plus one yeah
because the
the destination is exclusive in the
range function
for example in the range function range
one to
ten will be
yeah so we need to ah plus one here and
what's the third parameter
what's the sub parameter we ask you to
step every
every time we want to step how many
times two
two times so we put a two here let's say
we ask the computer to do it this range
function you will give an iterator and
the computer will do the math for you
and here there will be even number right
so if it's even number what should we do
what should we do range what should we
do here
if it's an even number what should i put
here
plus one l plus one last one
r plus one and three where down that's
it
yeah the computer will just do the math
for you yeah you see yeah as i said
if it's even number it's the answer is
the same as l plus one yeah because
if it's even number it's not all number
okay
we we can actually do this math if you
want to
compute this grand uh function we can
just do this
we can define our f function and define
f function
l r and what's the if air
if air is like odd number let's say
and how many let's say how many
odd numbers between this range right
if l is 5 3 two seven
we turn three to seven how many all
numbers between these
how many numbers between uh three to
five two three
seven three four
five six seven how many odd numbers
between
three yeah so we can do this we can do
what
we can seven minus three
divided by two is three five these two
but we need to plus
a as a one at the end
yeah okay so that would be
three yeah okay and how about eight if i
put a it's the same a minus three
divided by two two point five but we use
the two plus one three yeah
okay so you the answer would be return
r minus l
divided by two and one
plus one plus one okay and then here
we don't we can just do this
we can just return f
l r right yeah
and then here i can say return f a
plus one all right yeah this
works because they we assume that error
is odd number okay
can we can we actually count and now
another way to do it better
yeah actually we are counting actually
this is counting
but another way of doing this is what
because
air and i look okay
here here is air this is zero yeah
i is here the number of all numbers
the num the odd numbers between this
range
is it is it equals to the number of all
numbers
at this range zero to r
minus zero to l minus one right
yeah got it
i want to click this bit but
if i can count this bit and count this
bit
the difference would be the answer right
does it make sense yeah makes sense okay
so
so if we count the counterfeit how can
we count a bit
from zero to the lower minus one yeah
because
we want to increase the lower but no
minus one how many how many
how many all numbers in this range
l minus one
one minus zero and how many numbers plus
one
divided by two that's the lamp let's
number uh
let's see the number of all numbers
between these three and what's the
number of
uh all numbers between zero to r
can you give me an example
to
r plus
one
yes and what's the answer
the number of the all numbers between
zeros and is this the number
of all numbers between t r two to l
minus one is this and the difference is
what
r plus one divided by two minus
l divided by two that's the answer
can we can we can we okay do this three
and five
five plus one divided by two
minus three but divided by two
let me check let me check is it
[Music]
r plus one minus two divided by two
r alpha one yeah yeah that's right
seven okay it's seven plus one nothing
seven plus one divided by two
is four four minus one okay this is one
three okay let's give another example
like two two
two two twenty okay how many are numbers
let's say three five
seven nine eleven thirteen
fifteen seventeen nineteen the 9 right
yeah let's put this 20 plus 1
divided by 2 minus 2 divided by 2
so that's 21 divided by 2 is 10 in 10
point
but we we just discard the fraction yeah
minus one it's not uh isn't that
10 minus 40 but why is
nine oh yeah it's nine yeah one two
three four five
so what's the time complexity for this
one
[Music]
eric can you get it what's the time
complexity for this approach
oh what
i want oh one well because we are not
using we are not iterating yeah
what's the space complexity
uh do we need to use space
do we need to actually use space
now if we're not using space what's the
time complex what's the space from
brexit
oh come on give me a number
one yeah one here that's it yeah give me
a number
yeah i just give you a thing now it's
like give me a number what number n is
no number okay
if we're not using any space it's all
one if it's not
third one okay because we are just
calculating yeah so we're just
calculating it it's
mathematic it's just all one yeah so we
can just
just do the calculation so yeah that
will be it for today
thank you very much bye