go hello hello mr all right
yeah okay so today we are going to talk
about the
binary tree how can we check if two
trees are the same final industries
right just check can you stand up
yeah so at least two minutes three
percent
are these two five and two the same um
nine
why why is that oh because one hundred
three and one doesn't mean
okay so the number nodes are different
so they're definitely not a
equal same binary okay how how about
this
i like the same no why is that nice
sorry sorry which one come on
this no the values is different so so
there are two things we need to check
the values yeah the values
the values of the the corresponding node
should be the same and the structure the
second thing is the structure yeah if
the
node if a tree has a left tree
and the other tree doesn't have left
tree it's not equal right all right
yeah okay so let's let's
implement it um using what kind of the
algorithm can we use to implement
to to check if two trees are the same or
not
um yeah the network sorry
differences definitely your preferences
both okay okay so that today we're
going to use the definitions because
it's easier to implement okay let's say
define and we're going to pass two
parameters yeah a
and b three okay and b column okay so
what should we check
first we shall check um the root yeah
the load of a
and b okay so what the if if one of them
is empty what happened
um and one of them is no yeah
if both names are empty okay so first of
all we need to check for
if both three are empty if a is
noun and
i what b is known so yeah what what do
you
put here b is none
what do you put here oh oh
yeah which were first and end first
and now we'll be turning one
if both are not written right yeah
because
empty equals empty okay and then one of
them is empty how can i write it
if at this point at this point what does
it mean
is is a
so not both three are not
empty at the center right so what should
i do if one of them is empty yeah
if a is now
b is now what should i put here
oh and then return what b10 yeah because
at this point if a is now then b is not
long right
if b is not a is not number right yeah
if a note compares to noun it's false
right
okay then at this point what should we
do what should we check next
we shall check the rate the value yeah
so how can i tell you if what
what if what return first can you tell
me
yeah it's what
the aim is a a
what the value the value what
and then now so these three at this
point a and b
the root is the same here right what
should i check
what should i check now
the left and the right and how can we
check the left and right
um what's the word how can we check if
we
what how can we three
how can we check the left tree and the
right tree
so what should we do now um
what should we do we show because the
tree is recursionally defined yeah
because
yeah yeah the question so we are calling
this function to check the level right
yeah how can we write it return
something and something can you tell me
i need something involved the same
calling the same
written what come on you've checked in
the rules
ready yeah we want to call it
is
[Music]
three and the right trig we are checking
we are comparing the
both the left three yeah we don't know
how big the left tree is but we're
calling
this recursion function to check that
three and then we just write it
both needs to be the same right yeah
why this is working because look a tree
two trees are equal if the notes are
equal
and their left trees are equal and then
both their right trees are equal am
right
doesn't make sense yeah is this is the
what's the time complexity if that
if there are any nodes in a and m nodes
in b
what's the time complexity
do we need to check and then if the node
is one
there's one node in one tree and then a
minion node in
in the second tree so how many nodes do
we need to check
how about minimum
we just need to check the minimum yeah
if we if
we don't need to check one million no
why because it will tell us first
once the one tree is finished yeah but
in the worst case yeah
yeah uh what's a space complexity
[Music]
it's the same yeah is that the same
minimum
yeah minimum because of the
because of what because of the recursion
because yeah usually the computer
maintains stack yeah we're done yeah
and we can implement it using uh not not
notification we can use the
stack thingy but it will be more
complicated we can talk about it maybe
tomorrow or
the day after tomorrow okay yeah to
maintain we maintain a stack by
ourselves but it will be a lot easier if
we
using the recursion because the computer
generated the stack
maintain the stack for you when you do
this functional choice
return sam and the computer will just
put a stack generally stack and put it
called color functioning does it make
sense
yeah okay
i can do it yeah if you understand you
can do it of course
yes
uh are you sure it's eight or left
yeah because we check both the left tree
and
right three yeah be done left yes
okay and then what
yeah it's n and what does n mean both
needs to be true in order to be true
so
yeah that's it for today good job we're
done very well done
say bye to people