go hello hello mr area are you all right
yeah
yeah so what what did we talk about
yesterday
oh um we talked about
um what oh if
two um binary trees are the same seven
bananas
and we're using going back to the video
uh 190 something
how do we check if these the two trees
are the same a
and b how do you check it how do you
check do you still remember
color yeah how do we check it do you
still remember how we earn
deficit that's what search okay so first
of all if we want to check event
we quickly review a little bit if a is
noun
and b is noun
what should we do return what
if both trees are true okay
and okay if a
a
okay and then we need to recursively
check what
we need to declare what same and what
we need to recursively check what if
these three
at this point these two nodes are the
same and what what do we do next
what do we do next we go we push
um what
a dot left b left same um
right yeah this is because the time
complexity is on right
yeah the space complexity is also oh
okay so this is stefan search eric look
okay every book look at me yeah
so we compare these we compare these we
compare these we compare this we compare
this yes this is the order
if we using a breakfast search we
compare these
we compare these we compare these
these we compare these we compare this
yeah that's the breakfast search
breakfast okay so let's do it
preferences and in question search what
kind of data structure
do we need to use q okay so
so for example i have a q q what's kill
first in first first thing
meaning that okay so if i put it now
here
that at the beginning what should i put
with uh should i
initialize the kiwis i'll vary a load
a load okay so if there are two which
route or a pair of loads
which one two loads so what kind of
how look if there are two dudes this is
a this is b
so what should we put here initialize
what what kind of thing you put in there
now it's a node or a player note
or
what kind of data structure is this
uh immutable immutable what's this this
is the list and what do you call this
this is a list i want this i'm a bucket
pupa this is called tupac okay super is
immutable list okay at least for example
i
i can say x equals a and b and x equals
uh this is y equals a and b the
difference is
that if i count if i can set it x 0
equals c that's okay but i can't say y
zero equals c that's not okay because
this is immutable
constant yeah it means that when it is
created
it can't be changed okay is
never created it's not that creative
it's not change i mean
what what's the opposite of immutable
what's the opportunity multiple um
[Music]
what's the a time no no immutable
what's in means the opposite a mutable
means the changeable
it means three times because you can do
whatever you want okay so foreign
okay so now i want to use the double and
key q yes so q
q r d q okay
so what should i put it give it at the
beginning
right so i kind of tube a and b right
yeah look that's how you put a tuber in
uh in a queue with the bracket is the
cheaper in the list
and another cheaper thing two point one
two point you know it is a three
it's a cheapo and uh yeah yeah
no no no this is super but this is not
this means the black parentheses called
function call this is a
this is a function princesses but this
this means that it's a tuba okay why
because look if it's a tuper you got a
you've got nothing
no characters before if it's a function
n like uh
max remember max one two this is not
your this is getting the one and two
which is the maximum okay
this is the function call okay okay so
now we have a tuple a and b here
a and b and then what should we do why
why
why why why why
you mean still nice investigation
it's the same as len q is bigger than
zero okay so we're left s2 elements in
the queue
so what should we do we with this we
will take the element
in front of yeah so let's take the note
yeah so let's take
p and q equals another p
because we have q here so let's say
p plus q is the q so let's do it
x and y okay x sub y equals q
dot one why there's a dot yeah because i
look
i put two elements a two part so i want
to take it out
put it in x and y pop one
and left pop left yes because if you're
not saying pop
if you're not if you just pop what does
it mean it will just put
anything he wants no no no no
no a and b you put the b
yeah pop top means probably right
pop right pop left means pop left if you
for the first thing first of all you we
we want to take this why
does it where why do you just if you
just
put a cute up part why does it do right
good good question yeah because we have
pop left and then the up
the one you don't specify is pop right
okay so look if we pop right
this is first in lasalle right we want
to pop left
because when we append this direction we
will take this this is first
insert right if you first thing take the
last thing
it will be first thing that's our
eastern stack right okay so we now we
take
two elements two nodes in a pair so we
want to compare right like a different
search
if x is noun
and y is num what should we do if that
both
both both nodes are empty what happens
no no no at this time remember at this
point
we're just taking the note there may be
still some notes in the tree we want to
compare
right right
that's fine so we won't we don't want to
ignore so that can
there are two things you can we're going
to skip these and continue so what
keyword should we put
continue our break no no no break this
continue continue what's what does this
mean
it means that i will skip everything
there and i will go to the
loop loop again right yeah continue
it's not a new okay so if x
is non o y is none
okay remember we have this in different
search so what happened if
one of them is now what happened
can we in can we make uh what should we
do
first return first yeah return first
right yeah
all right okay then what should we do
we should compare what we shall compare
the what we should compare the word
value okay so how can you tell me what
to do
um we should
what compare why don't value what
and what oh
we want to compare the value come on
compare the value how do we compare come
on
[Music]
not equal why the value return
yeah that's it i know what should we do
now what should we do now if this note
is
okay then we want to do what if this
note is supposed one we want to do what
we want to do what girl right
sorry go on the right hop on the left
left then right okay left and right and
what what should we do here
q dot what you do what kill the what
there are two things here
k dot
[Music]
open what kill 101
obtain the value
we we have checked the value here
already so what should we do now you say
the left and right what should we do
uh left right okay so what do i put here
there are two parameters what should i
put here
think you need to think x y
x y x y is here what should i do
of the notes comparison and then you
will go to the next one right
ready yeah does it make sense yeah yeah
actually we can we can use these
as a as a stack we can use it as a pump
and then it still works it's just the
order will be different right but it
still works
but it's not a perfect search it's now
kind of using the stack right
we push it and we take it out yeah so
the order of checking the notes doesn't
matter right
because we're always pushing the pair
right
does it doesn't matter if i check this
note first or least no first
no because like eventually i want to
check all the notes right all the pairs
why did you do left first yeah good
question because
we want to do the you know breakfast
search yeah
breakfast so it's better we put it top
left
what's the time complexity for this one
um
[Music]
and this is m
what's the term complexity yesterday for
the different search
[Music]
if one tree has one note the other three
has a minion note i
oh yeah
space complexity what's the space
complexity
the space capacity in the worst case the
queue will be filled in
with what
maximum because
every time in the worst case when we
talk about complexity we always talk
about it in the worst case we're not
talking about in the best case right
we're talking about
worst case so in the worst case you'll
be you'll feel
maximum yeah
in the worst case let's say uh it's a
bit shaky because
i as we said this is a binary tree
right it's a banana tree and every time
we
keep pushing and then popping right
so the note would be uh
if we if it comes to the it will be o n
you'll be all n
n plus n right
is it uh
no no i i think it's just all mean and
because
given this time complexity if it's
different you'll be active
right so you'll be o and plus o and o
mean and
this is the case okay okay
uh does it make sense here is it the
same yeah
which one you think is better
from which one yeah the definition of
preferences which one you think is
is better it's easier if i give you
to write it which one you think you were
you're remembering remember the
definition to the professor
checking the two binary trees if that's
them if i have to remember one
no yeah i understand and remember if you
even
which one you think what come on give me
a
answer please
yeah i think yeah
i think this one will be easier for me
to um really yeah i think
you think
is gonna be challenging oh my god come
on i can write it
you tell me what to write and i'll write
it for you okay um
[Music]
a and b you want to write the template
your preferences come on
uh i think it was which one
which one you think it would like the
least one i just raised was
that was first research i think
okay so what do we want to write now
what was it
what there are two trees i will i want
to compare it to that
so what was it that's what is your
professor which one is
so how can you write it down um
what do we need to declare q okay so
let's
name it q equals one
[Music]
sorry okay q what u as well
there are a and b always the root
q what key equals
yeah come on thank you and then
of course we do it right here and
there's i think this is the cheaper
amd okay
we're going to take it out right we're
going to take it out from the beginning
so what we'll do
do the problem okay then i have x and y
what should we do
we should check if it's equal right yeah
so what should we check we shall check
first of all if person none what
happened
in x x is
[Music]
oh yeah
yeah because as long as we found a
mismatch we just return yeah we can
first we don't need to continue right
but the reason we want to continue here
is that there are maybe
notes let me be still some notes in the
queue we haven't checked yet right we
have to finish
everything in a note okay and what if
what
um if it's not equal the value you need
knowing
what happened we can we
if it's not equal what happened not
equal we shall return
false okay and then
and then what and then we have
completely
okay then what happened go to the left
and go to the right how can we do that
um what we want to well
this is a kill and now we take the no
out
and then we want to do uh the preference
append what does
x dot
um
okay and at the end we finish all the
checking
and here what should we do we
turn but then
yeah because no violation we found here
okay so you know yeah you know yeah
but for search right so can you tell me
what's the diff what's the sequence of
rejecting this is one two
three four five this is
one two three four five
so can you tell me how using this
argument breakfast search
how are we comparing the notes yeah
so we um
yeah okay and we are doing
a and b and you're going to put the
notes in here in the queue no you just
tell me which order
we compare one and one and then then two
and two uh-huh
and then three and three and four
and four yeah when we compare two and
two
we put a three and four into the queue
yeah got it so
so what sorry look just a little bit
just in case you forgot right look this
is a queue
all right look look one and one here at
the beginning yeah
another take one and one out i push one
kids what about the kids two
two and two five and five right
and then the next one i take one off
the you take the two and two out and
then you
push the kid what is
you see that's the level yeah five three
four okay
two five three okay that's what how how
it works
that preferences to level by level okay
got it
okay we're done you can do some special
things at the end
um