go hello hello mr area all right
uh so today we talk about these three
numbers the direction change okay so
given these numbers
there's a few numbers one three five
four three okay let's see
if we plot these numbers along this x
axis okay let's say that this is xx this
is y
okay so one is here
three five four
three okay if you throw these lines so
can you tell me how many
times that the direction is checked what
i mean direction changes
if you're going up and then you go down
that's the direction change or if you're
going down and then
suddenly you're going up let's say
there's some change so it's like a peak
click here how about if it's
a horizontal no that's not direction
change or if it's here this way it's not
a return change right because it's keep
keep the trending
but here is the change in the direction
if we go up and then we're going down oh
if we're already not going down and
we're going up
let's say the return change how many
directions here
how many directions come on you can see
it why two
why is it two where is the two where's
the two
one why just one look that's the thing
we're looking for all these yeah
yeah yeah okay so how how can we do this
if we're given these
n numbers then we want to count how many
how many of these yeah how many of these
oh i know what to do okay you tell me
what's next actually i don't
you don't why so
don't don't worry say say this ideas you
have
you must have some ideas tell me tell me
the ideas you have
tell me the ideas
[Music]
around it and we want to have a
like a thingy like that ah
other changes okay
okay that's very creative okay so how
can you tell if it's a changes
let's speak let's cause it's like yeah
okay so how can we change uh how can we
detect these
the patterns okay so the pattern we are
looking for
is what is something like that or that
yeah something like that or not yeah
yeah okay so the trending the trending
must change right the training
so if i tell you look one three if i use
this number minus this that will be two
yeah this number minus this will be two
this number minus this will be minus one
this minus
this one will be minus sign so can you
see the two
t minus one minus okay so can you see
how we can make use of the difference
between the next number and the current
number
as the trend the next number and the
current number
so can you notice the difference 2
2 minus 1 minus 1 what does it mean if
we
look if the if
they are all positive
actually no what is it i actually don't
know
so look if it's positive if it's stay
positive
does it change um
does it change come on two to two or two
to
one minute it doesn't change if it's
still if it's still negative
it doesn't change the only change is
that if it's going from a positive to
negative
or if it goes to the negative to
positive if the sign has changed
remember we
talked about the sign oh yeah if the
sign has changed remember what sign
let's say the sine function positive x
sine sine function what is the equal
look we can say
let's say okay what's the sine function
sine function yeah second function x
what does it equal
if it's one it has three possibilities
three
one zero and one and one zero and one
minus one right yeah
if this is if x bigger than zero what's
this
x y and what come on tell me x
which is zero zero equals zero and then
x
uh smaller than zero okay okay so
so is the difference span if we say sun
data data data means that
why are you using the triangle yeah
that's what it means data that data
means the difference
data data
sin delta x what
sine theta x is
is um look
maybe some data okay so
theta x one x two
can we write it if it's smaller than
zero so how can we interpret this
so look uh let's
go back to that one three five
three one okay
if we we talk about if this is currently
if we talk about
this is data x1 and if this is
delta x2 so look so
if delta x1 times data x2 the difference
is smaller than 0 means the sign has
changed then it must copy be counted
as one direction change right so if
we're going through this
array numbers by keep checking of the
current
data data x and then we check the
next data data okay data and if
the sign has changed then we increment
one okay
okay let's do this
define define uh chain
changing direction or they're changing
let's just
changing the numbers okay in the
beginning
n equals length numbers yeah we just
what does it mean yeah
[Music]
okay so if n is smaller or equal
too what does it mean if only there are
two numbers or less
and what should we return number of
changing if
there are two numbers or less we turn
around
yeah yeah of course because two numbers
there's no changing line you can't find
any change right
right all right okay okay now the
current data okay come on let's say
how about let's we call it slow okay you
want a slope
if it is going up that's positive
positive
positive if it's going down that's
negative
if you're going straight let's call it
zero okay slope
got it the longest
[Music]
this is on the swing you go up okay okay
so slow what does it mean
what look at that they are numbers
they're numbers
numbers okay that's there's one three
five seven
four five five four okay so so
the beginning would be which one the
beginning let's level
sorry the slope slope going up
three three minus one come on three
minus one and then five minus three
hundred
okay look so we we just use the numbers
yeah uh
let's say numbers one minus one
one minus numbers
uh zero yeah then
let's start with which number for i
in branch range what
when you are now we know this is current
stove yeah
so now we need to start with which one
let's start here right five minus three
yeah so and n equals well i equals one
zero one
what's this i was doing five
the index the index zero one was three
to n and then common let's say
current current slope current slope
equals life equals
this is i current lands i mine as well
uh minus one i minus one okay
okay and then we we know this is lower
yeah
this is slow and this is current slow so
if current slow
what current stop and the slope times
it together even if it's one if it's one
if if it's what then we
uh let's answer here and equal zero and
the plus equals one
so what should i put here if current
swing
and and slope times together yeah
multiply
if current is like times slope
why is it times why y is not times look
if it's this
2 5 minus 3 is 2 times 3 minus
1 is 1 so it's going up right
yeah yeah so how about look if it's
if d here 5 to 7 that's 2
2 5 minus 7 minus three
minus three is smaller than zero so we
are looking for a minus zero yeah
changing remember this is changing it's
smaller than zero
yes smaller than zero okay and then
after this should
what should i do is to change the slope
so if i look the next one will be moving
right
so what happened to the slope what
happened to us though
it's like we um no no no
no slow
current slow and then move to the next
one what happened
what's slow now look look how he is
there slope
current slope and the next iteration
what happened to the slope what happened
to this slow current slow
it means that yeah and what was slope
equals
it's not equal to one because slope is
used in the next iteration
no no no current slow slow what happened
to the slope
slope here and you move to here slow
slope
is always the previous slope of
current slope right so slope equals what
previous like we we try this previous
note if it goes to the next internet
yeah that's what i mean current slow
yeah
all right and then there's one thing
missing
oh
give me a give me a give me a number oh
letter come on
what's the space go backstage
you're not using any uh space that's
nine year then
actually we are using space but this is
constant space that's why we say one
yeah but
we're not using a ray or something that
is linear with the number of
the number of things yeah
okay
you need to understand okay it's not
equal as well
come on
yeah look remember slope coming slow
moving to the next next
next yeah kind of stuff will be equal to
the previous level which is the current
stop in each iteration right
because going to the next one right
going to the next one the current slope
will be become
previously actually this slope should be
called the previous low
okay what the mean time what that's how
i do my time
isn't that time yeah yeah yeah but here
this is one into the time here
okay and here what should i do
it's like sorry what do you mean here
what
that's in that's it
so what's missing here come on if we
change you if we're changing this level
we're going up and we're going down
down yeah so look previous levels
kind of slope it times them
yeah if it turns them is what then
yeah come come
come on you really need to understand
otherwise he's always forgetting
this is slope this is current slope so
the two numbers
if that if how do you check it
yeah come on write it faster come on
you're too slow kind of slow yeah yeah
times yeah times one
slow yeah and what happened if these two
slope
if one going up one going down or one
going down one going up
what happened if it is changing
direction if it's smaller than zero
right
and what we count it as a change in
direction which is
which value very obviously
plus yes that's what it means yeah okay
that's it that's it for today thank you
bye bye
okay hi