hello hi hello mr are you all right
yeah what's this binary tree
tree okay yeah good uh note a parent can
have uh
at most two child right i know with no
child it's called leave
the note the only note yeah the only row
a parent which is a room yeah yeah you
know what i
i was going to say okay so now i took
your line
yeah good so today's task is that if we
are allowed to pick
as many numbers as possible but given
this condition is that we can't pick
we can't if we pick the parent we can
pick its direct children or
if we pick the children we can pick the
direct parent
right so if we pick one yeah if we pick
one we can't pick two and
if we pick two we can pick one and five
and six okay
so for example what's the maximum sum
that you can
you can get from picking as many numbers
as possible
what's um sum together
what sum are we trying to add up to
yeah that's the question the number of
the the
sum the maximum sum that we can get
from picking the numbers from this minus
tree but only on one condition is that
we can't pick
the direct parent or the kids
okay so for example this one how what's
the sum you can get
what the sum the num the sum
come on the sun what's the matter
okay so um you can try
coming up with a field three six five
three well done yeah six five three
that's
fourteen right right if we pick uh
two then we can pick one and five six
yeah then
we can pick three that's five yeah yeah
if we pick one we can't
be stupid we can pick these two so it
will be one plus five plus six less
twelve right
still smaller than fourteen yeah we're
done so 14 is the number
we're looking for so so you understand
this problem um
so how can we solve this problem i mean
proof of thing so proof of thing for
each one we can pick or not pick right
yeah yeah but so
proof of thing if this end is that n
note
so how many possibilities are there for
each node we pick
two yeah we don't know o two to the
power
m so but about this solution two to the
power of n
we need to filter out those in valid
solutions yeah inverted solutions
meaning that if we pick one we complete
these two everywhere
one two without and just kidding no no
so so but first of all we need to
generate this much uh this many
this much solutions right and then we
need to filter out
filter outlet loads inverted solution
and then we need to compute
the sum right computer sum usually takes
n so the time complexity will be
o 2 to the power n times n right this is
too much got it
this is too much yeah am right
yeah the problem with this solution is
that
if we pick these we don't need to pick
we know we don't need to try picking
these yeah these would be a lot of
duplicate inverted solutions right so
far
is for each note how many for each note
we have two choices yeah all right we
can pick on a pick yeah okay
we cannot pick or not pick so if we can
do this
you know we can define the function
define the function okay
let's let's define a function
define
so uh let's say pick
okay so we have a loot but if we tell
him we add a second perimeter saying
if we need to pick or not taken let's
say we want to take
uh let's say to take okay to take
to take color okay
if loot is now what happens if it's
empty what should we do
return what
okay now if we to take okay if this note
we are saying to take
if we take look eric look this is the
tree okay
this this note we are currently here
root yeah this is good
if we do to take so we need to return
what
we turn this new dot value yeah all
right because we are taking this okay
all right we are taking this but if we
take these we can't take these two right
i'm right yeah so
what should we do we can play a password
all right plus one look if we take this
root
at least is what this is loot on left
right
unless it's rule okay so look
if we take this right if we take these
if this function if we take down we
can't take
that's right so this function will
return the maximum value if we take
these current load right so if we take
this root we obviously we need to take
this
value right class ready plus pick
pick one rule download the second
parameter from left
read
and what with that
false yeah let's that's why yeah but if
we're not taking look
it's not taking it's not taking
if we don't take this one right we can't
take greed or left
we can take these and we can also not
take this right
am right does this make sense
so look for the left we can take or not
take for the right we can take another
how many possibilities all together
so the left we can two
two and then this is two possibilities
so how many all together
on the left like we can take or not take
yeah
two times two so we can pick
okay i'm going to write this yeah all
right
so take blue dot
left we pick loose
left
two right plus
very quick plus pick on left uh okay i
don't have
enough space so basically look we want
to get this maximum of
these four choices maximum of leads we
pick
we pick the left and pick the right
right will be true right two two oh we
kick the left
these are the left left left left and
left i i just right left left
left and here another function is right
yeah
so look so basically we pick two
two left that we pick both left
and right pick a left don't pick it
right
don't pick the left pick it right and
don't pick it
both left and right and we want to get
the maximum of these right okay
yeah doesn't make sense pick
pick so you have a big pic pick no on
left to pick
rudolph right to pick noodle left
uh to pick a little right first pick
do the left first pick do the right tool
and it wasn't
the last one pick root on left
yeah okay so for each one we we're going
this peak route so
what's the time complexity for this one
tricky
and there's something missing there's a
word missing
what's that cash you add on cash if you
don't
put a cash that'll be every time you go
to release
you you'll cut you compute over and over
again right for each rule right
am i yeah so if we put a cash in that
that's right what's the time complexity
after
putting the cash
because for each node we only compute
two states peak on a peak right so
actually it's two times
o two f but we drop the constant is o n
right
all right yeah yeah
does it make sense yeah look if we know
doing cash what happened if we don't
do the cash
so if we don't do the cash but
at some point yeah at some point
we're going to calculate these we we're
going to calculate one
stage over and over again right okay
yeah so what's the maximum what's the
what's the value we need to return peak
low maximum
maximum one because at the beginning
we need to return maximum repeat route
take
true oh
so well pick pick room two or one
and pick blue first with the maximum
yeah at the root of the time
so if we pick these or not pick these
right
yeah if we pick this if we pick these
we don't pick these to it and you'll
call these two functions here right
yeah if we don't take these and then
these two values are
are calculating again right so that's
why we need to do the patch
at least it's what top down or butter up
yeah because we want to take it at least
then because
we will need leads to leave and that
will be tucked down let's that's why we
need to put a catch stop down
so can we do this butter up maybe we
can yeah so butterfly is that we
calculate from these
all right from the leaves to the root
yeah from the leaves to the root
so for each note if we can return two
states
if we take these or not take these right
all right so for each load we can only
we can
take this one and take this okay so
let's do this
define let's call it uh dp okay
dp load so but we don't need to
parameters yeah so
if not load if not load if
it's empty we return to value
zero zero look this is a cube with
return two values zero
in python you can return two values
using the columns or multiple values
yeah
this is called tuple we return two
values
okay now we take left let's say take a
left
look take left
not take a left okay we can do this
this is taking so this the first value
is that if we take this
taken the current note the maximum value
we can get
the second value is that if we don't
take this note the maximum value we can
get yeah
from this note yeah from this final tree
am i
yeah okay look so here
is that we take these notes eric hey
look look at me
if we take this note the maximum value
we can get
from this subtree yeah if we don't take
this no
the maximum value we can get so take
left not take
left equal as dp wow
what what should i put here take left
not take that equals dp this is
recursion
right because can you tell me what
because look we haven't solved this
problem yet but we are
dedicating using i uh recursion
to delete it to delay this calculation
recursively
until it reaches the root right which is
the
leaves which is zero zero right okay
and again here take a right
not take the right
equals one ppy
[Music]
yeah okay now this is the best part
so now we have to take left to not take
a left take right not take
right okay so look we now
we so here okay so
this is the loop yeah we are here at
this one this is the loot
so now we're calling the dp do the left
to the right so for these two bit
absolutely
this will be has four values right this
has four values
so for this node for this value if we
take it
if we take it all right so the first
value we want to take it
take take take
boot okay take root equals what if we
take
the root if we take it
we we can't take these two right yeah
so what should we what's that what
should be the value of take note
what should the value of take load
take we we can't take so which value
which two values if we take these which
two values are
which these are therefore valid
not take right yeah not take less
plus not take right right yeah
yeah okay now if we not take a look
not take a look because
even left add take flight
sorry what does it mean no no no if
we're not taking the loot how many
possibilities we can
we we can 2
9 4. okay so if we don't take this we
can take
these or not take these and we can take
these or not take this
right yeah so if we don't take these
we can take this or not take this which
which one
the maximum we will pick is right all
right
yeah so that would be what maximum of
what
maximum work plus maximum one
can you can you continue maximum water
maximum
right okay wait wait a minute take a
look
we can we take root we cannot take left
or
not take it right and plus load of value
yeah because we already take it yeah
so this is missing yeah okay
so not take a look if we don't take
these we want to
pick the maximum of two solutions on
each side so this is
we can say here will be take left
and not take left there yeah take
left not take that and then yeah
which two values we are returning here
[Music]
no we already calculated the first value
is we take it and the second value is we
don't take it and for the load we
already know
take a look and not take it low so what
should we do 10
pay yeah and comma
note yeah not take so now we are solving
the cases for for current rule yeah
based on if we take this look look
if we take this root we can't take these
two loose so these two values we already
calculated from recursion
but if we don't take these two loose we
plus the current value a lot of value
yeah
but if we're not taking the route then
we can try we can take the left
and not take the left plus take the
right and not pla
not take the right right am right yeah
so
so i don't know if this take
right take a left there are two
solutions they either take these or not
take these
and here is either take these on the
tables but we can only pick one right so
it will be the maximum of two choices
and then return we need to add at the
end we need to return dp
here uh dp load the maximum of dp rule
yeah so we'll return maximum of
dp load right because it should we take
two values but
for the root value we have two choice we
take we pick or not pick
and then we want to return the maximum
right yeah
this one is butter our top down
butter because we we are look we these
two locations we are delaying until the
bottom and once at the bottom the leaf
we know
uh the empty node we know the values and
we're building up the
dp values from the leaves to the loop
okay so let's bottom up dp
dynamic programming yeah dynamic
programming because we're passing the
value up but for the top down remember
the previous one
is recursion right recursion with
minimization remember
we use the cash yeah cash yeah cash to
build up the
to remember the over those values yes
top down
top down recursion top-down dynamic
programming
and these complexities oh and as well
yeah what's the space from black speed
what's the space complexity
[Music]
oh and yes because because for each
value we are we are we are traveling
only once from the bottom up yeah for
each note we
need to calculate two values take it or
not take it am i right
yes and then because look we take it
don't take it
this note we just need to to
this node can calculation needs to based
on the
two four values of its left and right
right
it doesn't care other values because
these are values
already don't directly affect these two
right it's already
there right it's the it's a it take left
take right now take left don't tell what
is the immediate is
its value is there right so we already
know
right am right does it make sense
any questions any questions
any questions ah okay i'm going to
i'm ready you ready
okay which speed you can you don't ready
okay i'm going to take this just this
take a look can you write a take a
little part
take a look take a little equals one
take a look if i take this value
if i take this
[Music]
and there's one thing you need to edit
plus do the value yeah we're done
okay looks really cool yeah that's it
that's it for today good job you can say
bye bye to people
bye bye bye bye