[Music]
hello hello
hello hello oh yeah baby
no no no that's not very polite
[Music]
hello ryan hello
okay so today i'm going to talk about a
little bit about
the list in python
and there's a few useful
python functions to control to uh to
manipulate the list okay
yeah so list in
python can you
can you sit down please so remind me
what is the list
list is the number one
yeah always you know already uh just a
list yeah uh
contains a few uh number elements yeah
so for example like n
one three five two four
this is the least right yes
okay one two three four five first
four seconds
so if we want to know how many elements
in the list
how many elements in the list do you
know how to get it
no we can use this function called
length
okay len n so this will give me length
and yeah how many one two three four
five
so if i want to know the maximum and i
can use this max
yeah and that will give me
maximum the maximum of n is one
two three four five the maximum of all
these numbers
is five yes and again
can you guess what's this mean
and what you will give me five
minimum i mean
i know i mean one yeah well and how
about this sum
some of all of them is 15
one wow that's quick 4 9
11 15 yes okay and
this is the basic yeah and how about
if if i want to know the average
yeah average do you remember what's the
average
the sum divided by number please please
the sum divide different number okay so
that will become
you can just do this sum and divide it
by
length and right that will give me
five numbers that will give me yes yes
if you want to be youtube you need to
behave otherwise i'm not uploading to
youtube do you understand yeah
okay so these are built-in functions for
python do you get
so it means that we don't need to
implement it
if you want to implement for example
this mean how do we implement
yeah if you want to implement this we
can just do this
if i yeah mean
yeah then we pick the first number okay
so which is the
answer answer is and zero yeah
this is bracket means the first number
yeah and then we
all we need to do for looping the in
all the elements in the list then check
if the answer comes the minimum if
the column minimum is smaller than the
animate in the list
then we replace the current element
equals
uh rep uh no actually
if answer if the current element is
smaller than the
current minimum then we replace it yeah
replace it with the current minimum
yeah okay yes i'm right
and then return return the answer yeah
yeah yes if i if the current element if
we find the element which is smaller
than the current
minimum then we replace it but but the
good thing is we don't need to
implement it because it's already built
in this function we can just use it
right yeah okay so now you know that
if we want to get the first animal we
use this n zero right
how about the second element how do we
get it um
[Music]
and one right yes this is the first
first element is n0 second animation c2
the next n2 is the third element right
it's always start with zero so how about
can you make a guess
n minus 1 what is that
what what can you guess can you just
guess
n minus one
what does it what does that mean from
this direction it will be the last
element right
and how about n minus two
it will be three no you'll be released
second to the left and minus one and
minus two and minus three is it one
sorry where is one one and one is three
and minus two is and minus one is four
and minus two is two
you see okay how about this
how about this n
two four
column four do you get it
two zero one two right this
is two yeah and where's four position
look where's four three four yeah this
is four
but this returns five and two up to four
okay
not including four don't get it this is
from
wrong and this is two yeah from two
right yeah okay so get it so this is the
important list
and how about we want to add one element
to it
at the end we want to add a segment to
73. so
and dot a pen you know this is a word a
pen
a pen seven independent yeah yeah a pen
and you cut you
put a seven here yeah you you can also
write it this way
n plus equal what bracket
and seven yeah so this is basically to
append another list attend another list
seven
until the end right and want to remove
this bit
remove the first element remember and
the top is zero right
this will give me one how about end of
top
top this is to remove the last element
okay
yeah so let's give me four
okay so now yeah this is pretty much it
okay
yeah okay goodbye to the to the keyboard
okay bye bye goodbye