go hello
hello mr ariel are you all right yeah
okay so can you tell me what's telling
drone remember we talked about this a
few while ago
perrin john what's paranormal um
when he reverses the
[Music]
yeah and it can be even number or all
number right
it could be something like e r r e right
no i'm just making anything up it's
[Music]
so do you still remember if we're given
a string or a list
yeah a string or this how do we check if
it's a pairing
remember how do we check if a list
at least or a string
at least or we call it a rare how do we
check if at least
string is a pending drum
reversal well yeah one way we reverse it
so
how if we if we s is the b or string how
can we check
return reverse it
s equals how compliment reverse this bit
um yeah this is the one
poison way to do it and another approach
is what how do we do it
um how do you look look at my hand
look at my hand
j equals the length yeah the length
minus one okay why are
i smaller than j right if
s i not equals as j
return y
plus plus and then i plus equals one j
minus equals one right that's the two
points i think yeah
correct yeah actually there's another
way third way
is that if we calculate the index how
many ways
are they quite a lot but this is the
most typical three one okay so look
look if this index is zero
what's the opposite in at the other hand
if this
is how many characters is it two four
six seven seven characters if this is
zero what's
this index
seven minus one minus zero okay if it's
one
what's this index seven minus one minus
one one yeah if this is two
what's the mean that's seven minus one
minus t yeah that's it
so we just compare i index i
with with what n minus one minus i
okay and we just compare these right
until the meter
yeah we just can we just need to con
from i from zero
to n divided by two yeah
we just need to go into the middle yeah
we don't need to go further right i'm
right
correct yeah okay so you understand
this complexity is all o n right okay
so how about the linked list we want to
check if a parent
is a penguin is in english what's the
difference here all right
what's the difference even list and
what's the list what's the difference
between this and a link list
list link list a link list
has numbers in circles
let's visu vivid visual yeah
that's how we visualize it right and
and connect it by line connected
okay so listen look at this is list one
two
three four right this is the list and
the link list is
one point point two point two three
point four okay so this is how we
represent it uh
visually the list is that the memory
is the continuous right so this is
comments
this is this is continuous so in memory
in memory you'll be just like that
these are together one two three four
right so it's
it's it's continuous if we know that no
if we know this
position of the one array we can
calculate two
and three and four that the computer
knows how to get the
value of two three four yeah it means
that access is one
or one complexity but for this one it's
not right i mean look
the one two one and two are not
it could be you know it could be
different right so it could be at
different positions so it could be
somewhere else come
somewhere else somewhere else right it
could be
ho ho it could be uh what's the sparsely
sparsely
allocated different way right this could
be as
yeah all right so how how do you
represent me for easy
yeah yeah no no you could be fine so
so at each note you will be your value
and then you will be your next
all right next so what we need over here
to start the next position
right am right that's the pointer to the
next okay
so this one you before you will be only
storing
four values right but this one we will
need additional next pointer to point to
next why because the next one
is not on its next it could be somewhere
else
so so what does it mean if we want to
get the value of three
we don't know yet we need to traverse
from the beginning
yeah followed by the one to the two to
the three so what does it mean what's
the term complexity of getting
number three
because we need to travel from the
beginning yeah yeah
well that's the difference here i didn't
i just touched your leaves okay
so what do you think yeah so
how is that different i mean so we can't
can we apply the equilibrium
the previous aggregate all right
can we apply the previous algorithm
maybe we can
the two pointer we can't right because
we only know
hey we only know the beginning here we
we are not
for example the two pointer thing yeah
two points i think we
we don't know the end right all right
and each note only points to the next it
doesn't point to the previous right
right unless
it's a two directional pointer yeah
two-dimensional increase so
meaning this way right all right can you
listen to me
oh yeah okay so can you repeat what i
said
it's like it can it can go
and it doesn't go to the
preview previous one it can get all over
yeah so yeah so for the two pointer we
only
we need to know the beginning and the
end and also
in order for the two pointers to work
the node has to
that node has to point to the previous
node as well but for this single
single increase we only point to the
next one
right it doesn't point to the previous
one how how how can we apply this
any idea
um one obvious example is
how you're holding
checking every possibility
[Music]
come on what's the what's what's the
difficulty here we know how to check if
a
array or a a string is pending term but
we
we are we want to apply the same
techniques on the linkage
so how can we do something to to do what
apply this diagram
[Music]
um
break it break it well like
split it in the mud
yeah we can split it but but what i mean
is that
is there a way that we can transform the
linkage to the
list so then we can apply the same
techniques right
yeah oh yeah that's very obvious to
think about
we know how to check at least uh uh
an array is a pairing drum
and then if we want to check the link
list the first thing to do is to
make it into um a linked list to a list
yeah yeah
okay so let's do it
number number four come on you need to
tell me okay
define let's say check
check
what do we need to do now start what do
we need to do
come on what do we need to do to what do
we say
what do we want to do now we need it and
this is the dude let's say no no
no no no no
[Music]
that's the note here at the beginning
know that it's here oh we need to
move we need to change it into
a link okay so should we define a list
okay so they say data equals how do we
define a list
[Music]
brackets and then what we want to
we want to what do we need to do now we
want to
work through the yeah we want to walk
in okay so while oh yeah why are data
while what why are not actually why or
not what should we do
what should we do with that why are not
what we why not is not the end it's not
the line
why not it's not the ang what should we
do now
which is
[Music]
one no
no the equals not the one
yeah but move to the next what before
moving to the next what should we do
we have the value what happened to the
value know the value
you need to um
change it into uh change it to what
know the value what happened to the know
the value
i i i'm currently a node and i have now
the value i can i know
already know the value and then i'm i'm
jumping to the node on the next one
but before that what what do i need to
do with the value
and put it in the data so how can i do
it
[Music]
data equals
data
a pen yeah
[Music]
what do we have the data is at least
at least the presentation of the english
so
we want to check how then what's next
yeah
what do we do next oh we need to return
what come up you can write it
come on we check we convert the node
into a data and we want to check in the
node if it's a link passenger
so what should we check checking out
[Music]
data
okay let's say we're converting these
we're converting that node to the data
and then we check the data instead
what's the time complexity for this one
i
come on if i ask you the space check for
any space we are allocating
uh one
why is one don't look i mean look at the
code come on
yeah why is the code where is the space
where we're allocating yes
this data stores the copies of the
values yeah that's it
okay so let's first way okay it's easier
for an english problem we convert it to
a list problem right
and we already know how to apply the
algorithm to check our list if it's a
paragraph okay
so remember what's a stack
what's a step remember
what's a stack uh it's
normally yeah what's the step first
[Music]
firstly so if look if
this this is one two
three two one if the increase is here
right
so if we travel these several days
remember previously we're putting in a
video at least can be used as a step
look if we put this into a list a step
so it's one one two three
two one right all right yeah one two
three two
one and then we we work again from the
beginning
so by here i work in the beginning i
take it one hour
and check if it's the same if it's the
same i move it to the next i take one
now
it's the same i'm moving to the next
take one now
[Music]
through from the head again and then we
take it from the big
from the end yeah a stack yeah correct
that we walk through this stack yeah so
we're like
this is the yeah look this is the
opposite order right
you see so if your parents are in the
option
oh yeah yeah got it yeah okay let's try
this
the second approach okay and remember at
the end
i want you to write one approach at
least one okay
i don't remember i did at least you tell
me how to do it okay come on
[Music]
what i think i need i think all of the
others are gonna be super long
no no look at this it's easy look at
check note okay now we use the stack
then we turn
stack equals at least yeah we can use
the list as a stack okay
come on yeah and then wire
why i know this part is the same so
yeah and what what what we shall pause
why not what should we do now we want to
put it in a stack so how can we do this
yeah put it in the stack okay so
tell me how to write it come on okay
um
append a pen open one note value
[Music]
all right now what's next
yeah let's call it head because no no
yeah
because we are changing the node here
okay now header is beginning now so what
should we do now
wire head
now now we want to compare the head
and the top of the stack so what's the
top of stack
this is st what's the top value how can
we get the top ready
but we if if the top of value is
head of value head head of value if it's
not equal to
top level very well so what's this
what's this this is st what's the back
of st
come on this is st 0
this is a stack this way yeah so what
what's the last element of st
st1 minus 1 yeah st minus 1
if it's not equal return
first okay now what should i do with the
head head
equals one and then st what
and then return what come on can you
tell me
i want to move three yeah listen to here
so what what happened to the head head
is there at the beginning
at the beginning i want to go to the
next one head
as well
yeah and then what happened to the step
step this is x take minus one and i want
to remove it
i want to take it out what should i do
st
yeah that's it what's the time complex
that's a
long one you're not remembering you need
to understand the approach
what's your space what's that
what's that's time conducting
um
we are going through the linked list
twice right all right yeah
the first first uh first uh first
pass is to place a note into the stack
the second pass is comparing right the
time complexity what's the space in
place
[Music]
okay okay okay let's see
i know actually we
we have two more approach okay look are
you kidding me
come on okay this is uh
look at it this is the increase yeah one
two three two one so
how can we get the middle of it remember
we talked about this
how do we how do we get the middle node
of the linked list
um we need that
what what how do we do it can you uh
what i think it's a rabbit and a turtle
rabbit yeah yeah yeah rugby and turtle
yeah rabbit the one which
i was very good at okay
okay so how can we how can we find can
can you explain
to me that how can we use the rabbit to
find the turtle okay
rob is
yeah so fast rabbit works two step at a
time and turtle works one several times
so look
my right hand he does twice
yeah two yeah yeah look look my right
hand is ready my
left hand is third okay okay let's go
look that's good two steps one two
one step two step
one step but it can't jump to the two
steps so that's the middle
slow the right the total will be this
low so
why are we wanting these meter
what are we doing with the meter
oh because either what happened to the
middle
why do we need the middle thing what
happened what's the turning zone
if we break it in the middle if we break
it in the middle
both sides need to be the same no no
no look not exactly one more step one
two
three two one if we break in the middle
so one two and two one so if we reverse
this bit
then you'll be the same as the first
okay okay
so we break in the middle and then we
reversely speed okay
okay okay let's try this okay
let's just check look uh note
okay fast equals load
equals no right at the beginning like
pointing to the first one right alright
okay
and fast to next yeah because it needs
to move two steps at a time
so what we do fast equals one slow
equals one come on
fast is because we're slowing forward
[Music]
sorry no fast equal
fast equal slow equals no at the
beginning they are pointing to the first
position all right
this is five equals nine sorry fast
equals no no faster equal is low equals
no so at the beginning
the first needs to work two step at the
time right
so what should i do with this plus
equals one
five equals two spaces
two bases what how can we move two steps
faster what
the link list first what's the next of
first
what's the first this is five what is
next
five plus one this is an english one
this is linked list link list
what do we do with the previous one why
not dot
no equals no to what next yeah fast
equals one
there's no note five we go over come on
so first it needs to work one more step
so how can the police
first equals faster next door
next yeah come on how high is that next
first
next next let's try look why
fast is not none and first next is no
none we want to move two step every time
okay
so now slow is the middle right all
right
yeah i know we want to reverse break it
and look
okay look okay so
here here is previous one yeah yeah this
is
this is slow here okay and then now i
want to
i look look at what i did i want to
reverse this piece
break it and reverse this make it this
way right make it this way yeah
all right i want to reverse this
direction
yeah yeah can you stop doing that
so at the beginning i won't have i will
have a right right
equals noun and now we have wire
slow and i want to
i want to save this value first p equals
load on x
okay and then what and then
slow down next
equals equals right yeah i want to point
it to back right
and then what should we do now
p equals no the next i want to this is
now p
p will be equals to here and then slow
down x
so the next is here i want to point to
the previous one right
which is none so i will remove this and
then here will be now
right right and then i want to move this
this is p this is slow and slow equals p
right
slow equals p
and p is this no no no no
actually it's right like the previous
one
will be equal to slow and then slow will
be equal to here all right
so right right would be slow and slow
with p
right all right so in this case we're
reversing that
uh right it was
do you understand this okay i'm going to
do it one more time okay look why the
equals numb at the beginning right
this is slow slowly
yeah i want to reverse this speed how
can i reverse this bit
first of all first of all i say this
value into p
yeah so i know this is p here right
look and slow down next equals right can
you tell me what's what's the slowdown
next equals y
slow down next i'll remove this equals
right here look
right at the beginning will be long
right and then y
equals no right will be equals no right
is here
and slow equals p slope equals p
right so slow b equals v and at the end
look at the end it will be
slow the legs and the next iteration
you're pointing this way
and the next acceleration from the
initial and at the end the right will be
which which node will be the right at
the end
which which now will be the right area
which node will be right at the end
one two three four which node the right
at the end
this is right that's the beginning and
why
look at it and then right because nurse
knows which one will be right at the end
just like me yes of course y equals no
look here
so it's right the slow yeah
so in the middle and then slow be moving
to the
piece another next so where at the end
of
this loop why is no which one which node
will be right come on i'm just asking
which node will be right
why why snow slow will be moving to the
end
[Music]
no no i'm talking about this one can you
do understand what this is mean
if you understand you know you know what
what's this bit
this is at the beginning this is slow
and what's this doing here
it's y equals none
next yeah and slowly slow down x equals
right
so you're pointing back y equals note
and slow equals p
facing this way yeah it's changing the
direction to this way so
what happened to this right at the end
what's the value of right at the end no
but y
equals slow you're moving this way come
on
so what's the right come on obviously
yeah that one the 15
so that would be because this is
reversing yeah so at the end
the right will be the increase so what
should we do now what should we do now
what should we do
[Music]
what should we do if i say left i have a
left
equals no so what should we do now
with left and right what should we do
we should should we start no we're not
sloping
so remember what happened to this
linkage one two
like if we break it into the half all
right
what we did is breaking it in half
and reverse this speed so look at e 1
2 2 1 and now reverse this bit
that's right yeah then i'll be one two
so what should we do with now this is
right
huh all right right is here and
left is here what should we do now come
on it's quite obvious come on
reverse it i already reversed it reverse
it
one to two let's check in it's the same
yeah chicken left and right but it's the
same okay so okay i'm gonna
erase this and then left right okay so
that's the easy part
wire left and right
right
if left top value
not equal right of value
what should we do if letter value is not
equal right already what we do
um
[Music]
and then what should we do with the left
hand left equals one and right equals
one come on
and then we turn what come on
next left equals left or next we're done
yeah and then we turn one okay yeah
we're just comparing left and right yeah
why is that because we already break it
into half and we watch the second half
so
the second half is star with the right
yeah the first half is starting with
left with the no yeah i was just
comparing yeah what's the time
complexity
what's the time of maxi
oh n what's a space complexity are we
using any space here this this approach
do we decide space we just mine or what
and
we are not using any space but the thing
is we are
modifying the list yeah we are making
changes to the original list i'm right
yeah okay
okay the last approach quickly we're
using recursion this is more advanced
okay
so define check
i'm going to write it okay no
not no why
what why do we call it node
if it's a tree that's a root right three
has a root if a node linkers
is not just one direction it hasn't have
a root right
okay it's just the numbing convention
so at the beginning note i will set it
to the beginning
uh okay so look
okay so the thing is that if i
i the thing is the the target if i want
to compare
i want to compare the parent release
that i want to compare this now which
original
which which you know we should know the
last one and at least no i want to
compare with original
the second one yeah we're done so look
we can use the recursion yeah let's call
it recursion dfs
node right if
not node we just return two right
okay and then i have an answer answer i
will check the next one
we see dfs no dot next
and then root will be equal
to at the beginning next
and then i can return answer that's it
okay i'll tell you later okay and i can
just return
d f s note that's it you see
is this simple look uh here i need to
add the access to this node so i will
add
one non-loader okay that's the syntax
you need to add
none longer route so he knows that when
when we
change this speed it's changing this
value not
not the scope inside this value so it
says non-local load means that this root
is here
not inside here okay okay so look
this is the recursion right if the note
is
nothing it returns true right an empty
node
an empty node a linked list is it a
pendulum
yes yeah okay then now i will check the
next one
but when these look when these this is
recursion when it goes only cause it
so at this point you will go you cause
it itself
cause it's until you reach the last
point last note
and when you reach the last note right
you wanted uh okay so there's something
missing here so i wanted to say
if i said we don't need to
say no no no no no
no at the beginning it's not okay so i
have to check it if little dot value is
not equal as
know the value and i want to i want to
return force here yeah
yeah i i want to return first so i will
go to the next
and then what's what what's the new
value is the beginning yeah
what's the last value that will be the
note will be
after the number will be last ready and
then
the load equals to the next so so okay
i'm going to
check this okay i'll tell you okay so
look
blue equals note at the beginning right
all right and then you'll call this
newton
recursion not next non-max dot next and
then it will be calling state
calling stack it will reach the last
point right then
you will check if you know the value
equals another value if it's the same
if it's not the same you'll return first
otherwise
do the value will go to the next after
recursion right
right and then this comes back will be
the previous one
right until it yeah does it make sense
the time contact is clone the space
complexity because we are using the
recursion is one right
yeah this one is a little more advanced
the problem is
why this work is because there's a stack
it's like a step and where is the step
is this recursion it's the recursion
recursion because every time we're
calling that recursion
right every time we call in the
recursion when these
goes to the end when this goes to the
end
right you stop here go to the end and
you'll come back
you'll come back you're calling step
you'll come back right correct
okay okay so i have talked about four
approach can you write the one
just one simple one define
check check rules okay no all right can
you guys see anyone
come on
anyone will be fine what's the first one
like i review it
convert it to a list yeah the second one
using the stack
the third one is the more complicated
one i hope you're not choosing that one
break find a meter break it into the
middle and then reverse the speed that
that's too much work
the first one the question do you
understand if you're not understanding
you can write it so i will sing the
first or second
how to start first i don't know how to
start off
sour okay tell me which one you you
understand
and i'll help you um
[Music]
come on it's your turn
yeah drop please i drew it on my finger
that's okay come on come on i didn't
know
what what do you mean which one does it
make pick which one
i don't know which one to pick the first
one maybe
convert it to a list that's the simplest
one simply
yeah you just converted this what
happened
if we want to convert it we just well
okay
okay let's try a list yeah how do you
define a list
let me which one
is on the first one or second one second
one is a step
yeah we walk through the link list
what does that mean advanced means it's
difficult to understand
and it's not it's not required if you
don't write it
and because it's harder to understand
is the second one with the stack yes
there yes
is it is it like this yeah what's this
[Music]
this is the third approach okay we
have the third approach we're breaking
into the half right
the step just and you you can use any
men to declare a stack okay come on
let me erica let me let me data let me
whatever okay come on great start
writing it
okay yeah write it
i need to put
keep going and then we want to put it
into the list yeah come on
um put it in this yeah
yeah and then we need to what what at
least yeah
something that's okay that's okay come
on come on come on we're taking what
time but at the beginning you need to
iterate until it reaches the end right
how can you
the wire keyword wire wire wire
whatever why your nose why
unknown because why not means that the
node is
not empty yeah why not yeah why not yes
okay column yeah and what should we do
put it in the link please come on
what should we do what have we done yeah
okay whatever
you need to indent come on have a space
in the beginning when you start with a
while
column okay what whatever the append
know the
value come on ready yeah come on
you see you name it whatever you should
write more
not a pen i didn't care oh come on
[Music]
no
but actually you can append no but you
you need to write more like
you know the value it's a value it's an
integer okay and now what's what
happened to the node
if we put this node into the stack
whatever this is a stack or list yes and
what happened to the node
we want to we don't know what indicative
yeah come on
okay and then i have whatever you want
to use it as the least so you want to
use it as a
stack we want to use it as
using this will be easier usually yeah
okay and then whatever
whatever it's this you want to check if
it's apparent how can you invite it
um we already know that yeah the titan
right how can we write it come on we can
write
whatever return whatever what return
whatever
whatever what equals what return
yeah okay yeah
whatever
[Music]
whatever you want to come
compare if it's a parameter so how can
we like ever
yeah well you remember this nice minus
one not top one okay
i did okay that's it that's it for today
say bye