go hello hello miss area
yeah okay so today's class is a bit
simple okay i
i believe you can do it okay so given a
string a
b b a c d
e e f i want you to tell me what's the
first
unique characters first unit a
b c d e f
what which one is the first unique
character a
is a
[Music]
a appears twice b appears twice c appear
once yes
d appear once e appeared twice f
appeared once so
the first unit could be c because it
only appears one right
okay if if it's a a b
b there's no unique characters and
you need to tell me it's minus one if
it's uh look at this one you need to
tell me it's 0 1 2
3 4 index 4 yeah but the first character
in the x0
yeah it seems very simple simple
hey remember how can we solve this
um yeah how can we solve this
we all have the data structures that
we're going to use
why would you listen to a point how are
we using the two points
um wait wait oh hold on
what's this yeah
[Music]
we have one point is a and you check
through the list
and see if there's another a i think i
think that's briefcasing
uh-huh okay so yeah this is if i'm at a
i want to check the rest if you say a
yeah yeah
if i'm b i want to check if they are
less they are b they have two b
so in this case you if there are n
characters
what's the time complexity and i think
it's
2 pi over 2 and square because for each
n you need to say for look for i
if n equals length of d let's say s
yeah s in range
n right and then i i need to do what for
j in range
another n as well if
look if i not equals
j if the index is known here j and
and what s i not equal x
yeah equals x three right so let's say i
have a duplicate
uh i have this unique
unique equal at the beginning i set it
to true
and then here i set it to unique equal u
n i q
u e equals one fourth right and i found
this i need to break it
and then if i say if unique
if i say unique then what happen
i is the first index then i can just
return
one i will be from
zero to so look i will be from zero to
n yeah for each eye i will for
j another loop from j from zero to n
but if it's not equal to b and if if
index here
is the same as this one the the
character at index
j equals at the index i
and what should i do if i integrate with
j i know
why because we found it unique yeah
after all is if his unique is true
means that look here we see look at
i even see there's no such index that
other than this index which is
has the same character c then this unit
would be
true right and then if i release then i
will return
which value i oj i think that's okay
i all right come on and then we ten
minus one here
what's the time complexity all in square
because here with your end and you're
another
yeah can we optimize it to our end using
kind of bigger structure
remember this is quite okay yeah
notebook
knew it so we first go through the
array uh to find to count how many
characters
how many how many times that
each character appears in an array right
yeah
okay so look
oh if we wrote that out that's a cop
c equals
what kind of default dictionary
dictionary dot com defaultionally and
it's an integer value is initial so for
i in s
c i wa
c i c is the dictionary and then c i
i is the letter and i want to count how
many of them so what do i need to do
c i y plus plus
c plus equal one
how many times i now
one yeah okay then look for
i look remember for i j
in immune can you tell me what's
immunity we'll talk about this
again yeah look s is this yeah
s is this enumerate just make it what a
tuper
look this is a b b a c
d e e f alright look okay
this is s right this is the s yeah right
if you say if you fall i
in s i will be a b b a like that right
you'll be iterating this
yeah okay yeah and if i put a
numerator what does it mean that'll be
the index
0 1 2 3 4 it would be two per
for each one right so i will be zero one
two three four five
and j will be one it's a pair
i will be zero please one two three
will be the other abc yeah this one so
okay look
if this look if one so what do we do
this
i is index j is the value so what do we
need to check here
if if um
if one is unique yeah how to check
c c u r c what equals what
equals one see what equals one
c i i i index oh j
c j yeah i i is the index
j is valid okay
i and index begins with indexes
the first one you can name it a b c or
whatever yeah a b
c d
is
come on index which one i z between i or
j j
i come on why is it confusing you just
said
okay i can't i can't make
[Music]
okay so let this thing look remember
this thing
what we talk about we can we connect we
click we can replace it with a
kind of python already have these to
count the number of the
times that each element appears what
does it call
see what see um
come on
[Music]
what are we doing here we we are
counting the number of times for each
character appears yeah so
when he's doing we you will have a
dictionary called this yeah
a appears two times right key value b
up here two times c appears one time
right d
appear one time e appears two times f up
here one time
key value pair right key key
value right so we are counting the
number we are counting the number of the
elements for each characters yeah for
each girl so what
in person we can use kind of objects
what c
[Music]
so all these i can erase all this
to what counter
c equals what counter called uh
it's from collection package collection
yeah
[Music]
is the same as this one what's the time
complexity
[Music]
oh
if i tell you if i tell you
if i tell you that the input is only
contains
only lowercase characters from a to z or
uppercase characters from a to z
what's the time complexity a1 why is
lower
because like wait does it catapult
catapult a and lowercase a count as
a new okay so if because look
space complexity yeah if we use the
counter
if i don't tell you that the string
contains only uppercase or lowercase
character it could be any right
it could be any right yeah so the worst
case
is that in the worst case is that
the end the string contains n characters
they are all unique
right so you need a counter attachment
to store
to be able to store n characters right
yeah
that's in the worst case aware but if i
tell you that the
the characters they are only uh
the s only contains uppercase all
lowercase characters and what's the
maximum
possibility that the lowercase uppercase
how many uppercase characters or how
many lowercase
26. 26. so in the worst case what
happened
that we only need the hashmap contains
only 26
so to be able to stop 26 yeah because
abc we know it's already 26 so a and
look it's constant right because we
already know is 26.
no matter how big is your n a minion
characters
yeah if there are minion characters but
if there are million characters and
characters only contains lowercase
characters how what how big of this
counter
do we need
how many how big is the counter we need
how big is the size of the counter
26 26 exactly because we just need a to
z to count how many
times does it make sense so in this case
it doesn't change
the the size of the space sudden change
doesn't grow doesn't
grow or doesn't shrink depending on
regardless of this size of s right so
it's constant
right but if i don't tell you it's
lowercase letter if a million characters
there could be a million different
characters unique characters right
so in the worst case the
the size of the space could be n right
correct that's the difference between y
y is one or one okay so look
if i tell you it's a lowercase character
so i don't need these right
i can just store this c equals
zero away times 26
right 26 and then i just need to do this
i just need to read four for
i in s c
i want to map remember if it's lowercase
what's a to ascii do you remember
what's the a to ascii the ascii code
a what was it again 96 97
yeah and i see seven you've got it right
okay so which function i need to convert
from a to
to 97. no
there are two of choice or d or chr
which one
r d o r d with an i
right yeah this converts to 97 and i
need to minus 97 right
yeah plus equal what
c is it's like a key value it's the same
yeah this is the key
except that this is a array with index
from 0 to 25
26 and a if a is 97 i minus 97 is zero
so it's like i have 26 buckets
and every time i meet the a i want to
increment
increment what's increment mean plus one
yeah plus one
okay and here look for either this is
the same yeah
no no no j j is the
j is the value right so what do i do
with the j
what should i do with the j yeah what
should i do
j is the value and i want to map it to
the index of the bucket
so what should i do
[Music]
ord is 97 i want to map it to 0 to 25 so
what
come on it's there ascii
order j minus 97. yeah that's what i
mean yeah
exactly because look or ascii -97
what's the if it's lowercase what's the
range of these
what's the range it's the lowercase the
characters
i is the lowercase character and what's
the range of this
what's the range of this um
97 i is a lowercase character what's the
red what's the smallest
a yeah i know what is a minus 97 is what
zero what's the biggest um z which is
um do i need to do uni actually need to
know
minus ninety seven equals one how many
calculators are
six zero to twenty six or twenty five
twenty five twenty five
okay so this is mapping from 0 to 25 and
then here j is again
so mapping from 0 to 25 i want to check
the bucket
well basically there are 26 buckets if i
meet one a i plus 1 if i mean
b two then there'll be two here right so
i go through these
buckets and if it's one that's the first
unique character right
let me return the index otherwise by
this one sorry
yeah yeah okay so now you need to tell
me you need to implement at least one
i'll tell you already are you kidding me
yes no define okay
first you need come on i agree with this
song
okay remember the counter thing come on
tell me
come on come on count c equals counter
okay okay then what's this counter s
okay
and then look what
we want to when we want to go through
from the beginning four come on come on
write it
you need to you need to practice to
remember otherwise you just
can't understand and remember okay and
what should we do if we have this c
object and we want to go through from
the beginning to the end usually
enumerate
the force okay for
for for i
comma j remember which is index which is
the value
i is in that okay in human life yeah in
numerator
enumerate yeah bracket immune level
we want to enumerate a string
so which is the string what's the
parameter f
index j if which one is the the counter
you see
only one character with intended index
otherwise
yeah yeah
yeah yeah four in the loop yeah of
course yeah
so this is the loop we are looking now
we're looking for each loop
what we don't want to do we're going to
do is put it in the body
here so that's why we have a space there
if what
can we write it faster right if what
[Music]
what's the how can we check the number
of
the frequency of the the number of times
it appears in the stream
where is this where is this stored
and where is the waste store here which
one is here
counter and what's the name of the
counter c
yeah okay if c what
yeah see what c
is the and then you want to start with
the key key value bracket remember come
on you need to remember
see yeah what's the what's the
key what's the key um which one
yeah j yeah it's a value
yeah closing yeah if this one no no no
no no
what does it mean by unique what does it
mean unique
unique means like how many times it
appears
one okay equals one equal equal one yeah
column come on i'll return what return
return i don't say come on return i'll
take here
yeah come on it's not that hard right
you understand you just need to remember
this index and we can
return what here if we not follow the
return minus one yeah
okay
minus one okay
that's it for today bye