go hello hello mr area everybody
yeah okay so today we want to talk about
the numbers
let's say one five 153
this is a very special number okay why
is this why how many digits these have
three three digits okay three digits and
one to the power of three plus five to
the power of three
to the power three plus three to the
power three equals
how many can you give me answer one to
the power three because this is there
are three digits
so it's technically one times three yeah
so one
yeah plus five times right and five
um 125 yeah plus
three times three seven okay how many
153 okay so what does it mean
yeah so it's the same we call this am
song armstrong
number okay okay
okay so today's task given the number we
want to check if it is satisfying at
least
right
[Music]
so i give you a number let's design a
accuracy
check if if it's this kind of number
okay
okay okay okay so in order to design
this
it's just a name in order to check
the first thing is to do what um
to do what what do we need to do three
tickets
so we want to okay so first task is
how many digits yeah how many
and digits second task is what
the second time to the power of the
digits
sum of power of digital sum of
power of digits yeah
correct and then let's just check okay
so
okay so look how many digits given us
integer
how many did you how can we do this how
how can we check if it's not
how many digits how many digits okay
let's take this one by one okay
so how many digits given the 153
how do you know how many digits
[Music]
yeah how do you know it's three digits
it's not string if we just string
if we just string we can use the length
right yeah
lens that now giving you three right
okay so
first uh so what to do if if
it's a string we know it's three digits
so we can
do what in order to get this
yeah in order to use this function what
do we need to do
we what do we need to do come on this is
a number we want to convert it to a
string right
how do you doing string yeah how do we
convert it
one five three into one five three
remember
join no no no no come on string come on
using the str if it is str153
it you'll give me this and how do you
convert 1533
from string to integer which function is
that the opposite what's
functioning not string integer int comma
you forgot that
integer yeah integer one five three now
give me give me one five three okay so
if we convert the
numbers to the string now we can get it
yeah that's one way
right that's one way
okay so we can just say okay define
the number of digits number digit
and okay so one way is what return
lens what
what come on i just told you um
the number yeah what number
1.3 this is n okay so we want to convert
it to
we want to convert it to a string
str n
okay that's one way the other way is
what
the other way is what
answer equals yellow wire
and answer
plus equals 1 and divided by 10
right written answer this is another way
i i
i told you i will tell you what what
does it mean eric look
iterate basis 153 okay
if one 153 is bigger than zero right
yeah okay this only works for the
positive number okay by the way if it's
not yellow that's a plus one there now
answer
i plus one right and so become one
and divided by 10 so what does n become
n is now divided by 10.
[Music]
okay but it's integer this is 15
okay and next one is n is 15 bigger than
zero
yes yes answer
plus one that becomes
two okay 15 divided by ten
um one yeah one
okay is one bigger than zero yes answer
plus equals one
three and divided by ten
1 divided by 10 um 0.1
okay zero okay because it is integer you
see y n may be quick okay
so what does it mean look one side three
becomes
one phi becomes one becomes zero every
time i get rid of the one
the digit i can read all the very much
distance
okay that's the way to get the number of
digits got it
yeah another way another way
another way look 153
okay equals what
10 to the power look how many 10 to the
power 1
10 to the power 0 is one ten to the
power one
ten ten to the power of two
ten to the power of three
um ten
thousand i think
a thousand okay so what does it mean
look
at 10 10 to the power of a
equals n right
equals n and then
what a equals
log 10 to the n right
10 to the power of a equals m you can
write it this way
right so we want to know the number of
digits a right 0.12
yeah okay so if we if the
n so we can just do this mathematics
okay
return so integer we want to convert
this to integer
master log you can also do it log 10
yeah also you can do the math dialogue
and base 10 base 10 this is the same as
log 10 and this is the same okay
okay that may say log 10 look at that
here
you still remember a lot yeah log n yeah
over again what's the time complexity of
sorting
array
yeah x y okay
uh so least log 10
and plus one okay let's say 153
maybe no n equals a hundred
a hundred how many digits
um three okay log ten a hundred equals
one
log ten a hundred ten log ten
hundred ten to the power of one equals a
hundred
two two so this equals one two
two integer converter integer two two
plus one
three three digits okay let's try
another number
a thousand why are you just keep doing
um no i'm just wanting to know ten to
the log ten thousand
equals one thousand
[Music]
three three three plus one four digits
correct so that's the way to get the
number of vision once we get the number
of digits
then we want to compare we want to uh
check okay define is
armstrong right
so okay n and what should we do
let's say every let's say we know the
digit the number of digits let's say dj
equals get digits yeah
number of digits get number of this we
already
know how to do it right n okay
and then how how should we check if the
sum of the
power of the digit
can you can you tell me how to write it
it's not difficult this is an easy
question
answer equals zero this is the sum right
right and how can i iterate the numbers
how can i iterate the numbers one three
one five three how can i iterate these
numbers
uh
[Music]
divided by 10 and return one
come on
so we want to check if answer equals one
come on can you feel the brand come on
[Music]
this answer is the sum of 1 to the power
3 plus y to the power three
plus three to the power so we want to
check which number is equal zero
why is it zero what's the question oh
um think you're not thinking at all
what's the question
okay so what's this this is the easiest
way answer equals one
um
[Music]
wait what what's which value is 153 the
key number and yeah put it in there come
on
is it ha okay and then what
answer i want to sum the digit of each
one so what what's the current digit
what's this current digit n is 153 and
what's number three here
and what how do you guess number three
from 153
um divide um
what i give you two one is this the
other one is this which one
so how do you use this to get 153
to get a three rounds
yeah okay what's 153 and
my mother
[Music]
153 more there is one come on it's not a
hard question right
yeah okay that will be confident this is
this is the easy question
okay that's one way what's the time
complexity
is log 10 n right because that's the
number of digits
that's the number of digits right
correct yeah
okay so the other way the other way is
we can convert it to a string
right we can convert it to a string
s equal s t r n right here
okay then answer equals zero and i can
just fall
i in s
answer plus equals
one oh the previous one remember it's
time to time it
so it's actually i i i need to convert
it to integer and remember previously i
forgot this
the digit yeah what's this
double two two stars square
to the power okay so look three
star star two this is equals to three to
the power of two right
it's oh you can write it this way power
3 2 okay
okay so this and then return
answer equal equals
and right the previous one okay i forgot
okay
let me write it again okay answer equals
yellow and you tell me why
why n and
answer plus equal
and divided by 10
star star one digit d
yeah you forgot this period and and
[Music]
answer equals okay
that's one way and we can just do this
return sum
we can sum this yeah sum what
some integer
i start
okay integer id but what's i we know d
what's i for
i in t
r m right this is
one line yeah for i in star and
and then we want to sum this part yeah
so basically we want the sum
look some flowers digit
sum in i power
d times times t so we want to sum
somewhat i to the power of d t
is the number of digits we want the sum
of i
i is what for i in
n but n is a star we want to convert it
to star
okay and then look we take this sum we
need to check it
equal equal
[Music]
okay
okay i'm going to answer equal zero
why uh something
uh wait wait wait answer plus
equals something okay and and
something return
and something okay can you feel the
blank
[Music]
wait wait wait wait wait what's this
and what was 10
[Music]
i think you did a bracket
and you did star
[Music]
equals 10.
oh yeah
wait the last one is a little
bit
[Music]
is
n equals one which is the sum where's
the sound come on
n is the origin number where is the sum
which one
which variable keeps the sum of the
digits
come on the previous one i yes
previously
i asked you to feel the end and now i
[ __ ] i still feel it
okay so you can hear
that's it that's it for today good job
we're done
okay say bye bye bye
bye bye bye bye say hello bye-bye