hello hello mr are you right
remember a few days ago we talked about
uh the island we want to counter the
number of islands right
one yeah one is the land zero is the
water right
yeah right
so how many remember how many how many
islands are there we only count how many
three
so do you still remember what what do we
do the other day
how can we do it
remember what kind of aggregate do we
therefore search so therefore search
so today the task is quite similar but
we
are we want to find out the largest land
the largest of them so which one is the
largest this one good
what's the size of it four
and yeah okay so any idea how we can do
it is the same
this is similar or what you just do that
creates anything and then you just
return them
max over instead of counting yeah right
it
is a slightly big difference right let's
do this okay yeah yeah but but it's
still there for search right
yeah it's
max max then right let's do it max then
all right now we we we have this m okay
color okay so now we want to find out
the rows
rows equals lens
m right what does this mean
what does it mean so
so which one is it which one is it
if this is the magic this is m
if this is m what's left m
what's left so which one which one can
you tell me which direction
which one is it this one or this one
this one yeah yeah okay and then
remember them
and
if one of the dimension is zero then
there's no point to continue because the
there's no landing okay now we want to
define
uh answer here answer at the beginning
is zero okay we want to
update this with the maximum yeah
previously this answer is to count the
lambda of the lens right
yeah but now we want to define the
therefore search look define
that first search so what
what's the definition doing here what's
that what's
what are we doing here that the devil
search
i mean what are we doing here do you
still remember
i mean what's this function supposed to
do it's
supposed to count
to count what no no no we we're not
counting today we want to return the
maximum
land size of that maximum length
so what is this supposed to do in this
case you return well
it's not returning a maximum you would
return what the size of the land right
okay okay so what does it need to do
take the parameter what does it need to
take
rows and columns the current pixel right
and then you will return
the number of the the size of the lens
right okay look
if r is out of boundary if it's smaller
than zero
or what c is smaller than zero or
r is bigger or equal than rows or
or c is bigger than equal and columns
return if it's all the battery what will
determine
zero yellow because there is no end okay
and then look
if it's not out of the battery if m rc
equals zero
right if it's zero what does it mean if
the water what should we return
[Music]
what's your return what's the size of
the water
the size of the water we are counting
the size of the land
and if it's the water what should we do
then the water
and we have it um
the deficit no no no
come on if it's land what if it's land
we are only interested in the land
and if it's water we don't care right so
what's what should we do
what should we do in this case we turn
return
i know can you tell me what's next
can you tell me what's next do you still
remember
now at this point it's a land is one
right
yeah okay then if i have answer equals
one and
what's right i should change the length
to water remember
remember what what are we why are we
changing the length of the water
oh so we don't come back
[Music]
okay and then now we need to expand to
look alright look here for example here
this is one right yeah we know it's size
one
and we want to we want to do what we
want to check on the neighbors
yeah we want to check on the neighbor in
four direction
right can you look at me look at the
ball
oh yeah okay can you tell me what to do
like next
so we basically um we do anything
that um
what well we are here we want to
we want to get the size of his
neighborland right
that was the deficit right yeah so we're
doing something like um
answer plus equal you can do a four or
you answer equal one
therefore search what's the fourth
direction um
[Music]
um ah minus one see
what what's next um last one c and
what's the another two
theme minus one uh
c plus one yeah oh you can do this with
four four d x d y in four direction and
then you can do it like
like that yeah our answer then return
what
do you think don't let me say it's quite
dangerous
what's the number what's the function
returning
answer yeah it's an answer because
answer is the size of the land okay
yeah got it returned
so now now what should we do
now what should we do now we show
we should go through the look we should
we should also uh
yeah r in range ah right
goes to each pizza right four c in range
pizza right
hello ryan yeah interesting hello say
hello to people hello
hello okay can you look we're going
through each pizza
all right he's crying right we're going
to eat pizza and then what should we do
we jump we should do what um we can
set the maximum yeah so answer equals
one
equals zero
we're going through each each picture
and then now
the next length is the dns with the
max what area the dfs function what's it
what should we put the left we
it's definitely what i said
for i we are going to each pixar and why
are we defining the different search
function come on
next one i literally just said that
next one um
and then come on
unless one parameter
max max of two thing next at least you
need to give a max with two things
so what's the other what's what's the
the other value where
we need to compare the next with the
other islands huh
other ones
the answer equals next what
[Music]
answer and then
another parameter what are we comparing
supposedly
yeah come on how high is that and then
we can answer yeah
yeah because this is four directions
so look here all right look rc rc
start with that ah here c here right and
then you would call this device to
change all this picture to
dll and then return what we
turn the max
come on what's this once you're going to
return d5 is here
yeah so so what's this return here
what's the value returning here
so what's that
how many five okay and then after we
turn five
what what happened to these ones um
you become what's yellow yeah why is it
becomes yellow can you point them
which landed because
um which line of code is it changing to
yellow come on point to me which line of
culture needs
yellow
[Music]
yeah yeah come on it's here all right
yeah okay so look
and then next one is zero you'll be
immediately returned yellow at this
point yeah it doesn't count it again
right
here here you when it goes to this point
this piece up
what it will do here can you tell me
when r and c style is here can you tell
me what happens
[Music]
yeah i mean so what happened to this
answer yeah
iso will return return
i'll make it to zero yeah make it to
zero and what do you think what
and you don't need two so this is still
bigger
so answer answer is already four yeah
four and this
will be two so two and four oh five five
five and two so which one is bigger
next to five okay so the answer will not
be changed
that island will return one and it will
change this to here okay
so what only the difference then then
previously is what
what's the difference previously
you just need to return
return what if you want to count the
number of lengths
[Music]
of them
so the previously previously
previously here yeah
previously we just have to change this
to what
answer plus equal therefore
rc then we these will be the number of
lengths right
but here we we we don't need this we
don't need this
and we just need to return what yeah
[Music]
answer plus equal if this is length
i only count it once right so this
should return
come on what one one yeah because return
one will be that of one piece right
right got it yeah does it make sense the
only difference is this bit right
correct yeah
okay now changing back so do you still
remember changing back
come on don't return
yeah this is written answer and then
answer
equals one can you tell me answer it was
over here
really it should be one because now at
this point it's at l is one side right
one answer one
plus equal right return answer and then
now look
answer equals what can you tell me you
already know before
max maxwell
come on write it quickly not soon
yeah i see you rc rc
rc is the coordinate of which pieces
yeah and then come on i know what
okay that's it that's it okay what's the
term complexity
what's an island
but yeah the number of the pixar is
matching okay pictures
okay that's it for today bye-bye