i give you a string with numbers like
1 3 two two
five six yellow
okay so can you find one
so a string with number one two three
four oh yeah
what is this me
a string of numbers yeah a string can
you find the largest
number which is what largest odd number
is five
no no no can you largest odd number it
can be more than one digit
35 13
and 225 you mean this one
no no no 15 200
[Music]
zero zero five o five
zero okay what's the biggest what's the
largest odd number
22 20 2006.
[Music]
before wow brilliant wow
that's very clever yes yes that's
exactly the strategy
and if we can't find anything any old
number like that
then you return nothing okay because
there's no odd number right you can't
make
a number right but yeah you all right we
stand from the right hand side
to the left we stop until we meet the
first odd number
and then we can construct a largest or
number by
by picking up all the chunks right
before that right
here again okay okay let's look at this
okay
okay today you'll be going to be a quick
one yeah because you got it yeah
okay defy a quick one largest
or number yeah s
so okay so can how can we write it
we need an answer
we need to answer actually let's do
what's the first number what's the index
right no no no we start from the right
into the left minus one
okay but then we start with length as
minus one and what's the stop
stop
what's the second parameter minus one
what's the third parameter
we want to find out if it's odd number
so how can you write it
if this this this character this fight
is a odd number if i convert it to
individual now what do i do
[Music]
we until we need all numbers yeah so
this is all if we check if this is all
numbers
then we return the chunk before it yes
so how can i check if this one is odd
number
please integer um modulus one
more than two but equal one right i know
we return chance of it yeah return
s how can i return trunk away
no no no i'm now at i position index i
yeah right like look this is here
right yes look at that this is i right
this is string now i is at this position
so how can i return chunk up to this
point
remember remember it is from two and
then you can
[Music]
minus one minus or plus one comma minus
one is less than this one
plus one even plus one but y is plus one
plus one not including this point yeah
actually yeah yeah remember this syntax
from two right
yeah from two actually is index from
here this is what two minus one remember
yeah that's the two
to get it it's like range function range
one two three okay what does it return
went one three um four from
two sorry no no no range one three
one two it does not equal three up two
this is the same thing okay
up two okay okay three okay
return left three times
okay and then can i have a rubber please
what was the rubber
okay okay if if no then we just return
empty string yeah
that's it yeah what's the term
complexity
what's up
[Music]
yeah you know what's k what's n the
number of
the number of the length of the string
okay the length of string okay got it
okay so look what's this okay that's it
one you did the hardest line yeah of
course i did it hardly this is
this is essence of this whole thing we
want to check if that integer and i
is uh is it
if if what
we want to convert this to integer how
can i convert this to from
36 minutes
[Music]
and then it will be the end no yeah not
yet
i sorry yeah but then now let's uh let's
introduce
for today bye-bye happy happy cookie
cookie happy happy