hello hello miss larry are you all right
okay okay can you stand up please okay
so
we're talking about the lines today okay
the line
so look given the two points if there
are two points on the white space how
many straight lines can you draw across
the
two points how many
how many straight lines
just one yeah you can only draw one
right
this is the shortest distance right only
you can only throw away you can't draw
more than one straight line but you can
draw some some curves yeah
oh yeah yeah okay but only one straight
line
only one straight lens if these two
points are not the same
right if there are these two points
collide each other
then you can draw as many lines as
possible but we are talking about two
different points
also this space okay so now
this is the line so
so look given uh x-axis
y-axis and we can represent the line
mathematically using this
y equals k x plus b
where k and b here are constants are the
numbers that we already know
they won't change constants and the k is
called a slope
okay the line of snow what's that slope
mean what does it mean
what does it mean the slope
slow is okay okay so if two lanes have
the same slope
what what is it what's the relation of
two lands let's
have the same slope
well done good job the parallel yeah if
there are two two
lines all the lines which have the same
slope
some k here they are in parallel okay
and b is the offset of that look for
example yeah
uh let's say y
equals y equals x
okay k one k is one b is zero okay eric
look okay come on come on
when k is one b is zero so this function
is
y equals x right so where is line going
to be
is it passing the number zero
yeah y equals x what's the line
going to be be like so how hard we make
sure you say
because we already know there are two
points if we can pick up two one when x
equals zero right what's why
so it passes this one yeah when x is one
why
what's the value of y one okay so it's
one one yeah
so one is here one zero okay so what's
the line going to be
you just you just connect these two
lines why you connect this way
this is the length one one yeah yeah
yeah yeah so this line is going to be
like that right
okay this is y equals x all right yeah
okay so look if y equals x plus
one what's line going to be
[Music]
what's the when x is zero what's the y
um x is one so here okay
okay as i say it's parallel yeah so you
should be something like that right
right that's the y axis look we can we
can double check this is minus one right
when x is minus one what's the value of
y
yeah minus one is zero this is y y is
zero right
okay so look we could prove that yeah
we visually we can see that when k
is the same slope is the same the lines
are paired in parallel okay
just the different values of b okay so
now
if if k is zero if the slope is zero can
you draw
any line which it the slow e equals zero
k
equals zero so you'll be like y equals
zero times
x plus b can you draw let's say zero
plus like
one what's the what's the big line going
to be if k equals zero
slope is zero b equals one and then that
would be y equals zero x plus b
and we know zero times anything would be
zero so y equals one
so can you talk to me where's the y
equals one
yeah yeah yeah so you'll be like that
yeah no matter
how big how big or how small any value
arbitrarily the value of x y will be
always one right
yeah we can see from the graph yeah
that's what it means
yeah so that's very useful to a
mathematics tool
to to visualize the land okay so now
today's task is very very similar
or maybe not simple but you know not
simple nothing but okay so given a few
points a on any endpoints okay
number endpoints encoding the endpoints
on the on the whiteboard and we want to
know
for example
the number of maximum
okay for example here the number of max
the max number of points that are on the
same line
okay so so basically we want to find out
a line
that crosses that crosses the most point
so in this example how many how many the
maximum number of points
how many number of the points you can
get here
what's the line going to be and then i'm
thinking like
yeah yeah we're done it crosses one two
three four and if you can draw another
line here but you're only crossing
three point yeah that's what it means
okay
so end point how can we
how can we solve this problem what's
your idea
what have we spent most of time
discussing the
concept of land in the last five minutes
[Music]
what's the concept you learned before
previously the line
y equals k times x plus b what's this k
so if i draw the line here these two
and if i draw the line here here
what happened what happened to these
these slopes any
combination of these these two leads to
these two lists to
mysteries too what happened today
what happened to the slogs i mean
what are the stuff it's like
um i'll understand
them yeah if they are on the same line
their slope
must be the same right yeah that's what
i mean okay so
we have n points we can prove forcing
the pairs
how many pairs are we talking about here
what's the term complexity if you want
to
proofread and n pairs remember
what's the time complexity oh
yeah and put so actually is n times n
minus 1 divided by 2 but this is o n
squared okay
1 square pairs yeah one square
uh so we we can profit one square
and then we can group we can count how
many
for for each pair we know the slope yeah
so look
this slope and then this slope is the
same now we increment one right and this
group
is the same with increment one so that
will be look what
one two three that would be three this
counter would be three
right and then look if we if we choose
this this
point and then we prove us this this
pair work
yeah and this the counter will be two
right
so this is the maximum number so we want
to find out the maximum number of these
values which is the number of the
number of the pair of the lines which
have the same slope
and if there are three pairs of lines
which have the same
slope and how many points are there
there are three pairs one pair of okay
one pair of points one pair of
uh there's one pair of the
one pair how many points two two pairs
how many points
four
i mean okay one pair two points
two pairs how many points three three
pairs how many points
oh it's plus one okay that's what i mean
okay yeah yeah
got it yes because each
each pair you have got the same same
slope
and then first of all these three is
number of the times
of the slopes counter and we plus one
which is the number of points yeah okay
so
let's try this quickly okay can you
stand up please
define a max
point and we have a coordinate
s and will be the length of
coordinates so this is the number of
points yeah
all right if n is smaller than three
what does it mean if
we only have two points so how many how
many lines can we have
one yeah two points if they have two
points what
does it mean two points then the two
points will be the lamb
let's say that so we just written two
okay yeah
and we assume that n is bigger than one
okay
because that doesn't make any sense if
we only give
one nine right right uh one point right
if
there's only one point you have can have
uh how many lines
across the point lots infinity okay so
if n smaller than three uh
maybe we just make it uh explicit if n
equals two return two right
if there are two points and these two
points are on the same line right
that's it so now for we want to iterate
for i
in range don't do this range
we start from 1 to n
i'll show you why
and then let's say x one
x two equals c o r d
s i okay then this is the first point
yeah
there are points here and we want to
iterate for uh
uh it will it proves the pairs this is
the first
the pair of the the first point of the
pair and then for
j in range
up to i okay up to i
after i and then uh no xb
x1 y1 okay x1 y1 and x2
y2 equals codes
so let's put i of j here come on
for j in range i x 2 y 2 equals
uh chords what i ordered
come on i t here this is the first point
j is here so what's your
and now let's so and here at this point
here we want to put a slope here in the
dictionary so when i say slow
slopes how do you define a dictionary
curly brace you can do this but let's do
a better way which is before dictionary
yeah
this particular one and in interviews
but before time yeah don't do that okay
okay so okay and now yeah you can do
this but look
this is a dif what's the difference
between these before dictionary and here
and and we open this
if a key doesn't exist in the default
dictionary
it won't you won't throw any errors but
look if i said d equals this and if i
want to say
d one
equals zero then
uh you know t one plus
equals zero one then that's that's not
going to work
right if you use this syntax because d1
is not existent
you know report error but for this one
that's okay because
it doesn't exist then it treats it as a
default value which is zero or default
dictionary so
we use this okay before additionally and
then
another the slow slope equals what
what's the slope what's the slope look
here
this is slow slow this this slope
slope equals this distance look this
decision
all right this distance
the y distance data divided by distance
x distance so you'll be theta y delta x
so this is one this is one that's that's
uh
that the k will be one and how about
this
if i have another small slope lines this
is two this is one that'll be two right
so this is y equals x this is y equals
2x
you see how do you get a 2 delta y
divided delta x y equals x delta y
divided by delta x equals 1 okay
so x let's slow what's the slope
y 2 minus y 1
divided by what divided by
x 2 minus 1 t minus y
x 1 come on theta theta y divided by
delta x
look if x two might equals x one
whatever n
we're dividing by zero right we don't
want to happen if
a value divided by zero what happened
one divided by zero
it's not possible it's not possible yeah
but so we want to check
if x1 not
equals x2 as else we give it an infinite
number okay mass dot what
and then we have a slow yeah we have
slow we want to put it into the slope
slows s
what should we do here
slows
we want to increment it now we found a
line which is
plus one
plus equal one okay right and here
none okay i have an answer answer equals
zero here
right and answer equals max
answer and then what should i put here
eric
all right can you listen to me so slopes
is at least iteration every iteration is
start a new slope right a new
dictionary right because we we check
this point eric
right so if there are two
so that i have to count out i have to
check how
what's the largest number of
what's the largest number of the most
common slope yeah so now we have the max
slows slow stop what
key or value
what's the key here key is the slope the
value is the number of the
time of the lines that have the same
slow right so is it key or values
yeah we're done values bracket
and then return okay you tell me return
what
we also determine how many points so
return one
what's the value return answer what
value
answer is the value and remember the
answer if
if there are two points if there are one
segment
one slow one slow too slow so how many
points
answer what
what
plus one what this is the slope
that's one right and another point
another another line
two so how many points when the slope
stop value is two
yeah plus one that's what i mean yeah
correct
because we are iterating the number of
pairs here i
j right right i'm right
does it make sense
yeah okay so what's the space complexity
are we using any space um
we have a slope definer you see o n o
o n squared come on o n o n square
so we have an endpoint for each
for each pair for each point let's start
with this
and we have how many slopes the maximum
minus one well what minus one yeah
that's uh
definitely minus one yeah okay so what's
the thumb what's this based on residue
minus one yeah and what we don't need to
line this one oh
oh what oh yes because look
the first loop is we pick we try every
point yeah
and at this point we find the line to
the rest of the points
and how many as as long as they are
unique here
there will be n and minus one slow right
that's in the worst case so these slopes
contains
uh most at most and minus one
different values so that will be o n
right correct
all right okay can you tell me this one
come on how do you calculate the s slope
you don't need to worry about these two
why x equals one
what's the slope okay y equals
y equals k x plus b if i align
drawing like that if i give you x what a
point here
a point here what's the slope what's the
k value remember this
we can draw a triangle delta y divided
by delta x
so x equals one
think it's something like f so
i said delta y divided by delta x what's
theta y
um y y two minus y one right that's
come on y two minus y one
yeah minus y1
what y1
okay and then divide it
divided by what don't need to do
no no no not double because it's not
integer
right we want to get actually the
point yeah yeah yeah the floating point
yes
x yeah excellent two
yeah delta minus x times one
yeah if x2 not equals x1 right if
it's x2 equals x1 we want to assign the
slope as this infinity right
got it yeah okay the last question
what's the value of the
when what's the line of the slope equals
zero
what does it look like can you draw a
line what's that
equals now equals zero i asked you this
before
i think it went like this yeah yeah yeah
okay
yeah it's the horizontal line to the x
right yeah
correct yeah okay let that just makes
make sense yeah so any two points yeah y
equals k
x plus p what's the k come on what's k
what's the what's what do we call this k
slope okay key okay slope okay yeah and
if let's take two lines have present
y equals two x plus one and y equals two
x plus two
what's the relation of these two lines
yeah because they have the same tape
right same slope so you'll be
something like that it will be parallel
yeah okay yeah
yeah that that's the most important
takeaway okay
for today yeah this is the night i'm
going to ask you tomorrow okay
okay that's it for today thank you bye
bye