oh hello hello mr area are you all right
okay so you know you probably know that
roman
roman number roman right
look what's this what's this
one i want this uh 2i yeah
what's this what's this three
and how do you lie for um
how do you like five
what letters do you have i mean
lcdm so so this is one
this is five this is
[Music]
that's even better so if i give you a
number like
i don't know uh i
uh let's do this okay l
x v i what's this what's the number of
this air x yeah
so tell me the number
that's 15. that's 10
that's five that's one 66
wow you got it you nailed it okay how
about i nail
it yeah you nearly how about x
er
40 so that's 10
let's 50 why this is 40 oh because the
smaller number is fast smaller so this
is will become
eventually you become minus 10 plus 50.
if the next one is smaller than the
current one we just add it
right and add i use the bigger if the
next one is bigger
so this one is the smaller one which is
two minus okay so today's job is very
simple given a
roman number tell me
how how many it represents what's that
number you represent okay
so so what's your approach
we just solve it you already know how to
do it so tell me the approach
you're solving this given under this and
it'll be much easier
yeah yeah we have suppose we have a
mapping table so
we store this mapping table in uh
set a hash map a notebook yeah we can
look it up
looking up the keys will be least
character the values will be the
numbers yeah so we can look it up yeah
okay so look
we go through this number and how hard
are we going if the next one is smaller
than
if the next one is smaller than the
current one right by looking at the
least we added 15 10
5 and the last one if if this one
is smaller than the next one
what we do we put a
so for this one xl so if this if x
is smaller than the next one right if
this
the current character is smaller than
the next one what should we do
how should we do it differently than
this one um
because because the smaller number is
first
yeah and then we subtract this number
right
and go through that okay that's easy
that seems the easy one
there was a time complexity
if there are a number and characters in
the roman string
okay let's do this
define roman
two integer okay
and now we get the s here okay
so first of all we want to keep the
value in the answer at the beginning is
zero right
so but we need to also need a a mapping
table so
let's do a mapping table let's call it
data
and how do we do the mapping table we
use the curry brace look
curly brace and then we can write i
i is one right comma look and
and v is five
okay except so okay i i'm not going to
write always why
i you know you know i'm going to leave
okay
yeah i'm lazy just to keep it quick iv
what i v x
l c d m do you find the acronym for it
no okay
wait wait wait wait let me think
come on wait let me think
you can tell people how to remember this
trust me i will it will be interesting
right okay don't worry about it
come on wait the video is funny okay
let's do this
and equals length and summaries the
number of characters in the string right
all right
come on okay i know we want to iterate
for
i in range
to to n minus one yeah we want to skip
the last one first because we want to
find out look if if current letter
the value will be theta all right all
right delta
s i okay you tell me okay
s i is the current letter yeah i think
and theta we're looking at the value if
it's a
bigger if it's bigger
or equal right or you think if it's
smaller let's say if it's smaller
if it's smaller than y
[Music]
the next one is one what is the next one
because
common index is i this is the plus one
yes i plus one and i'm using
the theta data look it up the value here
like what if this is smaller than the
next one
we subtract answer one
subtract one subtract
subtract which value this this from this
no no no but next one
yeah but for the next one we're going to
add it anyway right so we just
need to substitute data as i
okay i'll tell you s-i look at eric look
iv iv i
is -1 now and then i if i move to the
next
next character this will be five yeah we
just ended
in the next iteration right and as f1
s1 as what
if it's bigger or even what should we
[Music]
if it's smaller i subtract and if it's
bigger or equal what should i do
v i i what should i do what should i do
with this v
which one is it the same
okay so look these will
we'll skip the last one right skip the
last characters and then for the last
character we just need to edit right
so theta answer answer
plus equal theta what's the last
character
what's the last character yeah s minus
one
that's it okay look what's the tongue
complexity
oh and yeah we're iterating anytime
what's the space complexity
what's the space are complexity using
any space here
are we using any space here yeah but
this one
is is it growing as the number of s
so what's the terminology
a one we are using a lookup table but
this doesn't change
these we know the fixed we know it's a
it's a
a table with a fixed size it's a lookup
table key value pair yeah notebook yeah
key value pair yeah okay you're still
thinking about the aquarium
yeah okay i'm going to erase this okay
i'm going to
erase erase which be eat if
it was this big is what then do this
before okay
and
[Music]
do you understand what i mean the roman
con converting the roman number
what's the least number iv in in that's
the roman
what's this number in integer
do you understand this iv vi
okay you probably don't understand yeah
so s i
yeah delta s i bracket [ __ ] it
is smaller than delta smaller than delta
i plus one
yeah we're looking we are checking
that's one
data s i plus one you're missing the key
the key is say that okay
[Music]
is
another one and i'm missing color
yep that's it for today good job
bye bye bye bye