hello hello mr eurek
are you all right okay so i give you a
list
yeah one two five
seven nine okay and now i will give you
another list
another list this is one list let's call
it a
another list which is two
one nine seven
five okay
so now the touch is that
this is the the original list
and you can pick any sub list right
which is subject
continuous sub list right so can we
and then you can reverse the sub list
as many times as you want okay reverse
it
as many times as you want as many times
as you want
and then you have to make the same where
them well
you see this is going and can you make
these to this so what if
you can't if you can't then you'll
determine fourth if you can then you
tell me it's yes um you switch
d2 and you switch d3 yeah so first of
all
here let's stop this i need something
okay so you got it okay so if i tell you
that okay
i'm going to write it another way okay
um can you make it
remember reverse sublist as many times
as you want
well you could yeah
so it's hard yeah but wait
wait wait i think i can do it yeah
reverse these four
yeah these four yeah it becomes
one two five nine okay and whatever
seven
and then nine and seven yeah okay so
that becomes seven nine
and then wow you did it wow
okay so so yes so
how can we solve this problem we learn
something
as many times as we want it's a very
think about the thing look if
i i don't care about others if i want to
move these to the end
a number to the end or to any number
position
how hot how would you do it how would
you do it
if i don't care about others if i want
to move these 9 knives
to the end you need to um
and move it yeah and you do
the whole thing opposite okay and how
about moving here
and then it will be um seven one two
five um and then you will need to switch
one one with seven and then you need to
yeah okay so if i tell you that
uh i just want to move knight
to the end but i don't want to catch any
orders of these
so these will be five two one so it will
be like
five two one seven nine okay so how how
would you do it
if you want me if i want to move this
knight to the end without
changing the order of the other elements
it's five two one seven eight
how would you do it but can we change it
and then we put it back again
up to you i mean can you think about
yeah yeah of course as many
as many as terms as possible so how do
you do it
[Music]
wait
yeah think about it so the other
elements
won't change i just want to move this
together
and maybe
that's what i want so basically so i can
prove that i can move this element to
any positions i want right
right okay so the task becomes that to
check
if if it's possible to move any of these
to rearrange these
to the to the target
so in order for these to be become these
what kind of requirements does it do we
need to make sure these two arrays for
example
these two array needs to have the same
length right
all right yeah that's that's one obvious
yeah if it's different lens you can make
it right
okay so segments and how about
some lens how about if i have a minion
here
a hundred and this doesn't have a
hundred does it can
can you change to the target
the elements needs to be the same right
look if i have a 15 here i don't have 15
here
can you change from a to b
so if one of the elements is not found
in another
if one of element is not found in other
list
what happens can you change
no you cannot change right so for
example 15.
no matter how you swap reverse you can't
make it the target right because the
target doesn't contain the 15. all right
yes hey okay so what kind of thing what
kind of characteristic these two need
already needs to be remember we talk
about
you know check checking two strings if
they are
what the same they are the same after
the arrangement what do we call it
what do you call it like what do you
mean
you know you know what i'm talking about
like um
like
okay so what's underground um is when
if you got the same amount of letters um
same um
same character in each word and
certain frequency for each character
okay so basically we are checking the
same
same so these the length needs to be
same each number needs to be the same
number
if they are okay they are
two two twos and
here needs to be two twos right yeah all
right
let's one seven here needs to be one
seven okay and hopefully we check if the
energon do you still remember instead of
energon we're checking the underground
of the list of two lists right so how
can we check it
to to these uh endograms huh
so basically we are checking the least
energy how can we check it
define let's just check okay let's list
a and b hey hey wait i think i got
it it might not work okay so what how do
you check if two
array or two string i don't know we
talked about this before right i know i
know
wait wait i know how to solve a problem
you're talking about
um say before and um so basically
you just check if if they have the same
amount
or and they have the same amount of
character and
if if it doesn't have any and if it has
and if it's and you can just pretend
tree if
all of them that is okay
okay so first of all we don't want to
check it valence yeah if length
a not equals length b
then what should we do return
if the lengths are different the force
yeah let's let's sense for the endogram
yeah
if the two strings are different size
they come to the end one right
yeah that's not possible right all right
yeah okay now so how can we check if two
strings are undergone it's
basically the same how can we check if
the two strings are underground
um we can
first of all we can do what we can do
this
this thing in o and locker n how can we
do this so
yeah we can sort it yeah if we sort it
what happened
that would be the same yeah exactly
return how can we solve it so okay we
just say
sorted a
yeah okay what's the time complexity
what's the space complexity
okay another thing is that remember we
talked about
the one style we see the notebook what's
that remember i thought i used that a
lot to cut
counter yeah we count if we use the
counter
a then look if this is one two okay
and another one is two one okay so what
counter a
what does counter a give us it will give
us this one one
two one yeah two appears one time one
appear one
yeah and here comes the p
what does z equal
one one two one right so they are the
same right
yeah so i can replace salty with
what you want
let's just tell you come on yeah counter
filter just replace it with another i
like to put sorted
wait powder if you counter what's the
time complexity
yeah what's the space complexity
oh and okay so which one is better this
one is
which one is faster which one is faster
counter or sorted this one has a one
this one has
this one yeah yeah which one is faster
counter or sorted counter is oven
sorted is always again come on that's
really obvious which one is faster
oh and pick o n o o n again
this one is bigger this one is smaller
yeah so this one is faster yeah
then what's about the space okay space
we're trying to use the more space
different yeah because this one one is
constant this one okay so there the
chase
trade-off yeah you have your balance
yeah it depends on
what you want yeah you see we're just
changing one keyword from counter to
salty
this one is faster no no no oh and
nothing
although oh and looking bigger than this
one if it's bigger the complexity is
bigger than
then it's slower if it's smaller right
if it's a one it's faster right than one
right remember we talk about
complexity the slower number the smaller
number
means
[Music]
no matter how big of this number these
arrangements i mean
what's the difference but now i mean
what's the
what what's the difference between
a one and o n or
what come on i didn't know so what's
your question
look look i'm writing a table here okay
so here that's time
let's space okay if we are using
using the counter we using assorted
so this one time is o-n
space is
all right sorted time is o
yeah space is i want okay
so this one sorted is slower but use
less
space memory counter is faster but use
more
space okay okay so
the lower this complexity the lower
the better for both time and space
it will be great if both time and space
is a one
what does it mean online constant means
that no matter how many elements if this
anime is a minion
it doesn't matter we spell one instant
fast
oh and remember we talk about y equals x
yes
the other day yeah y equals so what does
it mean here
the n is here this is y equals x
right all right and what's y equals 1
which line is can you draw y equals 1
here
come on i think it's something like
this yeah yeah because y this is y right
this is x this is we call it n okay
look x is n equals
no matter how many n how many animals
is still one this is constant this is
constant okay this is constant
less linear linear o o n
log n i don't know how it's wrong but it
will be o
o n square yeah one
n is one you'll be one when n is two
you'll be four
so you'll be you'll be something like
that okay
so look if n is armenia you'll be from
the highest like
this so when it's like this it's like
why is it still two no no i'm just
just drawing something like that so told
you before it's really you'll be nice
you're going very slow very
well wrist what you call this slow yeah
very very high steep yeah steep
okay the constant is no matter how big a
median
n is there one okay we love this kind of
solution yeah
it doesn't the number of the the the
the number of the input the scale of the
input doesn't impact the resolution
right correct does it make sense yeah
yeah
you might say yeah okay that's it for
today
bye bye bye bye bye