hello hello mr eric are you all right
yes okay so today we talked about flip
zero
three zeros what does it mean so we're
given
we given a string a list of only zero
and ones
so one zero zero one zero okay
it only contains zeros and ones so every
time we can pick a digit
and then we can flip the digit and
everything
on the left on the right so when i say
flip what does it mean
it's like a coin yeah one is facing up
you
you flip you're facing down when it when
it's facing down you flip
you will be facing up so flip is one
operation
from one to zero and from zero to one
all right all right yeah
so the value if it's v then it will
become one minus v
okay okay yeah because if it's zero they
become one if it is one it will become
zero
okay that's three so can you tell me how
can i flip these to all zeros
remember if i flip these one
i need to flip everything on on the left
on the right
yeah zero and one one zero one yeah
everything on the right
and i flip this one yeah so
zero zeros and these will be flipped as
well
okay and do i need to flip this no
one zero zero zero zero one
and then zero zero zero zero zero so how
many
one two three four so you tell me four
times
three tell the minimum minimum of course
minimum
for the maximum you can flip each one a
limited number of times
if it's even number of times yeah if you
know one if we
flip 100 times so what happened
um
yeah yeah yeah oh if one flip a hundred
times you become
you become a a coin flip
100 times you know flip one if you flip
one hundred times what happened you'll
become one yeah you'll fix the same
zero flip a hundred times
the same yeah zero zero 99 times
one one seventy three times
one a minion
and two times um
one yeah you got it yeah even number of
times doesn't change yeah
zero all number of times it change it
flips okay
so so what's the strategy
what's the strategy how are we going to
flip it from
which side which is there because
because every time we flip one thing you
will change everything along the right
are we go to left to right
okay so so yes what are we doing from
left to right because that
if we flip these it doesn't change
everything on the left but change
everything on the right right
so we go through from left to right but
when we
we we check the current digit if we
zero if it's zero you know
we we don't change if it's one we flip
it but we also need to remember the
current
flip okay we need to have a counter
because look because l is zero okay
let's look at the second zero if
we when we check this zero we already be
zero
no right because we already flipped one
times
in the first digit so when we visit this
zero it's actually one
right so we need to flip it again right
all right
so if we flip this one and for the third
third digit
do we do we need to flip it no because
look
after the third digit we are flipping
two times zero flip two times
is zero so we can skip that digit so in
you know to sum up like
when we visit we need to take
consideration of account
which is the flips we have done so far
from the left to the right right
and then going this order we can we can
do it let's do it it should be very
straightforward
i'm sleepy you're sleepy yeah because
it's
too hard for you no and you get too
sleepy
okay
what's the numbers yeah numbers nums
okay so that we have this count
count equals zero okay this is the
number of the
flips we have done so far so now we just
need
to go through how how can we go through
the numbers
how can we go through the numbers how
can we go through the number from the
left to the right four
four one something in range for i
in numbers all right we can do this
directly here what side
sorry what side what side what do you
mean what's i
i anything a number an index or can we
call it whatever we want yeah
yeah for n let's say for n okay for
okay so now if
if n is zero okay
if n is yellow
if n is zero but if the cloud
is odd number right
if cloud is all number and
and count is all number let's say count
and one is odd number so what happened
in this case so if
n is zero current is zero but we have
flipped
what number of times so do we need to
flip it
again an old number yeah
yeah if n is zero current is zero but we
fit all numbers
so you become one one and do we need to
flip it
we're going to flip the zero yeah yeah
so we want to flip
yesterday oh oh what
if a is one and can you tell me what to
do here count if it's
and if it's n equal or equal one
if it's one but we have flipped
odd number or even number um
if reflect oh it becomes zero so we
don't want to phrase it so if
it were what
um
yeah if it's zero it means even number
if we count equals if calculated is in
one
but we flip even number of times so
it means still one right i'm right
now we want to flip it yeah okay
now we do what
we want to flip so what happened to the
car
yeah and we can
[Music]
what are we doing here we are counting
how many what
counting return what
okay huh that doesn't make sense this is
the number of count we
flip the number of flips so when
it's current digit look all right so
look at zero
and we're looking for one and one with 0
so what does it mean look
0 something 1 equals
1 equals 1 and 1
0 we're looking for these two cases 0 1
1 0. so can you tell me what kind of
operation the pit
operation are we looking for zero one
one zero if they are different
what do we call it yeah
exclusive or or to this yes i got
this is symbol of above six so we can
just do this
we can just do this this one we can just
erase it
and we can we can change this to
n exclusive cow
and one right if this
that's it and then count plus equals one
right
yeah got it yeah equal equal one
actually
equal equal one but we can we can we can
just
ignore uh just just uh make it simple
okay all right does it make sense
yeah no that's it
these two can be simplified by this
yeah because actually we are looking for
different signs zero and one
one and zero okay so it's basically the
exclusive off
okay what's the time complexity
oh
because we're not using any uh linear
addition space yeah we're just using one
variable
yeah got it okay so i'm going to erase
this piece okay so can you tell me
okay if n equals if current digit is
zero and what
i if currently this is one you know what
and this is all
okay okay i'll make it simple for you
come on
okay so you just need to tell me what
they did well these two
if current digit is yellow and what
what to do with the count okay yeah all
right
okay we do it yeah
okay come on faster
[Music]
and come on
me now
sneaky
and then what's next
i know what's the next one if we
currently there is one and
we we flipping we flipping one
or even number ten right one because
yeah that's it does it make sense can
you explain to me one more time what's
this mean
it means if we flip this
number if this current digit is zero and
we're flipping
all number of times yeah we need to flip
it again
and then we need to flip it back to zero
okay
if n equals one and count eight
and one equals zero
oh yeah oh yeah