hello okay hello hello
hello guys hello nice to meet you yeah
yeah
uh you need to say hello teacher hello
mr teacher
okay good okay
okay so today uh i'm going to
talk about an interesting problem which
is the
do you remember i still remember the uh
uh
parentheses yeah yeah these are premises
yeah
bracket exactly so this pregnancy so if
i give you a
string contains only these parentheses
yeah so for example uh if i leave
this is good good
not good not good
so can you tell me what should we do
here what are we doing you need a
clothing packet
and how about this this is not good
and you need an even number of those
this is good but but this is not good
this is even but not good
yeah so so quite close quite close
you're quite close
ryan do you get it so what's the news
here what are the losers
this is good
okay even this is not closing
what so you say even yeah
this is even
so you say this is not closing how about
this one
uh how about that
and that is still not valid so
so what do you think
yeah yeah
so okay so you're quite close because
they have to be the same number
of things that we're doing that yeah
yeah yeah yeah good job good job
yeah okay so so first of all yeah you're
quite close
yes yeah yeah ryan eric so
we need to find if each every
starting parenthesis should be closed
with parentheses yes
yes and every
you you can't start apprentices without
the bracket
the starting you can't have uh these
without these three together it needs to
match
yeah yeah and as you said there's there
should be
even number right because we are they
all
come with a pair okay so given uh
a string let's see how can we do this
okay let's define it
define f yeah we call it we can call it
valid parentheses but we also can
have this f just for sure then bracket
s bracket
don't look at my nose yeah okay so
listen to me okay
so how what's the what's the
what's the uh how do you solve this
problem i
like this how do you solve it
first it needs to start with a opening
bracket yeah okay so so can we we can
have a
count like balance yeah we have we can
have a balance
count if we meet the starting yeah
yes we increment this
we increment this okay
yeah if we mean this closing bracket
we decrement it right
all right yes
okay so we need to check at the end if
it's equal to zero
right if it's zero it comes with pair
but however
if if we decrement one and we find that
it's become negative number then it's
not valid i'm right
for example like look at this one now
one zero okay let's read it
yeah one zero
one zero read it one
zero minus one not below zero
it's invalid right you'll get it
how do you know the numbers i don't get
it this is
b we have a counter balance when we need
a
starting bracket we increment one we
make it one in
plus one yeah so b is not one we
mean this closing bracket we minus one
so one becomes minus one is zero right
when we finish this we check with b zero
yeah this is the same one zero
one zero so that's good one
zero but now we're meeting another
closing we need to minus one again
that becomes negative one so which means
it's invalid
yeah how about this one
minus one invalid yeah
how about this one
zero one at the end is not equal to zero
so it's inverted
yeah simple yeah is it simple
still get it okay so we can write this
easier
b yeah that's the very one
but you don't need a dot in the middle
no no no
no no that's computers displaying okay
for i
yeah look if i
equals starting bracket yeah
if i go starting breaking everything
what do i do
p plus equals 1 right
s as
if x is or we can check f if
i equals
ending bracket b minus equal one
but we need to check if we fall below
zero at this time right
so if b is smaller than zero
[Music]
yeah yeah yeah so this thing look this
thing
is the same as if b equals zero
return to
else return
but this is below zero at the beginning
meter yeah like one two two
so when we scan here one zero minus one
we return
fourth immediately without going further
but these look
see this this return here 0
1 0 1 0 1
you finish this it's not written in here
but
it will turn in here right you see yeah
got it yeah easy yeah okay
easy pizza okay so what's the complexity
of this one
even if the length is if the length is n
if the length of the string is n
if there are n string n characters o
[Music]
n because we need to scan once right
yeah and what's the
space complexity do we need to allocate
space no we don't need it so we see
which is oh
one constant yes yeah got it
okay so that'll be it today
say
oh