hello hello mr area
all right yeah okay so today we're going
to talk about the multiverse of three
and seven okay what does it mean
for example like if i give you a number
13 and then you can choose
any number of multiple of three and n
plus any number of multiple seven so
basically we want to looking for
three a plus three
three four one b no seven plus
so you can choose zero one two three
okay
so you can you need to tell me if it's
possible or not okay
if it's possible or not so another
example like uh
eight can you do it with a
no right that's right so if you tell me
it's false
how about nine you say okay
three times three yeah yeah but you
don't need b will be zero okay so you
got it
okay so how can we do it everything has
seven times
seven times tables or seven three times
table yeah and okay
okay how about the mix like ten
um that's pretty obvious ten three and
seven
yeah you see so so eat either in three
time table or seven times table all the
mix
so how how do we check the mix yeah how
we're checking it so any idea
any idea oh if it's
if it's in the ten times table it's
possible
but it's not necessarily the ten times
table yes yes
you're right in ten twenty yes of course
yeah because
i got three and seven and i could i can
just times multiple yeah one two three
four each but
how about like the thirteen you know
thirteen is seven
plus three times two right yeah so
that's one that's two any idea
um this might not work
but um what but i think
it's using trying to do as much service
as you can
yes well i'll try doing as
seven as we can
and then we can do another thing we do
okay it might not work okay
so wait wait let me find an example yeah
so are we we want to find the number of
so we we want to find the number of
three and if count
example yeah i know what i know
okay example of 16 yeah
okay so how what's your approach to to
do it it's given a
very big number what's your approach
such as
i don't know a hundred can you tell me a
hundred
it's hard right um seven tens and
three ten easy things yeah yeah
okay okay i don't know i don't know okay
something
like something like um yeah
look now let me just write a recursion
right
we can check it with this theory you and
you tell me look eric
all right f s n if
n is smaller than zero will return
[Music]
return one three
if and multiple seven equals
zero return okay
okay so then you tell me what to do left
okay and
so the number the number
so okay so what happened to the number
so
return we're done
we are working on this n so what's the
problem
so if any of these n minus three and n
minus seven
is a it's a number a multiple of three
and seven
then this number must be a multiple of
three and seven so i'm right
right
yeah look we don't know right all right
we don't know this n but if if this
number
all right if it's number is true
or if this number n minus seven is true
then this number is also true
i'm right so what
if f n minus 3 y f
minus 7 so what to do
what to do here come on
come on we should
what top down remember top down
dynamic programming top down we are
working on this
number case end listen to me array
you're
losing focus if we are working on number
n
but if we know f n minus 3 or f of n
minus 7
if any of them is true then this must be
true all right
yeah oh yeah yeah so what's wrong here
this is a true fourth question
if this is true all this is true so what
should i put here
oh come on does it make sense anyway
that's it we turn this at least go there
all right okay what's missing here
remember yeah cash
all right listen up okay let me talk to
me
dynamic programming yeah look if n minus
seven
they what's this n minus six
and minus three minus seven right and
then what's that one three
n minus seven minus three and m minus
look seven minus seven so look
yeah duplicate calculation
minus different places but but this
is the same value it calculates
difference so we need a cash
right as long as we need the explanation
yeah what's the time conversion for this
one what's the time complexity
uh come on
stop stop saying that oh n o
[Music]
it's fine okay this makes sense okay
how about if we just going through the
number of multiples
very good define f and
look if we're going for i
in red
let's say i is the multiple of three
okay yeah
multiple three so you will go to n
divided by three plus one right that's
the maximum you can get right
if n minus three times
i right if we approve using the i no
multiple three
if it can be modeled by what
if it can be the
three
i is the multiple three if i minus
multiple three i
can modulate by one seven seven yeah
then we ten
two
and ten
both okay
that's it what's the time frame let's
see i
and what's the space convexity i
one yeah we can do at least
turning this into one none one none yeah
so we can just say
return any
any means any of these is true any
anyone
and minus three times i more than
seven well equal equal zero for
what
in range
and divided by three
plus one yeah basically just copying
just arrange this into this
right in for these written two now we
can say any of these
and we are looking for any any i
i need this expression is true for i in
like that yeah okay
okay so all yours can you write it
that's your task today come on i'll give
you two you can
i'll do the first one okay that's easy
first one
[Music]
f
if it's yeah
or you can put all here or modular seven
yeah you can
write in the same but yeah yeah
and more or less
and
[Music]
minus seven right
what's the time company for this one
you're missing something
oh yeah
okay so can you explain to me what's
this
cash can you explain to me what what's
return f
n minus 3 or f n minus 7
that is
f n minus 3 f o f
return f n minus 3 or f
and minus 7 means that
basically
[Music]
that that thingy
so can you give an example like 16 for
example
n yeah and it's 16.
and if we know
f and f
16-3 yeah
[Music]
and
um
minus ten right if you minus three minus
seven that would be minus ten okay
the right on the right yeah
so you go to the left that would be
minus three go to the right that would
be minus seven
yeah you're already minus three and then
you go to the left will be minus six
that's correct if you minus three and go
to the right i'll be minus three minus
seven that will be minus ten right
okay minus ten so if you look at the
right
right note f sixteen minus seven that's
f nine right
and we obviously the nine can be
represented by three times three so what
does it mean
um we can do it by doing that
dynamic programming thing yeah yeah yeah
and the cache is to avoid
duplicate numbers yes because we know f9
we can three times three and then any
number if we can
if n minus three can be represented
right using a multiple three
seven then this end must be represented
by multiple three or seven yeah either
of these that's why we said all right
i'm all right
yeah okay let's see what the time can
practice
and space comes because we only won
bye-bye
my