hello mr area are you right
good okay so let's say
we have a few numbers like two three
four
four three two so can you tell me
that if we want to group these numbers
group
and their three conditions is through
each group
contains same number
all groups same size
[Music]
and the third condition is same
size and these two size bigger than one
okay
so can you tell me if you can group
these numbers
using these three conditions
yep size bigger than one
yeah so it's okay yeah each group same
number
all group same size two numbers two
numbers two numbers size bigger than one
yes two number two bigger than one okay
and how about how about another example
it's gonna be nine you sure
oh because two two four four
four
can you what
yeah yeah how do you group it how do you
make it
yeah i didn't say i didn't say the
numbers in each group
needs to be unique right they can be the
same right yeah
at least we lose he didn't say it has to
be unique
yeah i didn't say that's why you can put
it in uh put the same number into two
different groups or more groups let's
okay
and how about
one two two three three four
four nine no why is that
because yeah okay so okay so
so what's your idea of doing that okay
so for example given a list of numbers
one two three
if we want to count the number of
frequencies here
you want to count the number of
frequencies what's your
what's the what's the how how do we do
it in prison
we count yeah we count and especially we
use what kind of counter yeah
look this is numb okay so
if we actually see equals counter
counter numbs so what does it give us
what does it give us one two
let's say one two let's say two
one four three four three okay so what
does this give us
um one one one
one
okay so this is a dictionary okay c
is this which we did the left side we
call it what keys yeah this is the key
and this is the value what this is the
value
what's the key key is the number unique
numbers
in a in a way
[Music]
no no what i'm saying this key is unique
in these
right huh right one photo is
unique here right yeah and the values
when you see the number of terms they
appear right right yeah
yes okay so
if i change all four to a minion
let's say that's the answer
does it affect the answers no and i can
change three to achievement it doesn't
impact the answer right so the problem
is that we only need to
take consideration of these numbers the
count the number of actually count yeah
all right
yeah and if i write these numbers let's
say if i write these numbers in an array
like 2 2 4
look this is the number of times of the
frequency okay can it be grouped into
the
the groups with the same size and each
group has the same size at least one
can it to the 4
then what i mean is that there are two
numbers
two numbers of elements a two numbers
are element b
and four numbers are element c okay
yeah okay and how about four
six a is okay
uh yeah yeah yeah
okay a tricky one like
2 2 7
14.
wait let
i didn't say that this time okay
okay so 2 7 14 is that okay
why is that 7 and
seven is kind of odd yeah so okay
so how about three
and nine why are you doing two right now
i'm just checking three and nine is that
okay three numbers also
hey and nine numbers of b you sure yeah
yeah okay
okay so yeah that's okay so what were
you thinking about
no i'm just checking okay so what's your
approach remember
[Music]
yeah what are we how are you checking
with
yes or no how are you chicken with three
nice oh
okay this is not okay
look one one one and then there will be
two two two two two two
four six a
nine okay so you can group with one two
three four yeah yeah okay it's basically
like you're just taking yeah
another but if their prime number
in one is definitely not
prime number yeah if there's only one
two
yeah okay so if one two
what um two is prime number one two is
that okay
yeah are you sure one two
two that's very obvious not right okay
so what what um
times table it may be three times table
look this is three times table
yeah it may be four times four five
times table so
i didn't say two times okay okay so okay
so what's
what's the thing we are looking um
trying out the smallest number smallest
number yeah okay it's not this number
and we want to check if they are
multiple yeah
okay so y four and six is okay come on
why four is six
is okay oh because they're both
even numbers and they're both
tables that's the correct they're in
both two times saver so two
of two what is two of these four and six
what's two six
minus four and also they
they are both in four two time table
yeah
and this is the biggest in
two times as well yeah so what do we
call it greatest
weight is common divider yeah this is
common divisor
okay stop so
we're just checking the greatest comedy
riser
t sign okay s sign okay greatest comment
divisor of all the numbers frequency and
check if they are bigger
if the grade is common divisor of all
numbers yeah we can do the greatest
common divides of all numbers how how do
we do this
look we can we can just do this uh the
answer
equals the first number okay first
number so let's say this is
a a0 and now we can just do this for i
in a
answer equals greatest common divisor of
answer and i right and then let's regret
its common device of
all the numbers in the array right and
it has to be
bigger than one then it's yes otherwise
it's not
right let's check this one and two
greatest common divisor
is one so that's not okay this one
two and seven what is common divisor is
what
one one is not okay yeah one one
and any other number greatest common
divisor is one right
got it exactly
prime numbers except no it would be
multiple it would be still okay
if i give you a number 13 and
13 is a prime number right and how about
26 13 and 26
is still okay right because 13 and 26
greatest common divisor is 13.
you see yeah so we're just checking
the code the two numbers
so first of all we wanted to what
let's say the first number which is what
okay and we want to we want to know the
frequency yeah
so frequency will be let's say n
equals c dot values we just need to do
normal values yeah
values and we'll convert it to a list
these
seed of values all right this is n and
then we're going to do this a equals
and 0 for
i in n right
a equals what can you tell me a equals
one
and return a what another
what are we doing here what's the
function
[Music]
and what's this what's two values what
a and b a with s there's no b
where a and y we're looking all the
numbers in n which is the value
so what's that
what's this n is the values and i what's
that
i yeah come on all right okay so written
a
what a
that's one a one well talking about the
greatest common divisor we want to be
bigger bigger than once okay
okay so let's say uh the quantity is
common divisor do you still remember
define this is built in but we will
review it what is common devices a and b
how how is implementing it
21 21 and 14
what's the greatest common divisor seven
how do we do this
a and b okay so look
why are b is not is bigger than zero
a b equals b a modulus b
and return what we say one
a or b a yeah
so why is that look a b y b is not
yellow
a equals b b equals
a is supposed to be the biggest look
that's okay
a equals b yeah a will become b
and b will become a 21 modulus 14
remember what 21 divided by 14
remain what compounds seven okay now
b is not yellow a a becomes b
okay so seven right here fourteen
divided by seven how many left
remainder twenty divided by seven 14
divided by seven
zero zero okay so p is yellow so this is
like within a
so greatest common divisor a right
correct
so look this is doing that we can do
this
in one line
just fancy syntax yeah so here
we can just return reduce
reduce reduce value to a very well
gcv and then n
that's it yes yeah
we want to we want to use the gcd this
is a function
greatest common divisor to apply to the
list
to apply this yeah what's your time to
blast it
what's the time complexity
what what's the time complexity
what's the greatest common device
what's the what's the better the return
this means to bigger than one i haven't
forgotten
the question is common divisor is
roughly o
log n and when reducing at least so
you'll be n
so actually it's o and again okay
roughly okay
okay
okay i'm going to write this okay answer
equals and the first one
is 0 4
i in m
answer equals what
return answer
what can you feel the prank actually
because we're picking the first number
you can start with the second number
okay
come on you don't break my thingy
[Music]
and the answer is that greatest common
device of all
things
come on you you're asking me for a hint
i did not say that okay
[Music]
okay so actually is the
lowercase but that's okay you know how
it works
[Music]
we want to calculate the greatest common
divisor of all the numbers
and we're iterating the numbers yeah so
we how
all right and then last the greatest
common divisor is to be
what we know yeah
bigger than one okay that's it for today
[Music]
bye-bye