oh hello hello hello mr mr ryan how are
you today good
job everyone hey just you
yeah uh so today we talk about the chain
function so what's chain
what does it mean chain it's like the
metal thing
mental
[Music]
okay i got it okay so chen so today we
are going to talk about chain function
in python okay so can you tell me okay
if
i i have a a
at least two dimensionalists all right
look at this
yeah and that one two
three another list four
five another next six
okay so this is a two dimensional list
yeah one two three
four five six so if i tell you chen
i want to keep doing a chain a
can you tell me what does it look like
if i have
one uh if i this is like
iterator and then if i put convert it to
the list
okay so can you tell me what's changed
what what does chain look like
come on you you're quite close right
come on
one two three chain
[Music]
chair so imagine what's the chain from
here right you say
i think it's a just guess guess i think
it's like a chain like that
yeah that's a tupelo no because it looks
like a chair ah
no no okay yeah i i could try that's
very creative so
actually you would go through each
element one by one
and chain this like that it's never
existent at least
never there before so you'll be like one
two
three just a four five six easy yeah
yeah got it yeah so that's it yeah
that's what this
chain function means so you take you
take each this
yeah and then connect it can it and
like this look this is an iterator
what's iterator do you still remember
when we talk about iterator we want to
talk about keyword
style is why what what is it called
yield
yeah what does ear mean remember
remember for me promise yes so i promise
you given this
these but i'm not giving you one one
goal
yeah when you ask for it i give you give
it to you like yeah
yeah okay remember good memory okay so
if we want to implement this
okay given if we want to implement
actually the chain function supports the
multi-level okay not just
two-dimensional right
and here we are only given a
two-dimensional array
okay a two-dimensional list which is at
least containing
another list of these right so
it can possibly support you know a list
of lists of these so you can
support more than one you know
three-dimensional way maybe but let's
talk about chain function of
two-dimensional release
so if we want to implement this so it
should be very simple yeah
define chain a
wow
okay so now do we intervention remember
already
a is at least okay one two
three four so how can we iterate
over this list all right so what how can
we iterate
[Music]
okay and then after the i got this the
list so what should i do with like next
you join i it's already again right not
join
because i want to give the element one
by one right
so okay so how can we do the so if
i is this one i will be this this this
okay so i want to iterate over the
elements
in this this in i so how can i do it
i want to iterate the elements in i i is
the italian animal in a i want to
iterate animating that so how can i do
it
come on it's there come on
what's this for i in a and what's this
foreign
okay and then now i want to find out
what elements in i so how can i do it
for for anything yeah for j let's say
for j
there's a b there's no b come on
come on and then j is the element one
two three four okay and then we
want to
remember the keyword yeah
[Music]
come on what are we trying to do here
i'm trying to change the a
yeah trying to change a so we're going
to iterate the elements in i which is
the least
and then i want to iterate the elements
in
each eye that's j and we want to do what
the one j yeah yeah the j yeah
okay yeah okay
that's it come on today's first enjoy
yeah
let's see
oh
okay
hey
[Music]
okay that's it for today good job
okay that's it bye