hello hello hello mr eric are you all
right
yeah okay so today a task is very simple
this is an easy question right just to
get you familiar with the same text
again okay so given a list of numbers
one three five
okay all these numbers these numbers are
you know uh if if the length let's say
zero maybe not
three okay
so all these num look how many elements
are here how many elements
four elements four okay so n equals four
okay let's say
n equals four and all these numbers are
between
zero to n okay remember this
is the why does why why does
um a list and then a tree
[Music]
this is mathematic this means that
inclusive remember this is
exclusive so it's bigger than zero
bigger or equal than zero
yeah that's number x smaller than n
that's what you mean
if this is the square bracket it means
that inclusive
if this is the uh well let's call it
uh parentheses our bracket is it doesn't
have
this inclusive right it's exclusive
so what what i mean is that if n n is
the number of elements in the array
and n is four and all these values are
this have this range yeah we gonna all
equal and zero and smaller n
okay and then what we want to do to
transform it
as two so what's
index two zero one 2 so it's here
one zero one index one is here
yellow two
two and then three got it
yeah that's it today stars
do they get it these are the indexes and
i want to
what if you can't find the index yes
you can that's why i said these values
are within this range
so it's the index indexes there right
okay if it's one million you can find
this in one
yeah in a way right that's what i'm
saying okay
okay okay okay so any idea how we're
doing this
is simple form it's very simple yeah
it's very so basically you start with
zero
and plus one to the next one and plus
one
so what do you mean and all these
numbers are distinct means that they are
you know they are they are not duplicate
they are the same and they
they are not duplicate yeah like unique
yeah you can only find one
yeah the same okay
so what we do is we want to transform
the nums nums
i why the new numbers are
is to noms is for
nums
yeah so that's the transformation yeah
[Music]
okay
so can you tell me how to buy it if i
let's say f
okay so in order to return it we need to
create a
answer which is what also equals zero
[Music]
okay and then i need to go to the
render for each one for i
in range when you are
what up to n and what's r
n what's n here there is no n what's n
n is
what should i do
[Music]
okay so look originally is nums i
right and i want to get the value is
what
nums these will become index yeah
come on numbs i want to transform the
world
oh yeah
[Music]
here
what's the time complexity
[Music]
come on give me answer quickly
what's the space complexity
[Music]
can we do it simple way this is a bit
too
lengthy can we do a simple way it's not
lengthy okay so we're going yeah can we
do it better
we can just do it hand we can answer
at least at least okay at least one
nouns i
i want to return this dance i and what's
i
[Music]
that no yeah but but this is different
this is
this is iterating the over the indexes
right
but this is over iterating over
the values right but if you want to do
eventually you can do this way
return it's the same okay
for i in range
if you land now right
and now here i is index so i want to
return one
nouns what i
what what's the difference between this
one this one
[Music]
this i now is a index this is a
value
[Music]
yeah do you see the difference
do you see the can you tell me the
difference between this
what is this list and what is this come
on let's see the end of the queen
because which one is left side
because this one is from
from the beginning to the end it's
iterating over the i i will be 0
1 2 to the n right so we want to candy
this is the value
and then we use the value as the index
and why this is okay why this is
why this is simple i was i i
is a value
that two three four okay what's i
i will be two three four yeah and this i
will be what will be
two ah this index will be one
zero zero one two yeah you see the
difference yeah
yeah and if it's the index you need to
use the nums i to get the value
right and this is already well i'll get
it at the index correct
okay okay so why at least one method
okay just buy every one message i mean
yeah um
we're done that's it that's it
good job say bye bye