hello hello mr area are you all right
yeah so today we talk about this price
green tree please
yeah you had a lesson before right
please it's also called square some
stupid
square sum two plus okay
so what does that even mean so it means
that a squared plus b
squared equals c squared where a b c are
integers positive numbers positive ones
okay positive integers
okay so what is this this is very famous
remember
we call this right triangle yeah
this is 90 degree this is a this is b
what's this
this is that's c c c which is
a square plus b square right correct
yeah yeah if this is three this is four
what's this
that's five oh yeah three square plus
one square
let's equal 9 16 25
equals five okay okay
yeah that's a little review okay so
today
easy today's task is easy
we given the number n right this is
number n like
five if we given this number integer n
which is five three two one number
so we want to know how many a b c how
many a squared plus b square equals c
if a smaller equal
n bigger equal one b smaller equal
n bigger equal one c smaller equal n
bigger than one yeah basically these
numbers needs to be bigger or equal than
one is smaller equal than n
so a b c a b c all b
all belongs to uh this is called belong
that belongs to one
inclusive and inclusive okay
so we want to call how many of these
players if n is five so can you cut
how many pairs of these three four
five right and four three five
can you count any others yeah
it i didn't get it which one which [ __ ]
don't get it we want to count how many
pairs of abc
if n given these abc numbers are bigger
than one and smaller than five if n is
right
got it
okay uh good question yeah y has to be
at the last place
okay can you think of alice if this is
fine this is c is bigger than 5
that's what i'm saying so so we're given
this number
and we want to count how many pairs of
these are okay
if n is if n equals five and there are
only two
triplets which is three four five and
four three five okay
yeah okay so and
if is if n equals 10 okay if n equals 10
this is still okay yeah but also we have
what six
a ten and six eight ten
36 64 equals 100 right or
another pair which is what okay you're
doing it up t
yeah so all these three numbers need to
smaller than or equal n
right six a ten can you give me another
pair come on
so it's 64 plus 26 oh yeah oh yeah
what's the other pair
the other triplet eight six ten
yeah we're done so you need to tell me
is
is what is four right
any other pairs any other triple
receivers and it's given 10 yeah it's
only for you
okay any idea how we're solving this
you got the idea right you got the idea
yeah
the abc look abcs are between the rings
one to end so we what
we can do first yeah proof of weather
yeah
so we can ask computer to try how how
will we try improve us
how can triangle how can we try
easy we can do this
yeah we can do this for a in range
range what start from one and what
should happen here
the last one yeah because it needs to be
n right
and four okay all right when we when we
prove us and we want to bruise for sp
yeah
rent if answer is count yeah if answer
is
range one one
and plus one and you can do another one
for c
in range that's gonna be a long time
yeah
yeah okay now abc will prove what's in
it and then look
if if a times a all you
can do is to start a to the power of 2
this is the same as a times
a right plus b to the power of 2
equals 1 what
c to the power of 2 then we do this
answer plus
equal 1 and then we can add okay
this 8 a times times 2
you can write it as a times a or
power minus the power a two okay this
one
these three are the same thing okay okay
the same thing
okay which one you like the best these
three pick one
um
there's no right or wrong answer come on
give me one come on
equally
okay okay i like this one i like this
one this one
to the top the first one this is calling
a function
i just particularly like it um no reason
messed up
okay what's the time complexity of this
one
cubic where that what's a space
complexity
um
what yeah well can we do better can we
do better
can we do better
look we can integrate a b when we
iterate a b
can we calculate the value of c yeah
oh yeah we can generally remember c and
we just want to know if c
is smaller than equal and and it's also
integer right
so instead of blue forcing c we can get
rid of this eric
get rid of this so see what
c equals one you are
a times a plus b
times b okay i know
okay so let's square root a can you how
can you write this
square root of a
you can write it a square root of a is
what
a to the power of which number square
root of a equals one
a to the power of which number
come on give me a number a
to the power of one which number square
root of eight
no how is the 2 square root of 16 is 4
right it's which number square is 7
equals 16 that's
that's half of it so what what's that
half half 0.5 or half yeah this is zero
yeah
okay this is the same so if this is the
same i can do this
a times times 0.5
why this square root or or you can do
this
or mass power a 0.5 or
a 0.5 or you can use this function sqlt
plus a function master sqlt a this
is exactly the there's three ways one
two three
okay correct one two three you can
calculate this but this
returns a number not essentially like
integer we want to check if it's
integer right if it's not integer we
don't count it
yeah yeah square square root look
square root square root okay it's true
for square root
so look if c is alright so
we do work so we can do this integer
we call it integer integer
[Music]
square root so let's call it uh let's
call it sqrt right and
we call it integer so now c is that
but now we want to check if this is c
a squared plus b square we take a square
root but we want to convert it to the
integer
maybe because c might be 3.5 right
we convert it to integer using the
function just get rid of this 0.5
if c times c equal equal
a times a plus b times b
yeah and and c is smaller or equal
n right then we can do this we can do
this plus one even does it make sense
yeah yeah all right
so if c smaller e because c might be
bigger than
n and we want to calculate if c is an
integer if you see
because we are converting to integer bar
we only uh
we only keep the integer part right if
it's a whole if that's a square number
array what's a square number
25 is a square number 16 is a square
number right because the
square root of the equals four these is
equals five
is three a square number
is three a square number no because
because these
equal equals one point seven three
i can't remember if it's a fraction
number this is not square number that's
what i mean you see
if if c is a square squared number
i took the integer bar and times itself
squared itself
is also equal a times a plus b times b
and this
uh this requirement still satisfies so
what's the time capacity of this one
of this approach oh n square
oh yeah n squared what's the space
complexity oh
one yeah so which one is better
this one yeah also remember this square
root
we consider it as a one okay it's
extremely very fast
but nowadays the cpu the computer cpu
cpu
central processing unit is the brand of
the computer okay
it's a small chip it's a cpu smart chip
smart chip is a brand of uh
what of another cpu yeah
cpu cpu
central cpu cpu
central for assessing
unit okay the brand
the brand of computer yeah makes sense
it's a small chip it's not
[Music]
okay so so that one is is
uh o n square so we're gonna open square
but we can still make it faster
right why is that look answer equals
zero let's try it again
for a in rent
n plus one right so before we we
b will be also for b
in range n plus one right
and we do the do thing yeah
the thing is we increment answer plus
equal one okay
so look if c equals integer power
square root a plus a squared plus b
squared okay i you just use this one
okay i don't can say what
remember if c is smaller equal n
and and y what should i do c square
equals
equals a squared plus b squared okay
okay
this is not position if you want to
write it remember you can do c times c
or c times times two okay all
power c two okay okay
there's always three ways
look look the problem this is we can
improve this why because this is
incrementing one
all right right so what does it mean
remember we have three four
five once we found three four five we
also know
four three five interchangeable a and b
interchangeable right
yeah so instead of count increment one
we can increment two if we found one of
these
and one can increment two because we
found three four we know four three all
right
yeah okay so first of all first of all
a could a and b equal could a and b
equal
a and b equal yes or no
think a and b equal
look if a and b equal what happened a
square plus
a b equals a squared plus a square
equals c squared right
yeah so this is 2a squared
equals c squared all right yeah
if they are same i do the square root of
both sides
so let's square two times a equals c
doesn't make sense so what's this number
this is a irrational number
equation number in relational number
okay
so it means it's a number it's one point
four one four blah
okay this is if this is the number of a
number
you know it's it can't be divided by a
hole right
so it has the lone pair and it's going
forward
right yeah
so look a c a and c
could these two be both integer
no right if a is integer c must not be
integer right
yeah they can't be both they can't not
be both integer that's what i'm saying
so
a cannot be equals b right so we can
just do this we can just
we can just do this for a b b in range
up to a right we can just up to a yeah
instead of two n plus a so a would be uh
so a b will be smaller than a right so a
will be
b uh b one to
n right and b will be range of what
one to a all right look what's this
exclusive right remember yesterday we
talked about this is
inclusive so a we eat we brew force a
between
one to n inclusive and we grew from
speed from one to a
yeah this is up to a not equal to a so a
cannot be equal to b
then after that look and what do i do
what should i change here
yeah we're down yeah and then let's
so d what's the temperament taxi come on
come on remember we talked about
convexity we
drop the constant so what's the time
complexity sorry
what is the one look at this of a that's
a square
it's still all n squared okay that's
tricky one but because why is that
because it divided by two
it's actually cut my line
square so let's so let's change context
is o n
square divided by two but we totally
talk about complexity we
drop the constant so it's zero and two
but this one is faster than
the second one right it's the same
complexity you know when we talk about
convexity we don't actually measure how
fast they
they actually run yeah right but this
one is actually taking faster because
why
because actually it has the 50 speed up
right
yeah because look instead of b b instead
of going to
n every time i only go to a right when a
is what is two b will only only go to
one b
when a is n divided by two b will only
go to the half right you get it
yeah that's my sense eric yeah
okay so this is this is the second
approach
so we can also the other approach is
that we can
we can okay the last approach okay
if we can check we can we can have a
array array okay equals fourth
fourth times n
times n plus one so this array will hold
we pre-calculate the num uh the boolean
array this is pulling for two or four
see if it is true it means that this
number is a square number
remember the square number so we can
just do this for
i in range
range one range n and n plus one right
and we can do this one a r
i times i equals what
i times i i was from one to n and i
times i equals one
true right it means this is a square
number right
and then we can go through that thingy
again right for a
in range
n plus one and for b
in branch a right
a times a plus b times b
right
no actually actually no actually for a
in
a then we can do this b from what equals
one
and then y a times
a plus b times b
a a times a plus b times b smaller than
smaller than equal than n times n
then we'll do what uh if if
a r a times a
a square plus b square if
this is a square number right if this is
a square number
uh then we answer
plus equals two then b plus
equals one and we can answer
is is it is this working let me double
check okay
so what are we doing here is what what
are we doing is
if we use the particular array
right if a yes if it's uh
okay so if
actually b would start from the a right
we start from a because we're
incrementing two
right we have all right so a times
a plus b times b if is a small if it's a
square number then we increment so it's
the same thing yeah it's the previously
we use the sqrt
convert it to integer and then check if
it's a square number but now we because
we use the
checking of the array we already
calculated here
the time the next is still o n square
right let's space complexity what's your
space from rsv
[Music]
uh okay
yeah yeah yeah oh oh look look
oh n square right it's always good
you see oh let's go because we're
allocating the array of n squared plus
one yeah
okay square okay let's let's see do we
want to
let's okay so this you don't need to do
this
but at least you need to write me uh
give me a
define let's play count
call square sound
i'm giving a number n okay can you read
it come on
come on you'll be simple i need any
approach even the own cubic come on and
answer equals zero okay
all right every time i let you write a
four grip okay
maybe fine i'll do the first one
okay okay
you can do it better come on
four yeah a
yeah um
right yeah yeah yeah come on you can do
it
in range
one and plus
one yeah column
four
b in
range
one and
one four
one
yeah we don't want to check if a n times
a why are you writing there
they say there's a space if you have a
column yeah oh yeah
a what's a y a
you want to check if a square plus b
squared equals c squared right a square
you can say a you want to put an e layer
right
oh yeah
if
c squared equals a squared b squared
c squared
equals a
[Music]
what's the come from versus um
okay can we do better yeah okay
do you still remember how we do this
better oh and square
instead of looking because we know the c
right so c
we just do this integer path of square
root
or we can just do this a squared plus b
square right and then we do the integer
power square root of it
right and then we just do this if
fc squared equals a squared plus b
squared because c
is not integer if n and one and
we want to make sure c is smaller than
equal n and that's it
right just a little bit all right how do
you do this square root remember
square root of a is a
times times 0.5 right
because it's a half right right or you
can do this master power
power a 0.5 or
sqrt mess all right master sqrt
hey okay are you guys updating me okay
that's it for today
thank you bye bye bye bye bye bye