hello ryan are you all right
yeah okay hello kitty
okay so today we're going to talk about
a
interesting program called the number of
bricks
next layout okay so what does it mean so
given the bricks of the size like look
if this is two at least it's three okay
the size the wheels with
okay ten of weave and we have uh uh
we want to we want to face the bricks
okay in uh width
and then there will be arrays rows
the height okay that's high let's call
it height
the height okay so for example there are
four and each one is the same
because we consider the height of the
bricks is one
right so that will be one two maybe okay
one two three four five six high equals
six
okay so the width is five
how many ways of placing it we can only
place the
uh the break horizontally one by one
okay
so consider only one row
one row five you can choose
you can choose the size of two and three
how many ways of play uh giving
to place in bricks in a size
five how many ways of doing that
five you if i tell you you can pick two
and pick three as many times as you want
we have two types of bricks
so five we want to reach how many ways
of putting the bricks
there's six ways five five five five
five
five what is it no no no so five
well i have two and three i want to
place in here how many ways of placing
the
breaks two and three into two three four
no no just considering this
do you get it how many ways two what are
those
two three and three two we're done two
plus three
or three plus two okay so if five if
they are
if this is five and there are how many
how many rows how many heights how many
rows one two three four five six
so each one each row has two
possibilities
and how many ways of placing all of it
so to solve this problem okay so i'll
give you a number
so look this is a 12
12 why is it 12 come on why is it 12
to b to c
if there are two ways from a to b two
ways of b to c
how many ways of a to c six
before four okay and if a there are
three ways of a to b
and two ways of b to c how many ways six
yeah so it turns together another one
two ways of c to b two ways of a to b
two ways of b to c two ways of c to t
how many ways from eight to t
eight two times two times two whether
and
two ways for placing the first row two
ways of placing the second row two ways
of placing third row two place
how many ways of doing that there are
six one
six twos how many ways twelve why is it
twelve you you are good
here why is it twelve two waves of a to
b
two waves of b two c two a c two d and
two ways of d to e
and f how many waves of a to f
how many waves of a to have
you can give me you don't need to give
me the actual answer right
two 32
32 2 x 2 4 4 x 4
16 16 x 2 32 64. okay
so the thing is that you multiply you're
not adding it together you're not saying
oh 6 2 and then
12. it's the same okay a to b two ways
look right a to b c
d e f okay a to b
two b to c two
got it yeah because each row has two
possibilities and
how many ways of placing all these six
rows to
to fulfill the the wall with the
two bricks yeah two to the power of six
okay okay okay okay so how can we do
this
if we given a bricks bricks is the size
of the bricks okay let's say bricks
which is a list of two and three
and now we want the height
height let's say height equals
height equals one four okay
and then we have at least with
with with equals
five and then you need to tell me is
what is two to the power of four okay
because for we can use
use two and three bricks of size of two
and three
to complete to to fulfill
the war one one row of war
with size five it's two plus three or
three plus two and they are
if that wall has four meters high
right so that's two to the power four
okay
so remember we have talked about
these this this is actually let's
consider because if we consider this fn
okay if you consider fn is the number of
ways to place the bricks of this type
in the single wall and the answer would
be f n
y to the power of 1 to the power 1
so actually f n and f s n is f
the answer will be f v to the power of
height right
double double height to the power high
okay so that's the answer so we know
this height
is to be calculated this way so we just
want to
calculate this function f width we just
need to focus on these f with
okay so how how can we do this f with so
so we can we can rephrase this problem
as
given a number n
and given some numbers to pick okay some
numbers to pick
i i is the numbers to pick from the
pricks okay
this symbol okay this symbol look ryan
this number
belongs don't tell your don't tell your
mom you just started
okay belongs to brit okay
so so what f n
will be the sound it looks like you see
even the minus sign yeah
f n will be the sum of what the sum
remember
we talked about the sum this one sum
this is the sum
of f and minus
phi right well
i is belongs to the bricks
okay and and and
bigger or equal i okay so this is the
function we want to calculate it right
so what what are we calling that look we
want to calculate fn function
and we need to we need to calculate
f minus i where i belongs to bricks what
what is this argument called
remember what does this call
what does this call
remember
we want to calculate this function but
we in order to
calculate this function we want to
calculate these subs
function with the smaller values so how
can we solve this problem
you know using this
what what kind of function we're talking
about recursion yeah
and we can we can memorize these yeah
what does that call
if we memorize this minimization what do
we call it
yeah top down dynamic programming okay
okay so let's
talk about the top down okay
and you tell me what's right okay define
f n
f n okay uh maybe
we write it uh let's say the bricks
wait with the brakes we have got
something
cash now you know yeah bricks we we we
want to have respec
okay so define
uh define what we call it let's k so
call it as the uh
count okay just count count how many
ways of it and we want to have this
bricks
the input and a width and the height
okay with
which is the width of the wall height is
the height of wall
right okay so now we want to define this
uh
f function f function which is n given
n right if n
is smaller than zero return one
if if that if the wii
is smaller than zero written one if the
small width is smaller than zero written
one
how many ways to play right yeah returns
zero yeah
returns yellow so we can zero and if
n is one oh if zero then we return one
right
okay this is the terminal cases then
answer equals zero
we want to sum up for i
in breaks right
now what what we need to do answer plus
[Music]
equals f f and
minus i yeah f and minus i okay because
look
let's look look look fn
f n we just say is the sum of
f m minus i where
i is belongs to bricks okay
yeah okay and and i and
it needs to be bigger or equal than i
but that's okay we don't check here
because if n is smaller than zero we
would just return zero yeah
yeah written answer okay written answer
and what's missing here cash yeah if
we're not putting the cash what happened
what's the time come back see if we're
not putting the cash
if we put in the cash what's the
thumbnail i win
no i won no no no don't guess
now what's this oh this is if there are
n num
if they are n bricks okay so this is o n
but we're calling it right
so that will be we so this is all n
times
we oh we are calling look return
return f f word f with yeah
with times times this is to the power of
h
right yeah look this is to the power h
so f w is called for each
for each k f for each sw value right
we only calculating one but for each
event f
we need to sum up with greek so it's
actually o n times
w right okay yeah
doesn't make sense right
so if we don't put a cash value what
happens
explanation is exponential because
because these values some values are
calculating over again right
okay i can give you an example yeah so
let's say f
100 and then if the brick is two and
five two
two and five okay right so you will
calculate you
you need to calculate f f 90
a and then f 95 right
right and then that will be f what
f 96 and f
90 uh
okay let's write another way f
f2 and f1 okay f99 and f90
a and f96 and 97
and that would be s90a and
f f1 97
you see look this f90 is calculating
here and
here f97 here and here
and look there will be lots of
calculation under this f
right if we not caching this value
what happened when we come here we need
to do it again
right but if we remember we're already
calculating here we remember it
what we can do is well we just look up
the value in a
notebook right in a hash table that's
why we put it
a cache right so that's why because look
f
100 100 is what 100 is the w value
so we we actually just need to calculate
f0
to f1 to fw
for each for each f value we're only
calculating once
because we store it using cash right but
for each f function we need to
go through the bricks go through the
bricks right those are the bricks so
let's
let's uh n so
n and breaks so for each one so the
complexity will be w times n right
okay so this is called top-down dynamic
programming right
we use similar recursion with the
minimization got it
okay so tomorrow we are going to talk
about butter up okay
so can you explain to me what it is f w
time times h what's this
f with volumes times
h what's this do you still remember
what's this mean
2 times times 3 what's the answer
what's this to the power right 2 to the
power 3 equals 1
what's the 2 to the power 3.
what's what's what's totally possibly
come on t remember this f w is one row
right
and then if there are three three rows
what's the answer if there are two ways
of two ways of placing one row
eight yeah so what would be two to the
power three is a right
is three three two times together okay
three
twos come together or you can write the
power
two three it's the same thing yeah two
to the power three or two times times
three okay
got it do you want to write it here
answer one
anything right here what's this
right here the key part yeah remember
yeah come on right yeah
answer what we want to accumulate the
answer yeah
answer what when's the one come on don't
look
i think that's equals f n
minus i you are you know it right why
you need to unlock the
answer yeah answer equal f
f f what f
n yeah bracket yeah
yeah minus i right because we're looping
it
at least this is the location calling
itself okay got it
okay that's it that's it for today
thank you