hello mr ryan are you all right yeah
good so remember yesterday we talked
about the bricks problem we have quick
layout right remember
bricks they are so what what's the
problem can you remind me or
i mean so we have a look okay that's it
we have a wall yeah and then each wall
is okay i need a
plan a better pen so each more
for example like the brick the bricks
are height of one unit
okay so that's height so that's one two
three four
five h equals five and a width
yeah with let's say equals five as well
and then we have two kinds of bricks
two and three okay three and two okay
three and two and you can only place the
bricks
horizontally yeah one by one
horizontally
so how many ways of placing the five
yeah because five equals three plus two
or two plus three
it's a it's a uh you can pick as many
each break you can you can place as many
as you want so there are unlimited
number of each place okay so this is
kind of the
unbounded network problem yeah enough
set
so what does it mean is that you are you
want to this snapsec is the capacity is
w
right and now we have these different
items
each item for example this item is size
of three
which item is size of two and we want to
fulfill the left set with these two
two kinds item by for each item there
are unlimited number of
of these uh you can choose anonymity
right so
this is two okay so two ways three plus
two or two plus three
so this is two way and how many times
how many possibilities
we can place in the second row how many
possibilities
the first one is two and the second one
is how many
the same yeah is it the same
ryan yeah okay so the third one
yeah how how do you come up with this
number
say i times two
times two times two times two times two
so two to the power five right
because each the number of ways to place
the first row second row three third row
is independent they are independent
right
so the combination yeah the combination
is multiplied so two to the power five
okay
so yesterday we talked about the top
down so if we
if we use the f
f with okay as we to
to to represent a number of ways to
put the bricks yeah put the bricks in
the size w
so do you still remember it's equals to
what
it equals to the sum of
f or w minus i
where i belongs yeah remember this
symbol belongs
belongs to it looks like this ear
belongs to the bricks yeah
okay and f
f let's say f uh let's say
f k is smaller e is zero
if k is smaller than zero yeah and f k
is one if
okay we can just say f zero equals one
okay
okay okay okay so now
so yesterday we talked about this the
recursion with the minimization we use
the cache remember yeah
and then we can do this in minimize
recursion to
to solve in order to to solve f w we
need to
calculate recursively fw f function with
the smaller
value right so this is top down okay so
let's do it button up we can use it we
can we can use the
we can use another approach to implement
these to solve this dynamic programming
algorithm right
so right defined let's say this is cloud
function and we have the number of
bricks
and we have a w we have h
right all right right look so now if we
want to define another function define
f f1
let's say fn okay yeah
dp this is array we want to start
store this number uh this number the
first one dp 0 is what
remember is equal to one plus z return
zen yeah the first one is dbz
plus zero zero times n what does it mean
what does it mean what does it mean here
so this is
is equal to one plus zero
times your with your yeah so this is
this will come up with the array which
is one and then zero
zero zero how many zeros here how many
others yeah how many yellow yeah come on
and and then that's one yeah pp1 okay so
that's what it means tp is this array i
know we want to calculate this tp array
from from t this is 0 fdb 0 is this
value
and we want to calculate these one by
one tier dpn right
ppn so that result is dpn right right
and we can also use which number dpn is
dp1
the last number of the array which is we
usually use a negative number which is
what
minus one minus one well so so this is
the bottom up why is whatever
look we're calculating the tp from a
smaller number to the upper number the
top down what's that
top down we want to calculate the dpm
but we we then we
need to go back to the lower to the dpu
with a smaller value yeah
so that's what it means so now dp then i
can do this
for i in
range n plus one and plus one yeah
because we
they this is up to n okay and then we
want to go through the bricks
what's fj in what
in bricks yeah we only go through the
bricks but we want to make sure that the
the capacity is bigger than the bricks
yeah so we need to
check if what if
i become
okay and then we need to sum up with
that finger dp
i plus equals what d
p i minus j yeah i might say remember
remember this
this uh f n equals f
equals sum of f n minus i where i is the
bricks yeah it's the bricks
okay so that's what it means and then we
turn
minus one all dpy or dp1 db minus one or
tp1
time time height
dp minus one is the last element which
is what dpy
remember we just talked about db1 and
it's the same yeah
yeah this is the same too and then we we
know that fn so we turn
to return f and with time time
yeah f width is the times time high
remember f
is f5 is two right yeah times time
what's time time height
mean the power okay two times
times three equals one
two eight eight because two two times
two times two three twos times together
and you can also write it as power power
two two three two comma three okay it's
the same thing two to the power of three
that's two to the power six so it's it's
two to the power of three what's the
time complexity
i i a w h
w h well then look this is this is n
yeah w
yeah we're calling that w actually this
is w
h h h f w
and then h actually this is this is the
side
actually not w h because
uh not w h w n
n is the number of bricks okay so it's
all wn
okay times h let's call it uh
okay 2 to the power of power function
okay 2 to the power of
let's say x to the power of y x to the
power y
the complexity is log y okay
so actually the complexity would be o w
times m times log height
okay so that's the complexity n is the
number of bricks
yeah w this is w and
and because at last we need to times
with the
h which is the height and if we want to
consider
x to the power of y compute that these
the compound velocity will be
o h here oh log h why is that
why this is a power remember we talked
about this
2 to the power 100 what's the time
complexity
how many times you need to times the 2
to the power 100
100 times that's linear linear you don't
need to times
this you can do this what let's let's
consider this
one two three four five six how many
you can do this times six times that's
six times right
yeah but how about if i tell you i can
do this
two to the power of six equals what two
to the power of three
times two sixteen no no no no no
two to the power of three times two
right
four is eight times two is six
so so what what does it mean two to the
power of three times two
so how many times i'm doing that total
house three you know only times two
times
yeah so you you can get these two times
and then
times itself times itself
sixteen so how many how many
multiplication are you talking about
look if you do this six times you get
one two
three four five five times okay you
times it five times
but here you only times it how many
times four uh three times
because i can kick you like this this is
two times yeah
two multiplication two times two times
two right
yeah that's eight and eight times eight
so that's one two three three times so
which one is better
which one is better this one yeah
because it uses less multiplication
that's what i mean yes
if if a to the power of b if b
is an even number if b is even number i
can always do this
a to the power of b 2 and then i do this
right look right if b is even number
i can do this because this uses less
inter multiplication and i can save half
if
b is odd number so if b is all number
equals a
times a times e minus one right
look yeah because look there be b with a
a uh two to the power of three equals
one two times two to the power of two
that's it because the three times of
three twos times together equals
one two times two twos right okay so
what uh here a to the power of b we want
to calculate
the time complexity is not b okay okay
okay
yeah okay that's it for today thank you
bye bye bye we're done good job