hello babies hello mr ellie are you all
right
okay so today we talk about a list
problem
three for a list of numbers yeah seven
nine five
uh a 10 okay
so this is the least considering of uh
consists of uh seven numbers
and you know the sub list sub sublist
sublist or service i mean like
i think that um what's the difference
between sublist and subsequence
so list is
[Music]
like you can see three and five and yeah
it's not it's not continued but it
you can chew but the order doesn't
matter yes three seven
six this is subsequent four seven six is
a service continuous okay
so how about if i wanted to to tell me
if it's possible to reverse
only once so i want to reverse only one
sublease
reverse ones sublist
so you can reverse any subjects only
once can you make
this this sorted sorted
sorted in ascending order okay in
ascending order so from a smaller number
to the fifth number
uh so for example this case can you tell
me if it's possible
to do this all right if it's possible to
reverse the subjects on these ones
oh yeah you
um can i need the more pen these are
running out
ah interesting yeah yeah you're right
yes
i got a good pen okay
how about if i yeah you're right if you
reverse this pin that would be three
four
uh three four five six seven and eight
ten yeah
three four point six seven eight nine
okay okay so given any service
so now let's say three
four how about six seven five
uh a10 is this possible
reverse any service
why is that because there is no way yeah
yeah it's not okay so okay so this
sorted you'll be three four five six
seven eight ten right that's obvious
so if i give you this hint how can you
tell me how can we do it
how can we change it is this the same
yeah
[Music]
okay and then um
okay so you find out the first first
difference it's this bit
and okay so how about this how about
the the next step this
is
yeah this is the last last
difference and then what's next we find
out the leftmost and the rightmost
difference this is a bit different
but what so you gonna reverse it so
that's why
seven six but it's not everything else
ah
way down we're done yes so yes you're
right yeah
so we find out the first difference and
find out the last difference
and then the index will reverse this bit
yeah to see if it's
the same as as the sorted so if it's not
the same then it's not possible if it's
the same
like this one five six seven you reverse
this speed will be the same right
okay so what's the term complexity for
this one
[Music]
what's the time complexity if you
if we if we go
that's right but how about we want to
get these certificates
what's the space complexity
this is the additional space come on
yeah we want
we obviously we need to all right
oh n because we need the oem space to to
store the target yeah original
remember a few days ago we talked about
reverse sub-list
as many times as want and to check if
the target soft can convert it to target
right
yeah and that's bubbling yeah remember
then we
it turns out that if in order to convert
to
from the source to the target we need to
make sure that uh
we need to check if the two lists are in
the ground right remember still remember
yes okay so let's
let's do this
if i we
just check okay check check
and then let's alarm lumps okay numbs
okay so now we want to store a copy of
the
salted array so let's call it a r array
okay
array equal as well salted
yeah look salty salty num
all right okay satin numbers
this is the iterator but we're going to
put this yeah
or just saute okay and then now look i
equal i j
the left and right okay let's call it
left and right
left right equals zero the right will be
equal to one
right equals the last one minus one
length
a r minus one okay okay
then why they're not mean why are
smaller than
r okay and what n is the
nums a
right look if it's equal to
num air
l plus equals one right look
why the left and right you know mid y
left is smaller than the right and if
the
original original number and
away at index air is equals to the salty
version right
okay salty version is the this one okay
can you write the next
can you know the next this is finding
the left
that's most leftmost position that
the first partition the ar a-r-l is not
equal to numbers so can you write the
right-most one it's quite similar
wire r
left small
um r and
every hour eq
l equals
[Music]
this is l we are changing the right yeah
i said
r okay ah yeah
okay okay okay and then what i'm
we want to check we don't actually want
to check this yeah
air
this is the salty version and this is
original version come on listen to me
l to one and two until the different one
which is all right but it needs to what
what plus one yeah
we want to check this is the third thing
yeah so we just
check return ai okay so let's
we need to convert this to sorted yeah
so we can just do this here
list this okay so now
return a r l
r plus one equal equal
yeah what's uh okay can you tell me
what's the time and space complexity
again
so we want to come listen listen away
the numbers
these b we need to reverse it to check
if reverse
equals starting right so actually here
needs to reverse
right reverse this remember we want to
reverse it to check if they are same
right
yeah and then convert it to this
okay does it make sense that's
shorter yeah that's shorter yeah that
one is shorter for one before
which one is shorter numbers l column of
plus one
yeah no no no we need to reverse it
remember
if it's 5 6 7 this is 30 if it is
7 6 5 we find out the left is here right
is here we need to
reverse this bit to see if it's the same
as the salty version right
let's yeah yeah so let's reverse reverse
but we need to convert it to the list
so okay got it actually we probably
don't need
this but that's okay okay
so this bit what's the time complexity
for this these two loop
what's the term complexity for these two
um and
oh and just a one right you're meeting
your lens okay
right okay yeah
okay uh i'm going to erase something
okay no
just the last bit okay okay okay we got
the air here
come on we got the r here uh
what do we need to do
the square bracket okay
[Music]
yeah from the air to
column yeah
[Music]
square bracket okay
we want to check if it's the same equal
equal
equal equal yeah
yeah oh the cat is sneezing
yeah least
lift come on right faster
yeah convert it to this bracket and
reverse yeah
r plus one closing bracket
closing a bracket parenthesis
and another one closing parenthesis star
star you need to close though okay
yeah okay sorry that's it that's it for
today
bye bye bye