hello hello mr area are you all right
yeah so remember what's the humming
weight
we talked about these a few years months
ago you eat
ham and you wait how much did
what's the what's the decimal what's
this in binary what's it
what's this in decimal which number
15 15 yeah 15 in decimal okay
so this humming weight is four okay tell
me
what are those what
[Music]
maybe um one two one zero one zero
that's what that's two to the power
three plus two to the left ten
right so the hamming weight of ten is
two
timing way of fifteen is four okay so
can you tell me what what i'm looking
for here
what
yeah the number of ones yeah the number
ones is the hemingway okay
so that's good so do you still remember
how we calculate the hemingway how do we
take it like coming away remember
define hemingway let's do this hamming
weight
a number hamming weight okay i mean
a number and how do we calculate the
humming weight
there are two ways at least two ways of
doing this
two ways of doing this can you give me
an example like we can convert we need
to
convert it to string to string yeah
is it is it already decimal already
but we need to convert another to the
string in to the binary
is it like 1 no no no no it's a decimal
it's 15 it's not a number
yeah it's a number so we need to convert
into into this yeah what function you
convert these to this
no no no if you yeah if you do the
strings
str15 then we could give you this
right yeah but if you give you the
binary 15
you'll give you uh you know some
variable here
uh i think it's zero b one one one one
okay
and then here let's pin 15 and then you
you can count how many of one so we can
do this
return ping
and bin for binary yeah dot count
column one column
so what's the term complexity for this
one we are converting these two
to uh to this is log n so it's login
right log in but and we we're going
through the login string so login
times login okay to count number one
okay that's one way of doing this okay
okay
log in looking okay login square to the
phone
don't bite my cables cat he thinks it's
strange
okay so the other way how can we do this
how can we do this so if this finally is
one one
zero zero zero okay so
that's a bit a low
no let this is finally how can we do
this how can we do this
okay we can cut it oh no it's already
yeah we can in binary we can come
remove the very most yeah
one no almost one to zero then we add
one
and we move it at another one
and remove this at the number yeah
okay so how can we do how can we remove
the
the rightmost one what's the right most
how we do move this one
minus one and we do what this is n and
then how can we make it
as eric how can we make it as one zero
zero zero
right yeah n minus one is this one right
and n is this one so what operation i
need to do to make it
this one come on
[Music]
n and then there's n minus one so what
operation i need
is
look minus one that would be one zero
one one one right
right this is binary yeah one zero one
one one zero and minus one that would be
one
zero one one one so what operation i
need to get a one zero
zero zero zero oh i think if that
x excuse me
how many of binary operation no if it's
all there's one right
you know all one is one right what's the
other one
what was it o
and and yeah and and exclusive oh
there's three kinds yeah
or is one of them is one come on
i just come and one all is one
see one of them is one is one right
n is both one needs to be one right
both needs to be one to be one right
correct
exclusive always they are different
right because they one
all exclusive zero is one zero exclusive
one is one
zero exclusive zero is zero one
exclusive one is zero okay
right so in this case what what is it
and so it's
n yeah and okay so we can do this
so another operation another one yeah
another one
defined let's do it another one f f n
okay
now let's say answer equals number one
yeah the second one
implementation y y or y of n
right now together
no no no no i'm just implementing the
same idea twice
answer plus equals one and what we
want to remove the rightmost one yes n
and what equal n
minus one
so this one complexity is
all log n right it's better than the
previous one this one is
because first of all you want to convert
this to binary yeah
we are looking for the binary so how
many how many
digits we're going to if it's 1 1 1 1
then you need to
that's log n right in binary yeah okay
that makes sense okay so this is one way
this is another way actually if we can
also do this we can also
go into each each digit so instead of
look
we can do this answer plus equals
n and one right the rightmost bit
and then we can we can shift one
position to the right so that will be
n shift shift array
and shift shift equals one
okay and one yeah one because look
we're looking at the rimer's digit and n
if it's zero it's zero if it's one one
and one is one right then we remove it
we shift it one that's another way but
this one is not as efficient as
as the previous one because the previous
one we are removing the one only we
speak
we are especially looking at ones right
if there are lots of zeros
this one will go through each bit by bit
but this
the previous one it will just remove one
so it's a little bit faster
all right correct okay if n
is a 32-bit it uh you know
integer then this takes almost 32 times
to
finish that in this case we are not
talking about overload and we are
talking about one right because
it takes at most 32 iteration if the end
is
we know is you know
yeah okay so now so given that uh
given uh so as given a number
uh a list of numbers like 1 15
2 3 we want to we want to solve these
numbers
so the numbers by humming weight okay so
the more hemingway that you'll be
you know you right the more hemingway
will be the
in ascending order right and if there is
a tire
there's a type let's say if we finally
is one one one zero zero or
or what one zero right
if look the coming wave of both numbers
is one
and we need to put these numbers first
because this one is bigger so we already
know that
this the function the saw yeah so we
just have to
put a key right define let's say
f lumps yeah
we just need to do list return
soft sorted okay sorted and nums
right look usually we do this and we can
put
provide a key we want to sort it by the
key which
is what we can call this number
number
x f x or r g
x this is the humming way the hemming
weight
um but that second time second parameter
will be x right
that's it so that will look
we're passing this this as a new
parameter key equals
key equals key equals number x
yeah that's the point of x i like your
return of two parts
look at this will return the two parts
the first one is hemingway so basically
you will saw
you will saw the numbers by two things
one the first thing is the hemingway if
the hemingway
is the same then you look at the actual
value okay so
that's what it means yeah okay
okay so actually you can do this as well
you can so
num dot sort yeah soft and then you can
do this key
equals this is the same thing here right
and then return num this is the same
thing
okay written so and actually you can do
this
reverse if you want to start it from the
largest to the smallest you can do this
reverse
reverse equal reverse equals two right
by default is false right
so this is something uh you can do this
passing the parameter
reverse or key right key equals
number x x so let's take an x
and return a tuple which is the first of
all is the harming weight
and the second value is the value itself
so when we pass this
lambda key lambda is a short function
that takes the parameter x
you we are based on the hemingway first
you have your sort solar numbers sorting
the numbers based on the hemingway
and if you laser tie if there are two
numbers the hemingway is the same yeah
can you give me an example of two
hemingway is the same two numbers
which has the same hemingway just any
example
come on the number ones are the same so
what are those there are a lot of
examples
hello it should be quick
what
come on two what any any example
think in binary hemingway
number one says the same so can you give
me a talk
in what in a num in an integer a
and b if they are say i say f a equals f
equals f b
so what are a and b give me example lots
of examples
hemingway's the number of ones in binary
is the same like 15 is one one one one
okay so can you think about another
number which has four
you know for what four ones but
different wait wait
it's quite easy yeah you put a zero at
the end what happened if you put the
zero
right what happened if you put a zero at
a binary
what make what does it mean
what does it mean if if one is one one
zero is one
two yeah so one zero zero is one
two yeah so you put a zero at the end
what happened
in binary
[Music]
double it yeah you double it so you give
me any number and then you double it it
has the same timing where
100 and double it two hundred they have
percent hemingway all right
okay fifteen and thirty right
fifteen thirty
sometiming way right four do you get it
yeah two four
eight sixteen they're all seven coming
away only one okay
yeah does it make sense yeah
okay so uh if each layer have some
hemingway this the first parameter is
the same and then we'll look at actual
value
right look at the actual value so your
thoughts based on the actual value
what's the time complexity if you have a
thought
um
[Music]
okay that's it for today that's it for
today
okay can you write a hemingway function
come on
what
we convert it to binary string
how do you convert it to binary string
the function start with start with b
yeah being b i n star so for binary
okay and what do we do with that
we are on the count right
count yeah dot count
kawa f kawa
what are we doing here binary come what
we turn it into binary string we want to
count how many of what
um
how many words one there are how many
card ones
bracket come on i just
have one you want color function call
one you need a bracket come on
yeah yeah i know what needs to be
quoted because it's a string right oh
okay
yeah doesn't make sense
it seems not you you're forgetting yeah
i need to do this
more right okay that's it for today
bye