go hello hello mr area are you right
yes okay so i today uh we were given a
list of string
like abc a list of strings string away a
b
and then maybe a a b c
and b c okay that's it so if i tell you
that
you you can for each each um so this is
the
list of string with three uh three
strings and you are allowed to
move the letters we arrange the vectors
so we re rearrange the characters
yeah so basically you can put it a b c
you know you can just
you know arrange it move it to different
um
strings yeah yeah yeah any letter i need
to show any string any position and
can you make all the strings equal yeah
okay this is quite obvious so how do you
move like
you move them second string oh
one of the a doesn't matter from
beginning yeah
so that will become abc okay so another
example okay
um
complicated
for this one can you make a can you make
it the same
by rearranging the right method yeah
i need position so yeah can you do it
[Music]
why ah this one yeah
it's so easy yeah look at eight look but
this
is abc abc but this is acd but that's
okay you can just move here
move to any you can still yeah so
because you can move the
characters around to any strings any
partitions
okay so given a list of strings how can
we make sure
how you check can we do it so what's
your idea i mean
say firstly yeah
okay so
[Music]
the characters and see if we could
divide it by
n because so in python we want to count
the number of frequencies for a string
right
so what kind of data structure are we
using what how can we count
remember that how can we count
um how can we talk for example
yeah we have encounter so look the cow
counter so cow counter
counter what you call this string this
string is in
all the string combined yeah
how can we make all the strings together
concatenate all the strings in the least
academic
together we use what join
so we join with empty string so
m join john a-r-r right
now s will be the key keys will be the
character
the value will be what now what's what's
s what's what's in s s is a key value
pair right
key value pair so what are the keys
keys are the character right the unique
characters yeah
yeah the values will be what the
number of them the number of times they
appear in all the strings yeah
yeah okay so the numbers and then what
should we do now we just need to go
through
each value to see if what
if what
can be divided by n right so how can we
check that
which which which operator good number
is
modulus so this modulus n equal equal
one
zero yeah we're done okay so let's try
this
and think about the time and space
complexity okay i'm gonna ask you
in one minute if i check
array uh uh let's say
what uh s okay
i say another way okay now we what do we
do
n will be length of s and
uh actually
let's say ar array a real risk
and then s will be equals joined
john ar right so s is the string of
all together all the letters all the
strings in all the lists
and then c will be the counter
counter s right so c will be the key
value pairs
keys the need characters that the values
will be the number of times they appear
in all of these
on all the strings and then what should
we do now
so we can go through for i in
c dot values right yeah we're going to
go into the value if
i modifiers what
i models which one is value and n
is
o join o n counter o
n values of o and o n okay
what's the space complexity
are we using this space here one
here n is the number of the
characters in all the strings combined
okay
yeah the number of characters in all the
strings combined okay
so we can do do this make this shorter
okay so we can do this
yeah we can just return
o right or what
uh let's say x
modulus and equal equal zero
for x yeah yeah for x
x in c dot i mean what is x
value here x
for here i define x here for x in c the
value
o means every every x in
c dot value it needs to be multiplied by
n equal equal to zero okay
right these four lines can be replaced
by this one
and then see the counter s you can look
you can move these into one line right
right so c can move here
right so you say one and and look
and and will move here okay
so what does it mean a one nine or x
modulus length a r
equal to zero for x in counter
string dot john a r right the values all
right
so you just need one none okay got it
can you write that whole thing
so it's not confusing that we need to um
read in different places yeah yeah i
think i
particularly think this is better
because it's more clear right if you
squeeze everything into one eye you'll
be harder to understand right but some
people fancy this one
so in person you can do this one liner
okay so some people prefer these but
my personally i personally like these
it's more clear but it's the same yeah
it's the same yeah
okay one liner yeah because look it's
easy yeah
okay so you don't need to do this
you know this is fancy but you don't
actually need it
right you don't actually need here uh
so what i'm going to do
gonna rub it is yeah i'm gonna drop this
out
yeah come on one four four one come on
okay follow up
[Music]
that this generally we're going to go
through the keys or values c
and then c c dot y c
dot c double key or value
keys unique elements values and the
number of times they appear within
values various practices
values values values values
us e s
ues bracket bracket
okay and then we want to check if i
and otherwise at the end if if none of
the violations we found then we returned
to obviously okay
well i'm very well done today okay say
bye that's it
bye