[Applause]
remember yesterday we talked about how
to check if a string is a valid
parenthesis right yes how how about i
ask you this question how about if if i
given i
give a a string
which is contains the parenthesis and
tell me
how many how many uh brackets
or premises do you need to make to to to
put into the string to make it a
valid parenthesis for example like least
then you should give me zero because
it's already
valid parentheses and how about this you
should give me
two because you need to put one
parenthesis here
yeah your two right really and how about
this one i don't get it what you mean
oh how about this one look uh but
this is the one we inserted okay
you need to insert one so that's that's
one all right
i have to make a valley so for example
this one
uh please how many
what's the answer yes one because you
need to put one here right
that's one and how about that
how
[Music]
how about please please
open it to your knee one
ten two yeah because you put one here
and one here yeah
okay so you get it yes
so any
idea how we solve it oh um
how do you solve it ryan any thoughts
any thoughts
[Music]
yeah i mean just how many uh how do we
solve this problem
um
of course we keep a variable balance
yeah
to the b value because the
current number opening brackets
parenthesis
yeah okay so like look one yeah here
left bracket is one
opening parenthesis zero okay so that's
zero
how about this uh if i don't have left
okay so look
that's minus one right so if it's minus
one then i
how about i have uh that's only two
i know one here and then
and then the balance will become
zero again and then this one is one okay
the end now we add one more because the
the current opening packet
is one so we add one more and hover
river
one zero
minus one yeah so we add one more yeah
one so to get it all you can do this uh
uh you can put this list well you can
put it here right it's the same yeah
yeah and how about this one
one alright look one two
what's next
one right one and then you have one more
then you add
one how about this probably this is
interesting look
minus one yeah so every time we we find
it's negative we
add one here to the answer and then
one zero
yeah minus one and another one
when one is falling below the zero we
don't
increment we will make it zero uh we we
make it immediately zero and put it
under one
okay do you get it okay so this should
be very simple okay
how how do we do this define yeah okay
define let's say repair okay repair
repair parentheses all right
and s let's call it answer
equals zero okay this is the answer
we're going to return alright
yeah and then current parents right look
balance
balance we call it zero at the beginning
for i in s
look if i equals
left parenthesis right open in
parenthesis
then what should we do now we should
increment the balance right
this is the the code to say how many
opening brackets we
have right s l is
i equals the closing parenthesis
then we need to decrement decrement
the counter to one right right but if
it's below zero what happened
if it would be zero it's quite similar
below zero then we make it zero
right make it zero but we need to
increment the answer
what's the end here what's the end
return
can you guess what um
what's the what's it what's your answer
return
y'all say answer okay and what's what's
it what
eric's answer maybe
maybe no maybe also this is
not quite right you we still have to
we still have to do what
plus plus one
no no no yeah plus b yeah
remember when we do this
one two one
so we have one left right it means we
need to close
one bracket am right
do you get it it's quite similar than
the one yesterday right
the chip and if it falls
in the bracket sorry if it's
under zero if it's under zero like this
look
if if it's under zero right if it's
under zero
and i and answer increment one and then
my appearance is zero because
now i can stop okay do you get it yeah
so look how many do you need
three yeah because look always smaller
than zero
minus one minus one minus one make it
zero make it zero make it zero and
increment the answer three times got it
yeah babe
yeah you need to make the balance yellow
otherwise because
yeah yeah yeah because if you're not
making a zero then this
this will be incorrect right because
you're adding the answers and parents
together
right yeah how's the complexity time
complexity is
do you still remember our
no no no no no oh
because we're going through the string
once
it's exactly what okay so that's good so
how about
any questions say god
no no no
so any questions so far no no no
questions
okay so um
yes say goodbye here bye
mario blue