hello hello hello mr ariel all right
a long time ago we talked about
apprentices yeah fantasies so given the
parenthesis
how do we check if it's a valid if it
comes with a pair
so this is not right yeah and
this is what not
at least is yeah
and this is nice okay so how can we do
it i need one correct
yeah how can we do it we um use that
balance that we um we use the counter
to count if it's opening if it's opening
a plus one
closing minus one if any time it falls
below zero
then it's not right yeah yeah so look
plus one minus one is zero one
zero one and at the end we need to check
it with zero
right this is minus one now
one zero one zero that's good zero
one zero one no because at the end it
needs to be zero okay
so today's tasks are a little bit
similar but different quite similar okay
so we are given a pair
so you need to keep tell me the longest
the longest longest valid
valid subsequent uh the quantities
pairs so quantities per subsequence yeah
what's the subsequence
[Music]
so long is valid subsequent so
which one this one this one
this one yes so that's six one two three
four five six
okay got
how many
yeah how about the one bigger than that
how about this oh yeah yeah so so well
yeah so let's the longest would be
six right yeah
you you return the number of parentheses
exactly because we want to find out the
number of pairs right so it needs to be
an even number that's a good catch
so how can we do this how can we do this
any idea
it's quite similar so so we any idea
so before if it's negative it will
counter it's negative we just return
faster because that
at the beginning the previous task is
was checking the
the string with the red parentheses but
now we are
we need to find out the number of the
valid pairs
so it's if it's negative we just ignore
continue negative
ignore continue and set it to zero right
and then we start here one
right one two
right okay now if i mean this
closing parenthesis what does it mean we
increment we decrement
to one right so if we still above zero
about equal zero
what does it mean if we have a if we add
this point
we are not violating the balance count
the balance is still above or equal to
zero after we inc
equipment one what does it mean it means
we already
have a corresponding pair right yeah
okay yeah in order to be
valid it has to be come in patch compare
right
you have a closing one so there must be
a opening one
got it right right
yeah okay so now this is
now the quarter is one yeah the counter
the answer
answer is one okay and the balance will
be one the balance will be one
and here two balance will be two right
but we're not doing anything to answer
because we're not meeting uh closing
minus one balance will be one and the
answer will plus one
all right balance will be zero
yeah answer plus one so left three
quantities
times two is six okay
does it make sense yeah it looks like
it's time seven
yes okay so
can you repeat what i'm saying just make
sure you understand oh
because it times two at the end yeah
yeah but how can we count how many yeah
they say that say that firstly
um if it goes below zero it's um
we set it back to zero from them next
it's like one and plus one again that's
two
and then and what cases uh what do we
mean
when do we plus the answers if
if um that is a
is bigger than zero and we need um this
closing yeah yeah what would be the
closing we increment because if we move
the cur
opening we don't don't know if they are
closing right
so look this is yellow right equivalent
counter
one two three right the the patterns
count one two three but we don't know
if lay less uh closing if we mean here
yeah so we we add the one we need
another one
we added one we need another one
everyone okay
yeah that's how it works okay
doesn't make sense yeah okay so okay
let's run it anytime you want to write
okay
define longest
subsequent valid valid parenthesis okay
when parenthesis
s so we have an answer
and we also need to a balance yeah a
balanced counter
which at the beginning set to one
zero answer equals balance because okay
and then for
i in s we go through each
each characters in a parenthesis string
if i is opening
what should we do
plus one here one plus one balance plus
one
plus equation as here is the
if if this string only contains the
opening and closing
so we don't need to check if it's
closing because if it's not
if it's equal to opening is here errors
it should be the clos
here it should be the closing yeah yeah
right this is coming okay
that's what um
we need to check if they obviously
[Music]
come on tell me if look here
one and then zero yeah
what happened what happened to i said
yeah equal yeah then what happened
we plus one which one five one and the
plus equals one
and as if it's smaller than zero what
happened
if balance is smaller than zero zero
yeah we started to balance
here at this point right at this point
it means that at this point
the previous one does not count anymore
right
so we start with the new one so balance
equals zero
and return within
okay what's the time complexity
if there are any strings and characters
in
s what's the term complexity
what's the space complexity
and the one
why you say oh and where is the space a1
come on
yeah okay
bye