hello hello mr area are you all right
yeah okay so today is it
in front of it night right now
yeah yeah yeah okay so today we talk
about uh the keyboard
and typing okay so given a keyboard
a keyboard no no it's too complicated
i'll do one very quickly
okay you'll throw a keyboard okay
so i'm going to put the maximum the
title to the maximum
typing
maximum typing you can
invest the number of words you can type
maximum number of
what you can type
okay so let's take q-w-e-r-t yeah
y-u-i-o-p
[Music]
i-o-t
a-s-t-f a-s-t-f
a-s d-f and g
g h j k l
okay and say x c v b
z z yeah
keyboard layout of the 26 characters
okay so
how about let's consider this this one
okay hello
wha hello okay if i tell you that
a and d are broken so you cannot type
this you know think about it like
but these two keys are just broken right
so a and b
so these two uh how which word can you
type hello
yeah but you know do this yeah
yeah all right
anyway likes
play okay if i tell you
c and s is broken okay
if i tell you
okay if i tell you c c and
s are broken you cannot have these two
so which one can you
do it um
playing yeah so you give me one or one
okay one word okay
so any idea how we're doing this this
how are we doing this
so first of all we need to
suppose this let this uh
these sentences are separated by y
spaces so how can we split
the sentences into words i just say that
using that function
if you want to split the string by a
delimiter
which one should we use join no no no
the opposite of john john is
the opposite of join what's that john is
make a
array into uh
you know make it together right no no no
start with ssp split
yes please turn the opposite spreader
join
split got it john john
john look one two three if you join
you join and you become one two three
yeah split
okay george split okay so we can split
by spaces and then you become words and
for each word we
we just need to check each word if
if all of the characters are in
i are using these broken key letters and
all right if you're using broken
keywords
we don't need to increment the answer if
we if all the letters are not in the
broken list
so how do we enable the one lookup for
the
to check if the letter is in a broken
letters
what kind of data structure are we using
you know if we want to enable checking
something is in something uh yes what
what does that
no it's actually not necessarily the
code we just need to check if something
is in if something is in a list
so what kind of data structure are we
using
notebook has headset set yeah headset so
first of all
first of all we put the broken letters
okay so let's do it define
this is broken
all right okay let's define
let's say let's just say f function okay
this is broken
okay so let's uh sentences and then
broken letters okay broken
broken letters okay let's see okay
so first of all we please in a broken
letter
into a headset so set yeah
set we put it in a broken broken into
the headset so broken
okay then answer is the number of words
we can type equal zero
so first we need to split it yeah
so if we split it let's say array okay
let that work let's put it words here
yeah
what equals
empty space yeah then these words would
be a list of strings they have these two
words okay
yeah yeah and then we need to go through
this one therefore
in in what for word in that broken
meanwhile in what we just please
we want to go through the list of words
for what w in one word yeah what
okay so now w is a string yeah like arry
then we we want to go through leads to
check
if each letter is in not in b right
so we can do this if or look this is the
keyword or or or means that everything
in here needs to satisfy the meter
criteria
for what i in
not in not in
d yeah what's i what's i
i can make it every plus one no
i in what so what is the worst so
look for each letter not in b so for i
in what what's this
what's this come on b is that
set of program so for i not in b for i
i need to define what's i was
and yeah in that war particular if left
we need to do one we need to draw
and we plus which one price one answer
is a plus one equals one and what's
missing here
return
okay what's the time complexity if there
are any
characters in the string in s
o n
what's space complexity
what's space convexity oh and
why is that one because we're using my
name but
here's a noble actually it's o mu
m is the number of broken characters
yeah o m
okay o m so look we
why is this oh and look at there is a
phone it's a thing why is it 01
because look we split the characters in
the string right
in words and we go through each word
each character yeah
how many times n times we need to check
each character
to see if it's in the b right so let's
say
that if all i not in b
for i in w you can expand this into
multiple lines but this is the
um more easy way right it's a more
straightforward way okay
so if all what can you write it and
that's it
oh god you don't have to be kidding me
right
you all want you all right
i yeah or anything yeah it's not
yeah not in which is the lookup table
b yeah not in b
uh oh i know in b and we need to tell
computer what's i right
for for you need to say for for i
in i is
[Music]
w yeah w w is in words right so
i is in w so i is each character in
this word and w is in words so
what is a list of string of words right
like every
line's playing and w will become every
less brain
and i in w so i will be e
r i c got it yeah okay
you got it that's it for today good job
good job