hello hello eric are you all right
yeah okay so today we'll talk about very
simple
problem concatenation what's this mean
concatenation
of arrays what does this mean
concatenate okay it means that you
come that you call a cat
and then you aim it and yeah it's put
things one after another nation we put
one thing after another okay
so i have a array all right a
one two three and i have another array
b equals four five six
so continuation you pull them together
so look yeah
so how do we do this in 1915 how do we
use
in python how do we do it
do we need to do it actually it's very
simple
a and b need to be in the right order
no no just put a you just put b after
a that's congratulation yeah so you
don't move anything doesn't matter if it
gets one of these
yes no no no just keep the original
order so you put these at the end so
yeah so what what do we have this here
yeah we're done that's that's that's the
basic today okay concatenation over to
the left
but today it's uh we talked about
something you know
interesting is that i have already done
yeah
and i want to make it make it look dumb
equals one two three right yeah i want
you to return
a concatenation of itself so you'll be
one two three
and one two three
so how long does it mean we just double
it
easy double it well done so you can
return if
this is number return one nums
wait is the numbers one two three yeah
okay
return numbers
[Music]
what do we have before nouns and notes
come past nouns yeah that will work and
also return
numbs you can also what two
three numbers numbers what too
well yeah that will also work okay so
how about if i tell you written
nouns
how about if i tell you you can't use
this
you can't use the and
times okay
so say i think it's something like
so if i tell you you can't okay so
you make two nouns and then you put them
together
oh
no i you can't put the two numbers so
that's what i'm saying i give you one
hint
so how about if i have an array i'm
gonna push it
one two three at the end you know
usually anything
no no no no if we want to push some
element at the end of the list or what
do we have
what kind of message we i will use star
with a
p apart p
append yeah okay
[Music]
we can have answer yeah answer it could
be a separate so if we want to keep copy
remember we have a diff copy
yeah i could just say d copy yeah answer
equals one
copy copy copy dot d copy is from copy
package
deep copy copy
copy with what number we want to put it
so so what happened
answers and numbs are different right
i'll copy
exactly are to copy what happens if you
put answer equals numbers
what does it do what does it do look if
we do this answer equals
nums what happened what's the difference
between these two
answer the copy numbers and answer the
numbers
what's the difference um i'll say
it's a copy of them and what's this
it's just norms and it's an alias this
one is
called you know it's not difficult it's
shallow cop here
shallow shallow copy the opposite of t
so what happened answer is deep copy
they are separate they are individual
right so they're independent of each
other but at least one answer
numbers whatever so you'll be one two
three here and if you do this
answer will be like that it's an area
numbers will be like that
so if you you say answer zero equals
zero right
the num zero will be also equal to zero
don't get it it's an alias
yeah but follow for the deep copy
it's a separate one two three so if you
say
answer zero equals zero it doesn't
affect the number look at it
okay yeah so in this case we're using
deep copy yeah
d copy here and then we don't want to
follow
i in nums what we do with the
answer answer
okay
come on
yeah that's it so that will append and
return
if i tell you if i tell you
if i tell you that
i want to push to original numbers right
one last solution if i want to push to
original numbers without
allocating a deep copy
so i just want to push one two three
here what happened
what do we do so basically
this is a picture anything let me think
i can follow this yeah you can tell me
yeah i i think you can solve it it's not
that hard
with a little bit thinking so uh
okay so do we need to actually know the
numbers yeah so i give you a hint
and equals let me think okay
no hints
[Music]
interesting so yeah so i push
what i need to push how many elements
here
wait wait say say so say so
so
okay so um so so
[Music]
okay so what should we open we're going
to
n is three zero one two and i is zero
one two okay so now stop ten
open one
n is three i is the index i want to
append one two three so
what should i put come on
sorry i wait
what look i is the index what's the
value of the index
what's the value in the numbers what's
the value of index
you don't get me okay so this is the
index zero this is index one this is
index two so what's the value of
index zero one yeah
how how can i get it with the index this
is index i
so how can i get the value come on
um we just get to the beginning
what's the if the index is i the array
is noun
what's the how do you write it how do
you write it
how do you write this syntax if i want
to get the i e
value exams at index i
uh what what should happen here
what should i put here
what should i put here they have two
symbols
okay i give you a little come on in
flare it's there come on it's there come
on
it's on the ball what should i put
between nouns and eyes
come on it's there why you don't get it
what
you don't understand what i'm talking
about okay so i want
the index index is i
and then array is nums
so i want to get the eyes the the
the value and numbs uh index i so
in person how we doing array
the first array the first element of the
array how do we get it
numbs what the first element of the
array
is zero zero what's yellow
bracket yeah that's now what i'm saying
bracket okay
yeah okay that's it okay so you you
actually
remind me and i said something if i want
to look eyes from that and i can just do
this
noms
but i want to append the first
n elements so what should i do here
i back it it's not
yeah that's it okay so
at least there are a lot quite a lot i
need
any any come on are there any rules
no no no just do any you can do a simple
one if you want
[Music]
okay i don't mind okay
return come on that's
easy today what
there's no answer come on oh there's
none so just numbs
oh it right
we're done that's it for today good job