go hello hello eri are you all right
yes okay so today we talk about linkedin
remember
what's english language usually you know
english is a link
okay like that yeah
no you know if it's the last one so
usually you have this head there is
increase
you have is english how do you define
english class
node okay note and then you define
define that's a constructor
i int yeah init
and then you take a what a value and the
next
equals to num right usually like that
and then
uh self dot value
equals value that's a class of the note
yes self defined yeah and it needs to
cover next
self dot
next equals next
okay so so this is the link
the definition of linked node so each
node it has the pointer points to next
right it doesn't know the previous one
right
and usually for a link this problem
you are given ahead right but today task
very simple
you you don't know the head right you
don't know that why
because i say so you don't want to have
it and then you want i
think
you are only given a note right and i
want you to remove it for example
that's one two three four
and then you're given this now
i want you to remove it and make an
english but this note is not the
the last note okay you're guaranteed
like you're given a note which is not
the last note okay
why you are given a note which sorry
what if it is no no i i'm just saying
the note is not the last note okay
node is not equal to tail that's the
given condition it's not a tail it's not
a form so given that they called
the tail the last note okay so listen to
me you're given this note
it just looks like a stick you're given
this no okay listen
i i want you to remove it so eventually
you're given this one
three four and now
okay that's the end the last note what
what's
now no no means empty
no no okay okay so any idea
any idea okay no it's the same as
near yeah you know this was near
empty there you know empty
nothing okay you can you can
any idea um so
look because because of this no for each
note you only know what's next right
and you can't do this because if you
delete this what happens
if you take away directly take away that
will happen
the link will be broken right all right
because if
you take this you might know what
happened the previous note
points to nothing got it and the link
will be broken into half
got it yeah
make sense okay so eventually i want to
make you like one three four yeah
can i give you a hint that you can copy
chrome now you don't actually need to
delete it just have to make sure it's
one three four no
okay that's one great thing okay
say
you're just making another another link
listen
and just and copy all of it from that
blue note welcome well that's a great
that's a great story you
first of all copy but but the thing is
that you don't know the head right how
do you copy the link list without the
hair you don't know
that's the problem if you're given that
one
please that's the given condition okay
okay
if you're giving a head then you can you
can iterate from the head right
until you can check if it's head is the
note back so you're supposed to be given
one three four and
the head is one yeah how do you know
that
that's given no that the thing is that
you're given this note you don't know
the previous
you don't know the neck you you know the
next but you don't know the previous one
so you don't know if it's the first note
or if it's in the media note and how can
i return one three
four what do you mean
i mean that's if you take away this note
then
this linkedin will become one three four
right
yeah you just don't know but eventually
if you
take away the two you will become one
three four and right
okay okay
okay so how can we do this uh
i know i say you get
[Music]
there are two methods we can do it
there are two misses
i can tell you
come on if you need take time i can tell
you
okay i want to remove these two wait can
can you just can you just believe the
arrows
tell you which error the arrows
which arrow any arrows
which which which error you mean the
next
thing how do you delete the next uh the
error error is points to the next
yes okay so which how do you get it how
do you
i don't know yeah yeah of course if you
delete it you'll be setting the note
note
next to none to know that you'll be
deleted it will be
same as not if you if you say no
next equals none
then you'll be eventually did this right
if you said no the next noun then it
will be
this will be broken into half right
that's what i mean
yeah okay okay so how do i do this
come on if you know i'm going to give
you the answer
it's okay you don't know okay do you
know
any idea come on what's your thoughts
because like can you delete
you know you can't delete renee directly
yeah i can't get this note but i can't
do this now right i know it's next right
so how about if i did this now
i know what's going on yeah so before i
do
this note i want to make this note and
copy of it
right yeah okay so now become
what if no yeah then i can say no
don't next uh
actually i need to save this n equals
not the next
this value yeah and now it's this one
and then i can say no the value
equals what and the value right
yeah right so what does
mean this will become three okay
okay know the value equals end of value
and then i need to do what no dot
next no dot next equals to
what here yeah so what's that
what's this value what's this note no
don't x equals one
what's next now no no no this note is
what
this is n what's this b what's this
and the next okay right then i set it to
here
and then all the next thing is i wanted
to do this yeah
and d e l yeah did it
and that's it okay so what do we do
now what what do we do with n equals
node next
okay n is here right this node
the value i copy from the next node this
node
next next i say
i point it to n the next right another
complete this now
that's one way another way what's the
term complexity for this one
[Music]
come on what
why is the end why is that
all i do is just rearrange this what's a
one come on
yeah make sense that common sense okay
so another one
is what another way another way
let me think another one another way
okay so if
okay i tell you look one two
three four five
okay no i want you to do
this one so you become
[Music]
one you become one three four
five no
wait can you delete can you even leave
this one at any moment any um
wait so it's quite similar but
what we do is what look here look at
look at my hand
what does that tell you two pointers
no no no look i i this bit is the pit i
want to keep how about i move it one
position to the left 61
so every time 2 equals 3 3 equals 4
4 equals 5 and i did the last one right
yeah every note is equal the value
equals its next node
right last one
now but the next last one and i will
just delete it but i have to keep a
previous one to the last one and the
previous tone next
equals num and i think it's equal
sorry that's the point five i would
defeat it
it doesn't matter i would remove it
right okay okay i write the code so you
probably know okay
define remove
node okay you will give it a no you are
not given anything else
so first of all you have a previous now
equals noun
the previous point the second to the
last right
so wire while no
dot next okay then i can say
no dot value equals one
no the value equals the next value no
don't next
value the value and then i have to save
the node previous
the node current no previous equals no
and then node equals
no the next right
right and then the previous one the
previous is now on the second knot
right because previous is second now
previous stop next
equals noun right and unknown
node is the last one no so i just have
to delete
no why what's the time complexity for
this one
what's the term complexity for this one
huh sorry
no there you go uh o-n yes because
you know if there are n notes if the end
note in the link list if i don't want to
remove the first one you have to shift
end right you have to see it well all
right got it
okay any okay two messes right one
oh come on come on the first one is easy
right
think about it think about it i help you
think about it
one or by the way all one better or old
and better
which method is better
here right you can write it here
come on come on you're giving this node
right listener
so what do we do before we removing
these nodes
what do we do yeah yeah come on come on
first of all you need to save a value of
that this is no and what
what's the value of this what's the no
okay
[Music]
no no no no no no no no because this is
the given
condition now and whatever equals now
the next right
now because this is given okay whatever
and then what this is whatever and what
i want to say no value equals whatever
the value right
i think okay yeah i want to say this no
exactly like that so what should i do
what are no term next
[Music]
value whatever yeah whatever top value
yeah i know the next equal whatever next
and then you can remove whatever right
got it easy right
whatever the value right
x equals whatever the next need you want
to point to the next you want to point
these
to the list right you know the next
equals whatever the neck whatever not
next it's here no the next
point is through here all right curry no
the legs
yeah yeah equals whatever does next yeah
pointing through here all right
whatever
and then you don't babe yeah and then
what happened
there for delete
whatever yeah what's the time next year
then
i won yeah what's the space complex
theorem
sorry what's the term come next to your
game what do you say
i want a one what's the specs from xp
uh any space where you're allocating one
or one
exactly okay that's it for today good
job
bye