hello hello eric are you right
yeah okay so today we're going to talk
about diagnose of a
square metric so what's square matrix
like one two
three four if there are four columns and
there'll be four
rows yeah five six seven eight
zero one two three three zero one two
okay
so four square
square metric
if there are n columns so there should
be n rows okay
i want to calculate the sum
the sum of diagonals
so how many how many numbers are there
16. yeah how many diagonals are there
how many diagonals in this case
[Music]
how many how many numbers are on the
diagonals
eight yeah eight so just some of these
values
simple this is even at f4
and how about the odd number like one
two three
four five six seven eight nine
so how many odd numbers left
how many how many diagonals number there
and five five so they are five
yeah and there are eight here so eight
equals
two times four at least three yeah
so if it's even number is two times
three minus one why do we need to minus
one
because we go across and mean yeah we go
across if we times two we need to
subtract one yeah because this number is
counted twice
right correct yeah
okay so how can we do this easy right
so we just need to sum up the numbers
yeah but pay attention to these if it's
in the middle
if it's in the middle then we only need
to calculate at once right
so look if we if this is n
if this is n we iterate
range range let's do a range i
in range n yeah
so what's the index of these these
diagonals
what's the index how do we if this
matrix is m
how can we access this number here
and zero zero because it's two
dimensional yeah and here
one one yeah and one one etc okay
so if n is from zero to n minus one yes
so it's
m i i right okay
yeah so these columns is mii
and how about this
i is the row so if i'm here so it should
be here right
so it's the mirror remember let me know
right if there are n so what's the
coordinate of this
n minus one minus i right remember it's
like the reverse
mirror yeah all right
look if here i want to calculate this
the i is one right i want this
two right zero one two how how do you
come up with two
four minus one minus one right okay yeah
and if i is here it should be here
four minus one minus two is one
okay and here i is three
four minus one minus three is zero okay
so using this formula you always find
the corresponding
image location so it's
so i we want to add m i i plus
m i and minus i minus 1
yeah but if if n
minus i minus i my minus 1 minus i
is equals to i we don't we we don't
add it right because it will be the case
in the middle you can't add the number
twice okay
easy yeah fine work yeah easy
define diagonal
sum metric m
so we want to get n n equals length m
and if n is only one what does it mean
return one if there's only one element
yeah we only return m zero zero okay
yeah that's diagonal it's only one
number then
answer equals zero right four
i in range range one
um two n twenty n yes
okay then i want first of all i want to
add the number answer
plus equals one answer plus
equals and i what
i i i yeah
okay and then i i need to calculate the
the opposite let's say j
equals n minus i minus one right
if one if
look this here i'm calculating here
here is i right here it's i and then
it's
it's image part is here is
n minus y one minus i is j
j is here right this is the diagonal of
this
yeah i want to add this number yeah and
my eye is in this number right
answer plus this is these are these ones
where i want to add this
only if this point is not the same as
this point if it's the same it's going
to be
right
[Music]
um
and yeah what's the space complexity
usually that's really good okay
okay that's it right now nothing
no b come on come on it's
easy you want to add these and at least
and only at least if it's not the same
as the left one
okay you can do it i trust this
answer plus equal one um
yeah the first coating i is the row j
yeah okay yeah
look that's i this whole pie is n
so what's this yeah correct
so look here is j he's
here and here is i i want how big is
this
um
minus one minus
minus i and you need to minus one minus
one okay and if i not equal
yeah if i know equals j
that will happen
oh that's okay yes the shooter code is
okay
as long as you know how do you get it
yeah
i know you're going to say yeah
all right if i know you're gonna say
what does it mean
what happened if i equals
bye