hello today uh we talk about a math
problem okay
yeah okay so given that
and people are people these people okay
there are lots of people he's standing
in the line yeah a lot of people i'm
wrong with that a lot
hey okay so all right ryan listen to me
yes we are they are end people okay look
at their own people
and people and are you are standing
somewhere but you're not sure
which position you are in right so you
could be here and keep it here
right but you know you know there are
eight people in front of you yeah there
are eight people in front
you and b people at least eight people
in front of you
at least eight people in front of you
suppose you are here right you are here
you are here
so there are at least eight people in
front of
uh at least eight people in front of you
and here
you and most and most big people
at the back of you okay here is frank
here is from
and he's back
so look you're facing this way yeah so
there there are
at least eight people in front of you
and and most
b people at the back of you i give an
example right
so that if there are three people yeah n
equals three
and if i say in these you
you're not sure where position you are
but you know
at least one people in front of you and
one people at the back
yeah one one people one person one
person at the back of you so
how many possible petition can you be in
this game
where why is one middle yeah it's in the
middle because look here at one people
at least one people in front of you and
most when people are at the back of you
can it be here
no because there's two in the front and
none of them
wait wait wait look yeah you can be here
look
you say at least one people in front of
you right but there are two people so at
least
one two three there's one there isn't
any
that's okay atmosphere so it could be
here as well
so there are two two right that's what
i'm saying at least
at least two people at least one how
about
the back none zero is smaller than b
right what's b b one people a
a equals one b equals one so
can it be here no at least one because
we've got nothing so this
condition does not certify okay okay
so yeah what does it make sense it could
be this one or this one right
yeah i know and then all you need to do
is look in front of you
if if there is a person in front of you
he says
yeah yeah so how can we solve this
problem okay so we're just
using three four things how do we prove
first
i check in each one okay so like okay
on my first one okay turn me around ryan
okay and then and then okay
i haven't found only okay is it
is it it from the front is it smaller
than one
yeah so we just checking right look we
can check if we're here right
yeah in here here so this is the way we
professing we check
each possible location and we check if
we satisfy these two conditions
at least a in front of you and at least
at most b at the back of you right
okay so so and if we satisfied
we increment the answer okay so define
three parameters and a b what's missing
okay now is the partition all right
let's say position is i
answer answer is
equal zero okay so now yeah okay
and now we need to check look if if
at most b at the back right so i needs
to be smaller than b
equal b right look why oh look look
here this is i so
b yeah needs to smoke this i
needs to small equal than b am right
yeah
could it be b
well not really
look if and most and most
yes and most right because
so look look there are np
and here is i so how many of these here
are here
and here is n here is i and how big is
this
um n minus i
and minus i right yeah you cut it
n minus i and elite and these right
at least and minus i plus one actually
right
and minus i plus one
at least bigger equal
than a right right okay
yeah and if i remove this equal so i can
remove this
one right so n minus i bigger than a
is e is the same as m minus a bigger
than i
am right yeah
and then y i is smaller than n minus
a and if this is these two conditions
mean satisfy what we do answers what
plus equals one and what happened to the
eye
we start from left to the right so what
happens
okay so look check what are we doing
here
look at this is very important the term
complexity is what
and space convexity
then look i look i is yellow
i want to check if it's yellow look if i
don't check this
why n is i is zero y i smaller than b
and the plus equals one i plus equals
one so
what's answer in this case
look if i don't don't if i don't
consider this bit
so what's what's what does this doing
why i smaller than b
answer plus equals one i plus equals one
can we calculate the value of
i of answer
yes look i is zero every time you
increment one until it reaches b
every time you increment i answer will
equal one so what's the answer
what's the answer what's the value of
answer when this loop
breaks look i
start from zero zero one two yeah until
b right
and each time i increment one answer
also increment one right
yes so what's the value of our answer
when the i is equals to b
smaller or equals to b um
[Music]
b plus one yeah because yeah yeah b plus
another i chose b smaller than b right
now b plus one because star from zero do
you have one okay here i
added one more look i added one more
condition here
all right look y i is smaller than n
minus a
so if i don't look at this bit if i
don't i look at this speed
i will increment how many times and
minus a right
and answer would be n minus a right yeah
so if
i to please two condition and put an n
so what's the value of answer
b b and a
smaller or bigger of these b
and n minus a look i is smaller than b
and i
is smaller than n minus a so what does
it mean i is smaller than 100
i is smaller than a thousand so what
i smaller than b yeah i explained 100 so
we want to know which one is smaller
right
yeah so the answer would be the smaller
value of what
smaller value of one b plus one because
zero
will be all and this right so can you
write it yeah do you understand now
all right do you understand
so all these can be improved
into one single line return
with our minimum of what two values
minimum of a and b
sorry minimum
one
what is this doing here b b
b plus one right and a
this is ah this is i n smaller n minus
a so what's the value what what do we
say
look i smaller than 100 and i smaller
than a thousand
so what's this mean y i is smaller than
which condition will be
will be yeah smaller one right
so when i increment how many times
answer increment how many times
so look this when i is
when b is smaller the answer will
increment b plus
1 times when n minus a is smaller
because this is equal smaller not equal
so your increment
and minus a times right
so what's your happen here n
minus a where down does it make sense
correct what's the time complexity of
this one
this is the same as this one which one
is better
i like the bottom one
yeah this is quicker and what's the
sound complexity
[Music]
come on my smartest one yeah because no
matter how big is
n we can just directly calculate the
answer right
does it make sense eric do you
understand why we can transform this
from o n to a one how can we improve it
do you understand look if b is a
10 n minus a is a hundred
so if it's same as y i smaller than 10
and i smaller than 100 i will be
increment one so which condition would
be me
will will be break
i increment from zero to one two three
four five which number you will hit
first why i smaller than ten and why i
smaller than hundred
the smaller one right yeah the smaller
one so
when it hits the 10 answer will be 11
right
got it all right if this is a hundred
and this is ten
so so these will be hit first right
right okay look every time we increment
i
we include my answer got it so basically
we want to find out how many iterations
this book does
right right so it's the answer of
because look is i smaller than one
something and i smaller than another
thing
so we want to find out the minimum
iteration minimum number of these two
values right
and this is the number of times i
iterate got it
i iterate and that's the answer because
answer increment as i increment e plus
one because i smaller or equal b
when when this loop exists the i
answer will be increment i plus 1 b plus
1 times
i smaller than n minus a when i equals a
minus a you'll be
iterated and minus a times right the
time complexity of one because
mathematics no matter how big is this
okay okay so
give me one answer that's it give me one
answer
okay you write it for me okay come on
which one
yeah doesn't make sense
okay in one sentence can you describe me
what have you learned today
hi what's the problem today
what's the problem today
if you want to tell mommy if you want to
ask mommy
and can you describe me you don't need
to tell me the solution just tell me
what's the problem
the problem is there's not enough people
and you don't know where you are
yeah there aren't people yeah but you
know what you know is what
and most b people
at the back right and eight people in
the front
at least eight people in the front right
and then you want to know how long
how many of possibilities you can be
right okay
yeah okay you can tell mommy that's bye
okay that's it