hello hello hello mr mr right now
all right so let's
let's look at this uh list one five
three
uh two one right
okay yeah one five three two one so
what's sublist service continuous
sub list okay can you give me an example
of a service one five three two
one okay that's a good example so okay
so one five three two one look
has the same person the last value look
this is the perfect example here because
the first element is one the
last element is also one which is the
same so this
is the sub list good service that has
the first and
last element is the same so how many of
those in in this list
how many of those six yes
six years yeah why is it six
[Music]
we notice that each single element is
the subject which is also satisfying
this right because they
for each quality service of size one the
first and the last elements also
is also the same okay cool how can we do
this
how can we count it define
call okay let's say these nums okay
how how can we how can we
compute this list how can we count it
any idea answer yeah and yeah
[Music]
we can always do what we know
usually we can do what
poor forcing yeah how can we prove us
yes
how can we perform
checking every surface right yeah so in
order to just check this out
because stuff is we can prove something
in oh and
what's the time from xt is n square
right
so look m equals length number right
look if these one side three to one we
can check the pairs yeah one side
one one one five one three one two one
one
two five three five two five okay yeah
so this pairs o n square because it's
what
is is actually n plus n minus 1 plus
n minus 2 plus plus 1 i and this
is all usually is is n times n plus one
right divided by two but we drop a
constant the time complex is always
square okay
so on square answer
equals zero for i
in
for right in range
start with air and n right and then how
can we check if the first and the last
element is the same
if one if zero
so what's the value of left and right
and left value
left is index and lumps is the array
so what's the value of the index and air
remember that day i i talked about
i and what do you put here what do you
put here
yeah i just send them
and
[Music]
yeah okay so that would be the proof of
thing but
look can we do better yeah can we do
better look one
two three one let's see look
if we use the hash map to remember the
number of terms that the number
which number is appear in this one so
can we use that look
look here one appear once
two appear ones three appear once but
one here we
up to this point including this we
appear twice so what does it mean if
this number
one has appeared twice including this so
what does it mean
we yeah because
we know it already appears up to one
right
one and one appears twice up to this
point so
there should be two service right there
should be two sublease which has the
first and the last element the cell
right okay so in order to use that
what kind of data structure are we using
no book okay
still we need to use the answer equals
zero okay and a notebook
let's say sin equals how do you declare
a notebook
food before before yeah
and then default type is integer okay
and then what do we do we go through
each number for i
and column number is i then we need to
update the
counter c i plus equals one
okay and then we appear including this
number up here that time so the answer
plus equal one
on the particular scene i yeah we're
done yeah we're super clever
yeah we tend to answer
[Music]
okay let's see
because the time complexity the blue
forces
the this method is aware right so if you
put it in the term complexity if it is
the size
the size of the input n n and then
o n right this is o and i this is n
right size
n yeah and then o n is this
linear right o n square
okay okay so which one is better clearly
this
this is better right yeah this is one
this is one okay what one one
if there is less one one square is
smaller than n is bigger or equal than
one right
so it's it's actually one is better than
one square because it has lower
complexity okay so that's incremental n
i know okay so i think that's right
[Music]
okay that's it great job today
great job good job bye bye