hello hello mr harry are you all right
yeah okay so today we are going to talk
about cypher you know what this means
cypher what does this mean
this one c-i-p-h-e-r
cipher is a it's a
cypher what's cyber it's a it's a
disguised way of writing something in
secret
okay do you understand for example like
if i want to
to tell you a message right and this
message
can only be understood by you and me
okay
okay so if daddy wants to write
something to
eric write a message i want to say hello
but i don't i don't want other people to
understand
right so you and me come up with a way
to transform this message
into something so other people cannot
easily understand it's like a secret
language between you and daddy how about
if i tell you
a b c d to the z
right and then a transform to
n or n turns to n
b o
and m m n o p q
right actually d here is to m okay
and lower case is m is two to the z
so here are 13 characters you know we
know it's 26
in alphabet right yeah 36 characters so
now here
a to m is 13. and z
is 13. right if i tell you i want to
convert a message from a to n b to o so
hello
c d e s
sorry o oh yeah o to b so
a to n is it's two way okay
it's two way good question okay got it
so every time you want to write the a
you write
n every time you want to write n you
write a because
please hello become you
you what let me check you'll become what
hello will become what u r y y d
u r y y p
okay yeah
ryan we're talking about what's like
what
is like disguise way of writing
something in secret
so for example if i want to tell you the
message eric or ryan i want to tell you
hello right but i don't want other
people to easily understand this
language
so i tell you okay how about i have a
working table from a to animal
if and a every time i want to write the
a
i write n every time i want to write b i
write to o
and the vice versa every time i want to
write o i write a b
so look hello can i tell
you let's do this
so so look let's write this u u
r y p okay so it's actually let's extend
this table okay
a b c d e f
g h m n o
p no no no 13
2 4 6 a
gh i
j k l right 2
4 6 8
and ok 13 n o
p q r s t u
v w x y z okay
u so this is like a encrypted kind of
encrypted message
so you whatever
why
my name my name is
hello so so look you are y p so what
if we increase you are b you become
hello if we encrypt hollow it will
become your
b so what does it mean if a message we
encrypted twice what happened
what happened if we do this if we do
this draw
how we call it what 13 yeah because
rotating in 13 places
right what you have 13. if we do this
function
is red okay so i tell you look
what 13 uh
let's do this row of 13 rod 13
and eric what does it become
red r-e-v-p okay and how about if i tell
you
row of 13 again so what's the value
yeah well that's what i mean so at the
same message performing the road 13
twice you become you you won't be not
changed right
because look e perform
what's the encrypted version of the e r
and what's the encryption version of r e
you see
yeah that's what i mean yeah so that's
the cipher okay you know what sideways
yeah
it only performs to the up application
lowercase
and all other characters like space uh
exclamation mark question mark doesn't
change okay only
and digits don't change only letters
right uppercase and lowercase characters
yeah you perform this mapping
okay yeah okay let's write the function
to do this it should be very easy yeah
remember how do we do this
we we're going to need the two function
remember to convert
converter string converter character
into the
ascii code remember yeah
eric what's a ascii remember
what's a in ascii code um
what's 60 60 and what's
a yeah with an 87 wow
this time where brilliant okay and how
do we convert from
a to numbers which function are we using
um order okay and how about convert it
back
um
c
character yeah all the character okay so
look
that's good so we we just how can we uh
do this we want to add to 13 right
right yes okay so let's put it in an
array
a or equals at least yeah we put a list
and then how can we
concatenate into a final string using
which function
if it's a list and we want to put it
into a string remember this function
okay good job i was going to give you
two options split and john i know you
say john okay
okay so now four i
in s i go through each character right
all right
all right i go into each character
so for now i will i i need to make sure
i need to check if it's uppercase or
lowercase right
how can we check if it's upgrades how
can we check his lowercase
we just check if i is bigger
if it's bigger equal a
smaller equal z let's have a case yeah
but you can also write this if i don't
look look if i dot is
upper okay let's load up case and how do
we write even if lowercase
if i is low lower
and if we spoke if it's either uppercase
or lowercase you can do this e
i is alpha okay
that means it's it's a character it
could be uppercase.lowercase if other
okay
so we can say okay yeah yeah alpha okay
so is this
if i dot is upper okay it's
uppercase if i uppercase
then what should we do
what should we do first of all we should
get the
character yeah 65. so if it's 65
and we need to find our home we need to
find
out what's the position of it by minus
65 yeah it's home it's which characters
which alphabet
in this is 65 65 we need to map to 0
okay
66 this is a this is b we move back to
one okay
first of all we go get this number we
plus 13
because look at mapping to m right plus
13 but it could be out of you could be
more than 26
then what do we do we model it as 26
yeah
so if it's 26 it goes back to the first
one am i right
anyway does it make sense and we get
this number then we use
which functions chr right to get a
corresponding encrypted version all
right
yeah i are you sure you you it's it's uh
yeah for example like a
0 0 plus 13
modulus 26 is what is 13. what's 13
what's the thing 13 is n right and it is
n n is 13 13 plus 13
modulus 26 equals 1 26 modulus 26
26 0 and 0 is 8. you see
so n will become a right that's what i
mean okay
yeah okay so now if i is upper
so i want to append a dot append
a power chr is upper is 65
plus order
of i
minus 65 right plus 13
right modulus 26
yeah yeah okay
and then if air if okay l if i go
is lower you do the same level
only you only change one thing which is
what
you change here from here we only only
change one value
if it's lowercase 96
97. yeah you change 65 to 97 yeah
yeah because minus 697 is
to calculate which position in alphabet
is i plus 13 is the mapping
yeah because a map to to n
right and s if it is a other character
what do we do
what do we do we just append what
if the other characters we don't change
so in this case we obtain which
which variable
rotation rotation
okay another way look this is not easy
to understand already look this is not
another way okay how about if i write a
a function
i put a two variable here okay oh but if
i say
a
[Music]
a b c q z so here
what do we do abc
abc define we use this file function
find phase to locate the retainer index
okay index one i
and then plus 13 and modulus 26 okay
right look
b c the string we want to find this i
character if it's a return zero the
index right
and plus 13 model 26 is the same okay so
this
string to find string to find
find something find i became the index
first index that this character appears
in the stream right if
you have to find it it returns minus one
okay
yeah if you say abc the e or z
uh to z find you find the question mark
right it doesn't appear in this this uh
string so it says minor one
i if it if you find a what's the value
of it
a b c d f g find a
uppercase a what's the variable
no no the fine the index which index
has the yellow yeah that's what you mean
so we find the index
plus 13 model why do we need to modulus
why do we need to modulate 76
[Music]
why do we need to multiply 26 huh
look at n n plus n
is 13 right plus 30
is 26 it's out of these
is here but we need to module 26 to go
back to a
got it yeah if it's in the second half
if it's in the second half we need to
add 13 is out of this boundary
and we use the modulus to go back to the
first half to mapping
so that's why we a map to n right
b map to what oh right
right look b plus 13 is here
there we go b plus 13 is o is here
but o plus 13 where does it go
[Music]
to b to b yeah how do we go to the b
oh plus 13 is here but with modulus 26
you go here right
that's why wait wait it does remember
yes okay okay so
let's see so tell me uh one thing you
you understand today
about the cypher i was
okay so can you can you tell me that
ah arrogant ryan in
love 13 and that's it eric and ryan okay
arrogant ryan what's ryan do you want to
wait then let me write a mapping okay a
b
c d e
wxyz okay so can you tell me
ryan in in the secret language
are you sure ryan what's wrong
yeah yeah okay ah i'm ready
yeah oh yeah elephant okay
okay
[Music]
good job