[Music]
okay so
today we'll continue talking about uh
parentheses called valid parentheses
yeah this will be your last day of
parentheses yeah
so remember previously we talked about
valid processes only including these
brackets right
yeah how about if we also
consider curly brace and square bracket
yeah so if it's a very princesses it
could be something like that
yeah something like that
do you get it yeah this is a valid
because
everything is impaired but this is not
impaired
this is not this is not
do you get it yeah
this is not right because even it's
opening close but this
does not match right yeah okay so
our task is to do to design an
algorithm
algorithm yeah algorithm to to solve
this problem okay
yeah thank you for doing that
so remember any ideas
i mean how do we do that i don't
understand what we're doing
i was just talking about that i mean to
check if it is a string
like that is if it's a very this should
give me force
this should give me true yeah
these two these
two these
uh this fourth okay
so remember previously we we we
use a balance counter right when we meet
opening with plus one when we mean
closing with minus one and we check if
it's yellow right
if any time it falls below zero then
it's invalid
all right because it falls below zero it
means we don't have enough
opening brackets
like this one
zero minus one one is negative one is
below zero it means we don't have enough
opening all right
so it means we will deal with ten
fourths immediately
if this one is one and this one minus
one
and this uh a3 and this quantity
and this are three and this one three
no look it could work a little bit but
no
look if you add two what happened like
if you're saying that uh
uh these at one and these at two right
and this s3 right yeah oh okay so if
this is minus two all right and
hopefully
one one two one one is yellow this is
apparently not very
valid yeah did you get it so this this
of course stuff you know what
got it yeah okay
so the the tricky part is that we need
to check
if the opening is the one we want okay
even yeah so remember we talked about a
sec before what stack
can you remind me
[Music]
the beginning yeah why you change your
answer to first thing first off
okay so let's take visually okay if you
put something in
put a if we put eric in
then we put ryan in
the stack technical alphas
and then mommy yeah and ryan and eric
you see everything goes
in first but glass out yeah yeah okay so
let's first signal
so how about if we meet these leaves
we will meet one of these yeah yeah we
put it this is the
filler we put it here
like this let's examine okay
okay yeah this is so very evil
yeah you need whatever you thought
you have to find me out a little bit
yeah yeah look look going this way yeah
opening i put it here yeah
yeah another opening i put it here
another opening i put it here okay now
it's closing yeah
what is going to mean any of these we
look
at the topless deck right okay this
topper stack is this
it doesn't match this one yes then we
continue
we take it out we continue does it makes
match this one yes we take it off yeah
does it make match this one no yes
i'm going to take it off yes yes and
then look if it doesn't match then for
example if you start to match
like that okay yeah doesn't match
uh this is the set
yeah if it if it is the
does not match right then will be turned
forth immediately
you see and at the end we need to check
if this stack is empty
if it's not empty it means that some
brackets are now closing right
like this if you look i push two twice
30 degrees of brackets and then i mean
this one i take this out
it match yeah okay and look what
happened
we have one more needs to be close so
it's not
a valid one does it doesn't make sense
so this stack is very useful in this
case yeah okay hop
right let's learn the problem can i have
like
raise the please razor man
eraser man
of course okay this is running out of
pink
defined you choose it valid
princesses yeah then this is
[Music]
this means the list but we can use it as
a stack right remember
yeah okay so why unite
yeah for i is s
column yeah
so now we need to find out if i if i
in look we can use in to
to check if this is enough in
in in this piece right
if it's in the open bracket curly brace
and then square bracket if it's one of
these
yeah if it's one of these then we push
it into the stack stop the append right
we push it into the stack i
ass right
in order closing brackets yeah
closing bracket wait wait wait wait wait
wait
closing bracket then you need to check
what we mean is we need to check
ryan then we need to check if the stack
is empty or not right
if we already mean this one even at the
beginning
the stack is empty right if we all have
the closing one
it's invalid we can't pop any element
there's nothing in the stack right
so we need to check in this case if then
nothing in the stack is invalid
right so we need to check a and
c is zero equals equals right that means
the second
minus one wait wait
wait wait wait look yes you are right st
minus one means that the the
look the top of the stack right
look if you are using a list like even a
step if the list is one two three
um do you still remember this before
this is one two three
yeah the minus one yes minus one is
three yeah the last element
yes zero is the beginning
right yeah
okay okay okay that's it that's it okay
now
if mistake if the the previous the
top of the step right even the top of
stack is this one
is the top topper stack
plus now current current one is
also in in what in this this
is a very pair yeah this is the red pair
this is a very pair right
if not in this is the red pair but we
are looking for not
so not this one
column return fourth right
yeah and then after that we need to
publish from the second t
dot pop
this is popular last element if we want
to pop the first element
yeah we need to check if it's listed
this is empty right let's take it empty
okay so
so can you tell me if i want to check
the beginning of
we want to even list this one two three
if i want to pop
this element out first first thing first
or how do we do this
first so he needs to go out so he goes
out
yeah that's st pop right yeah and how
about if i want the popular one
oh what do i do
that one no no what i'm saying that
if if we are using this stack this is
this as a queue we want to pop the first
element
out and we need to pop zero remember
this
zero means the first one yeah yeah
okay okay so this is the basic so
what's the complexity what's the
complexity
[Music]
because yes n is the number of the
character in the string
how about the space complexity
yeah space complexity do we need to
allocate a space for this problem
nine why not we're using a stack why not
because it becomes
what's your opinion
are they not cleanly sorry
you say bravely it doesn't matter i
don't know
make a guess it's on that
board what's the space capacity yeah
yeah
because we're using a stack yeah yeah
we're using the stack in the worst case
the stack for example if the string
is always opening yeah it doesn't matter
it's always
opening there's no popping right all
right
then the stack will contain these or
anime
the opening brackets so it means when
the end
when there are encounters in a string
you need another space
another space which contains and
cut and elements in a stack i'm right
yeah yeah that's
that's why it's called om complexity of
in both
time and space
[Music]
that's because of time yeah when you
when when we talk about time we talk
about how many times
how many iterations the computer needs
to process
right but this stack is if we are using
an additional
storage to keep the elements right and
in the worst case there is no
popping from the stack in in the worst
case
the string contains all the push right
all opening and then
this stack needs that for example if you
lay 100
a string size is 100 characters and i
need to add stack
which can hold at least
100 characters do you get it yeah this
is what it means first of all
okay good job today the last thing
say goodbye