hello hello hello mr are you right
what did you talk about yesterday um
we talked about sci-fi log
13 yeah and here there we use a function
called string.find
right string defined
so abc remember abc dot find
find in a character yeah fire character
so this is the string string sdr type
and it's a messer confine
file a target a character okay so it
returns the first
index right the string has the first
index
of the c in the string right for example
like
a b c d dot 5
b what does it return
number one yeah one because zero one two
three
one and how about if i i have another b
here it returns still one right
but it always returns the first matched
characters
okay so if it doesn't find if you write
let's say i want to find t
so it returns minus one okay yeah
so and this method is only if we
let's implement this method and then
we only need to consider finding a
string
finding a character in the string this
almost only applies to finding a
character in a string right if it
doesn't
if it is this given string it's not uh
if a given type is not a string then we
need to show an exception okay so in
python we use the raise exception
and let's be easy to improve let's say
let's just define
find and then we want to find the string
in a target right comma okay so that
that's a little bit different than
string.5 but basically different numbers
are and let's
let's implement here okay first of all
we need to check if s
is a string type so we can use the type
function array
if type yeah this is type
s okay if it is not equal
str if it's not a string with which the
exception we can do this
raise exception right it raises
exception raising
et cetera means something goes wrong
right
something goes wrong because look we are
designing this function
to find a character in a string but you
have given me
not a string type right so it means that
this function
cannot continue because i don't know how
to handle
when s is not a string type okay so
raise exception
and you can define exceptions okay can't
do it or whatever yeah whatever that's
it
and then we want to iterate how how can
we find it
all right how can we find it i'm going
through going to from which direction
left to right left right okay so then we
need to fall
and for what we want to get the index
and then get the value at the same time
so which function are we using
we use a function to return
to return the index and the value do you
remember what function is there
called e e star with e
what e e
new neuron enumerate yeah so look
for index and a value in
innumeral way the numerator
one innumerable
one what do we do
if the value equal equal
the target right target yeah
now we need to return the index which is
what
the second index which is what
which is doing that index i and if we
can't find it at the end we need to
return one
minus one yeah let's see what's the term
complexity
um and what's new
the number of characters in the given
string right yeah
okay so that should be it okay can you
write it that's it
that's it come on your turn and that's
it
that's it for today
for iv is the index is a value and i'm
going to find
if y v v is what if what
the target
what do we do if we find it if we find
it and what do we do
return the unit which one is the index
return but
i i put it right and if we can't find it
what happened
if we can't find it whatever
what's the time complexity what's that
space movement
good job bye