hello hello
okay so today we talk about the counter
remember
the counter thing in python you have
counter things what's counter
culture data so this counter data
returns a
key value pairs for for the unique items
in data for example like beta if data
is a b b
a c okay so this counter object will
return the dictionary
which is a key value pair so this
generally yeah
a curly brace so a
this is the key which is the unique
items and how many times are they appear
they appear two times
b appear two
two times c appear one yeah
curly brace okay so now today we if we
want to implement this counter object
so let's implement it okay let's say
define
counter island data
okay so then this data can be a string
or
a list or anything that
that's iterable right it's a iterable
what's mean
integral means that you can do this for
i in data thing right
so by the beginning we need to define
the return
data which is a dictionary before
dictionary
before dictionary int
this in test tells that that the
value the value type is a integer
and by default if the item is the item
the key
is not existing in the dictionary the
value will be zero
the value will be zero okay so now we
want to iterate
we want to iterate over the data so we
use the for for
i in data so that we go through each
item
each item will be character or the list
or the number in the list
or anything element in the list and then
now we want to reference the
we want to reference the value right so
how do we reference the value answer
square bracket i want to put here
what to put here what to put here
i right and then if we want to eat
if we want to increment by one
so how do we produce it plus equal one
plus equal one where down and then i
lost we want to return this
return
what's the thing we're going to return
we can answer what's the time complexity
what's example ryan i went
we're down wow when what's the space
from brexit
we are using an additional space for
storing a key value pair right in the
worst case it will be
needs and items and items in the data it
means
and why it's linear it's proportional to
the number of the
items right space complexity uh
complexes
om because we are going to each item in
the list
right so in their number there are n
numbers of
elements in the data right so it needs
one right
and that's it yeah okay answer i
answer answer i plus equal one okay look
this is the key value ryan do you want
to
i erase this bit can you can you
feel it okay
answer the answer is the dictionary yeah
answer i plus equal one right
good job