hey hello mr mr ryan how are you today
okay so what's gcd
crazy communicator okay so
grade is common divisor for numbers two
numbers let's say
four and six what's the greatest common
divisor of this all these two numbers
two two why is that
because they could make in the two
screen tables and which is the largest
one yeah
yeah okay so okay so we have uh
today we talked about the quality common
divisor for the strings
like eric eric
yeah is is
eric
eric okay
so the greatest common divisor of
everything
every eric is everything it's average
okay because look
both go into eric's same time table okay
okay doesn't make sense and the whole
body first
ryan i learned that
let's say ryan
eric something
yeah doesn't nothing nothing
why is that
because eric isn't my toy table
because because these these needs to
ryan you know face a really big string
yeah it needs to be repeated by the
consists of a small
small part right so these cannot be
divided by right because it does not
made up of pure ryan because it may also
have made up
with eric right yeah but
eric ryan
and eric ryan
eric ryan so what's the greatest common
device
yeah you see because look every grind
yeah consists of these two
okay so you got it so
so how can we do it so basically we want
to find
a string two strings a and b
and b let's call it s and t
s and t we want to find out the large
partial
portion of of
of s right it could be it could be
it could be something like that a b c
a b a b
a b and then here will be
a b a b a b
look so what's nothing no
a b a it would be a b
right but it's not a b a b because there
are only three parts
they are they are two right so let's
that's the greatest common divisor is
okay yeah make sense
does it make sense if i put another a b
here yeah
yeah yeah
so any idea how we're doing is we're
doing it by
string yes that's the string so
it's a string so so look for the numbers
is easy we just need to find the largest
number that goes into both
time table but here we want to find out
the largest of what
not a number what is that a string what
is that
large is what what what is this called
what large is what huh
subscribe always start with the first
one what is the call
prefix prefix yeah remember we call it
prefix
so we want to search before the last is
prefix that
goes into both content and what does it
mean by both
both string it's not a number anymore
it's a string
so we want to find out the last prefix
that can be made
made up of all the both strings
for example the prefix of this one a b
yeah if a b a b made up the first string
by two prefix yeah okay and then look
a b a b
a b a b okay so so
for example this area we check out
e is e the prefix
by making up the array no because it's
not e e
it's e yeah also does not make up eic
so we can only take the first word eric
and we check if eric makes up the first
one yet every maker first one
make him say second one yes because
every area okay
okay
and he's on every line is arrayed
made up of everywhere no because it does
not repeat
yeah so eric ryan made up of the second
one yes is everybody and everyone
okay so here before we got these
let's say it's a d
made up of a b ap yes it's a b
made up of
a b a b yes a b a b a b is a b a b
made up of abnormal because only only
has only one part yeah
correct there is a b and b
so so for the answer is a b
because these the prefix we are fighting
finding the largest prefix
the largest prefix which is
can be which can
you know can you if you put
put a prefix times
n times okay i don't know how many times
on that
times n times confirm the string
the first string and then the second
string and then we call this
prefix is the greatest comment divisor
of the string right so so
my turn yeah okay so
let's implement this one okay
by the way what's the time complexity of
checking two numbers the
greatest common divisor a one no no no
n g c d any and guess and ogcd good
choice that let's
one answer what's the time complexity of
this one
a and b o
roughly o log a
plus log b okay
okay roughly the i is a gcd okay
okay roughly lock level okay yeah uh
okay so just define g c
d string okay string let's say
a and b to string okay
okay so string a string b
equals the length of a
why are you doing l a and l b
l a equals the length l b so
a thing another thing equals another
thing of
four things together right so leave a a
equals then a
lb equals and then b okay so just down
yeah so this means that this is this
equals here
this is here it's a two-part two-part
okay
two things these two things i want to
assign the value to these two things
all right okay and then now
and now i want to have a function later
okay i want to check
so now i want to check from the every
possible
with largest prefix so i will go to
prefix for
i in range
style from the largest prefix yeah
because we find the largest
prefix so which is the minimum length of
that all right
i don't know which one is bigger so i
want to start with
mean l a l b
and then tier 0
and then minus one okay so look
if the string is a b a b
and another one is a b a b
a b okay so for example look
this is uh this is a this is
a this is b
so the air n is four right
and then a b is one
six okay and i style i from
four right so i want to get a prefix
the first prefix is aba b so this prefix
will be
it doesn't matter which one i use yeah
so i can just use if it's not the same
then
if let's use the a or b it doesn't
matter okay a
the prefix is comma
i right yeah
right and then i i just have to let you
check i have a function check prefix
quickly i define this f later f a
check f a if if the a can be made up of
a couple times of prefix
also prefix
can also make b can also be made up with
a
couple terms of prefix what does it mean
it means the prefix is their largest
common
prefix yeah so it's the greatest common
device all right
yeah yeah so it's just a return
return empty
no no no look if even the largest pre
even the prefix
i'm look i'm going the prefix from the
fourth because the last
possible largest prefix is for letter a
b a b right here
right if a b a b made up the first
string a
and also made up the second string b so
it's the largest command
string the command string is commanded
yeah return prefix that's the common
string we are looking for
otherwise we we can't find that mean we
return
return nothing nothing because so
look at this f function so what does
this function do
so this f function is this means that we
want to check if this string
e can be made up of prefix
prefix times n times right
okay times n times
okay so now we write that what did mommy
say
hurry area define f
prefix s so first of all
okay lp equals length prefix
air s equals length s so if the
if the air s can cannot be divided by
lp what does it mean if it's
if if this is a b and then
if this is two character and then the uh
air s is
three characters what doesn't mean do we
need to check nothing yeah because you
can't
it needs to be a multiple right so if
s divided by lp
not equal zero then return
we can false yeah okay
and then we how can we write how can we
check one
[Music]
yeah prefix is this a b
pi yeah and how many times of it
and i can just times times air s divided
by l t
if it's equals x equals
s yeah look does it make sense yeah
i want to check if ap can make up of a b
a b
a b and i first i check this is string
two
minus two yeah this is length four four
then divided by two
yeah yeah and then this is okay
and then prefix id and how many times of
a b
two right so a b a b times two
so b is equal yes okay right
okay so this is one way of doing you
know we're checking the prefix
yeah but we can also do it better way
all right look
if i want you to tell me that look
if a b if two string
yeah a b let's say a b and a b a b
okay so these they are great device
the greatest command the gcd of these
two strings
is not empty right this is not empty
okay uh and how about is g a b a b
and a b a b a b it's not empty okay and
how about this
a b a
b and then a a
this is empty right yes this is md so
can you tell me how can we do this if i
have this string
here a b
so can you find out how can we check
how can we check
i'll go and check we can
[Music]
how can we check
we could check yeah how can we check we
can
look what happens we can make a list
if we press it together
a plus b here and b plus a here
what happened
[Music]
a b a b a b if they're the same okay
this one
is a a b a b a b a b a b
a b a b a b a b a b b and h
a b a d a a a a a b
a this is the problem yeah
if if the a plus b equals b plus a
it means we have a greatest common
divisor string which is not empty right
we need to be the same yeah otherwise we
just return empty
right right okay
so so the answer the algorithm could be
simplified very simple
easy yeah
so if a plus b
not equals b plus a
return nothing because this is
there's no yeah you you count right
you can't return empty otherwise i need
to find out the greatest comment devices
stream because look
if there are four characters and another
sixth character
the greatest comment divisor string must
be
six and four t two yeah yeah
the same so we we let this k would be
g c d length of
a length of b okay
you can directly use b function in
python you don't need to implement that
right
but if you want to implement that right
here and then return
a or b the first
k prefix yeah remember we're looking for
the largest prefix
which is a
okay here okay okay okay so
look this is simple yeah okay so let's
implement this
yeah define gcd do you still remember
these two integers
y b
wire a right y a
y a what a b
equals b
a modulus b right no return b
right all right written b rhythm b m
right
so why why a is not string is not empty
then we a equals b b equals a modulus b
okay right so this is takes the old
you know lock level okay and we are
looking for the largest prefix
today does it make sense
okay okay let's see for today
bye