hello today we'll be talking about three
divisors
okay three divisors thank you three
okay so number two how many devices one
and two
one and two so we only have two right
there
four okay four how many devices
three which are those one
four so
if i give you a number bigger than two
can you tell me
how how many two
devices you can be sure there
how many so
so any number yeah five let's say nine
nine how many divided one three nine one
three nine zero it always has one and an
excel yeah
okay so if it's nine you also need to
tell me it's
two right right yes i have six
four one two three four
then one two three six yeah so that's
four divisors so
which is not okay so if it's
if the input is four nine you tell me
yes two
otherwise it's false easy yeah it's busy
how can we do it
[Music]
what do you think i'm gonna check it
remember this is kind of
we talk about how quite the same
similar approach when we check about a
number if it's a prime number remember
yeah yeah we always check the do we need
to check the
prime factor the factors up up to
n do we need to check
look if this number is and we need to
check the factors
up to n now the dive axis
after n no no why is it yeah
because because you need to go halfway
through
how only halfway through we can do all
better than half right
yeah for example six we don't need to go
over
six yeah yeah but can we do better you
can
only get up to three we get
three halfway yeah yeah yeah yeah
hallway i know i know
uh let's put it this way a hundred
we don't know we want to find out the
diverse
the traverses yeah the factors
divergence
of a hundred what are those two
okay seven let's try it okay one
two three four
five
twenty five nine twenty okay ten twenty
twenty five fifty
okay twenty after this point i don't
think we need to continue why is that
because look
i have one i know the yellow the other
one is a hundred
i know two the other one is fifty four
twenty four twenty five five twenty
you see 10 okay so you can apply any
number
10 10 20 you see so what what's that
every time you find the director
n divided by the diversity is the
diversity right
correct let's say i i already found
four what does it mean four is one of
the
diverses so what does it mean for a
hundred
twenty five is also one overtime version
yeah yeah okay so is it half
no for this one is what square root
100 yeah got it yeah f ten
that's already comes from so it's up to
up to
square root yeah for example here as
well right
but this one why is this three because
your square root of six
is two point something and it's up to
three
okay so it's all it's close to half
that's what they
that's a very special case here okay
nine
square root of nine is three so we only
check up to three we don't need to check
above
okay because look i have three the other
half is one
also three okay and this is the special
case when
when the number times itself
is n these two dimensions collapse they
are the same
class so we just need to check the
diversity
and let's say easy-peasy
defined
let's say three
three zeros okay
and okay let's say if
and equal equal 1
even positive if it equals 1 return
return 4 right yeah
if n equals one or n equals two
right okay
now we have a diver we have counter
c equals three and we have i
also start from two okay
uh c equals two okay because the two c
one and excel okay c equals one
2 because we counted 1 and excel and
then we start with a 2.
okay then look why
i times i smaller than 1.
if this this direction we are trying to
check
if i times is smaller than one
smaller than n
yeah and right and then we have to check
e
and can be divided by i
right if n can be divided by i
what does it mean
if i is one of a divisor right so i have
the c
plus equal one right but
also here if i times i
not equals
if i times uh if i times i
i n what does it mean
if i times i not equals n means that
because you look
look we have n divided by we have
i we have i director so the other half
is what
n divided by i right
yeah and then
i and i when these two are equal
when i is equals n divided i
like three right look if n equals nine
when i is three so
we need to add one right but three times
equals one thing yeah here again c plus
equals one right doesn't make sense
because look let's take about this 100 f
if we found
out 20 if i found out the five
four the five plus one yeah at least
this is means that i found another one
because i thought every time i found two
right except if i found the ten i found
the other one is ten i only can
calculate one because these two are the
same right okay
yeah it makes sense
yeah does it make sense yeah okay
i'm going to ask you this later okay
think about it okay and then now
after this we just need to return
we can what c
equals three yeah this is the number of
two what are these two means what was
these two mean
[Music]
what's these two mean why why
is set to two at the beginning it means
generally or because you do the
beginning and the
end yeah the beginning end so let's see
let's one and end okay
two one and factors
and why here has a plus one here
like um he found the five and then
and then you yeah because they divided
it by the
end and then and then you find 20
is also divided okay and if it's the
same
if i times i equals n and you know
don't add it yeah you don't understand
number twice right
some diverse twice yeah for example if n
if n is 25 n is 25 and an i
is five right you find the five
five times five h h really
yeah so you only add one here right all
right
because five i'm right eric
i buy if n is a hundred it means that uh
five and twenty okay okay e e
e what's the time complexity for this
function
for this one
[Music]
what
no that's very easy
o n m okay here is the
missing i plus equal one right
yeah what what's the what's the time
convexity
if i want to pick a number start from
one
from okay or two and then
up to afterwards 10
and look this is i times i
i so a number squares itself until you
hit
n so what's this
squared yeah i squared
this not not this yeah o
n sqlt right because look
n is a hundred and i
is ten right am right
yeah can you know can you do it please
okay look okay look
here if we can put an e
here we can put an e here
if c is already bigger than three
is there a way we can just return first
immediately right we don't need to
continue right
even at this point see if we increment
c is more than three here all right
so what should we do here c
bigger than three returns
we're down let's speed up yeah that's
the optimization
yeah okay what's optimization
to make it better to improve it to make
it longer
because look if this is going to take a
few
other iterations to end and we already
know we already found more than
more than three divisors right so the
answer
is already known as false
right so we can skip the rest of the
checks
and return immediately first that's what
it means
[Music]
because at the beginning you don't know
you're not sure you're not sure
i put it here because look every time i
increment it here
i increment the c and once i found is
bigger than three
the answer is four right there's no no
need to continue
until we iterating exhaustively the
i am right all right
okay okay so uh
[Music]
that will be uh
we actually don't need these events as
well we can just
just do this yeah we're gonna just start
with c equals
uh i equals c equals two
and one i times i smaller
equal than n equivalent to this okay
okay okay
[Music]
okay come on
it should be easy then
ryan you want to happy together
why are you come on that's it
oh yeah
um
[Music]
yeah and then we also need to make sure
c plus
e plus equal one we're done
and what we found that once we found
i and we we also found n divided by in
what cases
we need to check if
yeah if i and n implying is the same
right
so i yes
i times i if it's not equal
okay if i times i
justly if i times i not equals
no equals one no equals n
and then one comma
yeah that's right yeah and also you can
put the even here yeah if c
m if c bigger than three then
yeah and then and then and then return
return for us right okay we're done we
got it
okay what's the time complexity what's
the time complexity
[Music]
oh
is actually this one yeah 0.5
0.5 okay what's the space complexity
[Music]
okay that's it for today good job
bye bye okay that's it bye