hello hello mr mr ryan i go right
so today we talk about removing the
elements in the array okay removing the
elements anyway
so given a number a list of numbers one
two
two two
three four five
okay so i given a list of numbers and
then i want you to remove
a target target let's say target equals
two
in place what's in place what does this
implies mean
in place what's impressive it may it
means
it's in place what's in place
in place means in place i know but can
you describe it using other words
oh it's in the right place can you
describe it without using the in
and place
[Music]
without creating additional space right
now okay that's what it means
in place and where it goes so i want to
remove that too
i want to remove that tool right
okay so i want to remove two and now i
don't want to create
an additional copy of it all of this
array okay
that gives me an idea just going through
everything i just crossed
through the ones with a target yes okay
so now
let's one four three four
five six seven eight nine okay
and then there are three three you can
put the
numbers at the end right or we don't
care about all the numbers at the end of
this point
right yeah so what you need to tell me
is one two three four five
after five right
what what is this function return is you
need to tell me the
new lead the length of the new list
after removing the target
so there are two four six eight eight
numbers in the array and then there are
three targets to remove
okay yeah i know what happened after we
removed three
[Music]
okay so any idea how to win this oh
the one i just told you
we we first look through the element and
find the target and then you and then
you use the two and put it
and you go to the end and swap it where
that okay so look at that
keep on going keep on going yeah yeah
okay let's do this
look let's do this okay uh
two two two okay let's say two two
two okay so i'm pointed at here right
that's the right pointer
right hand right hand pointer okay and
then i'm left hand pointed yeah
okay left hand pointer is one it's not
the target we are looking for let's try
two okay so what happened in this case
we scoop it sloping with five
with r here all right okay so we swap it
we swap it what happens so this
i swap it so when after i swap it i know
the value and the pointer right hand is
the one we don't want
it right so we can decrement one right
all right so what what should we do with
the uh after we swap it
i just say this yeah okay so look
i swap it here five two
so this is the number we want to just
discard right so we decrement the
counter here
and then five yeah
five okay we're going to keep it aside
two what happened can you tell me
whatever
[Music]
here are here right so swap it so right
here four
two and then x and then i i need to
decrement here and then four and one
target i swapping with this number yeah
the three
and two okay and then now i meet each
other so
so let's return these returnees yeah
l is here okay so what's
do you see one problem with this you
know in order
whether or not you know all right no no
because we swap it it will be not in
order
and we can also do it in within order so
how can we do this in order
we just take away it
one two two three four
two five six okay
okay so because we are doing in place
let's put it in the same place okay so
and
so we have a counter to put
we have an index a location let's say we
have a location j
to this this will give us the
position where we can put the
elements yeah we want to keep the
element yeah
and if it's not look one
okay one is the value we want to keep so
j equals zero
so i put it at here right so i override
it here so
one two we're going to skip these two
we want to skip these two so we don't
don't increment the j right three
yeah so what's the j j
will be one yeah one will be
i put it here three and then j will be
the next one will be two right
next one will be two so i plus one here
four
yeah i will put it in here
put it in here and plus one two
skip five yeah
five plus one six plus one yeah
yeah easy yeah so we use one one pointer
to
to and then we return this uh j right
because j is the index that we have j is
four
uh-huh yeah because after plus one will
be five okay
okay let's do this
define remove
nums target okay
j equals zero four
i in numbers
if the numbers are not the target we
want to remove
we want to keep it right so now we put
it at j right
so nums num j
equals y equals
who was what
[Music]
i i because i is not i is no index is
the value okay and then
once we put it j y j
y j y j
[Music]
plus equal one remember this is that and
return we can say yeah
what's the time complexity i won i went
what's this very similarly we are
calling
in place yeah in place what i want oh
one
okay so this is there and how about so
this
this problem is that uh the least
solution is that we keep the
elements in order right we're not
swapping it to the end yeah
remember the first one we're stopping
before the end okay so how do we swap it
to the end so we have our left pointer
and the right pointer left pointer is
the beginning and zero the right pointer
is at the end which is
length lines minus one okay
wire left is smaller than equal and
right okay
how about that look if norms
if nouns air equals target this
okay now we are moving the we are
swapping
right now
numbs are
equals we want to solve these two yeah
how do we swap a and b
how do we solve a and b a b equal as
well
baby all those ones are valid
okay so this is the python way to swap
two variables a and b okay if i don't
if you want to if you can't write it
something like that eric
a b equals b a is the same you want the
t equals
a a equals b and b equals one
t why why do we need a t here
tab out type everything
why do we need to save the value of a
because a
i assign it to b and b needs to assign
to y
to the original value of a which is
saving in t
y okay so can you tell me what what
happened what's this b
equals what's the problem of this i want
if i want to swap a and b b equals
a was b b equals a what happened
are these going to work is this going to
work
is this going to work yeah no no why why
not
because because um
because it will be less than yeah
look i can show you look three and five
okay a equals three b equals five
a equals b then one five
five five and b equals a or five five
right
yeah so this is not the same as look if
a
if i do this a is a is three b
is five and then t equals a
t equals a which is t equals three a
equals b
phi a equals b yeah and b equals t
you see 5 3 yeah i use a variable to
save the original
why because this is the p 4 yeah this
this will not work but in python you can
do this
a comma b equals b comma a okay let's
symbol f okay so numbers
a along with r equals y i want to swap
it
lambs are i norms area
and then once i swap it i need to
decrement ah
right minus equal one okay and
s a has one if alarms
are not equals t then what you will do
with the left pointer
[Music]
make sense is it is it does it make
sense
yeah is it my sizing yeah
[Music]
okay ah okay let's see i'm going to
which method you think you will remember
this one or the previous one this one
this one your choice i'm going to erase
this okay anyway
okay okay so here possible
come on it's easy
[Music]
remember one okay
you try to remember you know what
happened if we we move
[Music]
are we going to have titties
yeah i never
[Music]
um
okay good job bye bye
the same complexity yes oh n right
okay a one space