hello hello mr away are you all right
yes okay so today
we talk about a link list so remember
link is
yeah that's one two
three four
and another five okay so easy okay so
here is the empty near yeah
none okay the end that's the head
that's the head that's the head
okay so easy i want you to do it like
that
every two i think we've done that before
which one today is a simple task swap
these two so
becomes two one swap each for a pair
four three and then if they're only one
left they just keep it
right if there's six here you swap it
right if they are odd
each number you forget about the last
one if you are even number you just swap
everything in pairs
right okay does it make sense this one
yeah how can we do this
okay so how can we do this easy one one
easy solution
okay it's a brief thing yeah just do
whatever t
says right so how can we swap this we
can swap them
how can we make this to one for example
if it's one
i know
that's one way and how about the other
one i kick
yeah you can reverse it right yeah or
we can simply what we can simply what
how do you make this here
if i don't take i'll tell you the note
that the link
is that stays the same and what what
needs to be checked
a link is a link node a link alone
no no no no no no
swap what what
a note contains the value
the value yeah and the link right you're
talking about reverse the link that's
one solution the other one is i just
swap the
value right so how about it look if i
have these
i swap these and the value of the next
one and then after i swap it
i move two yeah okay
i move two okay so that's one way okay
how many ways maybe
more than three ways maybe today we talk
about two ways
yeah look defined
[Music]
swap let's know okay and how can
let's do this head equals not
an unlock wire head
and has an x
what does it mean if this node if i have
this now and the current note
look this is head and this is height on
next right
right head and head the next and then i
need to swap one so
the value of head and hand on this right
so how do we solve it head remember head
of value
comma head down next
top value equals one how do we say
how do we swap these two
height of value and hit the next value i
want to solve these two how do i solve
it because
the value equals value yeah
yeah and then after i swap this what
should i do i have
equals what i swapped
these two what should i do first i'll
move to this head
i should move it to where i should move
it to where
i'm here head i slowly already swap
these two i know what happened what's
your move
this is high what should i move two what
two
plus two there's no plus two head down
next
stop next next hey because head dot net
dot next
yeah donate to the next that's it and
return
return note okay that's it what's the
time complexity
if there are notes in the linked easy
yeah what's the space community do we
need action yeah
okay so that's one way okay the other
way you say the problem
you are you said upon uh reverse the
link yeah
yeah okay so i this one is a bit tricky
look look look
okay i i don't care okay the first thing
to do is what
this is something else the first thing
to do is reverse
these to make these links to here right
i want to i want to do what i want to
i want to make this link here right
right
all right yeah and then these needs to
links to somewhere here right
this is recursion i can do this
recursion right all i
do i have to do is reverse the ring okay
and i return this all right huh
look this is one this is two
yeah all i have to do is dive this is
still one is
i just have to reverse this link
pointing to
backwards right instead probably i'm
pretty well and i cut this link here
yeah i i remove this link here but i
need to point
these links to somewhere this is little
cushion i can recursion it
so please all right got it that's gonna
be a weird link
no no no no you don't care about these
can be done
can be worried later about recursion
right all i have to do is solving one's
problem at the same time solving one's
most
problem which is to
reverse list link right original is 1.2
points or something else and now i just
want to make it two points
one and one points to something else
right
got it yeah yeah okay that's easy
so look if first of all if note is
empty all there are only one node
yeah then i just simply return it's
there right
if there's only one note i don't need to
do anything all right
yeah if there's only one note how can
you we just return it and then now
that's the tricky part okay
so first of all tear
hair is remember this here
pencil tails tail is this bit okay
this is this is no dot next to the next
one
tail equals what
yeah because i'm solving i'm calling
yourself to solve this part right
now i know i what what
what's this bit the head is what that
new head
new hair equals another next right
this is the new head yeah no no the next
so this is the new head okay
and okay now head down next
at the next have the next original
points to that right
i need to point this back to what
to know right yeah
equals no right right
and then no no don't x equals one
no no next week what's what now the next
year what should i point it to
can you where down here is this video
way down
that's here correct right
and then these points to here these
points here and i need to return what
we've got
return this or this reason why
return head yes yes look here it goes
back here to equals another next no
hat or next equals no right here don't
necessarily know the next equals tail
right
now the next equals 10 we can have yes
does it make sense yeah okay
make sense make sense which one you
think
you can implement without if i i give
you two why is it
solve the value in pair the other one is
reverse the link in recursion which one
you think
you can do okay
yeah that one is more straightforward
yeah yeah
another way i don't want to write it but
you can keep in mind the other way is to
convert the linked list into a list yeah
if i convert it
if i put a lot in english into a list
right it's into a list and then i can
swap each value and convert it back to
the link list right
yeah that's one way okay so you tell me
the first one how to do it
okay head equals no
okay let's watch you tell me
why um
um wait head here
okay so this is head the head
next thing i
yeah means that if they have two notes
your head and head
next right yeah i know what should i do
what should i do i have
[Music]
head the value call my head already
and then what will happen um
i'm right here what should i do what's
your
head equals head down next or next
that's it only 10 no you don't know
because we haven't changed the note yeah
we just swap the value yeah
yeah we're done good job that's it for
today good job
bye bye