hello hello eric are you all right yes
yes
okay so the link list yeah we talked
about the news yesterday
english singular english what's simply
you didn't enjoy that last time
yeah simply linked list what does it
mean right now yeah yeah oh
thankfully what's single i mean
[Music]
only one straight line only one
direction they're pointing only
direction
and what's the opposite of thing
double double
doubling that means that it could be
pointing to next and pointing to
backwards
you'll be something like that but we are
talking about let's think
it's only point okay so each no three no
no not just two
so only the synthesis would be a node
contains a value and then point a link
points to another node yeah so it knows
means to another node
so here this is okay so this is a single
node and i want you to change it to so
let each node
points to points to
the value number of nodes ahead so for
number two
so meaning jumps to two jumps two
one two yeah so the two should be points
to
four here now and i don't care about the
one and then four
through four jump but it doesn't have
enough force knows then
because they're only one node left so
you you you
just needs to needs to jump points to
noon
to none okay another example like
one two
[Music]
so what was one one jumps to the here so
let's hear two
two jumps one two right so this these
will be
you have to start from the beginning one
one one yeah okay
yes start from the beginning so the
first note is always the no we don't
want to keep
then you can go one direction yeah one
direction
we have at foreign now there but for
this this is the now we
we start the head but not the head
so first of all we want to find out we
want to jump
the value the number of values in the
value
uh notes ahead we can do it right right
we can do it yeah
define let's say jump
and then note okay first of all if
there's the only one now what happened
if it's not not empty if it's empty what
happened
we just returned yeah he did nothing
baby pretend no
no no no right because it's empty then
there's no need to continue right
and then now look head equals no i
so here this is the note right i don't
care how many
i want to jump this is head here i
config i want to jump to the value of
notes so how can i do it i do a work for
loop right yeah
four four in range
when what red one
the head very well because this is the
value we want to jump right up like two
to head of value
all right yes and
how can we jump how can we jump head how
can we jump to the next half equal as
well
[Music]
have enough notes what happened if i
already reached the end
no it's not head what happened if here
not head or weapon
and pointing the nail thingy no okay i
can just break yeah
break right because look because you
just
break because if you don't break it what
happened the next iteration happens and
you return something
okay so what why what are we doing here
we are finding the head
the points to the next one so no right
now next equals
what jump
jump jump what can you feel the blank
and return
jump here i divide it jump i want to
because it will jump away
why got it
come on so what does this mean here
after this point this head will be the
head
for example here right here for example
if we
look hey there you go right
and i want to jump jump head i want to
jump jump jump
this is a head and i need to set no the
next equals head right
the jump head i need to keep jumping
because here is because
okay
[Music]
which part is the question um
yeah jump because yeah jump here got it
no yeah whoa does it make sense all
right
um okay i'm going to erase this
okay come on come on that's impossible
right come on this is a note
and then i'm here and i want to
i want to do what head is here head here
i want to find
head head i want to head i have to jump
to
this point and then i need to set it to
here can you can do it can you do it um
can you do it no no you need to write
the four loop first
four but i can write right there
break it only works in the for loop yeah
for
for anything for well yeah
for come on forward something
yeah something there i understood
something in range
this pen doesn't look like a pen that's
right
no no yeah i don't really
know the value it doesn't matter because
head equals no idea at this point has a
value here
has a value we want to jump we want to
jump
make the head jump head of value a
number of times
and then how can we jump how can we move
the head the number of times
okay and in the middle what if they are
if they are not enough head or nose
if head becomes the end what happens if
your head
reaches yeah and how can you okay
[Music]
right it reaches the end and then what
you will not have a lot
[Music]
um if not head
oh what break yeah
and i know the next no the next equals
what
no the next equals one now this here is
half
no the next equals what um
i need to recursively
[Music]
okay that's it for today good job the
time come next week
yeah what's n number of notes in the
thingy thingy
okay okay okay that's it for the day bye
bye