hello guys hello everyone
all right yeah so how do we add the
numbers
how do you end the number like one two
three plus four
five how how do we add these two numbers
how do you edit normally in mathematics
so you start from the right to the left
yeah the left and the right
sorry you start from left to the right
okay right here left
right to the left because i drank the
other that's one yeah
that's one come on funny okay so you add
these yeah yeah yeah eight and then you
come to that fifteen
no no no it's not 15. that's one okay so
five five eight and unless six
one yeah okay how about if i i have a
much bigger number here like nine so
what do you add this time
this little thing um if i was doing it
um okay say
equals 12 and then you get 12 12
and then you have a carry one right
because you put that one here right i
put the one at the bottom
okay it's the same okay at the bottom
okay and then
yeah i've never won a bottom of the line
so what here yeah no i think the one
lower than oh i don't know
okay okay good okay so uh
yeah so basically yeah it's the same
yeah so you got the
do it from the right which is once and
then the tenth and then
a hundred yeah as long as we have at
least one carry carry we keep doing
right right
okay so imperson yeah you know the price
and the the numbers can be arbitrary
big so if that if this number you
if you want to add it if given two
string you know very very big
only implicitly in person this number
could be one two three you know
100 of them and then you add another
very very big number
you can just simply convert it the
string for example this is a this is b
you can just do this converted converted
string to the indeed
in in the a right plus
in b right and then you
after that you convert it back to the
string yeah return
okay okay so let's that only works in
person yeah you
first of
yeah yeah yeah because the computer does
the magic for you behind the scenes
so today we want to implement this
without these we want to add a digi
number so you know how computer added
the digit by digit from the right to the
left yeah this is
general approach to to add the numbers
from the right to the left
okay while we're doing that
just to give you the idea how it
actually works
right so we need to understand how it
works behind the scenes
i know how it works method
a b all right okay so first of all i
need to
know the length which is n one
n two equals length a
minus one okay let's because they start
from zero yeah
uh and then length p
minus one okay so what what does
so look if one two three plus 49
okay so n one is is two
right this position we added from from
the
from the last yeah okay we align from
the rightmost digit right and enter is
what
what's under and what's the value of
empty
is the value of the
of length b plus minus 1 is 1
and 1 is 2 and 2 is what
and 1 is 2 right and 1 is 0 1 2 and 2 is
what
and 2 is 1 1 yeah one okay
now i also have a carry actually means
the one the one you put in at the bottom
here at the beginning you'll be
equal to zero right there's no carry
and then i have uh what i need to store
these numbers
like this is two
seven one seven i want to store these in
a double ndq and i
put it yeah every time i edit the digit
i put it in the
double ended queue right so answer
equals
what d-e-q-u-e-i
[Music]
yeah or you can put it in a list and
append it to the
to the flank but we use the uh
okay now while this is the loop why our
n1 bigger equals zero we haven't reached
the
left yeah we want to add a digit
digi by dj from the right to the left if
ln one right we want to
decrement n1 is equals to two and then
we want to add it to
this number these are yeah you haven't
we haven't we have we still have digits
for
a or we have we still have this
different
b or the carry is bigger than zero yeah
because if
you look 99 plus one what
zero but we have a carry this
this is carry c okay y c is zero okay
now i want to put it the number in x so
x
will be equals to carry first then if
n one bigger or equal than zero
then x plus equals a
and one right and i need to convert
this to integer right so i put x plus
equal integer converted the integer and
can you write the second one if
n2 bigger or equal zero
whatever x
plus equal in
[Music]
actually look i i if it's bigger than i
i use this number i actually have two
decremented yeah
and one minus equals one right so i use
the digit and then i need to go to the
left right so here
again and two what
minus equals one okay
okay now the x will be the sum okay
x will be what 3 plus 9 equals 12 right
so x will be 12 but i want to put a 2
right right so what
answer the append append left yeah
i want to put it for now put a
current x y x is 12.
i only want the number two so what
should i put here
x y 12 i want the only one
the digit 2. i want to put the digit 2
in the answer so
x1 minus 1
2f how how do you put a 2m into 2
why is it minus 10 if if it's 22
wow how do you minus 10 how do you get
the number 12 to 2
how do you get this number remember we
use that thingy
what what ten what ten what ten
x was ten divided by ten
x divided by ten will be one
and i want to get that right most digit
the the the thing is the how do you
divide it by 10 and get that one
remember what what does it
what do we call it come on x
x y it's not right
divided by 10 is one
and x what ten is two come on
you forgot that thingy
shift there's a no no there's a one here
and there's a
murderous yeah modulus okay okay
hello this so x modulus 10 right
and then now look this is 12 and then i
what's the calorie is
10 is one right yeah
so i need to put a carrot c equals one
c was what c is the carrot
12 12 i want to get a one here so
c was what x y x
what time come on divide by ten divided
by ten
okay and then return now answer
is the uh double ndq yeah i want to join
by by one um nothing yeah the
join joined by
answer yeah yeah okay so this look this
is the number
actually i need to convert it to a
string because
only string can join so star like that
you have to
convert this number to the string and
then i can join
does it make sense does this make sense
is it is it the same does that make
sense
okay okay any questions
any questions any questions
okay i'm going to erase these two better
oh come
on okay come on either
me island
x is the number and i want to my space
answer answer is a lot of pen left yeah
you don't need this
[Music]
left okay apparently
x is the number we the x
yeah okay okay
you want to convert this to the star
okay but let's find star stream
okay convert it to a string okay
next yeah okay okay okay and then
what happened to the um carry
actually is the eleventh carry equals
one
where down let's say what's the time
complexity
if there are n the end look
a a number has
a characters digits and b number has b
digits so what's the time complexity a
and a b so there are eight digits here
op digits here so what's the sound
complexity
minimum a maximum maximum
of a and yeah because look if they have
two there are ten digits over one and
then two digits of
another one so you need the tenth
iteration right it's the maximum okay
oh maximum a and b okay well done that's
it for today
bye bye