hello mr ariel are you right yes okay so
how do you i give you a sequence okay
like one three five seven nine do you
notice what's so special about this
sequence
know they're um odd
all numbers okay and how about
look if it is one five
seven
this this is not special but this one is
special why is that
because
the odd numbers these are all numbers
but how what's so special about this one
um
i think it's
huh
um
what's that
[Music]
they're all adding two adding two okay
so the distance between each number is
two right it's the same okay so like one
two three four five this is also that
how do you write calling what speller
was a r i
a r i t h
t h
m
e t i c c
yeah sequence we call this aromatic
sequence so each number
the distance between each number is the
same but
what what we mean is distance is the the
next number minus the previous number
okay so how about is one five
one five one
right the distance is also four but look
five minus one is four one minus five is
minus four and four so this is not right
this is not
right so we we are looking for the
numbers that uh the first number is a
yeah the second number is a plus b
the third number is a plus two times d
and the next number is what
a plus three times d etcetera okay right
a so
the whole sequence you can put it as a
time a plus k times d
okay so for given it's not
uh
so can you can you tell me
all right can you tell me what's a and d
in for list 1 3 5 7 9 11 et cetera
what's a
t
right what's a
the a is the first number which one one
one okay and what
what's k uh what's k is the number okay
what's d
d is the decision what's t
two okay so look this this sequence we
can write it as what one plus 2 times k
1 k equals 0 is 1
k equals 1 is 3 k equals 2
is 5 k equals 3 equals 7 okay
yeah okay so now we we know this
sequence ok so so i give you a few
numbers like uh but they are not in
essentially in order so for example 7
1 5.
so can you tell me how can you rearrange
these numbers to make it a animatic
sequence
so you become what
so can you do
one three five seven easy one three five
seven okay
okay easy okay so
given a list of these numbers not
essentially in order can you tell me if
you can rearrange the sequence to make
it aromatic sequence so what's your
thoughts
how do you do it um
how do you know it's one okay from this
three seven one five how do you know
it's one oh you can do it one three five
seven come on it's it's very obvious how
do you do it
how do you do something come on how do
you do it
um you definitely start with a smoothie
yeah smaller speakers and how do we call
it how to check
we can what
we can work
we can
check
how can we check how can we only give a
second number and then use our
previous one okay so before we do that
we want to what we want to what the
numbers come on we want to what
we want to put in the verb here
the numbers can you can you imagine how
do it
yeah that's the word i'm looking for a
thought yeah we saw that
so what's the certain time come next day
if that number what's the time
competitive if we sort the numbers
um
again yeah
okay okay so we only saw the numbers and
if we saw the numbers how do we check if
it's a aromatic sequence
uh if we go to the second number
minus subtract the previous one yeah and
then we check it
and the distance that needs to be the
same right
and how do we check if the distance
is the same we can put the distance in a
set and we can't finally count the
number of the distance
unique distance in the set it has to be
one right
right
yeah we can use the set yeah notebook
okay
okay so
let's say defy
is an arithmetic sequence okay
and numbers
first of all we only thought yeah nouns
dark soul right
okay then we we put a distance in a set
the active
we start with the second number so what
should we put here
should we range will be
one one and then to the length of the
numbers
okay then the distance is what we we
want to find is this d dot add
what's the distance we want to put
the previous
or any bigger than one will return wha
what does this mean if now if this set
contains
two different distance then we know it's
not a
aromatic sequence right
that's how we determine
we don't know what
okay
and then here we can just return because
we already checked here so we can return
one
okay like if if i don't if i remove this
one so what should i do right here
length b right the number of the unique
distance is equals one okay
do we actually need to
to put a set
no okay if i tell you i don't want this
i don't want this i don't want to return
this will return true right
so if if what
noms
i
minus nums
i minus 1 not equal what
can you tell me num is what
minus number
you put the two numbers here
return four right
right look at this one three five seven
we start from this one
yeah i is here i'm minus the previous
one not equal as what i minus this not
equals one
come on
if the distance we can get the distance
around which number
which two numbers
[Music]
yeah does it make sense
yeah
what's the term complexity
[Music]
sorry
this speed is what
this bit is what's the time complexity
of this bit
and what's the time complexity of this
beat
okay so what's the
final
complexity of this hole again yeah
because this is dominating yeah this is
bigger than that you can say all nokia
plus n right and this is constant i mean
this is adding together but so this one
dominating so you you can drop this
this one is dominant because it it takes
more time right
come to that skin
okay
i'm going to erase this bit okay and
then you tell me i'll return you can
drive one of these come on
and that's it for today come on
come on yeah i play a few few one you
can
yeah you can
remember the notebook or you can do it
without a notebook okay any anyone think
about it how do we check if the number
we already started and how we are going
to check
yeah
instead remember if e4
yeah come on eric this is your time okay
eric it's your turn
sorry
you don't know what is what
what what are we doing here oh you can
put it in a in a d in a high set
remember
sorry
i don't want to equate that
you don't want to have okay that is
numbs i minus num i minus 1
i'm pretty sure it's one yeah
what is this
yeah yeah
numbs one product minus non-stop
uh
[Music]
one and then we have we are iterating
with the i right so the i
and
the elements at i and then minus
subtract the i minus one right
if we know equals
is the first distance but we want to
make sure that the rest are the same the
distance i look i start from the second
number right so num if not equals num i
minus num i minus one remember
[Music]
i
minus yeah november number i minus knobs
i minus one yeah
yeah and then we we found a
a difference in the distance so what
should we do we turn one
return
yeah return true if we don't find any
violations and here you see we find the
live violation with return
that's it great job today good job bye