hello
hello area all right
yeah
so
let's review the binary tree first okay
the binary tree what's uh
what's the uh the final three has the
two kids they have two kids
the each night can have a
almost two kids and only one lude lute
has no parents and each other notes has
only one parents okay
okay
okay so if
if one note if e for this is this is the
primary tree and every level is for zero
we call it
perfect yeah perfect by anything yeah
okay
if a final tree is fulfilled every level
is that possibly the lowest one but the
lowest one
can only be fulfilled from left to right
then we call it
complete binary okay complete the
country so but is this a complete binary
no
why is that
because
it's there's a gap between yeah the last
level needs to be
yeah fulfilled from left to right and is
uh these
uh
how can we uh let's say
is lisa
complete the planetary or fulfill uh or
copyright you know yes or not right
because every level needs to fulfill but
and the last level needs to be fulfilled
from left to right okay we got it okay
so uh what's the final research tree
um
it's just like
a normal thing and what's the what's
special about it the primary surgery and
the parent networking with parents
right
the right needs to be bigger than their
parents and that needs to be smaller
than the parents here so when we search
locate the value either try to set your
value in the financial street we can we
can compare the current value if we like
we want to find a 5.
it's smaller than the root so we know
it's somewhere in the left tree right i
will keep walking every time if this
binary structure is balanced yeah
balance quite you know it's balanced the
height difference between any two nodes
is smaller than one smaller equal right
now with every time we do this
comparison
we can drop half of it right so what's
the time complexity of locating the
old log and we're done because every
time we drop half okay
down okay so now we talk about hip
remember the hip
hip is a binary data structure you know
a balance or we call it yeah balance
it's and we have two kinds of hips max
head and mean hip
okay the max hip so a hundred
ten
twenty
five six
six that's okay that's okay and then we
call it seven
eight okay
so what's special about max so the root
the parent
is bigger than the kid
okay then we call it maxi
and the what's main thing
the opposite is smaller right one two
three and it'll be four
five
six seven okay
so the parent is always smaller than the
kid
so what's special about asymmetric the
time complexity to retrieve the max or
mean the root
is one okay
it's a one okay so we want to build
a heap
why we want to use the heat because we
want to make
we want to take advantage of these you
know the constant time to retrieve the
data
from the root which is which could be
max or hit me
and to maintain it for example if we
want to put the value
inside it if we want to insert the value
inside the heap or taking a value
outside of him or deleting a
data
element of uh from the hip what's the
time connection can you think about
the in the worst case can you guess make
a case make a guess if we only if we put
like a 200 here how can we do it
if we take one out of it what can the
time come next
it doesn't matter for the max if we only
put a 200 here
so you can imagine there will be a
restructure of this right yeah
so
could be if we put we're comparing we
sometimes we need to pop you know swap
the parents with a kid and swapping out
of the until we reach the root right so
the time capacity will be o log n right
yeah to delete it as well if we delete
some
uh
the best cases is what if we just delete
this one this is the leaf now we'll just
delete it that would be one right
but if we want to delete the loot
like if we wanted to do we need to do
some rearrangement right yeah
sometimes involving swapping the parents
with the kids so the time come back
still be like overlooked and as well
okay but
these are quite a complex uh algorithm
right so
we will not cover today but you need to
get this general idea of this uh to
maintain
maintain a hip usually takes all log n
to
add a new element in or to
remove the element for example if i want
to add a another element like uh maximum
like one and i can just put it here
right without without restructuring the
main uh the mind hip right they look we
just put it there the terminal xt will
be just a one right yeah
okay so that's the
why are we using the heat okay
so how can we store the hip in
in an array
for example like this zero
one
two
three
four
five
six how can we store this in the array
do one two three four by six oh yeah
yeah we can just put it because the look
is a complete or it's a complete
[Music]
uh perfect pioneer tree yeah remember
perfect is kind of complete right
perfect it's kind of at least it's
perfect and you've removed some of the
elements from the lower it's never
the leaf from the right and it could be
complete so if it's complete we can just
please look in one by one level by level
yeah breakfast thirst yeah usually
zero one two three four five six
okay so
so
so look for this index the fbc index if
we want to retrieve the the left kids
what's the index of the left kid if if
the parent is i what's that what's its
left kid
index
what is life kid
what is like it
if this is i what's that what's the
index of this
plus one plus one
times two plus one right
and
i know what's this
times two plus one what's this twenty
plus three yeah times two plus two okay
okay for example two times two what look
two times two plus one is five why you
said plus one plus one is here
correct two times two plus one two times
two plus two right
all right yeah okay so given the heap
maximum let's say today start giving a
hit
we want to verify
if it's a max max heap okay because for
each morphology method
is that each numbers each pair each node
is always bigger than the
uh kids right
yeah will using the index okay so how
can we do this
i'm going to do this
defy
is
max heap
i will give you my numbers okay numbers
first of all we want to find out how
many of them right now uh
what's the function to find out how many
numbers in
in the in array
in this
lens
okay then how we want to go through to
the
for i the index yeah in range redux
do we need to go through the whole
oh we can just go to the house
yeah because we don't need to go to the
the
we can only go to the hub because if it
doesn't have any kids the least doesn't
have any kids we don't need to check
right
yeah so girls are half and divided by
two
okay number one is
if norms
i
if it's a smaller right because it's a
massive if it's smaller than
noun
what's that what's the left left trial
of the numbers i what i
what's the definite of i
times two times two and one
times two plus one
[Music]
if it's the opposite
we want to check first that because we
for each for each lam's i needs to be
bigger than numbs i plus two plus times
two plus one and we also need to check
if the
if i smaller than what's like it
what's the right kid
um
okay so there's a small problem is that
sometimes these does not exist it's kids
there's no it's left or right it doesn't
exist so we need to check if this index
is smaller than n right so we need to
put a another n here so if if what i
times two
plus one is smaller than n
and
right
okay and then here
if i turns to
plus two smaller than n if the right kid
if we have the right kid
and also the loot is smaller than the
kids then we determine got it make sense
yeah what's the time complexity
one one yes okay
okay so i'm going to erase this bit
already
yeah okay so you can you can
tell me what come on you want to write
and
[Music]
sorry if they were i think i didn't see
what you're talking about
i want to compare the right kid okay so
how this is
if n no no no no there's something here
remember i i just talked about how to
check it okay
think about it how what do we talk about
think about
and we talked about
uh what are we doing here what what
what's it what what are we checking here
what's with chicken here
2 sorry
what are we doing here
we are
checking what right
this is therefore right
okay then what should we check in here
right okay so how do we check the right
something if sometimes
sorry if yeah plus two if i times two
plus two
smaller than one
then
we all want to check if we have a if we
then my kid has
n yeah
and and what
um
[Music]
okay so what what's what's the speed
before i this well
leave what and this
is what come on youtube here so what
should i do what's this be if i times t
yeah and okay
we're down today good job
bye