hello brother hello teacher hello hello
me
hello hello okay we're
talking about class yeah yeah yeah
can we sit down please can we yes okay
so today
yeah remember we talked about okay yeah
we talked about class before but
not in detail so today we are talking
about
the cloud and which is called
oop which stands for
object oriented programming
object oriented we're talking about
class
car not clock yeah yeah can can
can i can you pay attention please
object already programming okay
so everything in real world we can model
as
objects class and objects right
so there are two concepts one is class
the other one is object
okay so class we can call it as
object template object template
you know what's template the ten
plate template it's like
what's template what does it mean like
the speed i don't know it's like a
speed no it's it's like
uh how to put it this way uh it's this
you know the stem yeah yeah that's like
from template you have a stem and you
can create many many
stems right so class
yes so you can quickly make objects so
cook class
is object template which can be used to
create objects
so put it this way we have in
in um in person yeah
we can use this class okay class
and if we define an up class
person let's start with the person first
person you know
can you follow me now follow the notes
okay
okay so now we can have a define
with the
initialization initialization this is
the scenario
i'm about to say yeah initialization
initialize
self
[Music]
this is parameter of constructor we call
it constructor
do you know what these called with
constructors
define constructor to construct
something you know to build yeah to
build
exactly the function to build the
objects
if you're doing the wrong order it
wouldn't have one so we we have a
telemetry
these are two parameters we want to pass
in
yes yeah that's right and then we can
say
save save yourself you have me my own
let's say afternoon
[Music]
wait wait now after this yeah we
this is the simple very simple class and
then we
after this we can already define we can
already
initialize uh this is a personal
template
now we can say eric eric
is a person okay personally
then he will call this constructor yeah
this self is
it means that it's a mess of the
class okay and then we have this name
which is we can give you area yeah and h
and y n yeah i'm six yeah
[Music]
and then the first parameter this is the
first parameter we're going to pass
into the we're passing into the class
object right
which is called ryan the name on
six yeah so now we create two objects
look
this is object yeah okay two objects
and this is the class you see as i said
before
the class is used to create objects
and then this class look this class
the constructor beer the builder yeah
the builder function
needs two parameter which is name and h
and it will
assign these two parameters using
self.name
and serve the age as an attribute so
what does it mean
it means that we need to defend say
hello
look and then this one you remember yeah
and then we can do this what we can do
we can do
uh we can define a function inside this
person yeah we can say
say hello right say hello and then we
can take a message
uh the first time we always say yeah
message
when what can we do we will say twin
okay then look we can use this sentence
[Music]
plus plus you can press the string says
yeah says what
says message so after this
no no no look can i
can i please then then you can say look
eric
we call this function call message and
then you print
say afternoon okay then it's what it's
eric and then plus
says hello all right and ryan's don't
say hello yeah hello
you see this is the class yeah do you
get it hello it's a wood thing
sit down please be quiet require okay
so this is this is called uh
a person object and if we define another
one right
if we define i know like class car right
what name of the car right and then
speed okay you can take a speed
parameter
then again we can say save dot name
or brand you know whatever equals name
and self name
speed
car equals car and i give a name
which is audi and the speed may be
100 miles per per you know per hour
yeah so look this is two different and
remember we have eric i have ryan
there's three different objects right
created right yeah and then we can talk
about
uh using this if we have three different
objects then we can use
we can check using this
what do you think yeah it's like eric is
an instant look
it's an instant of person so this will
return true right
but how about this is instance function
this is the instant value yeah
how about audi is it a
is it a person object person is it an
instant or person
yes or no is audi is a is does it
belongs to
person class no because audi is not
person right
so this is a simple function to check if
the object
is an instant of you know instance
of a class so in other ways the class
is used to create instance which is
called
objects objects are instance right
so when we create objects like eric
and ryan the two independent object we
which have different names and age
right there are two different copies of
the person class
am i am i right do i have my
career yeah okay so let's that's it for
today
okay the last thing say goodbye baby
bye oh yeah oh yeah
oh yeah