oh hello water flash
hello mr eric mr ryan are you all right
yeah today we talk about a island
problem island parameter what's
parameter
um around it
perhaps
what does this word mean
if a square
if it's a square if the side is one
what's the perimeter
per
so what's this
if it's side of one
what's this parameter how much is the
perimeter of a square which size of one
um
four yeah
four one times four equals four yeah
because we have four sides two times
four okay how about if i give you
another square the same size
and what's this what's the perimeter of
this rectangle yeah you come to block
two number two what's the perimeter of
number number two
four
okay
i'm
so what's mean what's the terminator of
the what's the perimeter parameter of
llamas to block
sorry
you don't have to count so how do you
get a number
six with this you count you count
oh can you do this two
look
one square contribute four right so
actually it should be two times four but
we want to subtract
we want to subtract this meter
connection right so how many numbers
two blocks so how many edges how many
two we need to subtract two so that's
six okay another example
number block three
what's the meter eight
eight yeah how do you get it because i
just know yeah three times four
and i need to stop trying
six
eight
look how many one two three four
[Music]
yeah
so so so far what you will get if there
are connections if if i i added here a
square and if there's something here
and
uh okay if they are square here and then
i need to subtract two right if i add
another square here i need to subtract
two for this for the common edges right
okay
so today
so to say very simple all right
no no no
given a magic a magic okay a message
what's magic
come on
please
if it's one
if it's one it means a square if it's a
zero it means no and can you give me the
count of the the
island shape parameters okay
like that four nanometer so what is this
look look uh let's just one one one one
just
okay like zero zero
please
keep quiet
zero zero one one zero zero zero one
what's the parameter of this um that's
two what's the parameters what's that
this shape look what's the foot
and
four
what's the parameter of this so look
then that corresponds to this shape okay
so i want to find out the parameter of
these what's this
um
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 well down wow
how do you count um i just remember
that's um
eight
eight plus four yeah yeah okay so how do
we do this computing uh how do we
calculate with the algorithm on the
computer so i can count how many squares
right one two three four four square
four times four but i need to subtract
the comma edges which is here two
four four that's the other four yeah and
that these two doesn't have any
combination so that was that 16 minus
four equals square got it
easy yeah
is it easy
does it make sense does it matter ryan
yes
okay so let's find this problem okay
let's let's try this okay
if i
define
island can you please keep quiet okay
remember
the people over the world are watching
you two guys okay
you need to be a good
boy okay
let's do this i'm alright okay
[Music]
return zero okay
and then columns equals length and zero
yes
yellow equal equals columns what
happened
i don't want to do this again okay
answer equals zero
four
i go through each element in the i go to
each anime
in a metric right
yeah
so how can i write it for r
for r in one
five one for r
or in range
right
where you walk
in french
can you can you pay attention sit down
if rc is one what happens when this is
the current chord
plus oh yeah i need to pass four first
right
yeah
but i need to subtract the connection a
so i need to make sure
i need to check me here right look i
need to check here and check here right
all right look i need to check here if
it's uh if it's a square and also i
check here if it's an island right these
two islands right so if r bigger than
zero
and
magic
r minus one c
is one then what what should we do
answer what
if this is the minus two minus two yeah
we need to subtract these two uh minus
equal to yeah
yeah
if c bigger than zero and one
and n
ah
c minus one
[Music]
times rows ah
rows and columns they have also color
yeah because i say write down columns
what's a space complex do you use any
phrases
no so what which is one
okay okay i'm going to erase this
answer minus equals two here
oh and then what happened next if c is
bigger than
[Music]
last time yeah oh minus lc minus
one one equals equal one
okay
minus equals two and then return answer
okay so one question why why do we need
to minus two can you tell me
can you explain to people why we need to
manage equals
[Music]
why we need to check if i is bigger than
zero and c bigger than zero i say why
why do we need to check the pictures
[Music]
look if if it's on the age then there's
no more left right if the on the top is
no more top so if we need to check if
it's if i go zero that minus one will
become minus one which doesn't make
sense i'm right it's out of boundary
okay okay that's it for today