hello
hello everyone
yes okay so today we talk about graphs
what's graph
graph is data structure right with the
vertex and the edges yeah so the graph
will usually represent what with g
and then it's a set of what
a set of can you tell me is the set of v
and e what's really
vertex
and
vertex yeah
and what
this is vertex yeah
that's the vertex and what's this
what's this what's this
what's this the connections between the
vertex
what do we call it star with e
[Music]
e b
yeah
vertex and edges
okay
so
this graph can be directional or
bi-directional yeah or any direction so
we can it can be bi-directional
what does it mean by direction
or direction okay
bi-directional or un-directional which
is the same iteration
and direction of iteration this is the
same thing and direction
what does it mean
look if it's directional you can have
this has error one can go to two but two
cannot go to one okay
right let's dive can i have two hours
yeah if you want to get to go to one you
have to put this right here right
then by direction it means you just put
a one heck of the two two can go to one
okay
two can go to three so you can go to two
so we can go to four or four can go to
three okay so uh this is the first
transition okay so if today's top is
very simple given a bi-directional or
un-directional graph
because it means that one thing goes to
it can go to one
and
something like that one two three three
four
so for example this one if i tell you
can can you find the path between one to
four yeah yeah because you can go to one
to two two three four okay how about
there's a graph and not yeah
five to six
and then
seven
can you go from three to seven
yeah because look this is a separate
right there's no edges between these two
components yeah simple okay easy yeah so
we've got this problem so we are given
these uh
these so how we are given this input
like one two two two two three three two
these edges yeah so how do we represent
the graph
how do we represent the graph
diversity remember adjacent adjacent
magic yeah one can go to
adjacent magic so for example like one
two two
two two three okay two two three
two two four
okay
so how do we represent
how how do we represent this we can use
the
[Music]
key
key and the value so how can we do this
the vertex we cut the vertex is the key
how what's the vertex one two three four
yeah
one two
three
four i know what's the value this is the
vertex vertex
and then this is the
value values this is the key here and
the values will be a list of the
note vertex list of vertex
so one can go to do one
and one can go to two we are done two
can go to one
one
four three yeah one four three or one
three four yeah so a list of nodes you
can go to three can go to work
uh two
and four and that one
yeah okay so you see this is the node uh
additional hash map yeah the keys are
the nodes the vertex the values are list
of the vertex that it can go to okay
yeah so
so given this
given this data structure yeah we
already know how to build this the
adjacent matrix from the given edges a
list of edges and
how can we
find out if there's a path between the
target uh the start to the finish to the
end what can we do how many what kind of
argument are we can we use to traverse
the graph
traverses three three three is also
graph yeah remember we talked about
how do we travel a tree remember how
many kind of eggs
breakfast such well and
that's what this is the two we are we
have learned so far okay so today we're
going to use the breakfast
yeah yeah of course yeah i'm showing you
later
three is also a graph okay yeah three is
also graph so breast research can be
also used to a traversal the
graph okay
so if for example one i want to find out
if one can go to three right so i put
the one in the queue yeah but remember
the processor is the cube right we put a
q1 here
so we take one out what's the key of
that one what one can travel to two
right two
okay i put it to it so i take a two out
where you can travel to one three four
okay so do we need to visit the one
again no because we we already come from
that if we visit if we don't if we keep
visiting what happened
[Music]
it will never end right
because look i just cover one and if i
take i
i put a two and two and comma one and
then it will be a cycle right you will
do this forever right so we need to kind
of what kind of data structure to
remember the notes we have visited
hashtag or notebook yeah we need to do
this this is a special
headset all set yeah set notebook set
okay so we we can start from the
notes and then we keep doing this
breakfast search and here all the notes
has been
searched visited right and if we can't
find the note when we're expanding the
notes if we can't find the finish let
the end then
then it will turn first otherwise if we
visit it and we'll return to okay simple
as that let's do this
define
that uh
pass past exists
as it is
so we're given a
star star
and the end
and then we're given a list of edges
yeah as this
okay so first of all we want to keep
this address is the list of the staff to
end right so we want to build a graph so
let's say gua equals before
remember what's the key default
dictionary what's the key what key is
the notes and
value is the list of the integer right
yeah
list
okay
so uh
i think we also need uh uh do we need to
end
no we don't need the n okay
and it's the number of edges like one
two three okay that's fine then we we go
through these four for
s e
in edges right
so look
g
s
dot append what
open one
um look yes that is e right
remember this is five dimensional so we
need to also need a g e dot apparently
opera s yes
because s can go to e it also means e
can go to s there so i put it in in the
notes right
this is the remember the value is the
list of notes it can go to from s yeah
e s can go to e right e can go to s okay
so once we have this adjacent this is
called adjacent metric
adjacent metric
okay adjusting method and then now i
need to
do what perfect search right so i have a
queue how how do we implement a
performance search here using what kind
of data structure
dk what's the kill mean double ended
thank you and then first of all i need
to put what in it
[Music]
you can travel from a style you can
travel from the end it's the same right
you can start from the start or you can
start from the finish yeah it doesn't
matter okay let's start from the start
yeah start okay
i know remember we need a hash set to
remember the notes we have seen yeah so
sin
equals what
what kind of data structure
said yes that's set it says contains
only the unique numbers right
and i know how we need to tell it trevor
is why what
why what
[Music]
why
we have something right yeah why we have
something in the queue
then we have to finish uh place in take
a
element from the queue right so we we do
what
what the top left
what's the problem we want to take a pop
uh take a q the front of the queue for
the element of the queue
what
huh let's let's call it c
c equals q dot pop left yeah yeah let's
call it the kill we have the q we take
our first element look we couldn't take
a one out and
what do we need to do
first of all we need to find out if c
has been visited before right from the
scene yeah yes c in scene
continue right we have visited this yeah
can supporters continue
continue to the next without going there
continue means that continue continue to
the next loop yeah
continue okay
if we put a break what happened
um
it will stop stop you will jump to leap
after the loop okay that's what let's be
different
then
if at this point we haven't visited the
sea so we want to v we want to mark it
as a visit so how to do this cinder
[Music]
and now i need to
now this is called we already see note
that we want to re expand all the nodes
it converted right
so for
i
in
graph c right
and then what do we do we want to what
um depend cue a pen yeah that's why
open i
okay so
wait
[Music]
we
haven't
so if if c in sync so before left c here
we need to check if c equal equals n
right
because we already if this is the end
what do we do return one
reason true because we otherwise if this
finish what happened what what do we
mean here return one
what does it mean
[Music]
return
first it means that all the notes has
been visited but we can't find the n
right so that's the breakfast assume
right
yeah
okay does it make sense
[Music]
okay
okay so i'm going to erase this bit okay
so can you write this this is the most
important part okay so what do we do
here
um
yeah
four something for what
i yeah for i or anything like yeah
[Music]
g c what does gc mean
what does gc mean
it means
what
what does it mean
g what's g mean remember graph g c
what's g mean it means
what's i
i is the nodes
of nodes of what c can
what
what does this mean g s upon e g e upon
s
from s to e or e to s so what's the gc
mean
i can go to c yeah yeah all the nodes
can this is all the nodes c can go to
right and then we have nodes i so what
do we need to do
um
a pen yeah we want to push it into the
cube remember for the first research we
take the front of the queue
take the element from the front of q
take it out process it check if it's the
target element which is the end if not
if it's already visited or continue if
not
we explain the notes
if we expand the notes you can visit and
put it uh append on the key remember
yeah remember
what's by versus
[Music]
but
but the graph is the same yeah if you
look if it's a graph
it's the same yeah it's the same it's
the same right yeah so you start from
here so what's next you go to expand is
here here right and you take the tree
here because
yeah yeah and then the next one is you
take this and explain its kids here here
but you don't explain this one because
this one has been
visited before but why we don't have
these in the tree because in the tree
you you don't
you don't visit the parent again right
yeah
so we don't have that problem using the
set but in the graph you don't know if
that's parent right right so we need to
use this it doesn't make sense
what's the time compressed
oh n what's that what's n
number
of the number of nodes in the graph in
the vertex what's the space somewhere
um
yeah because we are using
dq and set yeah and the graph here graph
we have lots of this
place okay thanks thank you that's it
good job bye