hello
hello hello hello hello
hello mr miss ryan how are you all right
yes okay so today's test uh very simple
okay so today we got the uh
we got the magic
any metrics numbers yeah one zero
let's just make it simple only condense
one and zero okay
one zero zero okay only condense one
zeros okay so let's do this uh
so if if this is the matrix three times
three matrix so if we want to set the
um
if we want to set the matrix by zero if
if the
if the row contains zero okay so for
example the first note contains yellow
so we i get it
so can you and if it contains uh zero
for the color
can you write it
[Music]
good job so you understand the problem
yeah so we said that magic to zero if it
has the zero in
its row
or column right for example is zero so
you set all zero in this column and in
this row yeah you've got a zero here so
here and here and here here here but
only different this one okay
yeah yeah good point
you can go with the diagonal just the
horizontal and vertical so any idea how
we're solving this problem
we
the first approach we need to think
about is what
is what if we don't have any ideas
sorry revolving
[Music]
then what if it's a 0 then we
set all the numbers in its row
to 0 and it's columns
i like your columns as yellows yeah
but
there's a problem why is that
that's the people of doing right look if
i put it here right if this is a zero
yeah
how do you know this zero is at the
beginning
or not
so look at it when we reach this point
we set a set all the rows the row the
first row to double zero right
but how do you know but this is already
zero
but when you go to this zero how do you
know it's original zero or is it the one
we are already flipping
um
set
we need to remember yeah the first we
can oh we can do this no problem so
when we meet at zlo we remember
the row and the column right
yeah
yeah we remember the row and column and
then we when we finish all of it
when we finish iterating all the
elements in the rows in a matrix
we go through yeah we can push push this
row number and call the number into a
queue right
we push it into the queue
and now we go through all the rows and
columns in the queue
to to set all the rows
yeah and columns
to
zeros all right yeah
okay
so we can do this all
we can have two
two
sets we can have two sets one is the
rows
one is the columns
what's the set can you tell me what's
set
unique numbers yeah so if you look if
row stops at one
and row store another one it only
consists one right because it doesn't
contain the duplicate numbers right so
for example right right rows
dot add
one the first note and then rows
two
and then eric rose
stop at
one so can you tell me what happened in
the rose rose stock l1 rose a2 and rose
a1 so
what are the elements in the rows
sorry
one
two
two yeah one and two only it doesn't
have one because set
only contains the unique numbers right
right ryan yeah
so one because it's unique guys up here
before so we only record it once in a
sec yeah that's what it means so once we
have these rows and columns so what do
we what do we do now
what do we do
we iterate yeah we iterate the num two
leaves
and
we check if the current row if it's in
the rows
then we set it to zero right
or even like columns
even call the number in the columns
we set it to zero right
that's it do you understand
they understand
yeah because first of all we go through
these uh metrics we remember which we
call the number of we recorded rows and
columns
that contains yellows right
yeah
and then we go through the matrix again
and as
as we go through the metric we know
we know that row and column right and we
just have to check the row and column if
it's
been
in these two sets right
either one if it's in the rows or if
it's in the columns
then what do we do
we just do uh it raise it with a zero
right
that's it okay let's try
this is
not a difficult question okay
it's a medium default
define the set
zeros okay so matrix is zero let's do m
okay
first of all we need to remember the
number of the rows and columns okay so
let's do this r
c
equals what land m
and lens
and
zero okay let's just assume that this
metric is not empty okay it contains
only at least one element right the
minimum metric is this one yeah
one okay
just one okay this one
okay
so look now first of all we need to
contain the let's put the capital r
for the rows
capital c for the set for the column so
let's set
and then set okay two sets
then first of all we go through the
element in the row yeah oh why did you
do a casper
capitalized because
the the variables in the python is
capture us
is case sensitive okay so low uppercase
and the lowercase is different okay
so for look for let's say for i
in range when you are range
what what number
we didn't see each row for ranging one
okay so look if magic i j if it's yellow
right
so what should we do if this current if
this if the row i
row i and column j
the element and row i column j is zero
so what do we need to do what do we need
to do um
[Music]
sorry c
i row
and then
c dot e
come on
which one is column
which one is column which one is column
um
yeah that's it so first of all we go
through these elements and we found okay
so let's do that again zero one zero
one zero one
zero
uh let's do this one one one okay
so what what after these are gonna be
zeros okay let's place one okay so okay
so what happened for the r and c after
this these two loop
can you tell me what's r what's r
and what's c
i is what
zeros
come on it's easy zero
zero one yeah
okay i hope if i put this as zero as
well
so
does it change
no no this is the same is it the same
which columns contains the which flowers
contains zero and one
um
yeah still assembly which columns it
contains the zero one
and the first one and the second one so
this is the other one yeah
that's what what happened this code
this bit of code will produce these two
all we need to do i know what should we
do now we just need to go through again
right for i in range
renewable
ah yeah for j in what
inventory
nine minutes see okay ten minutes like
what should we do now what should we do
now we go to that element and what
should we do now
what should we do now
if
evo
colony is row is i if row
if i in what
if i
in what
which one contains the rows we just
visited come on
satisfy what what do we do now
we set it to zero yeah so how do we say
that m
equals i
will i and
j
equals
[Music]
actually we can return it or we don't
return it that's okay that's fine
okay
okay let's see yeah if okay so this is
pretty much it yeah we assume m is not
okay
if m is if not m then return return okay
otherwise it will return
here
okay we are going to set yeah i create a
set
what's the time complexity irc
what's r and z the rights and columns
okay what's the space complexity this is
quite tricky what's the space complexity
a
n
o what's n and
[Music]
and how many sets are we using
what are those
rows and columns yeah and how many rows
can we possibly have in the
row
how many rows
are right
and how many columns
okay so we're using two space so it's r
plus c okay yeah this is very tricky
it's not i up and z okay
got it make sense
okay
i'm just going to erase this bit okay
i'm going to be those three okay whoa
come on write it that's it
this is the road this is
[Music]
guys row and we want to check if this is
in what in
if
in i in r
yeah
or or what or c
[Music]
j is the column yeah j e you need to put
that space but that's okay
i wrote
j in one column
c yeah
and column
i know what we do we need to set it to
zero so 10
what do we do
how do we set how do we set it to zero
and
yes
um
yeah bracket yeah
let's grab okay yes i yes we're done
and then yes and then another one
zay yeah
and then yes well done good job and now
set it to zero come on
that should be pretty easy yes
well why you have a two double double if
you assign it you know you only use one
if you want to check it
check
one finger equal means i want to put
this zero i want to update these to zero
two two
double equal means what
we want to check if this is equal right
does it make sense yeah okay so one
thing to equal that's good job okay for
today good job