hello
hello hello
hello mr mr ryan are you all right
yeah
okay so we talked about the graph
the day before yesterday yeah the the
connectivity between the start and the
finish right okay eric that's it
the graph yeah by the direction of the
graph see it
that's okay
the graph what how can we represent a
graph that's it that's it how can we
represent the graph
all right
what
what what do we represent the graph what
what letter are we using to do the graph
which graph
yeah
what does it contain
it contains
what's this eric what's this
this is ashes and what's this
vertex vertex yes g we used uh it's a
collection of vertex and edges okay
that's the graph
so we want to find out if there is a
connection if uh
if there's a path that it could lead to
the end we're done from
[Music]
we use the q and we also use the
notebook to remember the vertex we have
uh visited right
and then how do we represent the graph
we use the adjacent
linkage actually it's a change in
english
adjacent language
what does that mean
yeah it's not adjacent metric
previously i made a mistake because it's
not adjacent material it's not just
increased why is that how do we
represent this graph the key
the key key is the vertex right remember
so if it's one vertex one
and then the variable value is the list
of vertex you can connect to so what's
one what's here
one can connect to
a list of two two can connect to one and
three yeah one and three
three can connect to
at least one
no no no it's just direct edges three
omega connectors and then four connect
two five
five and then five connectors
you see so these the keys are the vertex
and the
values are the list of the vertex you
can get directly connected to
yeah
okay so that day we use the buffer
search you know today we're going to use
the default search okay yeah it's quite
similar we still need to
use the hash
a hashtag to remember the notes we have
visited so it doesn't
form a cycle look if if i read it too
if i come from one and visit two right i
should i visit one again
do i need to visit one again no right
because if i go back to one will happen
then you'll go to the two again and go
to one and then go to two again so you
will do this endlessly right yeah
why would you choose one
because one is also connected to two
right it's a by direction why don't they
g3
yes you can choose the three as well i
mean they're expanding the notes right
if either two and what are the knowledge
it can lead to yeah we look up these
list here is one and three all right
look eric look
yeah okay so today we talked about
deficits how how are we usually
implementing the deficit
oh we're usually implementing the type
of search what's that for search
what's different
i mean
yeah and how are we easily implementing
with
using what style is our what do you call
it
edges okay
okay
[Music]
first of all h we given this a list of
lambda edges we want to form we want to
create a graph right we build the graph
with adjacent method okay
okay
g equals
before what
they bought
before
yeah defaultionally
and then list of
interface which is the
because look the keys are what are the
keys everything the graph remember we
just talked about this
two minutes ago what are the
keys in the graph vertex
okay now look at the form
s e star end in edits
[Music]
apparent e and g dot f and s y
y
e
all right
look this is x this is e remember the
bi-directional if x can go to e then you
can go to s right yeah yeah
the trees trees are directional graph
why is that
look this is a tree
it's actually look at the gra the trees
we talked about right it's actually
directional why is that because look you
cannot go to the parent
for usually you cannot go to the parents
from the kids right early so it's a
direction from parent to girl to the
kids right okay all right this is three
directional right but now we are talking
about bi-directional all
and directional yeah and direction
and direction okay all right this makes
sense
pay attention okay you're losing focus
right
you're thinking about something else
right no i'm not okay okay that's it
okay and then now
first of all we need to remember have a
set equal set
this is to remember the notes the vertex
we have visited right yeah so we don't
do this again right
yeah
and then what then we have these defined
we have what they find
something what cash
we don't need cash at the moment all
right dfs catch a cash yeah
star we start with the star to the end
right so what does this mean we want to
find out if there's a path between s to
e right
i know what it will do if s equals e
what should we return
we this is the base cases
because look
at s
y
yeah
return to where yes we're done because c
c is the number of nodes we visited we
are currently at s so we need to put it
at here yeah
at
s this is a set yeah and s
and now what should we do now we should
iterate over the nodes
that the gs right
wait okay so if i'm at s
where what are the nodes like what are
the vertices
for okay can you listen to me okay we
are at current no the vertex s what are
the nodes where can we assess the list
of nodes that the s connects to
remember this is s and then it connects
to a few nodes so how can we access it
where do we edit
where where are the
values
where is the graph g
yes yeah that's the okay so we go sooner
now yeah
[Music]
every ryan don't play with the cap come
on listen this is the
coding lesson okay so i is the note that
look everything this is like oh yeah
so first of all we need to check if we
have seen this eye before right
is
[Music]
what what and return true can you tell
me
otherwise return force here
return false
can you tell me what should i put here
if i
if i is not in thin and dfs we are
calling itself to find out
what are the two parameters here um
why is
i well because the eye is s connects to
look right
listen
e is somewhere here right i don't know
right but look s the next note is i
right i know x can go to i and i want to
find out if i can go to e right if i can
go to e
then i know s can go to u all right
simple as that right so but we have to
check if i is not in the scene right we
want to make sure we don't visit this i
over and over again right
so if i not in c and then we can if if
we find out that i can be connected
there's a path between i and e
what does it mean
a
that is true
yeah look
i what's i
s there is a path between s to i right
all right all right because s is
connected to i and then there is a path
between i to e what does it mean the
connectivity
s can go to i i can go to e so what does
it mean
s can go to i i can go to e what does it
mean
what's true
s can go to e there is a path
yeah does it make sense
doesn't make sense eric i don't we just
need to return s3 okay so ryan you
mentioned a good point about the cash
yeah
which is good
that's fine what's cash mean what does
cash mean
cash cash is
what does what does this cash mean
educational
explanation
what's catch me what what does cash try
to do here um
me minimization yeah memorize what does
he try to memorize
so it doesn't
go over again yeah
memorize okay so if you are calling the
s to e right and then if some somehow
later you want to find out again we
don't calculate this function because we
already calculated we already calculated
and that's why we just look it up in a
notebook then we can
directly return the value do you get it
do you get it
yeah yeah
okay so look if we want to replace this
cache
can you tell me what to do if i i don't
want to leave use this trick how can i
remember memorize it we want to use it
the truth and how about if i tell you
you can't
so we don't care we just do it yeah you
just do it how if we want to memorize we
use what what what kind of thing this
generally yeah so we need a dictionary
so we just want to look so how how can
we do this we look we just put a
dictionary like memo yeah nemo
because before
dictionary yes before
dictionary we should return uh uh
the value will be two or four right so
it's a boolean right what's what's putin
put it what's
[Music]
it means two or four yeah it's a value
of true or false look so with default
dictionary the default type is the green
yeah i mean and then here what do we do
if
we just put here is
if look at
s e
in
then what what do we do return
return memo yeah
mimo s e eric look
and then before here before returning
all right ryan before returning true we
said meemo
this is a cuba yeah s e equals true
right and here what do we do here we can
before returning force what do we do
me
look so basically
before right before we returning true or
false yeah
we
set the key eric look we said send a key
of prediction meanwhile right which is
look at what parameters are here what
parameters
s and e right so we said that as an
integer to two or false so basically we
remember the values yeah correct we will
run away so you speed up if you if you
have this much more cause to the same
input s and e right got it okay let's do
this that's it oh
my god
come on
you understand what what do you mean you
don't
i i
i not in c
and d f s i e
yeah you always memorize the easiest
part okay so in what cases are we
returning to come on try to understand
try to
try to understand the problem okay
if i not
what's important
and dfs
i.e
do you mean and tell me why okay because
you're looking for your name
[Music]
if i know you see another
dfs one i just told you dfs one
from what i to the what's the
destination e yes
i like returning too yes yes
come on
what's the time complexity
what's the time come next t
yeah and it's the um of notes in the
vertex in the clock what's a space
complexity
among us
it's the same yeah
okay that's it for today
bye bye bye