[Music]
ryan all right today good okay
so
can you do them remember what's
underground and gram yeah what's
underground can you give me an example
of endograms two lengths what's
[Music]
okay so can you explain to me what are
those i mean so what are item columns
what's endograms
the these two
what are them in common and these two
whatever you're saying
yeah they have less letters yeah senator
is means that
one corresponding to another look so the
same number of letters and same
type of letters yes eric e-r-i-c e-r-i-c
silent
silent okay okay this is underground
great i watch substring
substring
what's the substring
substring like abc
d e f g can you tell me what are the
substring of the length three
lengths three substring
in this in this string
ryan eric
how many
how many sub strings which are of the
size three in a b c d e f g
what substrings
[Music]
continuous so length 3 if i
if we are looking for then 3
the substring which are size of three in
these strings what are those it should
be very easy yeah
what are those
a b c d e f g
no no substring size of three abc and b
c d c d e
d e
which is defined e f g okay f g so this
is such thing okay so
so today we'll talk about endogame and
substring okay so what are those so for
example like i have a s0 which is
a b c
and i have s1 which is
c a
c
b d e
a
c b okay
so
we want to look for the substrings
in s1 let's have the let's ah
let our anagram with s0 okay so what are
those in this case all right look
abc
what are the abc in can you find the
substring in s1 which is the anagram in
stl
and um yeah
okay so you got it right so look bac abc
acb is okay so yeah so we return number
three easy
yeah yeah there's atp and another acb
yeah that acv yes exactly but they
consider the difference so there are
different substrings right this acp acp
they are both
the energon with s0 okay got it
so this is the problem man yeah so how
can we do this
so how do we check if the two strings
are underground if they are look if i
give you s0 and s1 how do we check if
they are n
remember define
check engram
how do we check it remember
we talked about this before we want to
use we want to check the number of
characters and
and their appearance the number of
frequencies are the same and we can use
the
we need to count right we need to count
counter string so in person remember we
use what kind of
how can we count it
hong kong county set
yeah but we can use the much faster way
which is capital c
yeah
so if this is easier return
counter
s zero
equals equal what
to check if these two are energons okay
okay so now look because we know the
length of the s0 is three yeah we know
this length so in s1
what are the what are the substring the
size
we want to look to check
we know right because we only we only
want to check the number uh
the the substring which are size have
the same size as still yeah so in this
case i check what plc because this is
the window of three and i move to next i
move to next every time i check the
substring of three yeah substitutionally
substring
subject and right yeah
so in this case we can check right so
how can we check so p a c we check okay
if it's that set we can use this one
right but when we move to the acp
we need to update this counter thing
yeah so how can we update it
when we move from bac
to
acb what should we do what should we do
with the counter one of the counter
because this counter never change uh
let's call the s0 never change right
this counter average but this is
changing call the s1 is changing of the
lead from phc to acb so what we need to
do is we remove the left mouse b look
all right this is very important right
now we remove the f mouse b and then we
add the right most b
right b a c to h b will happen we don't
need this b right
and we added one more okay acb to to
move to next what do we do
what do we do
look array
we get rid of a we add d and then move
to next what do we do we get with the c
and we add e okay move to next we get
rid of b and we add a
move to next
we add a c and remove d move to next we
add b and remove e okay so we just need
to
update this counter along the way right
yeah
okay then we can do this okay
this this is called the sliding window
okay because we know the size of the
window is
what n0 equals length
as zero okay this is the size of sliding
window always the stacking window of
size and yellow no we attack move it
move it move okay
define let's do this
define
cloud
anagram
substring okay count the as
s0 s1
column first of all we need to remember
know the answer answer will be equal to
y
at the beginning answer equals 1.
okay now n 0 equals
r
i is the
point
i'll show you what's r okay
equals length as s 0
n 1 equals length x 1 okay
okay now c equals counter
counter what sgnos one these never
change
counter s one s zero right
right right alright
pay attention come on guys you're losing
focus c equals counted as zero
and then what current let's do it
current the window okay the window
equals counter
counter what s1
if
c equals current
what does it mean look
what does mean look this is s zero
equals a b c
and s one equals
b a c d
a
c b okay for example like that okay
look all right
s zero the c c is adc
current is it s one no it's not s one we
need to do this s one up to n yeah so we
need to s one
two
the first how many characters eric do
you understand
do you understand
so look
c is this yeah
and current first of all first we know
is bac so s1
how many
what what should i put here n one o and
zero
and one is the length and zero and zero
come on zero is this one
yeah
okay and then if c equals current if abc
and bac the counter is our anagram so
what should we do
what should we do answer what
if this is the n comma at least the
first winner what should we do
um
plus one that's the plus one where that
yes that's what i mean yeah and then we
just need to move this
to the end right
so ah look r is the length as zero i is
at this point at three so zero one two
three i will be pointing to here right
i is the initial value so i'm here i
wanna move here ah yeah so what should
we do
wire
ah is smaller than
an n zero all in one
angelo
come on think about it n01
[Music]
okay so i need to update the window so
this is c current is the current window
so what should i do i just remove s i
should add the b right
look at it i should add the
these i should add these and remove
these yeah i should remove this i should
at least right
look so what should we do
uh
the current yeah current
this here
come on
s1 what ah
if this is r what's this
this is r what's this
r minus one and zero and
minus three f
minus and zero
minus equals one right but if this is
zero so what happened if this is yellow
we need to remove the key from the
decision area correct because when it
becomes zero what does this mean when a
a number of appearance becomes zero it
means this this character is not
it's not existing you know we can't
window so we need to remove the key
right so so e
is what
if current
s1
r minus n0 come up
equals 1 then we debate it we deleted a
key did it
it is current
s1 yeah s1
r minus n0
okay
right
and now what should we do if current
equals c what should we do
yeah
yeah if we if already update if we
already update it then we need to if we
already update the window and then we
find out the window is the same as this
window then we answer plus in person
all right
and how do we go to the next loop how do
we go to the next loop by one
hour
plus equal one left move this window to
the next year after last one
and return a little bit
awesome return answer we're done okay
so does it make sense what's the time
complexity
what's the time rest
because we're moving here right we're
moving
okay
okay so and yeah because look we are
moving this window yeah so we're moving
here not here right because this one is
here so sorry this end come on
okay and then
what's a space complexity
what's the space for mercury
[Music]
right and what's this space
look this is the same size yeah because
we you know all the time we just need
the space two counters to store
the number
of
energons right so what's that so it's
all n 0
times 2
n 0 plus n 0 0 and 0 times 2 okay got it
doesn't make sense eric okay
okay can you tell me how can we solve
this problem
um
win those things
if we don't think okay i'm going to
i'm going to erase two parts okay always
listing
okay
come on understand it and then
erase the
this bit okay you just tell me okay
okay okay just these two so and then you
need to tell me what happened okay count
the one
okay i'm gonna write it can you not play
with this one please this is for
eric ryan um
come on you wanna do it
i don't
current equals one counter one counter
one looks one
this one s1 we are going to use the
first
few
first few characters which is what and
there are whereabouts and here
we are adding this up and then what do
we do updating the left left part we're
adding the the new characters
and then what should we do with the
leftmost character in the window
what's this s1
this is r what's this r
minus minus
when zero weather yes okay so releases r
because the window size is n0 so we get
the previous left most window uh
currently in the window yeah because
we're shifting right
what does it mean by shifting we take
away the left mouse in a window and then
we add a new new
new character in the window so we are
shifting basically with shifting this
window okay
okay and then if the window if this
map if this occurrence becomes zero we
need to remove it remove the entry from
the map okay this is what comparison
because we we want to check if current
equals c then another plus one our plus
one we move this we shifted the window
one side to the right okay
okay that's it for today good job
bye bye