[Music]
okay what's prefix we talked about this
prefix before prefix sum
prefix what's the process for example
what's prefix
like look
uh eric what's the prefix of the eric
how many prefix
how many prefix of these four what are
those
[Music]
i see yeah and we also talk about
surface yeah what's the surface of this
what's the surface
um
come on the opposite c
c i
uh yeah i see
you understand this okay and we also
talked about the prefix sum okay we
talked about quickly some today remember
why do we need to quickly sign suppose
we have an array like
one two three four five six seven
okay so this is an array with and i just
items okay and if i tell you like i want
to calculate
the sum the sum between any two any
ranges for example i want to calculate
some between
three to five so what's the sum
three plus four plus five right
yeah
three plus four plus five which is
twelve what's the term complexity if i
just do it
like that you know blue force if you if
you tell me okay i want to start from
the
uh the lower ranges from three the upper
branch is five
and can you tell me the sum
and then we just do a loop for i in
range from three up to five okay and
then some answer plus equals the value
yeah
what's the time complexity for this one
and we're done because this the open if
the end if the lower range is yellow
right
upper range is the end
and then this eventually will be
looping all the i elements in the array
and then getting this sound low v-o-n
which is very slow uh not very fast okay
so how can we do
you know n is a minion it's a slow right
yeah
o-n is low compared to a one if we can
do it over one how can we do this one if
if
if we already know if we do this you
know if we're calling this many many
times yes if we want to speed up the
calculation of such uh such things such
as the sum between n and range okay all
right so how can we do this remember we
talked about a prefix sum how can we
calculate the previous sound so look
what's the prefix sum
what's the prefix sum of this eric can
you tell me
three plus three six yeah it's one plus
two plus three yeah so basically the sum
the values will be updated to the sum
of all the elements from the beginning
up to it right so what's next
ten ten yeah
and yeah 15 15 21
wait
so why is this useful because we only
get to calculate these ones right we
only calculate this one then we can use
these to calculate the sum between three
to five how do we get this
how to get the sum between here
okay the sum of these three elements is
it because it's equal to the sum of
these five elements but
minus these two elements
all right
look this i want to get the
ryan eric look ryan look
the sum of three four five right right
is it equals to the sum of one plus two
plus three four five right minus the sum
between one to two right
so okay so can you tell me the sum of
one to five which is
fifteen
the sum of
one plus two
yeah we just look it up yeah
so the sum of three plus four five
two
which one which one is faster this one
this one what's the time complexity for
this one
or one yeah if we are not considering
the building up because we only need to
build this up what's the time complexity
to be at least the prefix array
what
what's that
oh
[Music]
and yeah because we need to go through
this
one
so okay let's review this how do we
calculate these uh the prefix sum for
the array okay how do we get today
it's easier
define
prefix clear the prefix okay prefix sum
if this is the data yeah data
so how do we do this all right look
how do we do this um
n equals length
theta right
if n equals zero we just return all
right because it's uh we just returned
nothing okay
and then what should we do
all right
for
i
in
range we start from the first one right
and up to n
can you tell me what to do theta
theta one look
one two three we start from the second
one second universe yeah so theta i
equals one one
right
theta
i need to plus the previous one right
right and theta i plus equal
minus theta i minus one yeah
that's it
look remember we use the function
remember we can we don't know we talked
about the accumulative function right
this can be replaced by one
accumulate
remember we can
from
eater
import
accumulate what's accumulated i mean
i mean accumulate
what's this function mean
it accumulate that accumulator you know
bits by bits i put it together right so
all these can be
changed into uh
[Music]
i i uh at least return
is written data and then i can just do
it return
convert to this because accumulator
retain the iterator accumulate
accumulate
data and that's it
yeah we talked about this before so this
thing these three lines is equal to this
accumulation okay like we have a
built-in function okay okay let's review
okay let's talk about the subject today
which is the prefix sum for matching
which is a 2d remember we
yeah one dimensional okay don't touch it
it's shaking okay
the array is one dimensional right all
right one d
all right
2d what's 2d
2d
look 1d
1d a line 2d
a plan 3d you know we are living in a 3d
space right 3d yeah
z right look at one d
x
is a line 2d
x y
what's 3d
x
y and then there's a z i can't put it
here you know you you you put a you know
this is the key way yeah cubic 3d yeah
2d
square one d a line okay
yeah got it let's play basic so 2d magic
we have a 2d x and y
so look metric
zero one two
two one four
that is a three two one okay this is the
three times three matching
how many rows does it have
three yes the index will be zero one two
what's the how many columns does it have
three yeah three so zero one two the
index okay so we want to change this to
magic to
convert it to a prefix method what's a
prefix metric prefix sum matching
so all every element will be updated to
the sum of all elements from the top
left corner to itself well for example
like cll would be zero and here i want
to update this one would be one error
zero plus one okay and here look this is
the first row is the same as we talked
about the accumulated function right
eric look will be zero plus one plus two
right
and then took zero plus two
here
here will be the sum of these four
elements right zero plus one plus two
plus one and then four
will be the sum of all these six
elements okay and here will be zero plus
two plus three yeah
and then two
will be all these six elements right and
one will be all the nine elements that's
it yeah
ah okay
okay so how can we do this is there any
idea of honey
yeah i know
then how do we do this we can do what
yeah because these two yeah each element
right
right each element would be the sum
will contain the sum of the previous one
right so if we update the
if look for each row eric what happened
if for each row if i
do this accumulate thing like a perfect
sample of one d
right then i can do this look how can i
do this look zero one two yeah if i do
it two step the first one is i do this
for each row for each row i do that
accumulate can you tell me the for the
first one let's accumulate zero one two
zero
one and one
ten no no no two plus one three
okay two
two and then one
two plus one three yeah and then
two plus one plus four
seven all right
and three
three plus two
five
and
um
okay so now each row will be having this
perfect song right i know what's your
identity
[Music]
is that six survive to be bigger
yeah good good question this this is the
first step it's not yet finalized yeah
oh yeah i i'm just doing this for for
each row right containing the sum of the
previous one and then can you guess
what's next
um
can you tell guess what's next
come on if i do the rows and what
happened to the next column where the
hot colors we just don't need that so
each one i just do this yeah
correct
so how can can you tell me what's next
okay can you tell me what's next
it's yellow and antony what's that two
and what's next
five well done
one
what's next
four
nine we're done three
ten ten
sixteen okay let's just check ten is it
the same okay look zero plus one plus
two
three plus two
five plus one
six plus four
ten yeah you see we got this correct
let's check this again is it nine zero
plus one
two
one plus two three plus one
four plus three
seven plus two
nine okay yeah does it make sense so
first of all we do the rows accumulate
and we do the columns accumulate
simple
what's the term complexity for this
approach i will see what's r and c
right and columns we're done good job
okay let's do this it should be quick
okay
[Music]
you want more minutes right yeah and
then you'll be a good boy okay because i
want to play pokemon go
like an hour or more
yeah magic song okay let's do this from
scratch
let's do this um
the magic is empty then we just simply
return our empty yeah okay
okay
it's the same as yeah
[Music]
okay now let's do this
for each row right we want to do this
row right for r
in
for each row each row i can do this
accumulate right we can do this for c in
range for one two columns and then
matching
r c
[Music]
r
c minus one right and we also can do
this look magic
ah
equals least
so this one is better yeah okay
only all alternative look we can do this
for c in range start from one to columns
and then
ah
c plus equals matrix ah c minus one
right
this thing remember we talked about this
five minutes ago right okay then after
we do the rows we do the columns yeah so
r
for let's do for r in range
from the first row right from the second
we are not doing it from the first level
from the second row right from the
second row and then rows
and now we need to do this for columns
for c
in range
columns right
i want zoido
magic
r
c
plus equal matrix
[Music]
why do we need this metric uh remember
what's the advantage of using this
metric previous uh the follow one d we
want to calculate this we want to
calculate the sum between any range
you know in all
one constant term right for the matching
is the same thing look
one two if it is the area
[Music]
uh let's like this okay
let's just write some elements okay
okay so look if i want to get the sum
of these four elements all right
all right yes
if i want to get the sum of these four
elements what is the equal can we use
this
no no no yeah i know but how can we do
this how can we do it is it equal to
what are those x's
no no i'm talking look remember remember
i talked about this one plus one two
three four five six i want to calculate
the sum between three to four right
three three four five
equals to this sum minus this sum right
this is the same thing i want to
calculate this for anyway is it equal to
the sum of these
right
but i need to look at some of these and
then minus one
minus sum of
these
right and the minus this bit right
yeah
go ahead
this makes sense eric
uh
yeah so if i want to calculate this
fourth term i need to calculate i need
to minus
minus this repeater this will be this
stupid okay but usually you need you
want to get calculated minus one minus
this bit
then the sum of up to this point and
and know to minus this point at this
point okay
does it make sense
that's it for today
[Music]
that's what come on
[Applause]
bye bye