okay so we talked about the eight
experience of the club yeah
what's graph hey what's going on
um
[Music]
what's a cyclic means doesn't go all
around it doesn't have sights
can you give me an example of the dag
remember what kind of things
we have used before we have learned
before which is the daisy come on it's a
three three where down three is the bag
why because why is that gonna look blue
one two
three four yeah
it doesn't have errors but by default
you know the parents
you can travel from parents to the kids
yeah that's an error something can that
be an exercise
yeah look a cyclist doesn't have a graph
doesn't have science
from parents or kids yeah but how would
they get up again
good point we don't usually
remember remember the three notes we
define as this
so you know yeah
okay
value left yeah and then right
yeah this is the value for the note and
left points to the point left left left
note and right points the right note
look what does this mean eric
look the parent this parent can point to
left and right and for kids it doesn't
usually know what which parent right
but there's a way you can keep tracking
of this you know where it comes from
using this level search yeah by passing
down the current value okay
easy okay so
what have we talked about yesterday we
talked about this
yeah from zero look one
two
three
and then
here is this a tsg
is this a dag
come on is this a cycle
is this a cycle
look at
look at the arrows is this the cycle
[Music]
is this the side no come on you go least
but you cannot go back right so this is
this is a dad right directly a cyclist
aircraft it doesn't have cycling
look at the error yeah zero can go to
two but two can not go back to zero okay
so can you find the path between all the
parts between zeros and three
and zero one two three
so what have we used yesterday to to
implement these the agreement
yeah we talked about the differences
today we're talking about
culture yeah
[Music]
which you can
have you can have a pop pop
the both sides pop left poke
a plant left a pen okay so it's a cue
you can do operation perform operation
push and pop operation on the both sides
of the queue okay let's speak to you
uh can you can you tell me what's the dq
uh
uh what's the
what does the other ones need okay
what's the breakfast session
breakfast searching one two three five
six four seven
okay so let's implement this
okay it's right
first of all we need to find out the end
n is length of the graph okay graph is
defined as the adjacent link
list okay adjacent increase
minus one adjacent
that we we are finding the source
we are finding all the paths between
zero to n uh to m
and minus one okay so actually yeah
let's just do this to n minus one
so adjacent adjacent
adjacent increase
so g is adjacent into this what does
mean the the first element g zero
z zero what's d zero i mean
it mean look alright so what adjacent is
okay zero to one let's come let's let's
do this again okay uh two three
what adjacent is how do we represent
these adjacent needs of this graph d
allow
where is zero connected to
one two one and two okay and what's g g
one look g one what's what's one
connected to
one
sorry one is connected to one two two
let's see
what's g two are connected to
three yeah and then hey guys
and g3
area on two two three
ah
sorry there isn't a pointy thing yeah
yeah okay three points to nothing so
it's empty okay so look so see this is
adjacent is g okay
yeah you see the key
0 1 2 is the node and then it points to
a list which is has the nodes like it
connects to it yes this is
directions okay
so g and then in order to implement the
as we said uh we use the dq yeah let's
keep q equals dq
so what what parameters do we need to
we need to we stop we need to store the
number of the
the path the current path and we also
need to store the
to store the current node okay so at the
beginning
what do we what do we put in in it
what do we put in the area what's the
current now what we put in the tuber
yeah cuba remember the tuber what the
the tuber is the
contains the list of elements
yeah what's the difference between this
uh least
[Music]
what's the current
what's the first element to put where is
where do we start searching the path
from
um
from the beginning zero right and then
what's the path
n minus one no no no path will be at the
beginning will be zero right so it's a
list of uh this this is the current path
this is the source
so the tube tuber will be current
node okay and then the pass
plus okay so we we we just use the path
path is a list of the
a list of
nodes with integer and then this is the
integer okay
this has been
q okay
so
we put we have the initial note uh
so what do we do next we we need to have
the answer answer variable to store all
the elements all the paths right and
then
why why what
remember we talked about this breakfast
we need to find out if they are you know
what is the meaning of y cube well
there's an element
why is there something in the queue okay
and then we need to take the elements in
the front of key which is the current
node
and then that's a two player so we can
use the comma what's that what's this
path yeah
path
equals q y we want to take the
yes we want to take what's the
difference between pop and poplar
[Music]
poplar which direction we pop there okay
so we have a key
okay look one two three pop left what
happened
one is gone one is gone okay even
pop what happened
three is gone
yeah you see there's no top right okay
it's pop left and pop okay
yeah
because at least by default when you do
a pop from a list is from the right hand
side why
just by default the list the list here
is the list yeah it's a the list is like
a stack yeah
uh one two three
so look what is remaining then why can't
you turn the other side good point by
default this is one two three the list
is actually like that okay
[Music]
if you want to do this you can do this
if you want to take this take the first
element out of the list
remember we can still use pop but we
have to put we have to give a parameter
what we want to take this out pop it
whatever
hey
[Music]
no no you take this off pop one
remember there's a value i put here
yellow where then pops here okay if you
don't put the parameter you'll take the
last element okay
no no no left top left is only applied
to the heel but at least doesn't have a
problem okay yeah
different objects
different logic do you understand yeah
like uh
you can ride a horse the horse
the horse
horse has a right yeah
right master right
but a car doesn't have a right car we
have another method called drive you see
this is object oriented different
options have different methods
no no this is unless i talk about this
list
and dq there are different objects
that's why they have different they are
similar but they have different kinds of
methods okay it's like horse you can
only ride a horse and you can only drive
a car you cannot you can go you can walk
a horse yeah you cannot drive a horse
and you cannot ride the car okay okay so
okay coming back to this subject
coming back to the subject we've got the
current now we've got a path and then we
need to check if current node equals one
if current now equals the target which
is target
n
n minus one okay zero from the n minus
sign
okay minus one then we answer dot append
what we need to put this current what
come on
what's the part what's the answer answer
is the thought that mr pass and what
what's the
[Music]
what what what what's your opinion
what's your opinion
[Music]
and then
and then what happened
if we we do this and what should we do
what should we do what should we do what
should we do next
what should we do next
[Music]
which kind of note what's the word and
not what are the next note for next note
yeah next
[Music]
yeah we know this already
i know what should we do next
we should
we find the next note so we have we know
where it goes to next so we want to
build a path right
so
can you tell me what's right
what happened q q yeah we append into
the list in into a queue append
app and that's a keyword and the first
node is the next node which is what next
now
and the path will be updated into what
past plus plus a next note right we want
to give a next note this is the new path
right
correct
yeah
and there's one thing missing
whatever
two things
so it's least simpler than the different
search remember which one is simpler
the difference search you will implement
a concussion uh uh
remember we we need to
we we need to push and pop the
path right but for now we don't need uh
in the breakfast search we we just
update the path yeah we just push the
new path into the queue that's why we
don't need to push and pop
right
in the default search we need to push
push pushing a new node into the current
pass and now we call recursion we call
the current pass i call it a default
search
after we finish the default search we
need to pop
the note from the current pass to
restore it yeah to restore the state
where it was but for this one the
preference search will just update uh we
just push the note yeah the note and we
take it out from the queue and here
and we expand the next note which is uh
the next edges yeah and here is
anyone until we find the destination
which is n minus one what's the time
complexity this this is a bit tricky
because in the worst cases in the worst
cases what it's a directed
a cyclic link a cyclic one right so what
does it mean if you look it's yellow if
there are let's say that you fill our
finals okay cl can go to one two three
four yeah one two three four
okay
yeah one can go to one
one can go to
two three four okay
let's do this square
two three four
and two can go to one
three four
so you can go to four yeah so a
every node can go to the nodes which
have a larger value
to satisfy directly uncycling link yeah
so these how many know how many edges
one two three four five six seven eight
nine ten ten edges
there are five notes ten edges
yeah each one has two uh no look zero
zero one two four
plus
uh one two three seven so it's four plus
seven plus two plus one
yeah plus one
okay so let's turn 10 pages so they are
n when n is
when n is what and when n is five
is ten edges
so one n is six is what fifteen edges
right
is it right
we can totally we can do this again
maybe
uh
maybe two of
six
zero to
[Music]
let's write it in a tree okay zero one
two three four five
okay one could be one two three four
yeah
two three four five
okay so it's actually more than that
right look
okay so actually that this is not
entirely correct let's let's try this
again just four four edges zero can go
to
zero can go to one two three
one can go to two
three
two can go to three
yeah two can go to one two can go to
three
okay
so each node can go to the nodes that
have a larger value so by series by
series okay
uh by series it has the if i don't know
they will be have two
uh
two
n minus one okay roughly okay let's say
if it is the same at least n is four
four minus one is three two to the power
of three is eight one two three four
five six eight okay six seven seven okay
lovely
so let's the number of edges
and to build each one roughly it needs
the n right or n time
o n time so the compound connection is o
n times two to the power of n minus one
uh
is
10 it
the power of n minus 1 uh 2 to the power
n all right because 2 minus 1 times 2
okay
2 to the power n
2 to the power of n
minus 5 4
okay so the space complexity is is the
same as the time capacity because we
need and in worse cases you will need
you will need a
answer to store all the paths you have
to install the path
okay
any questions so far any questions
any questions so far
any questions
[Music]
yeah
um
okay i'm going to erase
okay i'm going to erase what
here
yeah this bit
this is the top bit
and then
and the next next okay two two things
here
can somebody help me
so you tell me what to do here
what do we know
what what do we want to do
so
karina so what what color now and
password
this is
equal as well
yeah so like because they're cute each
one you pop two elements kill the
problem right now
the first thing of best research is to
pop it from the front of the cube okay
and then here
we don't want to be aware
next night
[Music]
yeah plus plus
square okay
at least plus another is there next note
why we need a bracket here look if this
is this one two three
yeah we want to add another four to it
okay ryan this is a list
we want to add
it edit
so we can do this a plus one
a plus one
drag key four
okay okay look
this makes sense this is this everywhere
look
i want to add another element to it yeah
okay
oh you can look normally we can do this
a dot a pen right but 8.10 doesn't
return anything
yeah it often doesn't return anything
instead you will push the four into this
you'll change the value of a another way
is to add a
there's another keyword called extend
okay it's ten
and then you can give another list
okay four or five
something like that then you will become
okay can you tell me what what's next
it's ten four five what does it become
what's the a become
[Music]
yeah
you can count
concatenate
to list one two three four five and now
become one of the things we'll find
okay
okay that's it for today good job bye
bye bye