hello hello mr mr ryan are you right
yep okay so today we're going to talk
about uh an interesting uh data
structure okay so before we talk about a
new data structure what kind of data
structure have you learned so far
they have structure you know what's data
structure
what's data structure come on
um the thing is to
hold data so what kind of data structure
in computer science have you learned so
far you have learned quite a lot right
what are those can you give me an
example three
uh yes good job three is a data
structure what else
come on one you usually
stack way down when you're back
[Music]
the one we talked about yesterday you
know to
start with
g
g q is sticky
well done okay so these are our data
structure
set set or hash table yeah hash table
notebook yeah these are all the same
thing yeah yeah
set settings contains unique numbers
unique elements only hash table when we
talk about a table we have these keys
keys values key value pairs yeah
the the time why we need this
because we we want the constant time or
one time to look up the items
to check if the items exist in a table
and then it takes the one constant term
to put it
update the entrance in the table okay
and grab we talk about graph yes graph
these contains the vertex and then edges
it's a collection of the vertex and
edges
q stack yeah these are quite normal
three and the most important thing we
have least yeah at least
and list arrays
what else
link list yeah
linked list yeah english yeah we talk
about several problems around english
directional
english one direction
if it's two-dimensional we call it
doppler
doubly linguist okay two directional
police these are all graphs yeah you can
think about an english as a graph as
well right the graph
yeah dag yeah what's the energy
directing a solid graph yes yes directly
a cycle and it could be
undirected right yeah
it could be cycling as well and it could
be
yeah
okay so three yeah we call it yeah okay
if two trees what do we call it
yeah
foreign
uh today we're going to introduce a new
data structure
which is called
disjoint
set
okay
union
okay so sets okay so interesting this
this joint for example like this is
number zero one two three
so how many how many groups are there
how many groups
four four whether and if i tell you i
want to
i want to union these two and these two
becomes a group right and how many
groups are there
three yeah yeah okay so this is the
basic data structure so why is it useful
remember
remember we have these yeah
we want to find out if there is a path
between
remember a few days ago we talked about
it
we want to find out if there's a path
between zero
to five
right no yeah we use the
volcano algorithm
we have done two aggregates to solve
this problem to find out if there's a
path between
bitterness
we have uh we took between final parts
e6 in the graph right
yeah so what kind of agreement do we use
come on to travis the graph
to travel to the graph
what kind of algorithm do we use
[Music]
um
so for definition we find out if there
pass for purposes also we expand it in
the uh double ended queue and i will try
to
uh exhaust it all the nodes yeah before
we we find if if there's a path if
if it does pass we return to otherwise
we determine first so so to solve this
problem if we can consider this graph
you know as different
all right look at the beginning how many
notes
zero
one two three four five if this is five
notes okay
uh that's six notes all right
okay
so zero to one
these at the beginning these belongs to
different groups how many groups are
there
six six zero okay so i found the h zero
to one connected to the other one
so what does it mean
if there is an edge
zero and one belongs to the same group
right
yeah
so what do you mean i put it together
okay two zero to two what does it mean
i want to put the two in the same group
right
yeah
so same group
three to four
same group right three to five
same group
is zero and five belongs to the same
group
they're a different group so they are
not connected there's no path between
zero to five
is there a plus between zero to two yeah
why is that because they belong to the
same group
yeah that's why we use the strong set i
i'm just talking about
how how to solve that problem even
though this one is easier right
yeah it seems easier yeah i just you
know if i edge what does the edge means
these do not belong to the same group
right
and
it's now path between zero to four
because they are only different group
right
so this is very useful so
to solve this problem we need to
discharge that at the beginning each
note is different individual group
but when we have a
a function to call unite unite yeah is
it the way to correctly spell the word
merge to all we can to call it much
much
better
if we merge what is mean general one and
we
update the data structure to make them
make both
uh
belongs to the same group and we also
have another function called find
find parent
find group okay find group
so this will return a different group
yeah find a group of two right yeah
and we also have one
group count group
group count yeah to tell how many goals
are there at the end there are two right
and what else do we need uh what else do
we need
if it's a same group yeah belongs to
same group
so this is easier how do you implement
the same group two numbers
a and b
you just need to check if the group is
the same find group a equals to find
group b right if they are same group
they reproduce the group number okay so
what's group so at the beginning okay so
that's easy look how how can we do this
okay so first of all we have a parent
okay parent class let's define class
disjoint set okay let's try disjoint set
disjoint
set
okay so
at the beginning we want to have a
constructor remember how to construct
because in it
initially
and we're given a n n is the number of
the
at the beginning and the initial group
number okay if it is a
0 1
one two three four five so we just pass
one
six okay then you from zero to five
so that lets herself then we can
construct self the parent
parent equals least
range
n okay so in the beginning if any given
of six
six so the parent is a list list of zero
one two three four five
okay so what does it mean at the
beginning at the beginning zero one two
three four five
these six groups
these six
there are six group and the number is
the group id right
all right yeah
so how how can we make if if i want to
make a multi one and two
so what does it mean
i need to i need to change
right if i want to look one and two if i
want to merge these two what happens
so i just need to change this value to
one right
yeah then these two belongs to the same
group if i want to merge one three and
five i can change three to five or five
to three
right
yeah okay this is called a merge just to
change one the pair just change the
parent value of one note to and to a
value that's a good writing and
initially there are six group letter
group id these are guru ideas zero one
two three four five okay
okay
so now
save the parents
and then we need to find remember we
need to find what uh same group okay
that's same group same group
given two numbers a b how can we find if
the same group
how can we find investing group
tell me save the parent if they are
single what what happened save the
parent a and save the parent p what
happened what
what i love i mean if lesson group how
can we find the same group
we will
it should be i mean okay so there's
something missing here okay so look
yellow
uh
one
two right so if the same group at the
beginning
at the beginning we need to
have a function to find the parent of it
right to find the parents of it so how
can we find the parameter i give this
empty for for now so how can we find a
parent we need to have this fine parent
find parent function okay x let's find x
okay so so what does it mean what does
it mean look look
look at eric look if d at the beginning
this is zero and then zero will be point
two itself yeah and then if most one to
it one could be much here if we have
another two vertically yeah
three yeah so look
if three's parents if three belongs to
the two group or two two also becomes
school of one so these are all connected
right but how can i make sure at least i
want to get the value of zero the group
of zero because all these
three belongs to two two belongs to one
one belongs to zero it could be
there could be a link right so i need to
find out the parent of the x so how can
i say if
x not equals seventh apparent
okay seventh of parent x
if x equals seventh apparent x what does
this mean if at the beginning look
x equals ten separate x then this is the
group group
this is the parent of it right does it
make sense eric i i yeah that makes
sense
um
yeah
okay
look
everything
here is a look
if yellow right this is a good idea if
an elast right change here zero you know
i want to find the group of the parents
of the group of
zero clubs yellow is equal to zero let
me return here right
if look if this is zero and i want to
find the group of it
apparently it's not equal
right
so what does it equal
what does it equal look
um x is one right
x one is not equals to
zero right
yeah
third parent x is one it's not equal to
what so what happened what what's this
it should be zero right
so i need to do what i need to return
what find parent
save the parent x
yeah
yeah i just call it cell root save the
parent x
theta parenthesis is zero
yeah because the current is one
one
and then one is the same group as zero
so i want to find out the zero group so
i need to put this here so it could
because we call itself right
okay so that's what he here says look
zero
if if here is one
right
the second two is the same group as zero
and then two is the same group as one
right i want to find out the two the
group of two here
look i want to find out the group uh the
group
id of this one i need to find out
in order to find out the group of these
i need to find out the group of these in
order to find out the group of one i
need to find out the proof zero
and here
and here one and here the group of excel
equals
the zero the zero value equals the group
of
the parent of it right yeah got it
okay
yeah so that's why it says three
points to two two points to one
so
look
in the worst case right in the worst
case what's the term complexity of
looking at the parents of the
of of the elements yeah in the worst
case
or
oh and right now look if there are ten
yeah look it could be yeah
look if all these are connected
what happened if i want to find out
group of four
it points it says okay the group of four
is the same as group of three
okay the group of three is
two
is
right i need to follow the path right
yeah is there a way to make it
i mean better because i don't want to
query so many so in order to do this i
can can i need to compress compress the
path
compress the path so what is it the same
as what zero
one
two
three
four
right
which one is uh more efficient including
this one why is that it's at most one
yeah for you know i can't create it for
here zero zero points to the cell right
yeah this is the root right the group
root it's like a tree
right everybody got it
right and don't don't mess up with my
camera okay okay so how can we do this
how can we compress the trees
at the past
we just have to do one thing here
but we just have to do one thing here
eric
in order to compress the path
we will look it up
all right when we look it up look listen
listen otherwise i can continue when we
look it up
when we're looking on here
we want to point it out to four to let's
yellow right everything i i query up
when i clear it up the tree the past i
want to report the parents the group id
to the loot
right
okay got it so in order to do this we
just have to do two here
we just have to do is our
parent uh okay send the parent yes
parent
x
equals one
equals five parent
pie parent
uh
five parents
five parents uh parents
all right and then return
return what
reason one
return return
parent x is this currently snow i want
to point to the root and then this root
is recursively obtained from current x
uh five parent dot parent or x and then
our friendly return c of the parallax
okay
okay so so what happened here look four
points to three three points to two two
points to one one points to zero yeah
when i put it
no no no no when i put when i query
parent four
okay what it does is what parent four i
want to point to parent of three here
which is parent two parallel one and
paragraph so eventually this function
will do some parentheses so i will point
here
i will move this and i will be point
i will move this i will be point here
yeah so immediately you will become zero
one two
three four this is to call compress the
path yeah so that will reduce the
that will improve the complexity of the
finding the past five parents from on
roughly 201 constant time okay yeah
yeah when we clearly release we we
compress the path and this could be done
using interactivity okay not not
recursion how can we do this okay
everybody okay
uh define
find parent
first of all we want to find the parent
of x yeah so how can we do this
how can we do this
we want to follow up yeah so
we have this parent x equals x
y
p x not equals to x
what p x equals parent
okay apparently seven parentheses x
so now
p x naught equals x p x equals parent x
what's this mean what's this mean
what's this mean
three points to two points to one points
to zero what does it mean if x is three
what's the value of p x eric what's the
value of dx what's the value of px it is
yeah
all right look
p x is
x is three
why p x not equals x
p x is not equals three uh
yeah
okay so there's a problem p x equals uh
x y p x naught equals f of the parent
okay so here is let me say okay
y not equals to the parent x so because
look if if p x equals parent x what does
it mean if if a value x equals parent x
then x is the group right it's the root
right y is not the root
why this is not a root i go up i go up i
go out go up until i reach the root
which is zero it's pointing itself right
look alright
so eventually this px will be number
zero
all right
are you lost
okay so what's the value of ps
[Music]
yeah i know but when when x is three
so what's the parent what's the px after
this loop p s naught equals parallel x
pattern x is what
what's pattern x
yeah
2 is not equal to parent x
go here 0 is the parent x what's the
value of x
yeah so while
x not equals to p x
y x not equals to p x i want to compress
the load there so first of all i need to
do what
i need to do what
i need to have a value to save my value
equals
i want to save the value why
save the parent at current x i want this
this is the parent x value
and then i've had an x
parent x i want to shave to p x right
i know what x will be v equals to v
right
yeah
and then
finally i will i want to return the loop
which one is the root which value is the
root
come on
which one is the root we're trying to
find out
so here is that when we are not reaching
the
when we following these we
point this is to compress the path
parent x
i want to point to the px here yeah this
this is what i mean and like x will go
to the
b which is parallax
okay so this is the recursion version of
the previous one okay so once we have
this parent find parent yeah all right
we talk about fine parent and how can we
talk about uh check if the same group
come on
same group how can we check the same
group
a and b
how do we check if a and b belongs to
the sample
can you give me can you explain to me
not a coding can you explain to me how
do we check if a and b belongs to the
same group using which function yes
look yeah which function we talk look
what
most can you be more specific
with
sample what function have we talked
about
one minute ago
okay so if we find a parent if the
parent find parent value of a and b is
the same
is it belongs to the same group
yeah so look we can just do this we have
find
parents
a
and five
parent
b so what should i put here
what should i put here
five parent a and five planet b they
have to be
they have to to have to do one
to
if there are some group
ryan any questions
a and b belongs to the same girl what
does it mean
it means
belong to the same group
what they have to be equal or not
they have to be equal or not yeah yes
five pound a needs to be equals to five
parent feet in order to be in the same
group right
that makes sense right yeah yeah okay
so we have the same group and what have
we what now we'll talk about this much
okay how can we manage it
yeah okay that's fine merge a and b we
want to match that
can you not do it
can you not do it otherwise we have to
do it again okay
remember i talked about this before i
just have to assign one to another right
so in the in the best cases i if there
are two if there too first of all i have
to check yeah i have to check what the
group a
equals five parent yeah five parent
a
group b
equals five parent b
if group b
group a
equals group b what does it mean
they already in the same group do i need
to do anything else
no i just pretend right yeah
otherwise i i can do what i can do what
i can do what parent
okay
parent a equals parent equals b right
a equals one equals five parent b
uh
no the actual is good b
okay we we already have this group b
oh we can do this
parent b equals
what
pattern a equals group b or parent what
um
or what
come on we can do one of these one of
these one of these that's no great that
one of these pattern a
i can send it to group b or parent d i
can send it to guru hey okay yeah so
yeah it's the same yeah
yeah it's the same thing yeah
but
we want to improve this
why because look
look
which one is better if if they are
already too many if they are look okay
just imagine if this is a minion group a
group has a minion note right
yeah
and there's a group of just two notes
okay
yeah
and i want to merge these two notes two
groups
i want to match the two groups which one
is better moving this
which one is better eric
come on think about it this is a
question
okay i have a group a has a minion note
i have a group b which is just two notes
i want to merge these two groups
so
should i set these
the parent of these the root at the
beginning is pointer is that can i
should i set these to
these this is one way merge the b to a
or should i say least
like this is a loop to to to the root of
it which one is better b
b to a and and you
i think
you don't care okay b
actually
yeah this is oh any of these is okay but
it's better to make b to a yeah
yeah b to a i said i don't mind yeah
okay but i explained why merging the b
to a is better
can cannot tell me why imagine the b two
eight is better do you have that you're
less yeah
we want to merge the less
the size the set the group of less size
to the bigger size because in this case
we are not into we are not increasingly
over all parts right if if we move these
to here what happened to all these parts
that these will be more one more right
okay because i have a minion nose i need
to affect a minion pass
right if i
these note will be effective when i
could release these snow will be
affected remember yeah i want to shorten
the path i want to shorten the path
yeah i don't want i i want to compress
this part right by when this moves in
the bigger thicker set to the smaller
cell what happened
all these nodes will be affected
if i move this the smaller set to these
all these
majority of this path
will not be affected only it less okay
so in order to do this we need to we can
have these sizes okay we can have size
at the beginning equals uh one times n
right
we have a size of each group right
we have size of each screw and when we
merge it which first of all we check the
size which size which size is smaller
right we which size bigger we can we can
compare this if size a
if size a is smaller than if size b then
we merge the b uh
a to b otherwise we'll merge the b to a
right okay i'm not going to write it but
you understand this problem right we
want to merge the smaller size to the
bigger size and we updated the size size
x well self-doubt
size group a plus
equals sine square b all
set of the size group b plus equals
seven so size eight in this case we
always maintaining always merging the
set with smaller size into the bigger
one okay so when we
uh
when we when we merge the size yeah we
will merge the group what happened to
the uh
group
group count all right okay it's almost
going to be
complete okay so look
zero
one
two
three there are four groups okay
yeah
if i merge two groups how many groups
are there three if i move one one group
another another what happened to the
group count
every time i merge two individual
components what happened to the group of
total groups
minus two
now there are four groups i mean these
two how many goals
three yeah so why you said minus two
minus one minus one okay so i have i can
i can have two yeah yeah i can have a
connected count and every time i merge
it yeah in the merge function i if i if
they are not belonging to the same group
i merge it yeah i i mark working so what
happened to a good crop i can take the
coupon minus one right i can say the
groupon minus one and then i can have a
function i can have a function to to
yeah i can have a function to return the
number of groups okay so this is the
uh another function okay i think
i think this is okay so how many
functions for these two uh this joint
set
can you remember can you you don't need
to
uh you need don't need to remember the
implementation details for now but tell
me what kind of function do we need this
john said come on
find parent
i'll give you an example find parents of
a va of
element x
return answer 5 and what else come on
how many methods we have talked about
five parents and
what math yeah we want to merge two yeah
x and y and what
else what what else we want to find out
if they belongs to
come on
they belong to what
same same group belongs to the same
group okay same group
and what that what else
and we want to find out the number of
no the number of
no no number of
what happens if we merge two groups
no no no
find five parents we come in a five
parent we talk about a complex yes you
notice we only merge the group we talk
about much the smaller one to smaller
one to the bigger one yeah
same group same guru just calling the
fine parent to to find out if the five
parent x is the same as five percent
right but if i want to know
how many groups are there right
number of groups yeah how many of them
how can we implement this we just keep a
counter
number of groups yeah at the beginning
they are angles yeah you know in uh
at the beginning is their angles every
time we merge merge two things if they
don't belong the same group what
happened we minus minus minus equals one
yeah correct we minus equals one right
okay
okay so we talk about the disjoint uh
this concept okay let's go back to that
original problem okay and that's it
a graph
the graph
the edges we won't find out if there's
stuff like the path from start to end
okay
exists remember past exists and that's
the edges
edges
okay look
first of all i have a discharge set okay
let's say you dijon set d s equals
disjoint set
disjoint
set and there are n and edges yeah
n equals length
edges or whatever yeah
okay now for
star
and
in edges
so what happened here i have a start
remember at the beginning i talked about
zero to one there is an edge between
zero to one what happened what should i
do with these what should i do
considering the edges
at the beginning there are n edges and
not
and i found out if there edge between
zero to one what happened
d s dot what which which function we're
going to
make these two
come on we talk about a few functions
what
um
this is s this e
and we want to find out if there
any there's a lesser uh star
unless uh two yeah uh
[Music]
two okay so now we just need to find out
if there are paths between start two so
which function ds dot 1
ds 1
bcs dot
merge
we want to find out if there's a path
between
start 2 so for
this john said what what function should
we call
to find out if there are two elements
belongs to same group right
so this is same group
yeah
you see
so this one is it look
no no no wait wait wait
so remember before we use the definition
first buff we study strong set look how
simple it is yeah
the implementation is single right i'm
right 36 yeah do you understand
37 that's okay what's the time
complexity of the
digital set normally
which function which function yeah the
fine the file in the worst case if
you're not compressing the path the to
find the parent takes ln right but
usually if you compress the path in
practical uses it's not just one
constant right and then merge merge is
simple or one right we just assign one
to another right
because it fundamentally causes the fine
parents and then what
check check the same group yeah they're
calling the five parent
and
what else
nothing yeah nothing
okay so this is o n okay the time space
complexity is also o m because there are
n eighties no n notes and we n groups
yeah we need strong set to to store the
uh we have a list to store the number of
the
the groups for you for for for each note
right okay okay that's it for today good
job