[Music]
okay so today
we're going to talk about the how to
search
a value in a binary search tree so do
you still remember what's
binary tree or binary search tree
binary binary tree yeah
right each parent have animals two kids
this tree
like upside down this is the root this
is the leaf
yeah a leaf is leaf
the leaf is unknown without any children
right yeah how many goats can a
tree have one
yeah one that's the root and yeah and
then you can have many
leaves yeah this is like the tree yeah
okay and these are
this is a leaf this is also a leaf leaf
leaf this is
just a normal note it's not it's not a
leaf now
it's not a loot it's it's kind of
it's apparently of these two but it's a
kid
yeah remember this is their parents
but this is it's hit right
yeah so like eric
ryan daddy
yeah betty and grandma okay
grandparents yeah daddy and mommy
grandpa yeah
do you still remember the left nose are
always smaller than the parents the
right notes are always
bigger than the parents like this
is like 10 right and these will be
smaller that will be a and this will be
bigger nine
and this will be six maybe this will be
well maybe at least put it no this is 11
right
bigger than that and then this would be
nice something like that okay
right yeah smaller always smaller what
that one's flipping
right it doesn't matter as long as it's
smaller this is always smaller the less
notes are always smaller than the
parents
but right now it's always bigger than uh
uh bigger than the parents right but
look at this it's nice it's also smaller
than 10 right
so what does it mean it means that if we
want to search
9 we compare the root is it smaller
bigger
smaller so which way does it go
way it's smaller
nice smaller than 10. that way yeah so
it should be smaller
it should be somewhere here right it's
not bigger than eight
yes so it's somewhere in the right hand
street right because the right
children is always bigger than the
parents right
okay so this is the final
three so how how we search it we first
of all define the class
class three
yeah well what's missing here column
yeah and then we can define a
constructor and remember constructor
initialization and
we can have a this is the self and then
we have to
have a value right and then we can have
a left
and we can have a right
if we don't specify left and right we
can give it
a default parameter which is we can call
it left
you know left we can write left
equals num
it means if you don't specify a value
for
for left or right you will be
initialized to
nothing none okay so
then now we can have this self
dot value
equals value serve the
left equals left yeah and what's human
writing yes
left over right right
equals right yeah so that means that the
tree has three
three things one a dot yeah a three note
has one one value yeah
it has a value and you also have two
things to point to its
kids it could be nothing 24 is nothing
right
yeah because nothing
no so so it means that you can specify
the left
kids or like it right right yeah
okay so how can we search it
define for when we write and
yes it's like true or false true
for it's also it these these are called
special constants special constant
what do you got uh called the nouns
proper nouns yeah
yeah yeah pronouns yeah yeah proper noun
start with the capital
ryan i'm right ryan like ryan and eric
are special proper nurse yeah mandate
you say thursday that also proper now
start with
tea right they are constant new york
okay so search in the binary tree
let's call it search right and we take a
parameter root
this is the root of the tree eric do
double tree
and we want to search the value right
search the value we're searching for
values
yeah so how do you do this how do we do
this
yeah if if if the root is nothing if
it's
you giving me a number right then if
root
is number it's long look
if the root is numb we return first
means we can't find it right
all right yeah
okay then if the value
is smaller than root
top value right the value remember the
tree has the value yeah
so what do we do now if the look value
is smaller than this three remember
which is this
is a right the right one
now this is 10 we are looking for we are
looking for nine
the root the root is in ten then we go
to the left
okay so look return this is the magic
return
search we call the function
blue dot left right blue dot left we are
searching the left tree
with the value right so what do we do
we can read don't
write not yet because
yeah you're quite close remember we
haven't talked about when it's equal
right yeah so if value
equal equal to the value
return one value
now we already slide it we turn two of
us between two of us
okay i know what what was written here
return
no no yeah we we're talking about
smaller network
we don't write value
we're done you see so in this case we
always
you know when it's smaller we search the
left tree when it's
equal we can please we can move this
be right awesome oh good job good job
yeah
yeah my mistake yeah and then
this can go here as well right it
doesn't matter the the sequence
right if it's smaller we search the left
tray if it's
bigger we search the right way otherwise
it should be equal right
yeah then it's if it's equal then we
found it return true
uh if if we even find the rule
remember if this is the leaf node right
and it's still not equal to the value
then you will go
to leave no dot left or right leave
no dot left because leaf node does not
have
kids so leave no doubt left
or top right will be none right
i'm right yeah well and then you call
this function again and lose
is none what what happened to return
force false
you get it enough value gets propagated
and then you will return first this is
recursive do you understand
recursion yeah we talked about that on
the lesson one recursion
okay so we can also do this using
non-recursive method this will be
look will be something similar look why
yeah we're using the white root yeah
this is the root
okay this is the root we are here right
why root is not long right
it's not noun
while is not long now we compare e
is what value look equals
it doesn't matter a rule of value right
then what
what what we should do here
we found a value
return one two right yeah we found a
value
if value is smaller than root of value
what should we do now if it's smaller so
no no if it's smaller
go to the left look this is magic we we
can
we can do this blue equal loo
yeah we are done because after this we
still can't find the
value then it must not be in the
yeah in the tree right he looks like
that he looks like an e
do you get it it's easy yeah this is the
way to search
okay so the complexity
oh it's already been 11 minutes
every time i cut it in half yeah yeah
it's already been 11 minutes and 37
seconds
that's good five okay there's a special
case
look listen what what's the special okay
look this is good i mean
look look at if there are eight notes
right
or they are one two three four five six
seven notes
yeah and on average it needs the three
times right
one two three one two three one two
three one two three yeah
do you get it if there's seven notes o
log seven is approximately three yeah
approximately three
so it means it needs three hundred yeah
but how about
if this is called a highly balanced
finalist
tree means that but what what if a tree
is by balance
you know the balance you have balance it
means that
that at any level any number
left the minimum and the right uh the
three levels
the difference is smaller than one
that's called highly balanced
if this is not a balance look this is
not a balance tree
we don't have a left left kid we always
have the right kids
yeah do you get it this is not highly
but this is not
balance at all so what happens is still
a tree it just doesn't have left kit
yeah so it's like a list and if we want
to find the value
in the worst case we need to go through
seven times yeah and that
in that case this will be o and m right
if the value is here like if
we have one two three four five six you
are finding the seven
and the computer needs to go through
each list
the value and he needs the seven times
right this is not balance but
when we talk about a better binary
search tree we have to talk about
balance if it's balanced if we structure
like this
then it's o log n if if it if it's not
balanced
it's o n right does it make sense
yeah doesn't make sense okay good luck
good job today
oh yeah