hello
we're sitting on the bin
hello mister mr ryan how are you today
good good okay okay so remember we
talked about graph recently okay what's
graph a graph in the graph which is the
graph which is a tree
tree it's also a graph yeah data
structure and we can use it as a g
like that
what component does it have the graph
vertex energies v for vertex and e for
edges okay and they can have at least a
directional graph d-a-g d-a-g
directional a cyclic which doesn't have
cycles and
directly means that the
from a to b but not especially from b to
any okay so that's that and don't know
essentially yeah let's talk about this
directive graph okay so given the direct
graph okay uh
like look
one
and then
uh
two
three okay and then i have at least four
and then it's five
and six
okay
yeah
uh
so this is direct graph and okay so we
can have this weight you know the weight
w-e-i-g-s-t
weight associated for weight is the
association
line from four to six to eight
nine
not three to fight it'll make a pentagon
okay okay so what wait wait is like i
can have this i can have a different
weight for each ages i can label the
the cost for example like this
three
four and there is five two one okay so
what does it mean it means that from one
to two it takes
three seconds from one to two right yeah
maybe three second or three you know it
costs three three units
four parts for example or three seconds
four seconds can you listen to me right
now
okay second one to five
one to four okay one two four five
seconds and four to two
four to five
two seconds
four to six one second okay so you have
look at this number above the edges is
called weight okay you can
in real world it can mean something like
that
good point yeah yeah it's a tree yeah
three is kind of the d.i.g right yeah
we're talking about graph here yeah
three is kind of graph okay
that is a trait cag okay yeah it doesn't
look like this
it's a tree like root left right
[Music]
okay so the question is here the
question now we talk about a question
come on
given uh
given a star by like one given a star
equals one
okay we want to find out the maximum
time
for one
to deliver
all uh
you know to travel all up to all the
other notes
right yeah all right ryan can you listen
to me i'm playing with that okay your
own video okay come on
yeah yeah
yeah so
in this case what's the answer but one
we want to find out the distance between
the the shortest distance yeah so
let's start this decision for example if
i have another one one two three
let's uh let's a hundred okay that's
impossible no no no i'm talking about
100 seconds yeah okay so i'm so what's
the choppy distance between one two
three
um
go three four where that goes three four
this seven is is much faster than a
hundred no no it's possible in new york
i mean for example if there are lots of
traffic in this world right you know
yeah yeah and then the the gps the the
navigator
tell us that it's better to travel the
other road which is faster because
they're less traffic yeah okay
okay so the question
lights no no is no no no no no
okay
listen listen up um one
so we want to find out the maximum unit
okay so the first question is that we
want to find out the shortest distance
between one to each node okay
yeah or any nodes for example like four
to five is two and then if i can have uh
another one here
like seven here if this is zero
and this is zero what's the night time
oh zero point five zero point five it
takes how much what's the thirties
yeah
zero point
zero yeah exactly okay so given the png
a graph graph we also find out the
shortest distance between any two
any two okay we want to find out the
shortest pieces between any two uh
notes
so today we'll talk about this problem
right
yeah
because this is important to know that
if i want to give it a start i want to
find out the maximum you need to travel
all the nodes
from one
right
yeah
and then we can visualize it as the
shortest distance between one to every
other nodes
yeah and
you find the maximum right and sometimes
look if one doesn't reach seven
uh uh maybe ten here
right
i know but there's no path between one
to ten right so we return to minus one
okay in this case okay
10 is only its own so yeah
what's that
you mentioned uh your understanding is
that if if a node
one traveled to two
right
we know this cost us cost one
and if one travels to another any other
laws uh let's uh n
yeah if this is c2 and this is c3
right if c1 is smaller
if c2
plus c3 is smaller than c1
right yeah then we update the cost
from one to two with this update yeah
because this is not faster right
yeah we realize that
one thing no no no because we have a
weight we have weight you can you can
consider it as the time the cost
correct it's not a you know it's not a
geography distance it's the cost with
the cost okay
so
so we want to find out basically today's
project that we want to find out the
shortest distance between any two nodes
any two nodes okay
so how can we do it how can we do it
based on this if we update it
if we iterate all the nodes right all
the pairs
if we iterate all the all the pairs and
and we update the shortest path right
this yeah we updated something
if we find that
if we find a replacement while this is
working eric look
okay
why this is working i i i explained to
you okay can you listen to me look if
this is the path right this is the path
a question
a2
b
and then here would be c
okay so if if there there's another part
here influence there's a d and then
let's say e
okay
on
that i'm there all underwear okay
okay so we want to find out the shortest
season between d to e
okay if this is like a hundred this is
ten this is twenty
okay
yeah how about the d to a and b to e d
to a no no okay this this may be uh one
this is one okay
so look
look we can find out we can always
replace replace because a to b a to b it
costs the ultimate from 10 plus 20
instead of 100 right so we can always
replace the overall plus d to e to w
with this bit yeah so the ultimate path
will be d a a c c b e right it's much
better than d a a b b e all right yeah
yeah if i replace it with this and even
later i found out if there's another
part called the g
which is 5 5 and then i can update the
path the whole path with this one right
yeah with this one yeah one d a a g g b
e you see so we keep updating this until
we found the yeah the past the shortest
participation
got it yeah so if there are n
no vertex here we're talking about today
we want to find out the 30 statement
between any two vertex
in a graph
yeah in the graph
okay so the extension if if we
okay let us do this okay define
uh shortest distance okay shortest
distance
that's a graph okay and then we have a n
and any
number of vertices okay
uh
so first of all we want to have a uh
have a distance
distance distance array distance
if we use the distance
a two dimensional array a b
what does this mean
means the shortest distance between a to
b
the note takes the vertex a to vertex b
okay we use this one this is the two
dimension right two dimensional a list
of lists right so how can we do this
at the beginning we initialize this to
what's the biggest number you can think
[Music]
infinity okay so look it will be
mass
dot infinity
for what we do in math and we
range and right
now this is the least and then four
in range area this is a
uh
range n so this is the
this gives the this distance
to the dimensional ray which is which we
can visualize it as look the distance
this one one what does it mean
one two okay so it's the vertex one two
vertex two
the distance the short resistance okay
so can you tell me that uh
if
if what's the value of this like zero
zero
what should i give it like one one so
this this
a a
what's your should we
assign the values to it but now let's
see what is the distance between the
node to itself
okay so zero to one
okay zero to one this is
one okay and what's the distance between
zero to zero
come on what's the value what's the
what's the value that we should give
initialize to zero to one one yeah zero
zero yeah because it costs nothing to
you're already there yeah it costs zero
we're done so so
so what should we do
for i
in range
n right
yeah and then what what we do this i i
equals one
this is
come on this is from the distance
between eyes and the vertex eye to
vertex i i
you just said it before zero okay
okay so this look how this matrix okay
this magic will be something like that
if layer look array yeah if there is a
two dimensional right if n is like a
four let's do it as four okay if n
equals four so this is give a magic what
can you feel that magic
this iii so
this diagonal will be zero right
and what's what's other variables
what's other
values the other values come on what's
the aloe vera we initialize too
where's one what what do you mean
four
no n equals four so this is four times
four metric
and i i is zero and what's allah's value
come on
infinity infinity yeah so all these
values infinity yeah very big okay you
know how to represent the infinity in
mathematics
in mathematics you know how to
represent infinity what's the symbol
yeah yeah yeah look number a by
horizontal this is infinity yeah ryan
yeah if you look it that way it's a but
if you put it horizontally means
infinity
and beyond okay infinity the largest
number
okay is infinity okay infinity
okay
okay so we have this the magic right so
this i to i for example what's this
value mean
what's this environment
no no no what's this value if this is uh
okay if this is one
what does it mean
if this is one what does it mean
the second row
first column
so how do we lose zen in here is this
zero one
[Music]
zero so what does it mean this value
what does it mean
the distance between which two nodes are
one
come on
the distance between
one and zero is one right
three do you understand yeah this is
what i mean okay another one
what's the if this is two what does it
mean
this
zero one
and what's this zero one two
what does it mean if this is two what
does it mean
if this is two what does the mean what
do we want
the distance between which two nouns
one and two that's it yeah so this time
a b means that
the shortest distance between
a to b is here right correct that's what
it means
okay so now given these
so
what else we just need to
do this for k
in
range
n
okay so another another for 4
i
in
range
and this is easy to understand later
okay and then another four j in
range
and
so what's the time complexity if we
drive the three loops
what's the time complexity if we write
the three rows
so
sorry
oh
this is n this is n this is o and three
yeah o and q b
okay i will keep it okay
okay so we we we given this graph okay
but we haven't this graph uh
a to b
and then wait okay so first of all we
need to update this okay
so i write here we forgot here
okay
is that for
a
b
weight in g
for a b y in g and then we update this
distance
a
b equals weight okay
yeah this is the up uh to handling the
up uh
uh
handling the input all right hey
g
for a b that's the from the vertex a to
vertex b
cos the w right so we put it in this
magic yeah we put it in this measure a
to b w okay so now
look
if
okay so look if the note okay this is i
node yeah this is i node
and this is j node
right what's the what's the distance
between what's the current distance
between i to j how can we represent it
all right how can we represent it
how can we represent that
okay ryan come on what's the distance
between i to j
will be the minimum of what if this if
we found another one this i to j okay
right here
but if we found this k here
yeah
this is k here
if we found this what's the distance
between uh for i to k and k to j
come on
we know the i to j current a i to j is
this
i say right
yeah
what's the distance between i to k
this i k right
what's the distance between k to z
okay today yeah this casey
so
so how can i write this if this is a
is
look if this ik
look if this ik plus this kj come on
it's smaller than what we have
[Music]
yeah if this bit plus this bit is more
than any speed so we update this bit to
this b plus this b correct
yeah
so we can write using the mean so what
should i put here is this what
i k
plus
t square
j is bigger than
i to k and plus k to j so
j yeah that's it so look we use the mean
function but it's the same as look is
this is similar as one if this
if this i k plus this k k j is smaller
than this i j what does it mean it means
that we can use this path to replace the
the path between i to j right that's why
exactly what they mean okay
and the distance between
if we given a star the distance the
distance between after this the distance
the shortest distance between zero
to all the nodes will be in this is in
in this this zero okay that's it
zero one zero two zero okay what's the
time complexity for this one have you
mentioned have we mentioned
oh and
what what's the time complexity
oh and q okay okay what's the state
space complexity
oh
are we using any space
oh are we using any space what's this
this is two dimensional how many if n is
four nodes how many remember we talked
about this we have this what's that this
space if n is four you have how many or
one
i'm using any space come on what if n is
four how many units are there how many
so what's left it's n square oh n square
come on yeah i want the square
okay
yeah
okay i'm going to erase this bit okay
y
that's it
i'm going to
do this
oh and yeah this is all okay so what's
this
so this is i
to j we want to up we want to update i
to j but now it's a k if there is a path
i to k
i to k k to j
okay so can you tell me what to write
alright can you tell me what's right
come on can you tell me what to write
this one
huh
what
no no no there are four four four what's
this here i want to upgrade i to j i to
j
so
this
i j
equals one
yes
we want to find the minimum of these
yeah so minimum
of this i say yeah we want to keep
updating the value and then what what
what
what paths
should we compare to i j i j what will
pass to your competitor
what parts will come
what has given us
i to
k
plus one
yeah so is this
i k
plus this
what
k
k 2 y
okay yeah well that's it good job today
good job today okay
got it so this is the 30th part okay and
then if we want to find
find the maximum from
we have a star here okay s here then we
can return what maximum
g
uh this
this star okay star okay if this is not
minus one okay if this is or if this is
not max infinity
max infinity if it's max infinity what
does it mean
it means what does it mean if we if this
i
this if the value in this i j
is infinity what does it mean
every line
after this program if we steal the value
still my stock infinity what does it
mean
what does it mean
come on what does it mean if
the value is next to infinity
come on i mentioned this at the
beginning if
the value is still master infinity what
does it mean
it means that
there's
is there a path between
there is no path right if there is no
path then the value will be still
master infinity because if let's pass
right anything compares to master
infinity will be
will be updated right right if it's not
updated if it's not updated because the
the value at the beginning yeah except
this time node
it said this time all other values are
messed up infinity if this value is not
updated what does it mean there is no
path between
the two vertex right you can separate
right so you will not be updated so and
lastly will be the master infinity okay
okay that's it for today good job
say bye bye