hello mr eric mr ryan how are you
what's final research tree can you tell
me what's funny
numbers yes and on the left of the root
it's smaller and on the right of the
root it's bigger
yeah okay so the only
the left tree the notes on the left tree
are strictly smaller than the parents
and on the other side the right the
downs on the right tree are strictly
bigger than a
parent which which order which order
gives you know you know the least in
order if we travel the final stage 3 in
which order and we get
to get the
list in order the sequence in order yeah
which order is it
i give a few sorry
we are done in order which is two three
four so it is what this is now this is
leveraged right so it's l and r okay in
order okay
and which order gives the reverse order
gives the four
rn
ah and there this is called reversing
order okay you can't reverse enough
okay so today's task is very simple
given that finally substring we want to
find out of n naught and not and not
i know
one label one to n yeah one to n
one to n
and we want to
we we want
the the the
in order of these finances gives that
one to n you know in sorted order okay
this is very important right
so if there's one one one note
how many ways can we construct the
binary search tree
if there's one note one
it's just one yeah if it's two notes
two
so yeah like that one
two and what else
t one two one so two is the root yeah
yeah one
right two
n is one you give the one order n is two
you have two and how about n equals
three
your leg is wet n equals three how many
um do you want to give us draw a few you
two want to come you know draw a few now
come on
come on just imagine how many ways can
you draw here
one n equals three and equals three
please please ryan
you wanna have dada
yeah okay
okay okay if you're not drawing can you
sit down
if you want to have girl
yeah that's one way that's good that's
good that's good
what else one three two and then come on
three one two okay can you enjoy it come
free
one
two
okay one two uh
one two three yeah well done this is
hard to get okay one two three okay
three and any more
anymore
anymore this is perfect perfect
one yeah
um
wait yeah keep drawing here one is in
the middle that's right yeah okay
okay one i like you cannot have nothing
smaller than one right so one
and then two
and then we're still you probably no we
have this right
no no no this is not vanessa street
because left is big
yeah go here that's right
okay yeah okay another one uh do you
have to have more
do you have more this is the same as
this one what do we have more
do we have more keep sinking
we're done yes one two three okay yes
okay two go backstage yes that's perfect
one two three one two one
three four five five pounds yes
so if i tell you later i can group
the at least two
these two belongs the same and these two
belongs to the same
you know
i can group this and these two and this
one can you tell me on what basis i call
please and the ring
yes because this is the root of two this
is root of these two out of one and
these two a lot of three okay
okay let's see go back go back no
no drawing nothing come on
okay that's it that's it
go back sleep girl
so and when n equals three we got a five
answer yes five the answer equals five
so how how do we i mean do you have any
idea how to become
we can't using a counter using the calls
based on what how do we count
[Music]
dynamic programming but yeah we use the
anime program but you need to tell me
how
yeah but we first we need to find out
the way to compute the value okay to
compute based on the number of loads
yeah yeah
okay
so okay so if if you notice let's do it
ryan
ryan it's not funny
this belongs
can we focus now
okay so
let's define a g function g n
g function
g n means the number of ways we can
represent okay this is not gone the
number of ways would represent these the
number of uh financial
unique financial tree with endnote okay
this is the answer we are going to
look for okay
yeah
the answer we're going to look for okay
so now
g n is the number of unique
uh
this is the answer we're going to look
for okay so um
we define another function f i n means
that if there are n nodes and if we
place the i as the root
okay
if we place the i as the root here
is that n knows so can you tell me first
question is how many notes if i prefer
the i in the root how many notes on the
left-hand side
um
i
minus
one yeah and how many nodes are on the
right hand side
like if they are unknowns
n
minus
i
so f i n
is it equal to g
i minus y
and g
n minus i so
is it plus or multiple multiple multiple
yes because look these two are
independent yeah the combination should
be multiplied together so this is the
function and then
uh
g n
there are n notes and how many ways i
can put the i i put a
uh put a note uh
you know how many how many possibilities
can we choose to place the root note if
there are unknowns
how many if that and if i have three
notes how many how many different ways
we can put the dude
come on that's an easy question
no no i mean the root three yes okay so
look this because each each node can be
chosen as the loot right so this way we
can say
is what
s
f1 n plus f2 n plus t t of s and n right
yeah
yeah simple yeah so this one
we can use the mathematics symbol to
simplify look yeah this one
we can do it as this symbol look
remember we talked about this symbol
yeah like e for the opposite of e
right
this one yeah opposite of e this one
will be
i equals 1 to n
s
i
n right so look f 1 n plus f 2 n plus s
3 and plus t of f and then e course
equals this yeah
sum this leaves us some
sum of f i n where i is from i plus i
equals 1 to n right
correct so this is look so look if we
use this one substitute these two here
so what do we get so we can just do this
so g
g n equals sum of i equals 1 to n
g
i minus 1 times g
n minus i okay so this is the function
we get dynamic programming function
what's the g zero
c zero equals one g zero equals
g zero and g one equals one
yeah the face cases look t t1 is one
yeah
okay so look these labels are from one
to n if i
yeah
okay okay can you yeah
okay okay let's go
[Music]
back okay
n equals g so
minor if i uh if we we
shift this n right because if we label
this as 0 to n minus 1 right if we label
it and then this would be
g
i and n minus i minus one and this is
the same thing yeah if we shift this
okay g i times g n minus i minus one
okay
so we can implement this function using
dynamic programming how many ways we can
implement this come on how many ways we
can implement this function
[Music]
how many ways we can implement a dynamic
programming function
[Music]
top down
using cash on top down
okay so look remember this f n what's
this f1 equals fn minus 1 plus sn minus
two what's this can you tell me f zero
equals zero f one equals one can you
tell me what's this
can you tell me what's this
fibonacci number yeah so look fibonacci
number
let's say if i want to calculate f4 we
need to know which two values f3 and
f3 in order to calculate f3 we need to
know which value f1 and f2 f2 and f1
okay keep going look so look at this f2
f2 are calculated multiple times so if
we're using this top down
take the top down we need to use the
time uh
top dial use the recursion but in order
to avoid calculating please over and
over okay what keyword should we give to
the fountain
come on you just moved it
you just loaded
what do you mean
we need to give what what what key was
should we label the function
so we don't calculate it
yeah minimization and in this case which
he was
grow
come on it's there somewhere on the ball
come on cash exactly
so you're wrong why
so f2 is once calculated we save it so
next time look if f4 we're not
calculated at all we know f2 and then
when we get to f3 we need f2 again so in
do we need to kick in release f2 again
no because we already catch over here so
instead we just look it up
in a notebook which is for cash yeah
let's define the cash yeah you can
implement the cash by yourself right in
the function you can check if n is in
the notebook
then if we see no book we just return
the one the entry in the notebook and
before we retain the function we save
the value in the notebook yeah like f
and equals
the notebook and equals fn and return
notebook n okay
and the button yeah bottom up is what we
calculated as zero and now we catch it
f1 and based on the previous two values
we calculated f2 f3f24 until we reach fn
right
okay so now
now let's leave them on
the
this function
[Music]
define
okay i'm going to
okay okay sorry i'll do it you're gonna
catch you okay
ryan can you not you didn't drop down my
belly defy yeah let's wait don't define
g
n right so if n
equal zero
and equal equal 1 we tend
what's the base case of value which is 1
1 okay then we need to start i look in
python we have this sum function right
some function one two three four what
does the time
return
yeah you can take as many parameters as
well and we can also supply it with a
list
one two three four what does it give us
what does it give us 10 10 is the same
okay so now we want to sum
return
sum
remember g
i
times g
n minus i minus 1 for
i
in range
n okay
that's it yeah that's it this is so
simple the most difficult part is that
we
analyze the problem and come up with
this formula all right formula what's
the time complexity for this one
square
can you tell me what
oh square is correct can you tell me
what's one square how would we get that
um
i didn't say it
well that square is correct i didn't say
it what did you say yeah yeah yeah ryan
what why is our n square
because
how many
yeah because we need to calculate n
values the g value how many g values we
calculate they are n right
and for each one we need to give a loop
so let's n g n squared and n squared
what's our space complexity n
yeah we're done why
how many n values are we how many
sorry
one o n is correct why is it ln
how many g values do we need to
calculate one
two um one
y is one sorry
g n and value because we're using cash
we want to calculate the g zero g one
zero we need to at most we will store
the
n value that's why we have we we call it
gn okay
right okay now we we do this uh
butter up okay
define
uh
again let's call it gn okay
for the butter we need to store the
values in in a what in the um
in the list yes so let's call it uh
let's just call it something full okay
g
equals what do you mean
yeah i just
come up with a random number zero times
and
minus one right
what does this mean what does this mean
whatever what's this mean it means
number zero times n plus one how what
does this mean
what's it
[Music]
it means that um
zero times n plus one is zero
no no no no it's if this i talked about
this before remember this this is the
list of n plus one element so each one
is zero yeah that's the least yeah i
meant that yeah okay
so now the first one is g zero equals
one
g zero
um
g one g zero equals one
what value what value i'm giving it
one one yes
now we just need to iterate for i in
range
[Music]
m plus one and then
i now i is the
the number of nodes the number of nodes
yeah and then four
for j
in range range i
range i
so now we can say g
j plus equals uh no no no g i plus
equals gj
times g
what i minus j minus one okay
so it's a bit harder to understand in
this case
yeah because but
look i i
in the loop the first loop is the number
of the notes the number of notes and the
second loop is saying that which which
load which is going to be the root okay
which is going to be the loop so gi the
answer of gi would be equals to one
i place the gj and then i price this is
the formula right and then finally i
return return gn right this is uh an
answer we're looking for what's the time
complexity if you're looking this for
loop come on
how many for loops
um
so what's the terminal
roughly one square divided by two
because the j the second inner loop j
goes to up to n it doesn't go go to n
right go to the i it doesn't go to the
end so it's roughly and square divided
by two of our job constant okay what's
the space complexity here
come on it's very easy
all right you see so the butter up
if we look at the code the butter up we
can easily see that space and time
complexity yeah because it is easier to
understand but for the top down we are
using recursion so you need to think
about it right but
both solutions give the same
time complexity and space complexity
okay
yeah
okay so this is pretty much the today
but today we're going to talk about
uh actually this is a very interesting
mathematical problem and the answer is
in is called catalan look this is new
okay catalan
exactly
is
used i mean its answer for to this
question and many other similar problems
okay so what's canon numbers so
continuous numbers okay let's call it g
g n equals 1 equals
equals m plus 1 1 c 2 n c it might be
right so m
what's this c function remember
what's this function c what's this c
combination yeah i mean y and listen to
me it's quite easy
what's this c function remember we
talked about the cn c and p remember
combination permutation c
if i want to pick
three apples you want i only pick two
apples out of three apples how many ways
two two three no no no one if i want
that three two three apples i want to
pick two apples how many ways three
three
it's the same as three three one right
it's the same as picking one apples out
of three because look every time you
pick two apples you also
have a solution for picking one apples
right so this is c2n times n let's let's
let's check this if
g g3 okay t3 is equal to three plus one
and c
two times three and three okay so what's
this under four times one
c six
three what's this number six times five
times four and three times two times one
and then we have a four
okay so these
cancel out
these cancel out look what do we have
now look eric look
come on yeah
what's the answer of this
g3 will be equals to five look we just
cancel out everything except the five so
this is the catenal numbers okay n plus
one c two and n
and then it has the recursion uh
depending on the previous one g n plus
one
equals equals one equals the
two
2 m plus 2
and 2
n
g
and i i think it's it i'm not sure i
have to check it out
i have to look it up
n plus 2 2 n plus 1 n plus 2 okay sorry
m plus 2 to n plus 1 ok
ok
so um
so that would be if you know if if we
have this function
let's implement it in next lesson okay
this is the catalog numbers okay
let's implement in less than one next
lesson it'll be
quite interesting okay so today
we talk about is the number of unique uh
binary search trees given these notes
okay yeah
yeah
let's repeat the numbers okay that's it
for today good job