hello mr area all right
okay so today we talked about the final
three okay i i will draw a binary okay
here ten
five
ten
two
three
so this is the parameter and how many
ways if we want to remove one edge from
from this manager
how many ways
right
um
four
four four edges four possibilities so
what happens if i remove one edge what
happened what do you get what do we get
two threes we remove one edge yeah we
move one edge
one add two trees
two threes
you have financing what uh
if it's too balanced you what do we also
call it
what do we also call it
forest forest yeah okay
this is a concept so if i removed one
edges and we want to find out if it's
possible that for the these two binary
trees to have the same
uh
total sum okay
so for example in this case if i remove
this edge what happened the sum of these
15 15 and the sum of these
15 yeah yeah okay if it's not possible
just to move
for example this is a thousand then
apparently it's not possible then we
just return false
okay so given the final entry do we
still remember how do we calculate sum
in the recursion the definition remember
define the sum
yeah the definition sum definitely if
this is the load okay so it's very easy
right right can you tell me if not load
if load is empty what happened what
should we pretend
some return one
is empty what's the sum what's the sum
of the empty
come on it's nothing nothing what was
your return the sum the sum of the z
yeah yeah come on otherwise
yeah therefore search what
and look this is a tree
yeah this is a tree
this is a see any and uh i don't i don't
care all right again this is a tree it
has the left tree at y 3
and if it's not empty
the sum of all of these
equals 1
equals root of value
is this one plus
what's this b what's the sum of this
thing
no no no it's not my research here i'm
talking about
now i want to calculate the sum of this
financing right if it's empty i return
zero which is the base cases
if it's not zero auntie and it equals
the sum of these bit
yeah which is 10 yeah
hey look at me
and what's this bit what's this bit
recursion what's this bit and what's
this plus one
plus or plus one
um
[Music]
what do the left
come on what do you thought
that message because we're calling
itself to to solve to get the sum of the
left tree yeah and then definitely
search blue dot right right
right
and then return as yeah this is the
we have we have used this before to
compute this
the sum
yeah the sum of the binary tree we have
final tree
using the recursion data search right
okay so if i
put it if i put the sum okay so based on
this
let's let's
do this uh tree again
so if i have a scene which is stores the
number of
the sum the sum we have seen so far okay
so
what do you think it will contain the
scene
uh if i put it here
sim
dot append
a plan s what do you think what what we
get what do we think what we get pay
attention come on
if this s
return s what's this as this is the sum
of any
of any sub trees any subtree including
itself in this manner yeah and we want
to be called we want to remember sim dot
append we want to push the sum to this
so
how many such trees are there how many
subtrees
how many three subtrees are there
five
what are the subtrees two yeah this is
subject
three
and what else
ten
there's why isn't ten sub trees
including the left three and y three
because look s is the root of value plus
the sum of that tree and sum of right
tree right
right so two three is a sub tree ten
plus two plus five three yeah this is a
sub tree yeah you cannot you need to
pick all its
children right descendants right
so this is fifteen and what's the
subtree of this one
thirty and what's the subtree any out of
searching
is this a sub 35
yeah
okay so after this we've got this right
and we do want to remove the uh 30 30 is
actually the last one because when you
do this recursion the last last
which value is the last s if which value
is the last edge
i append this so if i call tfs root what
do you think what do you think
what's the last value of s
dfs boot
what does dfs rule return
[Music]
the sum of the whole tree right and the
sum of the whole tree cinder append s so
the last element would be the sum of
whole tree which is 30 right yes
am i right
what is the minus 5
no no okay okay so look this is 90
and what's the half of it it is
that's right okay so look this whole
tree the sum is 30. and if i split into
two and if they're equal what's if they
are equal what's the sum of that half
and the
yeah i know that's 30.
now i know what let's i know these is
sin
minus one right
right i know this is as thin rather if i
divide it by two
i mean
what's the sum what's the sum if i
divide by two if not two both threes are
equal
um
divided by 215 right if i get rid of
these
and
and i want to know
if there's a tree if the number
in the rest
which is equal to half of 30.
correct
yeah if it is then we find a solution
got it doesn't make sense
yeah then you know about the other ones
what do you mean the other one
[Music]
five and ten
and 10. yeah how about that yeah yeah
yeah look 5 and 10. this is 15 how do we
get 15
it's 10 plus 2 plus 3
right
and then
you cannot pick 10 and 5 to get you need
to pick 10 if you lace the left tree you
need to pick it and it lets you in right
three you need to pick it that's why i
look s equals root of value plus the
left three plus the right three the sum
sum of left three and the sum right
three you need to the whole sub tree you
cannot
you cannot just pick these two and we
ignore the right sub tree right because
it's there and then we we append all the
possible subtree sums into s
right and the last one is the sub tree
it's the sum of all every node
if we do this uh s look if these
let's do this step search and then stop
pop
right if we if do a t equals left s dot
power
x the problem we remove the last one
which is the sum of all sub 3 right
and then we just need to find out if the
rest if t
divided by 2 yeah and we look if t
divided by two in in what in this scene
right
correct
if it's in the scene
if we have everything in the c it means
that we can find a way to split the
planetary into half and both have the
same the equal sum
okay
okay doesn't make sense
what's the time complexity
um
yeah because we we need to visit what
every other every note yeah what's a
space complexity
[Music]
yeah why is that
yeah we a good job
and also we smell the stack yeah stack
recursion okay
okay
okay can you explain to me how what's
the how what's how do we solve this just
make sure you understand
yeah
yeah and
[Music]
say sorry yes okay
be quiet
yes
um
we're just adding olive
and we're just doing all of the subtrees
substitute sums into the scene yeah and
you know the
deficit root yeah
then you just divide it by two and say
it if it's yeah yeah if it's in the
if there's a sub tree sum which equals
to half of the total sub trees what does
it mean
what does it mean
it means yeah it's true there's a way to
split to split to remove one x split the
final three into half right and then we
can find out the subtree sum right yeah
because this this method is quite
elegant right it's quite elegant
otherwise
sorry it's all really beautiful
beautiful yeah good job beautiful egg
yeah yeah good job look at this we
already know this right but i mean maybe
100 days ago we already learned the
recursion to compute the sum of a binary
tree right 100 days a day probably you
know look base case is empty within zero
otherwise what's the sum
the sum of these nodes and then we do
curse recording the solving the left
tree and right here and put it together
return s all we need to do all we do
today
scene
and we'll put all the possible sum sub
three sums into the scene and the last
one would be the sum of all the notes
with the movie speed
and we compute the half of it right if
it's half of it if half of it is in
this in the uh in the list then
there's a way to split it into
easy the countdown
because we visited all the notes the
space somewhere because we use the theme
we use that stack yeah okay that's it
for today good job bye