hello
hello mr evie someone all right
yeah
okay so we talk about a
graph problem today graph what's graph
g yeah what's going on what does it have
how do we represent a graph
what do we have for graph actually
no no i'm saying is the graph in text
and vertex and edges yeah it's a
collection of vertex and edges
so let's use the vertex like look zero
one
and then two here look at this is the
graph a tree is also a graph
so look if the graph doesn't have these
errors yeah it doesn't have errors we
call it
what
we call it what graph if we have errors
we call it directional graph yeah
remember
direction of god do you still remember
d-a-g
yeah what's the
girls energy what's a cyclic name it
doesn't go
like around the world
it doesn't have it's not like that right
if it's a graph is that one zero one two
zero two one one two two two one and it
forms a cycle that's the side but the
cycle is it doesn't have something like
that okay
so we given today we talk about this
graph which is undirectional which means
that you know it's bi-directional you
can do it as bi-directional
know is uh let's say if zero is
connected to one one is also connected
to zero so let's save a friend okay
friends yellow is
friends your friend zero is
is uh has a friend one
yeah the mutual if i'm friend with you
you're also my friend right you're my
friend and i'm your friend right here is
friend of one one is also a friend of
jill
one is friend of two two is friend of
one so can you tell me in these uh these
three people
at least each for each people
and these own at least one friend right
yeah you see two of us this statement
everybody has at least one friend in
this one yeah yeah okay and how about it
zero to one
uh
and two
everybody is everybody having one at
least one friend right no which one
doesn't have one edition two yeah
obviously okay so
what's your thoughts i mean remember a
few days ago we talked about a data
structure what what is it called
set this joint set yeah this joint says
so what can we do with the disjoint set
we what can we do with patients remember
we use that digion set to to do what to
solve this problem to finding if there's
a path between a source to the target
right so look
one two zero one two and then three four
we want to find out if there's a path
remember from zero to four
right so we create a disjoint set and
every time there's an edge what do we do
we merge the
we merge zero and one into one group
right all right
and then it's the last edge between one
to two we merge it yeah and if there's a
path between three to four we merge it
right we merge it into one group and at
least at last we check if the source and
the target belongs to the same group
right we don't stand saying if it's not
belongs to same group what does it mean
it means that there's a path between the
source to attack otherwise it's
it's not possible right because
disconnected look there's no path
between zero to four right because it's
connected so can we use this digion set
to solve this problem
it's quite similar but
very
i mean
there's something very
uh slightly different
so eric look so what's your thought can
we use the distro set
so what is john said we can merge we can
merge two vertex
most of our we can check if two vertex
belongs to the same group right
yeah
and we can find we can check if the the
connected group the group sound the
number of groups yeah the number of
groups
we can get this and what else yeah
yeah we can find a parent
find a group number for five kilometer
five group which group it belongs to all
right
so
can we use this for to solve this
problem
any idea what's your thoughts
what what's your thinking
how do we find out if only if everybody
has at least one friend
at least one friend right
so at least one friend we can think
about at least one edge yeah
okay
so
what's your song any idea
i think it's something
don't worry just uh think about uh just
talk about what's your sauce any sauce
how is something
you don't have sauce so can we use these
dishes
yes
if you don't have any sauce what's the
first thing you need to check
source b
b
the question the question is to ask
if everybody has at least one friend so
we just need to go through everybody
right oh yeah and then check if it has
one friend right
oh yeah so how do we check if everyone's
friends so if we process this graph
into a
headset right we can just use a hashtag
uh uh
to store these the what key is that
remember key is the vertex
vertex and the value
is a list
of edges it points to right
x is equal to list of vertex okay vertex
is connected to
so if we pre-process these edges into
this adjacent linked list we call
adjacent inputs then we check we go
through each we go through each vertex
right
and then check
and then check what and i check if it's
if the list the size is more than one
right if it's no more than one if it's
yellow what does it mean it doesn't have
any connection to other people right
right yeah so remember if we give you
this zero to one you need to also
pre-process this one to zero okay and
then you go through the each one and
then let's say the time conduct stays
over if the end vertex what's the term
complexity
what's the time complexity
of our m square
oh well it's going through each vertex
but how do we check if there's a
connection or no we just check need to
check the length of
yeah this is a one so all n times a one
equals one
yeah okay that's one solution that's
root four thing it's good enough yeah
but we'll talk about using this this
joint set how do we pitch again
if we
it
it's fine
yeah it's fine
yeah here is more solutions there so
this shows that we create the distance
that we merge it yeah we merge it like
that right but look we're not checking
this group right we are not checking the
same group right
we are not checking the look this is two
group right
yeah
but how about this this two group you
need to tell me is true is false because
two doesn't have any friend how about is
zero to one
and then one to two uh two to three
you see
still two groups but at least everybody
has at least one friend you see
right
okay so so this is the
this is irrelevant to the group right
number of groups so how can we do this
no no no we need to find out the parent
the group
so if we find all the group the groups
for each vertex and then
look
how many groups how many groups does it
belongs to
[Music]
two right two look this is one if this
group one
group a right a a b b
okay so what does this mean so you see
every
uh the group number needs to be at least
at least
two right
and how about this even if he's
4 here i know this is group c c
only appears once right so if we can do
this
we can find we can put it in the counter
right and we cop we just
we just check the values
the key is the goal number the value is
the number of times the number of vertex
it belongs to right if
uh if the value is one what does it mean
if the word value is one what does it
mean there is only one friend there's a
friend which doesn't have any friends
right
that's why the girl number is one
because there's no other friend who
shares the same group okay so let's do
this
it should be very easy right let's say
define
uh check okay let's just call it
function full
uh
let's just call it g
uh maybe edges
okay so this john said this is
okay and then we do is what
for a b
in ts
a is a friend of b so we do this ts dot
or which function is it
come on
right
so now we call this look
zero to one look look at me two and
three again come on turn around please
let's look
zero to one one two two three there are
two groups right but we want to find out
the group number and put it in the
counter right so look what
uh let's say g
equals counter
counter
uh
ps
uh group five group okay let's go find
group
five group
i
right
this is the final group for each one and
for
i
in range and right in range m that's it
okay so now i just need to check return
minimum
g dot values
what d w
come on
g dot value is the number of
number of vertex that
that has have the same group so if it's
if it's uh
if we are saying if you're saying that
at least everybody has at least one
friend so what's this
the minimum the g dot value needs to be
what
at least two so it's bigger than one or
l is two bigger yeah
okay
yeah you see this is the way we're using
the
this joint set to solve this problem uh
but we can do it better right because
look
02 is the friend of one and so these two
cannot be the answer right uh cannot be
the the friend who doesn't have any
friend any friend right
okay
so what we can allocate a pulling array
a boolean pulling what's putting can you
tell
we talked about this before
it has two values put in
t
and f once this
come on
what's this
that's what it means binary true of yeah
it's the binary yes finally
so we have a boolean variable variable
and at the beginning they all initialize
to false
right and if you look 0 is a friend of
one so what do we do we set that zero to
two
we set a one to two
if two is fine or three what do we do
we say
the two and then the two yeah
we just need to check this array to see
if it has a
fourth right
okay yeah
okay let's do this
[Music]
okay
okay so look so look uh let's say just
uh what do we call we call it theta okay
theta equals
force
times n what does it mean first times n
sorry
come on times multiply for the value
multiple n times what does it mean
there's a list
with all fours how many fours are there
and easy yeah look at look at one times
three what is what does it become
one one one right yeah
yeah easy yeah okay so and how about
this
a b c
times two what is it what do we get
a b c a b
a b c we're done yeah you see this
multiple is very powerful okay
uh so we have this force and then what
do we do for
a b in edges yeah
and then what should we do this a is
friend with b so what should we do theta
theta
dot theta one theta is array theta
d tower
um
a is in front of b look a is the front
of b at the beginning f for sloth
remember we talked about
yeah a equals
two
two okay
theta
b equals one
okay so actually you can write we write
it into one line look you can write this
one theta a equals theta b
equals two right
okay so now we have a way with this way
okay so how can we how can we check
easily what
if there's a two values in in in here
how do we check if there's uh only one
kind of value here how do we check
um
so how do we check if there is uh
uh
okay so
how do we check if there's a two a laser
force in there
so look if if everybody is true right so
we want to check if there's a force here
so one way is that for i in
theta
if
not i
if i right if not i
if not i return four right
return first otherwise would be ten two
yeah this is what easy way yeah you go
through each variables in your data and
check it with false if uh if it's false
if it's still false then we determine uh
return force right all right it's
written true right yeah we want to find
out that what's
new it means to
when it's true it means that all of our
values in data is true right so how
about we can do this here we can just
say
return
data look we can use this data.com
count force
we need to say count force equal equals
zero okay
so what does it mean you will go through
the data to check that to count how many
m how many values are equal to force
right and this value needs to be zero
right great what's the time complexity
what's the space complexity what's the
space
ow what's a space commission
come on are we using any space here
how are you seeing any space here
yeah because there should be
no condo which should be lowercase okay
it took one millisecond yeah the cost
would be lowercase okay because
the computer take one
millisecond because
it's really fast okay let's say for
today good job
good job say bye to people bye bye
bye