hello hello mr mr ryan are you all right
yes okay so
we have what's fine entry
well
five let's say five six one is it a
binary
yes okay is this a pregnancy
no okay it doesn't have cycles yeah it
doesn't have a cycle there
well what's dng by the way remember we
talked about this
direction
directive a
cyclic lock okay so look if i have this
one to two
and two to three it has in this
direction but it doesn't form cycle and
how well is if i point point here does
it have tigers
one two yeah yeah you can say so we talk
about the binary tree
so how many subtrees are there how many
subtrees are there what's subject um
oh there are three what are else
six five what next six six one five six
one
five six one right yeah
what's the average how do we calculate
average
[Music]
plus eleven numbers
okay sum divided by
okay we're done so in order to calculate
everything we want to calculate the sum
and the count what's the value of this
one this subtree six
what's the average of this one what's
this four
how do you get it for six plus one
good job
given the binary tree we want to find
out the
maximum subtree average we want to know
this maximum substrate average
which is which one
which is which one come on which value
is it what's this
four yeah which one is bigger six yeah
so we find out that
okay okay so
do you still remember how we calculate
the sum of uh the sum first of all we
want to know the sum of of the sub tree
sub sub tree of three yeah final three
sub uh binary energy
we will use the recursion remember
root
and first of all we need to for the
recursion usually we need to check the
basic
base cases if loot is num or
or not
return what's the sum of it
what what's the zero nothing nothing
right if i want to return two numbers
what kind of data structure can you use
in python what kind of data structure
no no no data structure we want to we
can this is written a single value we
call it singular
how about we want to return we return
two numbers two numbers three numbers
even all you know more what's the three
in the forest
what's the
data structure we're going to use to
store
to store two numbers for example what
kind of data structure can you propose
to store two numbers
you can use the dq or the the simplest
one i mean or you can use the notebook
but i'm talking about starting just put
two numbers together just return instead
of writing one number i want to return
two numbers come on
wait is it
people
yeah this is this this is okay what's
tupa
it's immutable immutable
immutable
change immutable
this yeah
okay so not the way
even two numbers the first one is the
sum the second one is the count right
this makes sense if it's empty we return
nothing
there's no vertex there's no note okay
okay so in order to calculate the sum of
the
the sum and the count for this for this
function we want to return two things
one is the sum
one is the sum the other one is the
count right
so look if this is the root
and if i i have some tree here i don't
care and i have some tree here i don't
care which is this is to do the left
and this is noodle right
so how do we solve these two how to get
a together
yeah recursion that's what we call so
first of all we want to say some
left
and look because it returned two number
another count
count the left
equals definite search what
[Music]
because we're calling itself we have to
return two values and then you can tell
me what was that sum what
right yeah i know what
come on
okay so now we have
we have less sum of left and we have a
sum of right we have a count of left we
have count of right now what's the if i
put a
max average here if i have a max average
here
at the beginning we set it to zero so if
we have max everything here and
what's the
what's the sum what's the sum of the
this this binary tree what's the sum of
this planetary it will be
well s equals one some left
yeah plus one
plus one
somewhat
the three will be the level the sum of
the the entire binary tree will be the
sum left plus sum right plus one
[Music]
how many nodes are for this for this
tree
come on
come on come on you can get it
this is the sum and i want to know the
count
which is what come on count count the
left
and plus
plus one
this is called them what's this
yeah come right we already returned here
here and plus one
come on this is the number of notes in
the left three this is the right number
of notes in the right way and how many
notes are here alone one yeah plus one
okay
and now we have the sum we have account
so average max average
max average
equals max of what two things
that's f is equals to two things
max of what
we want to store the maximum of the
average
s right
[Music]
by c and then what's this what's the
second parameter
yeah max average okay
and then we want to return return one as
i said
the first one is what
acupuncture
this is the sum this is the count so
what do we return here
come on which one is the sum
which one is the sum the sum of these
whole three dude which one is the sum is
there
well
it's there come on which one is the sum
count
which one is sum s look sum
and what's the second parameter c c easy
yeah so looking can you put them around
no because the
because look if you put that around you
need to swap these two right you see
good point yeah but because therefore
search you call itself then you will
return to number
five we are assuming the first one is
the sum the second one is the count so
that's why we put the sum left count
some left if i swap it if i swap it put
the c and s you can see and as what you
write what should we change
um some left with count left and some
so we need to swap these two count left
some left
count right some right right
yeah you see this is returning the tuple
and i i use this a b equal look what's
it remember this syntax a dot b equals
two and three so what's a what's the
value of a what's the value of b
two a is two and b is three exactly yeah
you see exactly what's the term
complexity
what's the space complexity
yeah we need to know the question using
the step okay
so now i'm going to erase
[Music]
i'm just going to erase these two lines
these two okay just
yeah
remember
s and c what's smg
well i don't
come only s what's the sum of this note
it's there what's the sum and what's the
count come on
center front
some left some left plus
some right
and one plus
[Music]
yeah okay
you need to explain this okay otherwise
it wouldn't compare
i'm just lazy i need to write some left
some right are you lazy
because i'm your daddy okay
okay that's it for today good job
bye bye bye