hello mister i already missed the wine
are you right
yeah
we talk about island thingy november
island
we use the deficits to cloud the number
of islands right and we use the
definition to count to return the
maximum size of the island right these
two are similar we use this devil search
today we're going to solve another
island problem
is
given a two dimensional yeah two
dimensional two-dimensional metric one
is island a lamp
zero is what
water yeah you see okay so if i do this
one one
zero zero okay then one one one one one
one
and then one zero that's such a big
matter okay i'm just going to do
something okay
i think
yeah
you know it's not really
it is uneven
why are
okay
okay so this one is the length yellow is
water and how many lens are there there
like so many
one two three three seven
[Music]
yeah
i like a million islands no no no just
this look look at this why is the minion
you can count how many
uh actually here yeah
you didn't recognize that
okay
yeah
so how many minutes one two three four
five six six okay so we we we want to
know the surrounding island okay what's
the surrounding surrounding
surrounding island means that the island
needs to completely be surrounded by
zeros
all right it needs to be in
surrounded by zero so which ones are
completely surrounded by zero and the
first one the two one
why is this one no no no
no no no which one
one two three this one right some
completely
zero right not why is that
there isn't one here
that's fine it's not horizontal but look
it cannot completely we only consider
the horizontal like that yeah
that's fine and even here
look at this one
it is completely surrounded okay we only
considering the horizontal and vertical
we don't consider this thing no okay so
only this one i'll do the round okay
just listen to me
yeah i'm talking about this this one and
this one and but not this one yeah
because there's no water here and
there's no water here okay so in this
case return to
yeah make sense
if it's on the border
it's not the island we're looking for
because if it's on the border there's
something here that you can imagine this
this is not wrong houses
sorry
houses
okay houses yeah maybe houses maybe
houses houses
okay
got it
yeah yeah yeah what's the houses all the
football peach okay
all the
all the trees your furries yeah got it
so you don't know what's beyond these
beyond these okay
any idea how we're solving this any idea
any idea what's this
any idea
come on come on that's it okay that's it
any idea how is hormones well
we don't do we don't look at the islands
on people
yeah that's good good we don't look at
the islands on the border yeah so how do
we do this remember before we want to
count the differences right we only
count the number of islands including a
border right
so
how do we do it we just
we just go through each one if it's one
we do the definition and we plus one
right okay
so you delete all
how about how about if i do the
differences starting from the border if
it's an island
right and then mark this as zero and
then we can do this
[Music]
how about this island yeah yeah look i'm
i'm what i'm going to do is i'm going to
start with the border look further yeah
if it's one i do the definition i mark
it as zero
right here i mark it as zero here i
start here i mark it all zero
and then we just go through these ones
and count the rest that's right yeah do
you get it do you get this
yeah this is what we started doing the
different search for the picture for the
island
right
yeah
and after that look at all the
islands they're connected to the border
all the islands connected to the border
are marked as zeros
and what's not the second step we
already know yeah we start from then we
go through each pixel and if it's either
we do the different search and equipment
counter
easy okay that's a duty
did you just bring something daddy yeah
what about you
yeah okay i'm talking about it here
because it's a bit long okay so that was
bf card island called cows around the
island yes
magic okay
if
it's not magic if this given is empty if
the emt will return how many come on
yeah because there's nothing here
and then first of all i need to get the
rows and columns they are rows
columns
because lens and why are you writing so
small yeah lens and then
okay
[Music]
can you not touch my things please okay
he has so many money
[Music]
yeah okay so now what should we do now
what should we do now
we should define the deficit function
let's do it define define the first
search and then we have what we have
these rows and columns right yeah all
right
okay
look at me
so how can we check if this r and c's
within the border
okay so what's the what's the value
range of ah
what's the value range of c the rows
what's the value range of r
belongs to
start from zero to one
yeah yeah yeah look
what's the difference between these and
these
what does it mean this is r belongs to
zero to that's the range lower bar upper
bound but i use the square bracket and i
just put the things here can you guess
what's the difference can you sit down
why are you so busy ryan
no no no mutable is in there this is
inclusive this is exclusive it means
that you can have r equals to 0 but you
can't have r equals to rows so what's
the maximum value of r
what's the maximum right if it comes
with rows
none of the maximum
the maximum r is what i said i just say
it can't be rows so what's the maximum
no no no leave here come on cielo to r
rose what it can't be wrong so what's
the biggest number that can't be rose
um
rose wha
roy
yeah
okay and then these columns what's the
range it's the same zero two columns
so what's the maximum of c
columns
columns are it can't be equal to columns
so yes
column minus one minus one okay okay
so if it's out of range look
if r
is smaller than zero or c is smaller
than zero or
r
equal rows or bigger equal rows
or c bigger or equal columns what should
we do we just return here because it's
out of range right we're doing with the
first search so now i just need to make
this pixel at rc equals to then to zero
right
so m
ah c equals zero right
okay so now at this point so what should
we do we we need to do the definition in
fourth direction right
okay so calorie therefore search
r plus one c
that's what search
rc plus one can you tell me what's next
that's my search what
um
now the r plus one c r c plus one and
then what what is r minus one c
right and therefore wait what do you
mean oh yeah i was about to say what's d
r
what s
minus one yeah is it enough right look
at this at this point it's rc yeah i'm
here at this point
so what's what's r plus one c r plus one
c is here right
look at this here
rc plus one ah c plus one is here
r minus one c is
here
ah c minus one
yeah right so it's four direction yeah
yeah you can do this in four direction i
just do this in four direction
but we look
you you can do a loop yeah you can just
do this
for
c x
b y in inward what's the x what's d y
yeah good point it's just the two
variables to define the the opposite
yeah different
look
zero minus one
minus one zero
zero one
and then one zero yeah in four direction
and then
to what
d f s
r plus d x look and then c plus d y you
see so you can transfer this to this
because look look at this this is a
tuper
with
with four vectors for empty
the opposite of rows the offset of
columns right can you look at me yes
yeah okay
if i do this and then
this is the default search okay i'm
going to write this here a little bit
oh
are smaller than zero or c smaller than
zero or c bigger than equal rows or row
r bigger or equal
this is what what does this mean out of
range yeah out of
because then range
ic is out of the board and then i mark
it as visited i mark it as the zero mark
it as
water okay
right i want to definitely i want to
mark it what and then this one going
through four directions yeah going into
four direction
okay
okay so this is different search and now
i just need to travel the border how do
you travel the border if this look how
this is the
this is the magic and i i told you like
how to use travel how do you visit it
this
how do you how do you get the pictures
in the border
how do you get
i can go through each pixel and check if
it's on the bottom right how do you
check everything about that
i can do this for
ah
range no no no range rows yeah
and for
c in range
columns yeah
okay if you want if i equals zero yeah
if this one is i equals zero right look
look at this
this is i equals zero right
oh
what's this what's this law
what's this this is i equals zero and
what's
r equals
rose minus one yeah
and oh what's this what's this
[Music]
what's it
in the corner then i do this therefore
search
rc right
so in a border like if it
if in the border i do the definition but
it's better you put it here if if m
ah c right if it's the length you do the
difference right if it's not a length i
don't know the difference here if this
is one i do the difference right what's
the term complexity in this one if
there's a two loop here
oh
also sometimes
there are two
square
un square all you are rows rows times
columns okay it's better to be exact
yeah lowers the terms columns can we do
can we do better in just this bit can we
do better
yeah
can we do better do we need to visit any
of these in the middle
do we need to go through anything in the
middle because it's not bothered good
job it's not bother so we can just skip
it right we can turn this into two for
loop
so for
r in
range
rows right look
range rows
so
rook r is from zero to rows so what what
should i do i should just do this
massage
what's the column of this one
um
[Music]
yeah yeah look at i is from the rose
and i also need to do this right what's
the column
um
yeah
look because i'm i i iterate the r
color minus one you see okay so and now
i need to iterate these two right so
look for c in range
columns yeah
d f s
so what's this one what's the row of
this one what's the row number of this
one
what's your row number of the first one
what's the rules of this one
r minus rows minus one c
you see these turn into this these two
four so what's the time complexity of
this one if i don't
don't consider the the content of that
so
so what's the time complexity of these
these two this equine and this aggregate
yeah ignoring the default search okay
what's the time consumption this is all
asian what's this
this is
ah
and this is c so so what you are putting
in the middle
there are two four loops
separate independent plus yeah where
there you see you do this and two lists
so it starts together but this one is
what you do this for each one of these
you do this so it's multiplied yeah
make sense which one is better r
of course r plus three okay good job
okay so yeah we're going back it's a
different search right now we mark all
uh all all the land connected with
border into zero and now what should we
do next we just have to
go through
we just have to go through what
goes through the middle yeah therefore
search
goes to the middle um
for
are in range
what goes to the middle do i do we need
to go through that board again
do we need to go to the ball again now
right so what's your output here
rose if you put the rows what happened
it's the same you will start from zero
to
rows minus one right do i need to
consider do we need to consider the zero
and rows minus one
no so what should i put what should i do
list here
range one
sorry one yeah and then what's the
second parameter
um
[Music]
rows
minus
minus 1 because at the beginning
remember
range
up to 10 not including 10 right so i
need to minus 1 only right because this
is yeah this this means what uh if i
arrange what 2 10 this is this is the
same as
yeah you see square bracket
inclusive
point of this what
exclusive yeah do you know inclusive and
exclusive what does this mean
what does these two what's the
difference between i think one of them
is that inclusion
and believing one of them is
above the six under
no inclusion means that contains it
exclusive that does not contain it okay
so 210 means that
210 how
how many how many integers are in this
range
can you list the numbers
yeah inclusive detail i just say
okay so
what number is that between this range
the integer
i know two
three four five six seven eight nine
ten
inclusive that's what i'm saying yeah
this is the number okay
okay
uh we want to put the answer here
for the lens yeah the lens is not
connecting the robot here for c in range
what happens
yeah
and then
what
[Music]
right yeah
and then we need to implement one
ingredient
you need to increment
which one come on
um
look if it's here one yeah if it's an
answer plus what
one yeah
okay and then just needs to return
until
what's the time complexity
[Music]
um
why can you tell me why well why can't
you tell me well
because each each pixel is visited
exactly how many times i'll say
no no there are times the pixels and i'm
saying each pixel is on
constant time so that's all i see yeah
got it
okay so can you tell me how do we do
this just
you don't need to write the code just
tell me how do you what do you learn
today if you want to find a if you want
to find
uh
the
what
if you want to find the number of
surrounded island which is only this one
right yeah so how do we compute how do
we call the number of surroundings
okay i'm gonna break this
but
we first of all start doing the theft
search and mark the length as zero by
following the border right yeah
okay and then oh look after this uh look
what happens if i do the difference
which two bits will become zero
[Music]
these two okay and then i start in like
in the middle one yeah
yeah yeah i start from the middle one
yeah i only start here pixel five pixel
and if it's one
i do the different session mark
connected pieces to zlo and then i do
the
increment answer right and pretend the
answer okay the time complexity because
each pixel is divisive
a constant of time okay that's it for
today good job bye bye