hello hello mr all right
okay so today we are talking about the
longest
zero
sublist
sum
so what's sublist
um the continuous thing the continual
thing okay so one two three how many
sublease
wait can you give me example of the
service one
two
three
one two
two three
one display
is one three a service
no
[Music]
but it's a subsequent right you got it
yeah it's not continuous we have
something is a continue okay so given
now today's class is simple given that
num at least which is only
one containing one and minus one okay
and one minus one
we want to find out the longest
sublet which has the sum zero
so in this case what's the longest
service
one minus one minus one minus come on
it's very obvious all of it oh yeah add
it together how about this if these and
you need to tell me it's six yeah that
means six
and how about it only has one what's the
longest surface
zero because you can't find it there's
no minus one it can't be
good job
okay so now
what's
your approach we want to find the length
of longest what's your approach
um
how do we prove how do we pull first
how do we pull first
blue false yes we're done two false
two first
so we want to check the service can we
blue force all the surface and then
check the sun right
all right okay so let's do this
define
longest
service
lungs
at the beginning we want to have this
answer answer equals one
what's the answer
and will be equals to the lens right
there's a number
okay so for
let's do the left left
will be i right i in range
and yeah i i will be from left to here
and then when i is determined we want to
start with j for
j in range one
when you are come on i is here j will be
from here to the end right
so v one
[Music]
okay so now inj is the index
of the sub list from the leftmost and
the rightmost so how do we calculate the
sum what's
how do we
what's the subject the subject with nums
nouns i to
um
do we need to press one yeah so we can
use the sum function right
how do we calculate ourselves if sum
equal equal equals zero
and we want to update the answer answer
equals max max y
and
what's the length between i to j
what's the length how many integers
between i to j
two to four how many integers
three how do you get three
um
200 to
331 how many integers
including
in curve
okay
what's the how many individuals
how many integers between i to j if both
are inclusive
um
j
minus five
plus one yeah four minus two plus one
okay so here
j minus i plus one
and then return
what's the time complexity
[Music]
it where's that look
for
one end
in order to iterate this and loop we
need to iterate another end loops
but look there's no n oh and there's no
loop here why is come on
okay so look
we can improve this proof of thing yeah
we still we see approvals in the past
but
instead of every time we sum we
calculate the sum of the sub is from the
star
we can do some you know we can
accumulate the answer for
what is that look one
two three four
we we are now computing the sublease sum
of these
yeah which is what eric
which is what
which is three right
and on the j we move to the next one
alright look
j we move next one to here so what's the
subject sum of this new array one two
three
six yeah
how do you get a six
how do you get the six
well you already know this is three yeah
it's three plus three
right
you use we use the three you are not
doing this with one plus two plus me
again you're not doing this again right
the previous method is slow because
you will be calculating this speed again
but
we don't need to be calculated again
because here we all already know is
three so
we add a new we add a new number to the
surface
we just
accumulate the answer so
here
we put the x equals zero
and what should i do here
what should i do here
[Music]
what should i do here s plus equals one
and then if x equals zero
x plus equals one
number
j is here every time i i have j moves to
new numbers i edit it yeah what's the
time capacity for this one
[Music]
n square whether so which one is better
now
[Music]
yeah we need to improve yeah
okay so this is on cubic on square these
two are both proof of things because we
are trying every possible uh possible
surface yeah we
we first determine the left and then we
start right yeah and then we compare the
sum of these the subjects
do you still remember the basic sum
prefix sum
look eric look one two three four five
six seven eight
nine
what's the sum between three to six
um
eighteen
eighteen you're just taking it yeah yeah
i didn't
three plus four plus five five six yeah
this is one way which is all
okay and then how do you get it
ah okay okay so that's what i'm going to
take what's the thank you brexit if
you're calculating this blue forcing
just try you know adding the numbers
from the left from a given range
come on what's the time complexity if i
give you a range and i want to kick it i
want you to calculate some of this range
what what's the thumbnail velocity
oh and yeah because in the worst case it
would be n numbers yeah you need to do
it again and again but we can turn this
into the
previous sum remember remember this
accumulator accumulate function this is
a for example and then accumulate a this
accumulate a
accumulate yeah
what's the accumulator mean
accumulating you know i think together
accumulate yeah putting together so this
accumulate a will be what will be
one
one plus two three
one plus two plus three
six
ten
yeah
and then 15 i think together 21 21 s7
36 45
the sum of these four
is it the sum between
how many numbers this four number yeah
the sum of this whole number is it the
same as the sum of
of these
six numbers yeah
yeah this 21 is the first six numbers
and then minus the sum of the first two
numbers right
correct
yeah
the first number is 21. the first two
numbers is three
so what's that
eighteen right is it eighteen three plus
four seven seven plus five two of two
plus six eighteen what's the term
complexity is this is given they
accumulate this prefix sum is given
yeah because we we just need to look at
the tables look at this preview exam
pick these numbers pick this number
subtract and we got the answer this is
better right this is faster right
yeah because we are using the numbers
we're using the arrays uh the numbers
the the sum we have calculate we have no
one right
okay so now based on this prefix now we
can actually
we can actually uh solve this problem in
o n right
so how do we solve this we can actually
uh
going through these numbers
and then if the sum we remember the
prefix sum in the dictionary
right
yeah we remember that this uh prefix
term in addition and if it's already
appear
then we can we can substitute the
distance and then
we
store the maximum and if not then we put
it in a hash table okay so let's do this
define
okay let's call it full okay
you know computer full and bar yeah foo
by in case you don't know what how to
rename your functions your variable you
can always give this to them yeah so and
by it's easy it's easy to write it's
easy to pronounce right
yeah
okay
okay so now we will put it in this
addition the prefix sound let's say
prefix
prefix equal at the beginning we put it
in a different dictionary
uh not in a dictionary okay but i'm
going to put a 0 here a minus 1 i'll
show you why i put a 0 to minus 1. so
look for
the answer would be 0 right
the answer will be 0.
okay okay come on four
let's do it what's in your remember
enumerate how do you spell in your life
how do you say numero
e n u m u re uh
uh
okay so let's do this n okay enumerate
is very wrong
e-n-u-m-u-r-a-t
numeric
nouns
what's e-numerator let's take a quick
review eric
if it is eric okay e-r-i-c
yeah
this is a string
s equals eic
for
i in s
print
print i what do you think what we get
for s is a string e-i-c for i in s point
i what what do you think what do we get
what do we get
i arrived
you just print each letter yeah so
you're between e and one nine are i see
you'll probably do something better
how about if i say print for i
j in illuminate
innumerate
s and print i j what do you think what
we get
what do you think what we get
enumerate remember we talked about
enumerate
this is the index this is the value so
look three index zero
e
one
ah what's this wait that's i okay what
ah one r and what's this
three
i
exactly okay so here
i would be from zero
uh
incrementing yeah and n will be actually
very well
so now we have this
let's have this uh
current answer okay current
equals zero
current plus equals ion
current plus equal ion
we want to pass the sound sound sun
sum so we plus what right
we plus n right and now we we have the
this is the prefix sum of the the first
uh you know
first few numbers
and then we just do if look if this
current equal equal zero what does it
mean
anyway
if the current equals zero
column
yeah i know what does it mean
it means that currently from the start
to the current position look at that
from the current from the beginning look
one look at this if this array is one
minus one y minus one
one minus one okay
if at this point we have this sum one
minus one zero one plus minus one zero
right if this column equals zero what
does it mean
it means the longest the surface sum is
zero is from which place from the start
right yeah
so now we could just do this answer
would be equals i plus one right
all right look
yeah
then we can do this if current
in p
if current in p
if if column in p what what do we do we
we
if current in p so p current it stores
the previous
subject sum of previous uh summary sum
of current index right so the answer
will be maximum
of answer
what current index is i right
right so why this is working look if uh
if there are two sub is sum if if the
two previous sum is the same
now what does it mean
if two perfect sum is the same
then the this the lens
if i draw it look this way
okay
this the from the beginning to here this
is 100 uh this is means uh
uh
yeah right
and then another i thought later i found
out this is also zero the sum of
uh
maybe i put it somewhere this is the sum
of from
at the beginning to this point i
is a hundred
and then i found out later j here
the beginning from
the beginning to j
yeah j is bigger than i it's also a
hundred what does it mean
the sum between the beginning don't be
bigger
no no no no no look the sum between the
sum of this range the numbers in
distance is 100 and the sum of these 100
these trends is also hundred what does
it mean can you tell me what was it
what's it mean what needs to be more
here
more what do you mean because
you know that i did not
no no no because this could be one and
minus one it could be so what i'm saying
is that the re the sum the previous sum
yeah the sum between zero to index i is
a hundred yeah let's say under and the
sum between zero to j
is also a hundred i and j are the same
no no because
i enjoy j is bigger than i what does it
mean
it means that it means
no it can be start from zero so what
happened here
what happened here what's the sum here
zero good point yeah because the sum
over here is zero that's why
at it zero
oh yeah so what so this is the
length of the
zero summit
yeah it yes so we just need to calculate
the j minus i yeah correct yes that's
right yeah okay so so
look i here is i
minus p current okay
and then
as what as if current is not in p what
do we do
current is another thinking and p
current equals r
because what come on
tell me what we we need to store the
index right
which one is index
i all right let's see so you see
if current equal and here we don't need
to put it here right
look this is very tricky if currently
equals zero
because if current is zero answer will
be i plus one why is that because
this current is the sum between the
beginning
yeah in the beginning
so if it's a zero you can't find any
longest
zero
from beginning to current right right
it's always bigger right
correct look you have a number yeah you
have number you're going to
the beginning this is current sum
current will add the sum here sum here
look at me if at this point this is
yellow we found out this is yellow can
you find any subway some bigger than the
here you can right yes because i this is
already the largest the biggest so i set
it to i plus one right because stuff is
zero so the length will be i plus one
right okay and if we can remove this we
can remove this
and instead of here i can put a zero key
zero something some zero i could minus
one
yeah got it
okay so this will be simplified yeah
this is one one way so this is what's
the time complexity
come on it should be easy what's the
timing recipe
yeah we're just going to once there's
nothing here what's the space capacity
there has to be some cost right
how do we trade the
time for
what
how do we achieve a when
with the help of what which data
structure oh and yeah
you see o and square o and cubic i want
qp os it's slow but it doesn't use any
space the state complexity for these two
is one yeah because then but now we're
using o in space
we're using the space to trade
the time right okay
okay another way another uh algorithm
i'm not going to
talk too much here okay is that
we can store the prefix
we can store each prefix and then each
prefix we will uh we store the index of
it
so
so it'll be something like uh let's
let's try this quickly write this okay
full
nouns
and then look uh
prefix sum prefix sum at the beginning i
put a zero at the beginning zero plus
least list
accumulate right remember this
accumulated function
we can use these accumulated numbers
right and then now what do i do with
this accumulator because i already have
this say okay uh i also need to put
these in a uh
i also need to put this in a scene in a
hash table okay so sim let's say c
equals
uh default dictionary
no but
thing is the prefix because in the
prefix sum
and then the key key will be the prefix
sum the value will be the list of index
yeah it could be many as i said look it
could be from zero to i it could be sum
of 100 and from 0 to j you'll be sum of
100 as well so the key will be 100 and
the value will be the index which is
index array will be i j right so
deposition released
list integer right this is so the key is
the sum the previous sum the value is
the index
okay so now i just need to go through
the the prefix for i
in
prefix
in p okay
okay and then i can say c
i
uh i let's say i
j okay c in j
dot append
okay what a pen
i right i is the index
so
for each one then we have we can go
through the
the scene for
i
in sin
this is a complicated i let's apply the
answer here answer
equals maximum
answer
i i is the
uh
[Music]
i is the sum right and then j will be
the
scene i will be the list of array
lists of index and then i want to
return the the the lowest index and the
maximum integral difference so seeing i
minus 1 minus
i zero right
right and then return we can work this
is the easy part answer
yeah
answer
can you imagine how to uh why this will
work why this will work
what is work
so
so what as i said look
i i talked about this before
from 0 to here that would be i used to
be i
also here will be j right so look if
this is
if this is the
uh sub and the prefix sound alright look
look at me
see this if this is the sum s here right
and then this is some also the s right
so the previous the scene
scene
s will be
two there will be a
list of i and j right suppose like that
and the length will be j minus one right
yeah okay so i just need to calculate
this this video you see this is exactly
what i've told before yeah so first of
all i kick away look at me i calculated
the s the prefix sum the the prefix sum
uh and i store the same prefix sum the
index of previous sum to an array and i
go through this thing and the previous
exam
right this is the sum and i go through
the index and in the length
the the length of zero summary sum will
be the the larger because this index
array is the incrementing is is sorted
so i just have to what's minus one sin
at minus one what's that what's this
value scene i minus one where is it
what sin i seen s minus one which one is
i or j which one is minus one
i minus one what does it mean
the index minus one the
which one
um
yeah the j and then i zero is this one
yeah that's what i mean so it could be
any it would be another one i increa
it could be
a b c you know there will be four
indexes so in this case it would be d
minus a right this is the largest
uh sublist okay what's the time
complexity for this one
you look at this
and oh and what's the space honestly
are we using any space is this a space
yeah oh one oh n yeah
and a scene scene is the dictionary okay
okay good job so which one you remember
so far
come on which one the profession yeah
yeah proof of thing you can write it
there
really
sorry i can't write any of them why
[Music]
do you understand come on if you
understand that's fine fine
yeah okay that's right yeah you
understand how about let's implement the
the proof of thing okay okay
yeah proof of thing is better yeah
which proof was in the o and qp or n
square you pick one
i help you
let's do it together
i want cupid
i want you be all in square i didn't
mind pick one come on
pick one
pizza
can you come here let's do this the last
one and we
we can finish
so at the beginning we need a
variable to store the answer answer will
be equal
[Music]
for i in range wa
n right and then we we need to have this
sum for current sum is yellow
for j in range
star with the i to
to the end right
and
s plus equal one
num
and we need to check if the sum equals
to zero right
with zero answer equals one
answer equals
um
we want to start a maximum right yeah
max y
next answer and then what's the length
of current surface
what's the cut length
i to j what's the current sub place
length what's the lens of these
i
now j
and then minus i
plus one yeah okay i know what i'm
eating at the end
you see you know how to do it right
you see it
yeah yes you understand you remember
yeah why you say you can't remember and
you don't understand huh okay that's it
for today
bye bye