hi
hello mr mr ryan are you right yeah
okay so today we're given the array of
numbers a list of numbers
and we want to find out uh a meter index
so let's define this middle index okay
middle index what's negative minus one
i think no so middle index
you split the you split the array into
two halves right the left and the most
if the sum of left yeah we use this if
the sum of left yeah this meter index
let's call it
uh
m okay
we sum the middle index of uh plus
sum yes sum of s this is array s
up to
middle index m
yeah
give the index m is equals to the sum of
the
s
m plus one okay and plus from n plus one
to the end
so
so can you find if if there are multiple
mineral index just pick the decimals one
okay this is easy this is easy which is
index
two
what is that
zero one two
so you choose this estimated index
what's the sum of these that's five
what's the sum of this this 12 this does
not equal
oh what's this
wait wait yeah what's the middle index
come on define given this step
come on
why next to it
eight
the middle english still one two three
okay
so i picked these as the meanings what's
the number this one right
two plus three plus minus one is four
and what's the rightmost part four you
can choose the meter index as the first
one in this case
the left sum would be zero right if you
choose the in with the index the last
one the the sum of the right part is
zero
yeah remember this is the sum yeah yeah
this is some some simple okay
and in python we can use this any idea
easy that should be very easy
briefly
root for how do we pull first chicken
every
number checking every index from the
left to the right right yeah
all right
yeah
again okay so can we implement this
together yeah we see proposing from the
left to right right and can somebody
give me the eraser please aren't they
yeah
okay
thank you
we're sidekicks define
middle index diameter index
we have at least numbs
okay so now
uh we need to
what what's the end n equals length num
right the length
yeah okay so now what should we do we
should go for the yeah let's say four
i
in range
rendezvous
come on
and when you end come on
and now what's the sum of the left path
the left part will be
l will be sum then we use this function
some places impressive sum yeah
and then the left part numbs number
numbers up to what i up to i i plus
one
after i plus one right is it true i
don't know
what oh no
no normally i don't i plus one do i need
to eyebrow
yeah
genius okay so can you tell me why we
skipped the i we
why we skip the numbers i
oh because i is the one
which is the middle right yeah if
okay this is the tricky one what's the
time complexity
[Music]
this is m but here is another n right
yeah o n i
am right now right now n square but
these air and eyes
oh and
n plus n is like that
so how do you simplify o
2 times n how is that when cubic n plus
n 2 n
no i said oh
n plus n is not n times n come on okay
so o and q om2 times n squared so i drop
the constant yeah we drop the constant i
said n squared yeah yeah but you need to
understand how we're getting this okay
okay so
the the problem with this approach is
this sound right
yeah
it's uh taking time right do we need to
actually do this i mean
um she can can we improve this
yes so how can we improve this come on
if if this array right like one two a
minus one two three four five six okay
so if this one if i
i can i can do we can do this all one
time and that will be a sum of
everything the other numbers right we
can do this adding all the numbers yeah
right
and if we keep doing it keep adding this
if we add these
so we know what
we know
we know this path and we also we can
also use the s minus this particular sum
of this right here i think it's possible
why is that yeah i know i'm just i'm i'm
just saying that
we can accumulate
let the sum of the left path
the sum of the left path
yeah we can accumulate the sum of the
plot i plus one
and then we use this uh
i don't know bigger s s minus smaller s
then that would be the sum of the right
most parts right correct
it will be similarly as the prefix sound
remember you know the perfect sound
we talk about this previous time
remember
yesterday one
two three four five six seven what's the
sum of these people
um it is 12
yes but because what's the time
complexity if you just add in the sum
numbers
what can we do better yeah
and how do we go together and we just do
one
one different
okay yeah let's play with some we
calculate these into this accumulate
function and remember we accumulate from
here
accumulate
and that will give us what one three one
one two one what's next
one three
six
um 10
21 28 okay so what's the sum of this bit
is the same as the sum of these four six
numbers uh five numbers which is 15
right and i need to minus the first
two numbers right
yeah the sum of the
of these the numbers from
3 4 5 is the sum of the first sine
number subtract the first two number in
this case is 2 is 15 minus 3 equals 12.
look we're just looking up the numbers
and we just subtract one it's 12.
it's frosted it's the same it's a
similar
so
so we can do this okay
define
find
meat
in there you know this question yeah
this question
is the first question
or in the legal context today
yeah it's continued what do you mean
there's a context contest
programming context every two weeks
you know every week or probably yeah
every week yeah yeah this is the first
question
okay so now sum we use the sum how do we
calculate the sum of all the numbers use
which function
s-u-n yeah
and then
n will be what n would be length do we
need the n
problem we don't need an n let's do it
we use a c to compute the current sum
equals zero
for
forward
forward for for do you still remember
the enumerate function remember we
talked about the enumeration yesterday
yeah what's the enumerator of this abc
come on what does it return
what's the initial function a b c
and then that's here enumerate one zero
one two okay so for i
let's say x
in
enumerate
numbers
first of all if we check if the sum
minus
what
minus the
x
minus c
equal equal equal uh look
this is the array yeah this is the array
and now i'm i know that the whole sum is
s
and now i'm iterating the x x is the
middle middle element right if i minus
this element
and i minus the previous one so what's
what's next
what's what's this part is this part
right the y power yeah yeah
look the whole o is s
look at me the x current the middle
element is x yeah
and i've subtract x
and i subtract this this bit is c
and what you wrong should we get
what should we get the overall is as i
subtract x is middle i subtract c which
is the sum up to x
and then right so
what should we check the other half
equals one
c let's see
if we don't know it is
next return i right that's it and
what's this
and
yeah i know what should we do now
return return while return minus one
yeah
minus one that's no answer come on
yes it
okay so okay there's one thing missing
is there's c we need to update the c c
plus equals one
c plus equals one what c plus equal one
what plus
so look i i just draw this picture
remember the whole the whole sound is s
and now i'm at x yeah
this is x this is the index i yeah come
on
the index i points to x
and then my sum c is the value up to x
yeah okay because i put it please after
the e so it's like
can you listen to me put it here so this
here is c so what this should be let's
see right so if it's the c
if the left part is equal to the right
path right then we return the index i
and then in the next iteration we we
expand the c
increment c
to x and then we move the x to one
position to the right okay
what's the time complexity
[Music]
we accumulate the answer here right yeah
got it
okay
can can you write this
can you write this if you correct if you
know then i'll give it back to you come
on
look this is
s
equals one power this is the left this
is the right we want to find the index
which is the left part equal to the
right so what y equals that pen it was
what what what's this
yeah
dot
this is another one why this is another
oh i know okay let's take first date for
today space complexity is one okay
bye-bye bye-bye