hello hello hi
we're gonna have a break time
everybody
so today we talk about the dopamine okay
so that's the mathematics uh concept
applies to vectors so we use the array
array is list as a vector yeah you know
the vector what's better what's vector
what's better
can you tell me what's vector well
vector yeah something like that we use
that it says highest
what's call it magnitude
and direction
okay we'll come back to this concept but
as far as
uh what we can know here is that
the vectors it can be represented by
arrays list so we want to compute the
dot products for the two
dot products so we will use one a times
b okay
okay
look using this single dot
so what does it
equal
it equals will give me give us a
value
right it's not a list of values so
so what is it
equals to the sum
the sum
okay
sum of let's say this these uh the
number of elements in both elements are
arrays are n right
so equals i equals 0 to n minus 1
sum of a
i
times bi
okay so based on this can you give me
the answer for the product of a and b
come on
well it is
come on it needs to be easier a i times
bi and some i'll take that a i comes bi
so what's the answer
one times four plus two times five
plus three times six
um wait it is um four ten fourteen and
applies to two vectors of the same
length
and then we all we have to do is to sum
up the each
corresponding pair one four two five
three six right
yeah and if it doesn't have an equal
length then you we can't apply this
right it only applies percentage if
another one is there
for these two
no no because there's no subnet can we
just like seven plus nothing separately
no no no no
you have it has to be the same same
length for two
two okay
so to understand this sum from i to zero
to n minus n minus one a i times d i and
we want the sum of these
all right
correct
how can we implement it
easier
define
dot product
a
first of all what do we do what do we
need to do
we need to find out the length right
yeah so what's the length
and equation
length what
that's what
but we also have to check if b is the
same as n right so we can use the
function called assert what what does it
mean by answer
what does this mean a assertion
a-s-s-e-r-t assert
what's his name
in english
you know
you don't know let's find other means
that
to make sure right to guarantee to do to
make sure yeah
okay so we need to make sure n equal
equal length what b okay it has to be
the same length right
okay
so you wrap it out
so what happens if this does not satisfy
if n is not equal if the length of a is
not
the computer will just you know scream
okay you screen your your screen at this
point it will tell you okay and it's not
equal students b and then and it will
refuse to continue okay so that's the
way to make sure that after this we
don't need to worry about if we are not
the same length right right how can you
compute the screen just print an arrow
saying okay i don't like what you're
doing here because you tell me okay f is
equal to length b but what i thought we
i found out is that n is not equal to
then b then last i cannot continue
that's what basically it does here okay
okay so now we want to return a value
which is at the beginning equals one
come on we don't sum up the beginning
right
what value
in the beginning
no no no the sum there
is a value
we want to sum up the beginning what's
the sum
it's nothing so what do we give it
zero come on
four zero is nothing yeah there is
nothing okay for i in range
[Music]
okay so now we need to do s plus equal
one
[Music]
what's the space university
yeah okay okay can we use the some fancy
thing syntax like a zip do you still
remember the difference
we talked about this
like one two three four
and then this is a
b is
five six seven eight so
so what what's g for a b
what's the ap you know what's cheap
yeah yeah so i have a here i have b here
chips so what happened
one five two six three seven four five
and we also have a cheap longest if it's
different length
yeah if there's a nine here then you can
use the deep left uh longest but and
then this one will be
filled with number okay
we mentioned that before yeah so chip a
b
so if chip a b it will return a list of
two players so you become like right
right one four
one two five yeah
something like that it's three six yeah
okay so we can use this
look
we can just do this sum
okay somewhat x zero
times x one
four x
in
zip
what
come on using guess
sum x x what's s x instead yeah
x is a cube yeah yeah yeah look chip a b
look one two three
and then if i chip with four five six
so what does what do we get
one four this is a two four yeah
two five
three six yeah what's x x is this one so
x is this tube x yellow is here right
this is x zero
this is x one right i want to sum up x
zero times x one which is one times four
2 times 5
3 times 6 and i also add it together
some using the sum function so this is
quite fancy yeah okay
okay so i'm going to erase this and you
need to implement one of it
oh come on you can use the implement
first anything
we just when you just talk about okay so
first one this one dot a b we need to
add
whatever
s as equal
[Music]
we need to go to the index right
for
i
[Music]
and what's missing
it's not hard right okay that's it for
today good job bye
bye
sorry