go hello
okay that's it hello mr eric all right
what's magic
um
asthmatic what's magic
well it's this big little
[Music]
so yeah you can use the square bracket
or you can just use mathematically just
to watch the bar and okay this is the
same thing so this is two times two
matching what does it mean two rows two
columns yeah if this is
a uh a equals there how can we represent
it in python in computer
what do we what kind of data structure
can we use to store these kind of 2d
metrics the matching
what's this in person next list
at least it's the one dimensional so how
can we put a store list using
this in two minutes two dimensional
so
can you write a price and code a equals
one can you write
some stories
can you store these using the tyson list
a equals one
what
look here at least so what's this
it's same as a list of two lists right
yeah so okay
so a list of
at least one two and comma
three four
right this is how you store it in person
so what does it mean this is the list
contains two sublist the first place is
the first row the second is is the
second row okay
yeah
so how can i get the
row number of rows
of a how to get the number of rows of a
length a
weather and how can i can we get the
current number of currents in a
a
well done very well done okay very well
done okay
okay so in mathematics mathematics uh we
can add two matrix a plus b if or a
minus b if it's the same size is the
same size same dimension which means the
postmates have said number row some
number of columns
so if i have a metric like one two three
four
if i add another metric three four two
one can you imagine what can we get
can you imagine how how do you solve
this problem um you just add these two
same relationship okay so one plus three
equals four and then what's
next um six yeah sun position
and then same position five
third position five and how about like
one two three four
minus
three four two one okay can you imagine
what happened yeah um it's minus two
minus two um
minus two
one
three okay okay so yeah let's add
addition and subtraction is very easy we
just do this perform these operations on
the element at both matrix
then the same the same as the same
position okay right now we put it in the
same yeah
put it in a result yeah
okay so let's implement this okay uh if
if there are some different size we
cannot add yeah we prefer the
to throw at the exception and if their
size are different right okay
define
f
a b
okay let's do this rose a rose a
equals lens a yeah you know that right
right now we need to assert what's
assuming
to check you have to take computer lab
okay i'm assuming
r is strictly bigger than zero okay yeah
if we found out i is zero or whatever
the capital is green
okay it was refused to continue that's
what it means yeah and c equals length
what
this is the column and now i need to
check that
the rows and columns are the same as the
size of b yeah so result i equals one
i equals one
what's the number of rows in b
what's the number rows in b
length b
and
the columns need to be same this column
length
okay so this is just to check to prepare
let's okay we have the two metric which
has the same size and then b and we want
to add it together so there's no there's
a one way to do it is to allocate the
metric of
a separate metric right
yeah
and all we can just add it to a right
yes we get it so let's do this one by
one okay what's how can we add it to a
for
r
in
range row
r right
four
c
in range
column
then what should we do let a
a r c
can you imagine what's the operator here
and then corresponding one will be b
what what
yeah
i go through each rows i turn through
these columns
i see
what's this i want to
add these to a
so
class
and what should i put here
um
yeah you know
what's the time complexity
what's the time investing
[Music]
are we using any space
we're changing the space so we're not
using in this place yeah oh
we are not using any space oh one come
on
okay so uh
no if this is subset so if this
substrate there's only one character we
need to change
if this is substrate i want to structure
a to b from subject b
a from uh
such a b for a so i change this to a
minus yeah got it yes same complexity oh
i see because we need to go through each
element in the uh elementary and we
change that okay so
you get here so now we talk about how to
educate one yeah sometimes you you're
not allowed to change the metric yeah
because you are changing the metric here
so we if we we can allocate the metric
how can we allocate magic
c equals the same size we add at the
beginning
what zero
we put it there for
underscore in range how many columns of
how
this is how many columns first of all
how many columns of
this this
return value
columns c yeah yeah
and now we do this yeah this is the
color this is the
each row has the c columns and then four
underscore in
range
granular
how many rows
[Music]
are yeah okay so if this is the way to
allocate at least the list
with r columns arrows and sequence and
then you once you allocate it you just
do this you have crc
equals you can just do it equals a rc
and then minus brco plus a over c that's
got it
and if you implement this what's the
time complexity
what's a space for music
yeah we are educating this space okay
got it yeah it's not easy it's not hard
yeah
okay
so this is the magic
plus and uh subject uh add and subtract
okay so let's talk about uh
multiplied
okay what's multiplier a times b
let's check this
yes
okay so a times b okay so
the matrix only has
plus
subtract
and multiply there's no division okay
there's no division but
you can approximate
we can define the uh division by using
some uh
the inverse of matrix which you'll talk
about later so let's skip the division
for now okay a times b what's matching
battery multiplication is different
it's different okay
so
look
i show you okay
one two three four
times
one
one zero zero
equals one
it's hard yeah so look i did it no no no
no no
look
you take
you take the rows for for the first one
yeah and you take the columns for for
for the second one
you do the top plata remember what stop
we talked about that the day uh
yesterday
yeah
don't put that one two
and then look one two and one zero
what's the top product
do you still remember what's the double
dot
these two plus b2
what's the product
a and b dot product equals one
sum of i equals zero to n minus one a i
times bi right remember
yeah
so
one times one plus two times two times
zero
okay
what's this
one one yeah i think it's one times two
oh yeah
and um you take this and this remember
you add you turns it you times it and
you all empty together this is eddie
okay so look
right look at look at my hand
yeah
do that product and then you put this
answer here which is
one right
okay
and again next one yeah next one here
you take this at least
one no no no you just look at it you
take this first row
second column first row second column
first the second column so you'll be
one two
top quarter and one zero one what what's
this one times zero plus two times one
equals one
two two
okay so the same the second one three
four one zero
three four one
zero one three times zero zero four
times one four
you see yeah that's exactly the same
thing good job look at this
what's that mean
you remember you have a metric if it's a
square metric with the diagonal only
fear one right
yeah
all
we call it identity magic
okay so this is identity
and this is also identical
one one one zero zero zero zero zero
zero can you write the four times four
for identity magic
four times for identity magic line line
yeah
one one
one
and all honest you know okay okay
so i think this metric we will use the
use the
i to normally represent as identity
measure okay
look in order for the multiplication to
happen look the number of the columns
yeah
means the number of columns a
the number of columns of a
columns of a let's say c a
needs to equal as one
c a and needs to equal what
yeah the number of columns
needs to equals to the the number of
columns of a needs to equal the number
of columns of b right
right if it doesn't equal there is no
copper that you cannot multiply okay
okay
and what's the result
look if
if look look if this is one two three
four five six
right you can times one one zero zero
and that will return one
that will determine three four you will
do the same yeah as i say yeah right
look
you can do this yeah one two one zero
that's one one two zero one is two three
four one zero is three three four zero
one is four yeah five six one zero is
five five six zero one is six
so look
this is a metric of what
three row times two column right look
here and this is um identity metric of
two times two
this needs to be the same right this
needs to be equal all right got it
yeah
yeah yeah so what's the answer what's
the dimension of the answer
yeah i know but what's the dimensional
answer is 3 times 2 right you see
because these two are the same
and the answer will be three rows two
columns
okay
yeah
does it make sense look
a times b if a the metric is
ah
is okay let's do this
a
a columns and b
a rows and b columns and then b
is b rows and c columns so what's the
what's the dimension of the result c can
you tell me
come on
okay a magic is a rule of b columns b
matrix is b
rho c columns a times c yeah where that
a times c that's what i'm talking about
yeah okay
so any magic times the b identity magic
is uh
itself right
so can you tell me a times b
is it the same as b times a
equal or equal to
[Music]
you can plus the number one plus two
equals two plus one right yeah one times
two equals two times one the numbers are
okay yeah exchange
but magic is not a times b magic is not
the same as b times a okay
yeah because sometimes look if you one
times three and then you want to times
three times uh times five you can times
the i the result will be one times five
but if you reverse it what happened what
happened 3 times 5
times 3
times 1 right you can't multiply right
because this is this
not the same side right
why you cannot multiply right
[Music]
yeah then it's okay
so let me tell you got it the number of
look just remember my hand yeah
ah
put it here
yeah ready
good job look if i look
this is the first row right
and i want to do this the second column
right so where does it go first the
second column so here first row second
column
second row first column
the second row first column
yeah second or first you see okay that's
magic so let's implement this okay and
that lovely
okay that will be easier it'll be easy
divide multiply
a and b
okay so the the
first field
the first few are similar right so we
first of all we need to get a
r equals length a
and then we need to assert
r bigger than zero and then look c
equals length b
uh length a right we need to assert c is
p bigger than zero and we also need to
assert what come on this is different we
want to observe
how in what cases a can multiply b
the the first one a is r and c and then
the second the b is b
the b is one how many number of rows of
b is then b right
column
length b zero
so which two numbers should be same
r times c times these what which two
numbers should be the same
come on
the first a is atom c
and b is these times this in order for a
times b
which two number needs to be the same
at least one
plus
one two three four this is a and i want
to times something remember so these
needs to be the same as this this is
number of columns
and what's this
[Music]
length of rows of b
and this is just to pretend okay now we
have these then we allocate yeah we are
okay result okay let's do this big c c
but this is biggest uh let's throw
a the size is r times c okay and then b
is length b
times the
length b zero
okay so what's the result what's the
result matrix m
what's the result matrix m
[Music]
on these two are the same remember
so
so our columns are columns and length b
zero uh as rows and then b columns
as well and then we saw we have to do
this yeah zero
for underscore in range
length
p0 right we define this
and then four
in
range
all right okay
so let's just define this and then we
just need to go to each and each one
okay so look
a is here right so we just go through
four
r
in
range
all right
and now we go to c yeah
four
c
in
range c
all right
so we go to each one
and now we we need to go to work for
k
in
in manual
in range so what's the result no no look
r the result will be length b zero right
so we need to go to length p0 right
because this is the
the final dimension is r times length p0
so we go into the first two two loops
we're going through each element in the
result right so and 4k will be in range
one in range bc yeah
because c uh let's
okay the ones you see let's do this uh i
j okay i say inventory now all i have to
do is to sum up each one so m i j right
m i j is this one yeah
this one times this one equals this one
right okay so look i'm timing this this
is a
this is b right i don't want to put it
here right i want to sum up here so each
one will be the
contribution from a to b that's a plus
equal what
i k
i k is the c i k look
a
i k
times b
k
b look b's k k
k y
what's what's here
what's here
a i k times b k
j right okay and that's it return n
this is a bit trickier it's okay you
don't understand anymore but take a look
so why this is m i k m i k here
i j m i j m i j
m i z will be what
will be added keep adding this bit yeah
m a i k
times k will be zero to c at zero to c
right look look at my hand zero to see
if this is this column
and a i k here times b k j k
k z j j is the
which column right which column right
yeah look i know what's k k moving look
all right look
look at me moving moving moving
all these added to fij here
and here
msj mij is here
this is mij
can you can you look at me not moving
around and run look this is mij
yeah this is the result m right and then
look a this is b
a
a i k
[Music]
times p k j
eddie andy add the id from zero to c
okay okay what's the tango next t this
is what
what's time to make speak
what's the time look at how many how
many
sorry
this is r
this is length b 0 let's call length b 0
no no let's be zero let's call it uh
let's call it i don't know x okay
this is x if then b 0 is x
and what's the time constant
o r
times x
times
c
you see three rules yeah inner loop in
in order to finish our loop each r loop
takes
x loops each x loop takes c loops
yeah so the times of x is all r times x
times what's what's the space complexity
and what's the dimension of n
what's the x dimension come on
a what's the dimension x
number of rows number this is r times c
and l when this is b is maybe y times
c times x
c times x right
c times x what's that what's the
dimension of m
come on r times c and times this metric
a is item c
times x r times x yes well done good job
yeah so let's play some next day
okay that's it for today i i think you
got it tomorrow we keep talking about
the magic we talk about okay a little
preview for tomorrow we talk tomorrow
we'll talk about uh metric uh
um
you know the
multiply if you want to multiply
the power yeah power and magic
uh
the inverse we have
we mentioned about the division a
divided by b
okay
it's just
yeah it writes to be actually equal as
what
a times b minus one right right yeah
mathematics
two
two divided by four
equals what two times
four minus one right
yeah
yeah okay so
is it yeah maybe yeah so what's this
minus one
so it's four times one divided by one
okay so it's mathematics yeah so this
this will this is called inverse so
what's inverse
i
so something if a
times a minus one can you imagine equals
one
this is called inverse of a
you know
also
we mentioned about some something here
remember we talked about this a a minus
y is the inverse of a
you play times two
come on to something you draw this four
times four what is it
called um
i don't need to magic yeah that's it
okay okay yeah
yeah okay
yeah don't don't worry too much about
people we will reach that later okay
good job today bye
say bye-bye