yes good job
okay so remember yesterday we talked
about binary search tree
to search your value in the final search
too am right yeah
so can you tell me what's the binary
search tree it's like
a a tree with numbers yeah exactly
in circles
[Music]
yes so today our job is to validate a
tree if it's a binary search tree so we
call it validate
the agreement to very valid date
binary surgery so given the tree we have
to value
to check if it's a very valid financial
stream a binary search tree
is a the first of all it's a binary tree
right
so the final search it has to be a
binary tree
yeah what's binary two
yeah we're done finding two yeah two two
kids left or right
the second one finance search three the
empty
empty tree is also a valid financial
street okay
third that's the one the important what
about
this just one number it's a fine
research tree
it it's a very it's a final tree it's
also a fine research tree because it's
valid right
yeah apparently
thick this is okay and also the third to
do very important
which is the root value has to bigger
than
the left
no no this is one node is the thing uh a
valid binary and final assertion
and then and the loot has two smaller
than one
the right the right yes okay is this a
final research
tree no
why yes yes because this is bigger than
river
that's right okay remember yesterday we
talked about certain nodes in binary
street first tree
if it's a binary search tree like one
zero
two three and then
let's minus one and then maybe one
no it can't be one can it be two
no no because look this is this
is smaller than one but this is small
bigger than one so this can only be like
0.5
got it because 0.5 bigger than zero
smaller than one okay
so if you want to locate 0.5
is it smaller than one yes
so go left or right is it smaller than
zero
circle y or get left
but yeah okay we found it so the
complexity is what
yeah because it because n is the number
of the notes in the tree
and on average if it's this highly
balanced
what i mean high dependence is is that
the
difference the maximum difference
between any left tree or right tree
is at most one okay this is
uh is this uh uh valid
uh is it is a verified research tree yes
yes
yes is this a highly balanced uh balance
of necessity
no because look the difference is
this is the right no right now is
there's no right or but there are two so
the difference is more than one so okay
this is not
okay so now we given a tree we want to
find out if it's a binary search tree
so we can do it this way if we define
the window
like a minimum and maximum right yeah if
we know this minimum
maximum right and if a tree
is if a node value has has the value
outside this window and we know it's
invalid right you can't see the window
yeah the window
the maximum the minimum at the beginning
we just passed
infinity the minimum infinity and the
maximum infinity yeah
very rapid number very very small number
okay
and then when we go look this is one
this is i don't know this is something
yeah and this is something okay so the
beginning is
minus infinity and then pick it bigger
than infinity
so if we go right go left so
all the values in the left hand tree
we have no values smaller than one right
yeah that means the right window
is one right right the left window is
still infinity all right
yeah if you go left we update the right
the upper bound because it can't have
more than
you can't have values more than one yes
if we go to the right what would we do
the small bound is one right because you
can't have more
value smaller than one right so it's one
and infinity
all right so every time we update the
win
and max and then we check we recursively
remember verification yeah calling
itself in the lesson one right
calling itself recursively update the
value to
update the windows and just check if
it's a valid binary search sheet
okay so let's do the coding it will be
quick okay you can tell me
okay you can tell me what's right so
first first of all
five minutes away yeah yeah i know so
what
uh what's your way right now
and what's next
oh check bst let's call it and it takes
root load of rotary and then let's call
it
mean and let's call it max okay
min and max yeah
so we need to check the base cases if
the root is empty what should we do
tell me what to do okay if root
is noun okay or you can simply write if
not
good it's the same thing if not blue or
if
loot is long it's the same thing return
what
yes be confident yeah return true not
return true
return true okay
[Music]
okay now then we need to check the value
if it's inside a bench right
look look if
not stop value if it's
smaller than mean or
lose the value if it's bigger than
max column what you need to return
return
yeah because it's in the outside the
window then it's not ready right
yeah babe okay and then we need to
recursively check
check the left note and then the right
notes right
remember we talked about check the left
now
[Music]
okay so remember what do we check
return yeah
check bst check psg
left okay tell me what's the next two
parameters
i read the right no no no it takes the
min and max what's the mean what's the
max for the
what's the left left train oh a minimum
and the right value will be the load of
value right
because it can't be it can't be bigger
than the load right
yeah and then again and
check bst
blue dot right right yeah
and what's the mean what's the next
max so what's the mean
oh the right yeah right right hand side
what's
what what possible smallest number
yeah one which is root of val
right and
and what's the least what's the maximum
max yes well done
so together now it's clear yeah yeah
this
bit is checking for the loop so you call
itself to check
and here either if it's empty that will
return true
i or if it's not inside a range
right because it's smaller or it's
bigger then it's not in that range we
retain the force right
why can we do that because a valid
binary search tree
the left binary search tree and the
right band of the tree
is also binary right in order for the
entire tree
is a bst the left has to be a bst and
the right has to be sd
so this is b s t binary search should
look
so look what why is
but this is very simple uh recursion
look
if the note is a simple if it's nothing
if it's empty it's a binary search tree
right
if the value is not inside the range
it's not
a balanced surgery also in order for
this to be a binary search tree the left
hand
left tree has to be a binary search tree
and the right chain has to
be the binary substrate am right what a
complexity of this angular
what's the point
[Music]
oh what n o n yes remember
oh and why isn't it
you need to check all the numbers yeah
exactly because we in order to to verify
if a tree is the binary that's true we
have to
check every node right if you come if
you miss one note you can't be sure that
it's a
brand new tree right yeah okay so can
you tell me why yesterday we
we are searching for a note in the
binary search tree
the complexity is
yeah for example if it's if it's one
this is zero this is minus one if i want
to find minus
one i don't want to check
that one yeah i don't need to check the
right hand side yeah we're done we're
done good job today eric
ryan okay good job laughing
wow
okay good job today