hello hello
hello miss mommy how are you today good
okay so we talked about the metric a few
days ago today we're going to talk about
implementing the metric multiplication
of the
power function so a to the power of n is
a times a times a how many a times
together
um and yes what's the time complexity oh
because these they are n so o
we're done
okay so um
in order for two metrics to multiply
together if they're matching a and b we
if we want to multiply a to the metric b
right we want to multiply together so
the magic the dimension if this matrix a
is dimensional a times b you know a rows
b columns and b metric is c times d
in order for them to be multiplied
together we need
to make
sure b and c should be
the same should be the same yes so for
example like if these 1 1 0 0 this is 2
times 2 matching we can times any metric
which is two rows and
any columns yeah so it could be two
times n columns right so let's say if we
have times two rows and three columns
two rows three columns one
two three four five six we can times it
together so how do we do this we we can
do this um
yeah so this row we we multiply
we take the rows of the first metric and
multiply and to the operator of the
second uh of recurrence of the second
magic so but one zero one four we do the
dot product so the dot product let's
stop that
if two two vectors there are two vector
two arrays in
uh
vectors you have two vectors we
represent using array if there are some
lengths we can multiply together using
the dot product so for example like a
times b
equals the sum yeah this is true matrix
a and b trigonometric the arrays the
list vectors
vectors we do the dot product so it's a
sum of
sum of i equals 0 to n minus 1 if there
are n elements yeah and then we do this
a i
the first the element at index i
times bi and then we sum it together so
for example if this one zero one four
one zero one four
so the double side will be one times one
plus zero times four which is
one right so one
one zero one four and we put it here
which is
one
right
so this this the metric
is the metric is a information is the
square matrix and with all the elements
a diagonal diagonal is equal to one and
a zero
in the rest of place we call it identity
magic we use the i so what's the
identity it looks you it's quite similar
as the number one right so i need any
metric times identity matrix
it's the same it won't change right so
these times that if you do it perform it
it will be like one two three four five
six
and then you reverse it is still the
same right if it's
can you reverse it
one two three four five six if you times
the this is what two times three
right two times two rows three columns
and you can't multiply you can multiply
two rows to color right you can't do it
so how do we fix this if it's two rows
three columns the matrix look this is i
this is a
i can say makes sense but a times i we
can multiply it
this i needs to be changed because it's
no longer two times two identity matrix
is three times three times magical if we
can just change this to three zero three
columns so you'll be multiply uh you
will be much multiplying it will be much
better one one one three times three
identity metric instead instead of two
times two okay
so
so we talk about how to multiply these n
terms but is there a quicker way
let's talk about the numbers first if we
want to calculate 2 to the power of 100
one way is to multiply these two how
many times
how many times
100 times yes we're done 2 times 2 times
to
a hundred times yeah but that's going to
take a linear nino yeah linear
linear complexities because this a
hundred you need to do this a hundred
times so a to the power of b
to the power of n if you times the a
n times that's going to take all n time
complexity this is linear so what's
linear so you can draw a graph this is a
yeah and then
the vertical vertical axis is the time
the complexity
and if you draw the linear you'll be
like that
okay
okay so now we want to speed this up so
2 to the power 100 can we divide it
can we solve the first question which is
can we get computer 2 to the power of 50
first
yes okay so if we have 2 to the power 50
what what do we do to get the 2 to the
power of 100
square square yeah we're not so 2 to the
power 50 then we can say 2 to the power
50 times square right so what does it
mean
we
we if we do this proof force you have to
this 100 times now
if we do this 50 times 2 to the power 50
50 times we just need to do it one more
time so 51 so you see we save almost
half of it right now look look if we 250
we can keep continue to 250 equals 2 to
the power of 35 square right and how
about 225 if we it's not an even number
the n is not an even number how do we do
this
if 2 to the 25
what should we do
uh 2 to the 24
2 to the power of 24 times 2 yes so so
to sum up
the sum of f
a to the power of n
equals we can use the curly uh big curve
base equals 2 to a to the power of n
minus
n divided by 2
and squared is n is
even right even number and or equals a
to the power of n minus 1 times a is
n is hot
okay
uh
so what's the time complexity if you can
remember uh see this well every time we
we divide this n into half because we we
understand this right if we want to
solve this big problem we can solve the
half of a problem and on everything we
can keep solving this half our problem
half of her
we keep dividing into half so in this
case we the time complexity is what we
keep dividing into half right we keep
dividing into half
n times right
so
what's the time complexity of this one
so it's all
log base 2 m right what's log function
log
a to the power b
a b equals n can we write it as
a to the power n equals b okay
so if we draw these axes
so previously yeah previously we have
this oh
linear linear is on
now log n how can you draw the logan
function it's like that log
log 2 to the power of 1 so look 2 to the
power of
1 uh 2 to what equals power 1 0 right so
1 y
uh when
y this is y right
x so when y is 0 x is what
log y equals y equals log 2 x so when y
is 0 what's the value of x
this is this is why this is a one
y is zero what's the value of x
look look at this look at this okay
i know it's a
what's
a what's a a is 2
a
2 to the power of
0 equals what's the value of b
2 to the power of 0 what's this 1 1 okay
so when x is 1 y is zero so it's here
it's going through here right look at
that pay attention
okay yeah and then we if we drawing it
you'll be like there so which one is
better so two complete two egg run for
example which one is better second one
second one why is it better
why is better because look if x x is the
size of the problem right if we keep
increasing the x it does not the
complexity does not grow linear right
instead it would be
like left right you'd be like that
lesson it's reduced right
so the same we can do this with the uh
battery multiplication okay so if n
if n is the even number
we
divide it yeah and a square yeah
if n is odd number we reduce by one so
at the beginning what should we give to
the answer to do it
it's identity yeah we give you this
identifier first
and then we can keep this is the result
for example and then you know identity
for
for that energy times the a and times a
times a you know any you know by
following this pattern we can reduce it
we can calculate the answer if n is the
even number yeah we square it
if n is odd number we times it yeah okay
so let's write this okay
define
ma uh we say power power function for
matrix a
n right
okay so first of all we need to make
sure make sure the number of rows of a
and columns is the same here
why is that because look if it's a
matrix can times itself if a can times
itself
if a is the matrix
dimension of a rows b columns if you if
we need to be able to multiply itself
it's a times b what does it mean
what does mean a
a equals b okay a equals b so a equals b
so let's do this
so look the row the number of rows the
rows
equals length a this is getting uh
uh
the rows of the magic and then columns
equals length
a0 yeah because we're getting the first
row and then we return the dimension of
the rows so we need to assert what's
assuming in english
as a rows
equal current right
yeah and if we want to make sure we can
assert these as a
rows bigger than zero so if it's the
empty matrix we don't continue right
so other means that to make sure to
double check if the computer
find out the rows and columns it did
the computer will saw an error
and refused to continue
okay now we need to create what's the
result that uh if we multiply the
number of rows and uh the a what's the
dimension or final dimension of a
is it the same
it's the same yeah because the rows and
columns are say if you multiply it to
the same you'll be the same uh you'll be
the same dimension so we create a metric
which is called red
red equals 0
0 4
underscore in range
range column yeah this is the columns
and then for
in range rows
so at the beginning
at the beginning
at the beginning we feel that metric is
zero but we we need to
find out we need to
we we need to actually
we need to initialize the return metric
as the identity matrix so what's
identical matching if this look this is
all zero so what do we need to do to
make it identity matrix
what do we need to do to make this
natural identity metric at the beginning
it's all zero what's the identity magic
i what i didn't remember remember we
talked about this at the beginning five
minutes ago yeah you should remember
that yeah look
all the diagonals is the one all others
is zero so we just need to change this
value to one right
we just need to change this value right
so we use a for loop yeah four are in
rows
in range row there we want to iterate
from zero to range rows
and then what should we do red
red
r
r is the rows and which is the columns
what's the columns
ah the same yeah the
the first row first column the second
second number equals what one one
be confident yeah you know like that
okay so now we have this metric and then
what should we do now what should we do
now what should we do now so we we need
to
we need to
do this y we need to check why n is
bigger than zero right if it's bigger
than zero what should we do
if n
and
one
bigger than zero right if n and one what
does it mean if it's an even if it's if
it's
if it's odd number right if it's not all
number
so what we do we should we should add
red equals multiply yeah we talked about
multiply yesterday
red what
a
and now we multiply we need to make the
n smaller by half right so how do we do
it 55 or and all we can do is a divided
by equals two or we can shift one
one position to the right yeah
equals one right
and then now when we safety we need to
double
well what do we need we need to square
the edges by itself so a equals what
i equals one
multiply multiply what okay
multiply a yeah
what's the time complexity
we talked about this three minutes ago
look
if we talk about logan and it comes in
10 times but we have apparently not time
much praying and have we so let's come
back to this block area we stop 100 250
reduce 25 reduce 24 reduce to 12 and
reduce to 1. what's next
so yeah what's next
see yeah right now okay you're paying
attention good
okay so let's multiply okay the
any question so far no
okay
okay so can you tell me what's identity
magic
what's identity match which part is to
setting this identity matrix which part
this part this part
this one which bar
this fire yeah yeah okay and what's this
battery what if i'm and one
it's to checking when n is even or
number here
yeah
that's a question what
n is even or all number
n and one
if it's an odd number that we times it
one time and we what's this doing
divided by two when we reduce a hundred
to fifty we need to multiply to square
square a right okay
okay that's it for today good job
miss mommy bye bye
bye bye show him bye bye let people see
your hand
bye