hello
hello mr ariel alright today
yeah
so today we talk about the longest
substring with two distinct characters
longest
substring
with two distinct
distinct
characters
what's this thing
a b c c that doesn't exist anymore
this thing
it doesn't exist anymore uh
kind of distinct characters means that
you need yeah you need characters so the
longest substring what's that string
abc how many subjects
six
oh quick that was quick a b c for one
one uh character substring a b b c and a
b c
yeah
so that's five oh six okay
continue
so how the longest substring
right we can find this is the longest
searching with two distinct characters
because it has b and c only two in this
here it will be only b and c only two
right we can't choose this one because
the a b c c how many
how many three yeah a b and c okay got
it
yeah okay so that's the question
so any idea how we're doing this
if the whole thing is only
meaning
all of it
uh
what do you mean uh so again here a b c
c b
yeah
so how we doing this
first of all we can you know proof of it
we can if we blue first all the
substring how what's the term complexity
to proof of all assumptions
remember every time we proof of the
substring in a string we need o
what
sorry
we need to
substring the left and the right right
we need to prove what's the left and the
right right
that's the index and the writing there
so what is it
how much complexity it takes look if i i
will be blend from 0 to n
all right
zero to n
zero to n yeah inclusive and then j will
be
from one
from
i to n time
what's the time complexity all right
if i use the loop to iterate from zero
to n minus one and i have a second loop
which iterates from i to n what's a term
complexity
i have a loop i have blue
so if we each array proof of all the
substring we need one square and then to
check
to check if there are more than two if
there are two yeah
if at
how many distinct characters in this
state
with two
uh in this uh substring how many
how many characters distinct characters
in this substring we missed our entire
america well right it needs another
intent so all time complexity is what
oem times two
and then we need uh
times ten that will be o and qp right
yeah
okay
yeah got it
so we we can do better how can we do
better
how can we do better
how can we do better to do can we use
the
sliding window thingy so for example we
have a window and then
if we
uh
so we have a window like
you know the window abccp
so
at the beginning the window is a
okay so currently we have uh
we only have one
distinct parameter so we move on we add
explain the window ap right yeah now two
there are two which is okay now it's two
so now i add another if we if we satisfy
the requirement i keep adding
and now look this is the left this is
the right
so now what happened if this does not
satisfy right so the left tends to be
i move like that yeah
right
okay it says it's right that's okay and
then i reset if we satisfy i keep adding
to the right hand side now it's okay
yeah
pcc so
and at the meantime i'm like updating
the answer okay
and then look if i adding
uh
so the next is adding the b here okay
and then now this this is the maximum
substring we have got with two because
the the question is asking about the two
distinct characters yes if it's two
distinct characters
okay
so what kind of the data structure we
can use to keep tracking the distinct
characters in a window
what kind of data structure we can use
to keep tracking the distinct
characters in the window you know if we
only keep counting so we can use what
kind of data structure are we
um
call the weather notebook okay
so we can use the notebook
okay let's do it quickly
so
n equals length bands
so l r
equals zero zero okay at the beginning
then look the sliding window thing it
has this this kind of uh
format it would be something like wire
why the right pointer yeah why the right
point should be smaller than what
come on see which is smaller than one
while the r is not reaching the end yeah
so what should we put here
and we're done okay
now we we
the r is the we are in the position r
right
a a b c c b here we are air here r here
so now we need to add this r right
to the window okay so let's put a window
window here equals default dictionary
all right
different dictionary
yeah hint
yeah you're saying differentiation with
the content
okay
why are smaller n and what i keep adding
it i keep adding it then what what's the
window win
win
s
r
plus equals one right look
look at this
sr is the character a and i put it in a
wing plus equal one right and then now i
need to check the window if
y
if look it was
if air smaller equals r
n
and then length of the windows key yeah
because the windows key is the
is the number of in characters in it
right and i should i should do a bigger
than if this is bigger than two right if
this is bigger than two what does it
mean if if it's bigger than two it means
that uh
uh it means what it means that there are
more than two uh distinct characters in
the window right then we need to do what
we need to delete we need to remove it
yeah so wing
the left
s left
minus equal one right and if we reduce
to zero we need to delete the t right
if
we if we win
s l
equal equal zero we delete the key we
delete the key
wing
s f okay
okay and then now i have to air plus
equal one right i keep moving the left
if we keep breaking the law right every
it like breaking then i i i
i keep adding now okay now after at this
point now we are satisfied here so now
we need to put the answer let's answer
okay
answer
equal zero answer
equals maximum
of answer
which is r minus l plus one right this
is the length of the maximum uh
substring right substring
and then
here we need to do what we need to move
the right right
we need to move the right class equal
one and then we turn one
what's the time complexity for this one
come on look at the
look at the curl what's the time
complexity
all right what's your space invested
[Music]
oh and yeah we are using the dictionary
okay so look at this code i'm going to
use another example like uh
a a c
e r i
r y c d okay so look are you just trying
to make her a name yeah i try to make
out okay
answer equals you know
equals zero i equals you know
dictionary okay this this wing equals
nothing okay now
uh there's a key okay
so
i'm here right
r is here yeah
right here
r is smaller than n i knew as well i
think was here right it's smaller than n
then win r so it will be a with plus
equal one right that's what it means
this one
for the a
plus equal y
okay so now it doesn't get into the loop
because the windows key that they then
win key only one right so it doesn't go
to it okay now air is here
i is here right
yeah
i i
execute this one so what happened to
this wing
this will turn into uh because there's a
a is one and now i have another a okay
okay so now the lens key is also one
because lens keys is how many keys here
there will be only one right so you keep
moving ah i'll keep moving there yeah
answer will keep up at updating answer
now will be three two two right end of
b2
yeah okay now see i added so that will
be c equals one here right
you see
c u equals one and then
is it bigger than one two no it's equals
two so it doesn't get into here as well
and answer equals this so answer will be
three right because
because c minus r a there will be three
characters okay so that next one is
interesting okay look
i add the e
either s e e will be equal as one here
right yeah
look but look air's smaller than up but
that lands the key so how many keys in
the wing
how many characters in the wind
there are
four
what is well there are only three one
ace the keys the keys so look so i need
to air what's alpha s a right
yeah
keyboard that's one right
now become one reduce one one if it's
then zero no it's zero it's still one
okay l plus equals one
and plus is one so l is here
right
and what's the key it's still bigger
than two e3 right
so i still need to remove it so i i make
this to do a one reduce this to zero
eric look
i know what happened if this is zero
what happened
they did what does this mean did this
so they did it i just moved it yeah
and l will become here
okay so now it's satisfied because it
equals two not bigger than two okay so
now i can go and break the loop answer
equals answer r minus l is two
characters we already have three do you
get to understand this problem
yeah we will keep going
yeah
if
we have uh if
we're keeping adding the characters at
the right hand side expanding to the
right the window right and if it breaks
the condition that more than two
then we dedicate the characters at the
left
right and if we reduce to what zero we
take it out of the
map right the window map right
yeah yeah
do you see how how beauty this is yeah
do you get it
and the proof is just trying every
possibility of their
substrings and then checking right any
questions so far why
are you sure
can you explain to me
sorry i carry right
yeah yeah i know so so can you tell me
what's this part doing
what's this pattern
what's this pattern what's this part
doing i'm trying to do
what's
this one
[Music]
right yeah yeah
now this bit what's this bit too trying
to do
yeah what's this trying to do oh i'm
checking that
keys
yeah the key the number of keys is
number of distinct characters in the
window right in the substring if it's
more than two then we need to remove it
from the left hand side to take it out
of the window right
correct
yeah
let's keep moving the left inside to
make the window smaller to make the
substring smaller because now what i
have what we have got like abb
uh abc look
we want the two and those two we want to
substring uh distinct characters now we
have three so what what happened if keep
moving this
what happened it will you
if we keep moving at this point to the
right what happened
let's distinct characters will not
reduce right will not decrease right
yeah because we already have three
characters if you keep adding
yeah it will keep adding so how can we
fix this
we move the left hand side right
you're looking at me a lot we keep
moving and then am i right yeah yeah
okay that's why i'm moving yeah
okay
and the eyes are updating here okay
that's it for today good job bye