hello
hello mr eric mr mommy miss mommy
uh today we talk about
intervals okay intervals
so we want to find out we're given a
list of intervals we want to find out
the most uh frequent numbers in the
range and if there's a tie we need to
return the smallest number let's give an
example okay like one to two
okay let's draw
draw
draw a line okay this is x so let's say
one to two okay
this one this is the square bracket
means
inclusive right
and what's this mean
what's this
parentheses
exclusive remember yeah cheaper yeah
cheaper you do it like that but what i'm
talking about is
well yeah exclusive right
yeah
okay so
we only find uh
in this giveaway intervals there's only
one uh integers right we want uh it only
contains the integer so one two so we
put it one here two three ah right one
two so two numbers one two okay and
okay if this is one three
three
okay one three
okay so what's the most frequent number
in this range one three
one and two and then as
we said we want to return the smallest
number if that's the red time so we
return one
got it do you understand this problem
yeah
how are we doing this the same thing as
you did so what i'm doing here good job
what i'm doing here
setting on the numbers right and we mark
we need to mark the counter so look it's
one two
so what happened if we want to one two i
plus one here right right
and then i need to plus one here but i
need to minus one uh i i need to restore
the previous one right
and then look at one three plus one
plus one
plus one okay
so if we use the dictionary right if we
use the dictionary to remember that
intervals so what i mean the in
remembering interface is that given the
start point we said this uh if you
traditionally speak we set a star
plus equal one
and the end
and the n plus one look if it's d
n plus one the endpoint look if it's one
two and i need to drop to the previous
previous level we have previous counter
at a three because it doesn't that
interval does not continue at three we
need to minus equals one right
so then if we have uh counters scanning
if you if we have a line just imagine if
this line
right sweeping from the left to the
right and every time we meet
we increment we accumulate the counter
right and at this point then we can
we know
the number of times that number appears
ln
number right yeah
get it do you want me to explain it more
one more time look
so
given this one two one three okay i have
a decision right d1 plus equals one so d
t is a dictionary okay
d1
plus equals 1 so 1
1 right
t 1 the n is 2 2 plus 1 is three so d3
minus equals one so three will be minus
equals one right
correct okay one
d1 plus equals one
two here right
and d4 right before minus equals one
right that's the data that's the data
structure and now we go through from the
left to right look and we have a counter
like c
c added equals two we add the values
here equals two now so you become two
and then
minus one it'll become one
and minus one you'll become one right
okay so
minus one
oh yeah minus one equals zero okay so
look
here
there are two
what does it mean by two two is the
number of is the numbers that appear on
that vertical line right
right
right so at the beginning is zero so one
would mean two two is the most frequent
most frequent numbers right
so there are numbers appearing
twice
so it's one and two here right
and here
if one minus one will be one one here
it means that uh as not as three number
three it only appears once
there's only one number on whatever ones
am right okay
so so we are looking for the maximum
when we when we only see
so this is turned on offset yeah so
we go through the left to the right we
add it to
we minus one we minus one for the c so c
will be the
value of the numbers that appear on that
moment okay
so we're looking for the maximum
right if we we meet the maximum we
remember the number at the point and
that would be
the most frequent
number most frequent
and smallest number okay if there's a
type
is it a bit tricky to understand
don't worry i can explain more if you
don't understand
a little bit more right yeah okay that's
fine look
uh i'm going to
do this again okay look
so
so let's let's do this here look okay
interval one two another interval one
three
all right
zero here
one
two
three
four
okay so now
d1 this is style i i'm processing this
interval d1 plus equals one
what does that mean if i put the d1 plus
equals one what does it mean plus equals
one it means that at the point at number
one
yeah
we are having a one integer right one
more integer at that interval right
because let's that's what the interval
covers here
right
all right so d1 plus equals one it means
that okay at this point i would go up
the number will go up by one
right and d e plus one look at the
endpoint plus one it means that d3
at the number three the level will be
restored to the previous so it will be
minus one
right d3
minus one so let's have this d
subdictionary default dictionary in type
so
one
the number one
plus equals one will be one
and then d3 will be
three
will be minus one at the beginning is
zero minus one and then look another
interval d1 plus equals one
yeah so another interval covers this
interval right so d1 plus equal one but
now d3
d4 right three plus equal uh
three actually for these four e plus one
minus equals one
okay
so and
is here f3 okay so it's d
e one plus equals one that will be
becoming two
and then t3 minus equals one
uh d4 minus equal one four will be minus
one
so this is kind of a change the value is
the change
the key
the key would be the num num number
numbers on this assets
and the value will be the change
okay my chain so if i put this change it
will be uneasy to understand right so
so if i have a line sweeping line
sweeping
line sweeping
if you have a line sweeping from the
left the smallest to the right just
imagine a line sweeping yeah
when we have we we add the change here
at one we change two right
all right at the beginning is zero and
at one we change it to two so what does
it mean at this moment
there are two numbers
at least nine moment okay
okay and then i go to three
minus one
so the value will be
one right so what does it mean so at
this point there are only one number
covered
right
which is one one two three display look
at the previous interval one two is gone
it's finished here right
and then i go to four another length
another minus one
what does it mean it becomes zero again
right it means
no numbers
being
covered
being found in the interval
make sense
now it makes sense yeah okay let's write
the code
so we use the default dictionary
remember what's the
uh what's the
what's the difference between default
dictionary and an easy dictionary
what's the difference
it has this key thing yeah
this is the key thing so
if the key is not existent in the
default station that's okay the computer
won't screen won't complain you will
just give a default value if the integer
will be zero but if this if this d is
declared like that if there is nothing
here and you say d
one plus equals one
that's a problem because t one
the computer can find d one in the
dictionary right your screen but it's
okay if you if you define additionally
as the default additional integer the
key is not existing at the beginning but
the computer will treat it as zero
before that's what default com comes
into play okay
okay let's do it
define
most frequent number yeah most frequent
in the interval let's say interval let's
say
i because i okay
d
equals default
decimal default d right
in
because the value is the change and it's
the integer type
okay then we go through the numbers
right
four
star
and
in i okay can you tell me what to do i
write one and you tell me okay d
s
what
d s one
remember the change at this installer
interval we need to go out right
so what what is that
um
go up by one plus equals one where that
plus equals one and then one to the top
t
what minor is equals one t what
um
e
is it dropping an e or the next one
remember look one to two
two still has is the same right but when
the three
you'll drop right so it should be d e y
plus plus one yeah next one plus okay
now we have a counter we need to have a
counter which is the
uh we set the most most counter yeah
equals zero at the beginning is zero
yeah
and now we need to go uh have this
answer
answer at the beginning is number right
and then we go to the
sorry it doesn't matter it's numb
because at the beginning yeah
or you can put it as
zero it doesn't matter
okay good job c equals here this is
accumulate right remember we have nine
sweeping from left to right we use the c
to accumulate the answer right now we
need to go through that
go through our conditional so for
what i
in
salted
right we need to salt it sauteed
remember sausage is the key
keys
d dot keys right keys
and then i i have to to accumulate c
plus equal
d
i right right
yeah
so this is the number this is the value
the numbers that appearing on that
vertical line right
so now look if
c bigger than most right
what does this mean if we are founding
if we're finding a number which appears
more than the current one right so we
set it most equals to c
i know we need because the first time
from left to right we first time we find
the bigger
uh
more appearing numbers that could be the
answer then we need to update the answer
answer equal
equal one
what what's the number at the time
and then return
what's the time complexity for this one
what's the times on xt
[Music]
what's the something like
what's n
[Music]
yeah the number of intervals the number
of intervals what's the stakes from
christie
make sense
um well
a little bit
yeah so which part you'll not
particularly understand
you do not particularly understand i can
explain
a little bit more
well
i'm fine that's fine so you sure
yeah yeah yeah
i'm going to test you if you're
confident
yeah
that's okay come on okay
okay so look i'm going to
i'm going to do what i'm going to erase
this bit
let's do what should we do here
and
what should we do here
okay so there are two parts
here
and here okay do you want to come over
and write it up
okay
remember remember i have a
interval here right zero one two three
so what happens if we have a line
sweeping from the left to the right um
yeah
plus equal one
and then one two yeah star for example
is here and what happens when we need to
go back to
the ui
yeah
what
one
and then we need to accumulate have a
line sweeping i'm here have a line
sweeping from left to right and every
time
we
stall the chance so we have a c which is
like represent the current yeah yeah c
1. um we need to add a change right
at equal
which is the change i is the numbers i
know what change is available and what
what are you doing here you stole the
change here
so what
d b
what yeah yeah
yeah
i
okay that's it good job today good job
good job bye