hello mr mr ryan are you all right today
good okay so today we talked about
another problem in the metric okay
metric
so look at this metric okay i have leave
so this is the four times five five
times four matrix so can you find the
largest area whatever
that's the largest area of the square
metric square square
you know it has to be square
yes square yeah that's what i was gonna
say yeah so that's nine right but i
could also be sixteen
no why is it sixteen right that's
assistant no you can't find any sixteen
right the ones means that
you can't include the zero yeah one we
want to find the largest square largest
largest square subnet sheet okay
submetric
some magic
yeah with one yeah with one
okay
the problem is clear yeah
how can we do this how can we do this
right any thoughts any sort we can do
this
how can we pull first
by using a brief booth how can we go
first
so we're going to check every square
right okay so that's it we want to try
yeah proof of work okay
we're done perform
so we try we can how can we pull first
we proof of each
okay we when we meet when we have one
yeah
we try to brute force
the metric
just
yeah if this is one right look at me
come on if it is one we try to blue
force the matrix the square metric
starting the left top left corner equals
one right and we start to expand it
yeah if it is all ones
if it is all once we update the answer
and yeah we want to have account
account to update the answer all right
so what what's the code would be like so
for r
for r in range
row for c in range column right
and if matching
rc equal one then we can start we can
start the size yeah we can say say four
for size s equal s range from one two
to one two three four minutes
to the minimum of uh uh you know when it
reaches border right and then we need to
check this metric with the size s so we
we start with the coordinate rc
and we size we start increasing right
size from
what one to
something to something yeah to something
we can put it infinity but actually it's
not infinity i just said something yeah
i didn't know it all right do you
understand me and i will check if if all
informatics and this
if this is geometric it contains all
ones if it's all once then we update the
answer so what's the time complexity if
you if i don't write a curve if i just
tell you this is providing what's the
thumbnail
um
this is look we iterate with oic i can't
see but we need to check these
metrics yeah check the battery so what i
don't know
so look if it is magic here
i don't know what did you call the
matrix
what's imagine that it doesn't matter
look at you release this size ah another
eye
drake's name a matrix metric name
m for example
no m matrix it has r
column c
and so look at you look
just give one example look if you if you
start from the top left corner right and
that's a one and then
for each
you uh you want to check if all the r
rows and c columns are one so you need
to take another one c times right
right checking would take polacy
right and then each one could be one if
we can consider a metric containing all
one right
right this is a very special case we we
need to go through each pizza right
because each pizza is one
all right
and for each pizza i want to check if
the largest what is the largest sub
metric right so i need to expand this
right look for here i need to explain it
so let's analyze it so
together is all r squared c squared
got it it's very slow right if i see you
speak
make sense
yeah make sense yeah make sense
so we can do this we can the thing is
that why this is slow because every time
yeah every time you're checking you're
checking
you you have this duplicate checking
right because look if i check these
if i check this this is not matching
it's all one and then when i check this
method
i already know this is a
matrix right so i have to but i have to
check it again so it's duplicated you
get it yeah so for example i'm here at
this one ah i'm ready to spawn okay
everything's here yeah
alexa
okay i want to check this big this
moment okay okay all ones good i know
it's a square metric or four but now i
want to check here
so i i still need to check here the
small one right right i want to check
all the one so it's duplicate duplicate
effort to check in uh suck some metric
okay
so we can save it so we can
we don't want to repeatedly do that
again and again because that's slow so
in some way we want to use the dynamic
programming to save
the intermediate result okay so how can
we do this we can create a metric of dp
pp array right
with the same size if r
our column row sequence we want to
create a metric with r rows c columns
which is the same size right and then
what does it mean
it means that
it means that from the
this this means that the deep array
the submetric the area from zero zero
from top left corner to
rc yeah dprc
in this area the largest the largest
the largest sum square summit
doesn't make sense eric
so this this number here represents the
largest
largest square
some metric yeah
if we we if we define it as the side
right left side is and how can we get
the area
so if a square has the side n what's its
area
it's easy question side eq
right
ryan ryan
it's a sub square which is side of 4
what is area
16 yeah okay if the square is n what's
the size what's that area
well done good job yeah n square okay so
let's store it as n
the the side the largest side right so
now
now look if i'm here i'm here
i'm here okay i i'm going to process
this one
so i i already know the largest square
here right and if this is one this is
one this is one this one
then the answer would be the minimum of
these three points plus one right so
look i want to update this this dpr plus
one
r plus one and c plus one right if if
this is one right
if this is one and this is one
and this is one
so what what what can i get i can the
answer of dpr plus one
is the minimum
it's the minimum of all these
and then plus one right
yeah because i can extend i can just
extend it by one right i can extend it
by one because it's all one right got it
[Music]
yeah this is the dp array and db zero
zero if it is zero what happened if this
kind of point is zero then dp rc is zero
right because there is no point
am i right
does that make sense
yeah yeah
so can we convert it can we write it
okay let's write it okay
define
largest
symmetric soft square magic
okay and
and then let's say
ah
c equals length m
and column will be length and m y
and what
come on what's the columns of m
and lens of m1 put that number here
put the number
yeah we're done
oh now i'm going to create a dp array
dpri equals
at the beginning cl for underscore in
range
range columns right the columns
and then
for
in range m
so this creates a this creates uh
what is this two d what's this two dp
array this creates one a two dimensional
array which contains all zero and then
you'll be
you'll be the same size of m right so
you'll be arrows
arrows and c columns arrows
and c columns
okay and all zero or zero
okay so now i just need to go through
each one for r in range r
four c in
range
c right
right okay i go through this one and if
if what
if matrix
ah c
equal equal
zero right if current is zero what does
it mean
yeah it means that well
it means what there's no magic ending
okay so let's dp already
i mean
make a mistake dprc means what 0.000 so
it means that when it ends
so that that is square metric ending and
ending at rc here right ending at rc
okay at this area so if mrc equals zero
then we need to set dp
rc equals one
if this point if this is zero can it be
um can you form a
square matrix and then this one
no so we set it to
zero
as the s is one right now we
also we have answer answer equals zero
we want to written the answer which is
the answer will be written answer times
answer okay einstein times two angle
square the answer is the largest side
note area and the area is time is square
right
okay then
and what should we do if r bigger than
zero
and
c bigger than zero okay right
and one and then you can say
m
r minus one c equals equal one right and
yeah look i'm at this point rc
i'm at at least point one okay here this
is rc
and then i have a few yeah metric here
i'm at this point
right so if it's bigger than zero if
it's if it's bound if it's on the
boundary here or here
you come from a
bigger magic right because it's on the
boundary but at other points places
i want to check this one
it's this one this is one this is this
one and then i want to if these these
three are all ones yeah
and
r c minus one equal equal one and and
can you what's this point and one
what
one more what's this
r minus one and c minus one right look
this is rc
equals the mean
mean of which three numbers
which is numbers
it will be dp mean of dp
r plus minus 1c
and dp
rc minus 1
and dpy can you tell me the third one
come on dpr minus 1 um r minus one c r c
minus one what's this one
minus one
c one is one yeah
i want to get a minimum of these ending
these and then what do what
plus one right plus one yeah
plus one
and once i plus one i
at this point here i i can do this
answer equals
maximum
answer
dp
rc right so i can i learn can
get the
largest square lattice side of this of
the answer right and then return this
yeah got it so this is the dp function
plus one so why is it first because we
already know
yeah we already know
when we want to calculate these right we
already know what happened in the
previous one we already know what
happened
previous one
that previous one
so square matching i just added one a
little bit right
yeah got it
yeah
okay so now uh what's the time
complexity if you look at this curve
how many loops how many loops are there
um there are
two two so our
square
times
what's the space complexity
are there any space
are we using a space dp array yeah so
what's your term also space complexity
okay can you explain to me why we put
the answer answer equals max answer dprc
what are these two because we need to
find the biggest square biggest square
ending yeah what's what could be the
biggest square it could be the biggest
square could be ending at
rc each location ending at large
location right okay
yeah
okay and then we pretend why why this is
new answer time times what does this
is
largest largest side of the square right
right now we need to turn some to what
is good because we have one sine of
square u and
the other side yeah it's the formula to
compute the area given the side right
like
if
if a square the side has five and then
its area is five times right yeah that's
what exactly is that does it okay and
what was this part
if mrc if this is a zero what does it
mean if it is the zero why we need to
set dprc equals zero
because
if it just
it wouldn't be yeah the
the side of anything at rc
there's no right because you can't look
this is zero i want to add there is no
way to find a metric which ends here
right because this is zero right there
is no
no way to to construct a matrix
equilibrium ending at this point which
is zero right right great
that's why we set it to zero correct
this makes sense
okay dprc is the dynamic programming
right yeah zero for range and c columns
and then subreddit of magic yeah
okay a little bit okay thank you good
job today bye bye say bye