hello
hello are you all right mr eric mr ryan
okay
so today we talk about another problem
which is called the longest substring
yeah we know the longest substrate
remember a few days ago we talked about
a long distance with at least two
distinct characters remember yeah and we
use the two sliding windows and yeah
sliding window okay so today we'll talk
about a similar problem with longest
substring
but we want to make sure that each
character in a substring has at least k
with at least k
at least k characters
what does that even mean
okay at least k times appearing at least
k times okay let me give you an example
a b c c d d e f g if this is s is the
is this string yeah and if k equals two
k equals two what does it mean
so what what kind of substring can you
find in in in in this given string
a lot a lot and which one yeah can you
find the one which has the longest
it's the longest and every character
appears at least two times
so every character every character
appears at least k times so for example
like
is this a requirement a b c c
by the way the exception is continuous
right yeah substring
but subsequently it's not sufficient
subsequent you can pick a c
d f g here
subsequence is the
seek is a string that you delete one or
more
characters from the original string yeah
you can delete one or more and it
becomes a substrate but we are talking
about a substring a subsequent uh
we have talking about a substring okay
subsequence is
you delete one or more character from
the original that becomes the
subsequence but substring is that you it
has to be continuous right so look this
is a substring a b c c and can you tell
me if they are at least
if each character in the substrate
appears at this place
because a appears one b appear one c
yeah okay so we want to look for the z
d
okay c c d d
this is longest we're done yeah yeah
because each one appears at least twice
right
and then it's longest you can find
anymore which is
uh longer than that right yeah
so how can we do this with the suction
you know
every problem
almost every problem yeah with a
substring the first idea is to do what
yeah performing because what we can
easily perform right what's the time
complexity to prove for the substrate
substring look if this is a string
what's the
how do we profess the substring
how do we profess a substring proof of
the substring
how do you profess it
um we just check everything sliding yeah
the substring is to have a flow index
and two index yeah
from index to index for the position
when it starts and the partition when
the substring ends so we can blue force
this right
so for if if length is n then we can do
this for i in range
n and for j in range
range i or for j in range i
n right okay so let's in o n square
right
yeah
okay so once we have a substring we can
check if it if each character appears at
least k times how can we check it
remember how can you check it
um
when we said we want to count the number
of characters
appearing in a substring in a string
what kind of data structure what kind of
uh
thing we can use to do this to count to
count what's that counter yeah okay so
let's implement this proof of thing
first okay
defy okay let's just call it foo
sk
so n equals length actually first we
don't want to get the lens of the string
yeah eric what you're doing
so we want to
so how can we write the blue first thing
come on come on
four
for i
in range n right
this is the left part yeah and then
sit there please so i can talk to you
see that please
ryan can you see that
for j
in range
[Music]
there are two ways of writing you can
write okay so if
the string is s i j plus one so
i and where that i said okay or if it
you can do it if j
i
plus one right then you can
call j in range i okay
it's just almost the same right
okay so now what's this what's the
substring x equals s
i to j plus one right
all right so this is the substring now
we want to check if the substring
contains any scaling numbers then we put
it in the counter c equals counter
counter x
right
yeah now we have a counter so
see the value
if it's the substring seed of values so
how can we check if all those characters
appear at least k times using the seed
of values
remember what's in the counter how the
keys are the numbers yeah uh
them unless characters yeah
and the values will be what the number
of times they appear right
and if the minimum of c the values is
still bigger than k or equal in k
what does that mean
what does that
mean if mean
see the values
bigger than k bigger than equals k what
does it mean
it means what
what does it mean if the values the
minimum values look as i said the keys
are the number of the characters and the
values are the number of times they
appear right in the substring right in a
string if the minimum of the values is
bigger than k what does that mean
it means that it's not
there is what that is what there is one
each character appears what i leave
yeah yeah and then we want to remember
that longest answer equals zero and
answer equals one
maximum answer and then what's the
length of the sun string
[Music]
j minus or length x or you can say j
minus i plus one right
yeah
and return answer yeah
what's the time complexity come on
[Music]
square
overlays
yeah look don't forget this this is our
inquiry what's the space complexity
[Music]
any space we are using yeah there
when we say counter we we are using
space right you can see because we
decide the notebook thing oh and yeah
right yeah that's slime let's go
can we do better
okay so again this one okay
a b
b c c d
b
e f g okay k equals two okay k equals
two so what's the longest okay what's
the longest what's the longest substring
that every character appears at least
two
what's the longest you can find b b c c
d d
yeah you see
okay so now if i said
if i i know a character if i know a
character look if i know a character
which it only appears
once less than k times can it be
included in the longest substring
it's like e f g
a
include in the final longest substring
no that's right because we are looking
for the string that can every every
character appear at least can't have
right so this is at least
every every one
no
no characters appear
at least k times good job then empty
string
yeah
okay so look because we're looking for
every every character they appear at
least k times then if we find out
if we find out
this character is appears less than 10
times right less than k times
so it cannot be included in the final
string so what does it mean
so it means that i i can we we can split
the the string into this character so
let's do this look
um maybe this is not very good number
let me look at another example okay
let's play
say a
k equals three okay
a b b c c c
what's the answer that appears what's
the what's this answer for every
substring the wrong substring that
appears
before each character in the substring
appears at least three times what's this
can you give me what's that um
[Music]
that's the only substring that uh
satisfy this requirement okay so look at
it
yeah yeah if what if
if if let's say let's say look there's
loads of a's
yeah that looks
like what i'm saying is that look if
look at this a
it's a what does it count how many it
appears in the whole string one it's so
it's less than k right yeah
so it's let's say okay so we can divide
this a into two half two times
right we can divide this into two
because what
what does it mean because we can we can
divide it by a look at this release
another a here and another a
and then a yeah okay
so so
look a as i said a cannot be included in
the final string right because it only
appears less than twice three times
right yeah
so we can split the string the entire
string in by a
so we have what we have b
c c c
d d e right we have we we have these
right
yeah
because a which you can just ignore it
right because it can be
included by the in the final string
right so b
so the answer will be the maximum of the
recursion we solve the left part so
solve this part right we have to get it
so we have a function to solve this
problem and then we now split more than
two
yeah yeah but what we talked about
more
than
two parts yeah even more than two pi
that's okay we for each part look we
have another but we have if that we say
we have k equals four okay and then we
have another a here
okay a a still appears three times and
then we can split into c c c and
and d e right yeah three part so what
does this mean the answer
the answer
the answer is the longest substring with
every character appearing at this k time
must be in this kind of yeah
in these we just need to solve these
three parts right and how to resolve
these three five we can do this
recursively right so we are dividing the
program bigger problem into the smaller
one
yeah
this makes sense and then the answer
will be the maximum of all the
the
the solution to the sub problem right
okay
yeah
if we can't find any character if we can
find any character less less than k then
if every character appearing at at least
k time then what's the
longest
substring
if we can't find if we can't divide it
into the one group so what's the
what's the
mean so if look if it goes through this
if k equals one okay at least one time a
b c d e
and g so what's the longest substring
of that's what i'm saying if you can't
find any invalid we call this invalid
character yeah if we can't find any
invalid character then we determine the
length of the current longest because
this is that's the requirement yeah
got it so first of all the question is
the accuracy simple first of all
we go through we use the counter to
count the number of characters and then
the number of times they appear right
and then we go through these invalid
invalid characters and divide you and
include these by these inventive
specifier using a split
slit by these characters
and then the answer will be the maximum
of all these
sub problems
okay
yeah
okay that's do it so it'll be easier to
write and then
this agreement is quite elegant right
define
sk
okay so how can we
check look if look c equals counter
first of all we check the counter as
right
and then we need to go through each
character for our
the
let's say the key and value we have key
and value
in
see the items
yes what's see the items see the items
return a pair a tuple key and value the
keys under the character right and the
value hour
and the value hour i said the key key
value player what's key keys number of
these keys and characters and the value
what are the values
in the counter remember what are we
trying to do here
we're trying to um
reinforce yeah i know what what i mean
is the counter if you use the counter
object
a a b c so what does it contain what
does it give us counter you kill a
dictionary
a
what
b
one
c
[Music]
one okay so key value you see the
yeah yeah yeah i know see the items
it return the tuper
a
two
b one
c one okay so k is these the keys so the
v what's the v
hey you haven't did the keyboard on the
c
yeah yeah i know i know what's what's
the value
what's this what does that mean um how
much time how many times they appear in
the original stream so these how many
times they appear in the string
okay so v
if v
smaller than k right what does that mean
yeah if we found this k
k character yeah this is an invalid
character because it appears less than k
times right
yeah now we need to do a split file yeah
we need we can specify it right so this
s dot
split
spring work kov
b
[Music]
k
k v is the value yeah we split by it and
then we're calling the cell fool right
right
split by
split by k
uh so we want to return we can return
maximum
of foo
i
yeah for i
so i'm calling it for i k
for
i
in
s dot split
strip spring one three
oh we use another case so
let's not use the k here
uh
c okay let's use the c okay
c
for i k is the number of times it needs
to be at least a k times then c is the
character so we want to split like c
right
so we we have s dot split by c it it you
will split the string by the inverticule
you actually remove the invalid
characters and then for each inver uh
each
remember if this is a yeah do you
remember a if only appears
up here if k equals three
a only appears twice look at this
right so s dot x split by a so we have
three groups and we want to find out the
answer
the maximum of the answer to these three
sub sub problems which is four i k for i
in that right
yeah
and if we can't find this we return what
retirement if we if retirement nothing
if we can't split if we we can't find
any character which is
less than k it means all characters are
appearing at most k at least k time so
we'll determine what
whatever
return what come on
i said k equals one and a b c d e
what's the longest i just say acid oh
wait so okay so look if we can't find
any character left is smaller than k
so it means at here at this point
the whole string appear satisfy this
requirement which is every character
appears at least k time so we need to
return the current length of the string
which is what length
okay
yeah remember the previous angle is o
and
qb right yeah and for this one it's one
it's o and
o and one square right is that one
square
it's kind of open square yeah yeah this
is
still quite slow but it's better it's
far better yeah is it
still quite slow
why is it quite slow uh
look we first of all look at abc's
first of a string we go through this one
time right and then we split by these
by this and we do this again and again
do this
right go this so
yeah
okay
actually i think i think it's on yes
yeah pretty good yeah
especially if it is the
s if it only contains the
for example if it contains the lowercase
characters
so
there's only
at most o 26 n if we can do this
alternative six then which is one right
yeah
okay
got it because these see those items yes
these are items groupie you only group
it
once right okay
okay so which one
do we um you can remember
none of them none of them okay so let me
let me
write this okay so again so can you
explain to me what's these dividends
divide and conquer we call it divide and
conquer
[Music]
look this is the dividing conga first of
all we divide this problem into a few
sub problems
and now we solve this it's like location
we solve these
smaller problems right
okay
does it make sense
yeah
so we have a bigger problem and then in
order to solve this bigger problem we
can divide it into three small problems
in order to solve this problem we can
further divide it that's what it means
the first of all how do we divide we
first of all find a
invalid character which is less than k
times right because we are based on this
assumption that this invalid character
cannot be included in any
substring right it cannot be included in
any substring that's why
that's why i want
that's why we can use it to as the split
so when we split look if this is a we
split it
a cannot be included in the longest
substring so i can take it out right if
any substring included a
what does it mean
it cannot be the longest substring right
it cannot be the substring that
uh let's satisfy this at the current so
we take it out
so the the answer could be the longest
option could be in three parts could be
in here could be in here or it could be
in here and look yeah we know how to
solve this smaller problem right and
here we can
until if we find us
if if we if we can't find any invalid
character we just return the length of
the substring right
got it and this is your location divide
and conquer yeah got it
okay good job that's all for today good
job bye