hello
hello mr mr ryan how are you today
so remember uh how to reverse a sentence
a string remember how to reverse the
center it's very simple yeah
reverse
reverse the string how do you reverse
the string come on
um
and how do we reverse it in position
column column minus one yeah yeah
we want to implement that reverse how
can we reverse it look if this is
e-i-i-c-a like how do you reverse it you
become m-c-r-i-r-a
okay so how do we reverse this
how do we reverse this bit
we just use the two-pointer two-pointer
yeah pointing to the left and front in
the right remember
yeah and swapping this you become
c-r-i-e and then we move it
towards each other yeah and not stop it
as long as the two meet two pointers one
meeting each other right so it becomes
gi
uh okay
okay so today's task is quite similar so
we want to reverse the
only letters only the letters in the
string so for example like uh
uh
a b
a b dash
dot c d and
we want to reverse it it will become
what
we'll be coming
okay so it's similar so for example e
eric
uh
[Music]
we want to reverse this bit yeah so we
want to reverse this bit so look at me
okay
i if i change it here to e and i put it
here and right
but these i want to keep it in place and
ah
i will swap with a right
so a
so every noun lowercase character we
just keep it right and then ask what we
see
okay
so what just happened
backwards what just happened these these
this
lowercase character or state assignment
all our lowercase uh
[Music]
you know the english letters will be
swapped okay we'll be reversed correct
yeah yeah
so how do we do this how do we do this
we use
of course yeah yeah we use the two
points but we need to add one more
object we want to skip the noun
[Music]
english letters right we want to skip
the non-english letter
okay
so look look can you can you yeah so it
should be as i demonstrated so when we
have this note i
uh when we
we will skip
the non-english letters until we have
the english letters and then we have
still have two pointers thingy and we
swap it and then we
move two pointers towards each other
until they meet in the middle right yeah
so this is the only trick right let's
define
reverse
only letters yeah
yeah
s
okay
so the left to right i
j at the beginning will become zero to
length s right minus one right okay
yeah
i
the left pointer j the rightmost pointer
is the length as the size of the s minus
one okay look
wire
am smaller than j right when these two
pointers are not meeting each other in
the middle right okay
so now we want to skip that pointer
until we meet
the english letter right
alphabet so look how do we check if it's
a letter in
a
character is alphabet
right any idea
what's called f alphabet a
to z lowercase
o
a to z uppercase right
yes yeah
so how do we check it we can just check
okay okay we can check we receive bc
equals s i right
right
yeah and we can just check look we can
do what if c
if c
if we see right if a small you can write
it if a is smaller than z and c
smaller equals z
i or
like oh using more right
a
bigger c
smaller than bigger z yeah
this is one way to do it right
yeah
what's the ascii code of a come on
what's the ascii code of a
what's this
what
is 96 no
why every time you remember 96 97
what's this
um 65 whatever
so you another way is you can say if all
all the other these yeah or the bc is
this is the number you can say is bigger
than 97 and smaller than what what's
this what's this if this is 97 what's
the d
what's the z
what's the z if this is
yes 26 26 minus one
okay that's one way one another way
of checking this is using a function
which is very similar which one
if look if c is this yeah you can say if
c
that's it that would be the same thing
as checking if this
is character between a to z okay
lowercase or and all uppercase right so
let's so we want to skip the
the look uh we want to skip the num
alpha letters yes
we want to skip the num alpha letters
yes so hopefully we do this
we can do another wire
wire i smaller than j
and
not
a i
s i
dot is alpha right
uh it's alpha to what i know what should
we do i
if me if i is smaller than j
n
s i is not alpha letter now we want to i
know
equal one okay and another one we want
to move the right product so can you
tell me similarly
y
i smaller than j
and what
and not what s z
dot is alpha right it's the same yeah
after this problem what's happening i
and j pointing to the
english letter right pointing to for
example this is e
right maybe some here and then this this
is r maybe here yeah pointing to some
characters and now what do we need to do
what do we need to do
what do we need to do with this
how do we swap the characters and s i
this is s i and this is s j how do you
swap
we it a new thing
you can do it but in person you can do
it you know how to describe it's like a
d copy thing
a equals one b equals to how can we swap
a and b
[Music]
oh
what do we need to do now if i swap the
si and sj what do we need to do now
um we need to
we need to keep moving towards your
let's say what
i
plus equals one
and
j minus
okay so this s is is a string we can't
do this because string is immutable so
how can we do this we can do this uh we
can put a uh
answer equals we can break it into uh uh
an array right list s
right and now
it's okay here then we can do this
instead of s we do this answer okay
let's just put it a
a equals a
we swap it a or a is an array
right we we we can do this a or x it
doesn't matter again here and then we
turn one we can join
[Music]
join a right now
okay what's the time complexity come on
the letters this is the number of the
number of letters in the string
yeah what's the space complexity
look we are if we're using the list here
oh n yes or n because look
in a string look if a equal
look if a equals eric right this is a
string string immutable what's immutable
you can't change it so it means that i
can't do with i can't i can't a zero
equals
x i come to this right look i can't
change it because string is immutable so
that's why i need to do this list as
what's this as to break the string into
internal array so what what's that look
alright look
so this this uh area what does it give
us
what's uh this area you give us one and
the list brackets the bracket of
each character e
ah i
and c right if it's a list then i can
change it right i can swap it i know i'm
just swapping i use what which one
i can join
yeah
[Music]
oh
i
plus equals one yeah
j
minus equal one
okay and at least at last we want to
convert a to a string
we tend what how do we
return uh these in the dream return
return
join
what does that mean
what's this one here what's here
alpha is alpha what's what's what does
that mean the last question what's this
mean
it's alpha what does it mean
string
e
what does it
can you tell me what's these two the
value returned by these two
[Music]
there are two votes that's it yeah if
not if it's not an english letter we
keep incrementing it look moving
and if you're not implementing uh if
it's not ingredients that i would keep
going there okay what you're doing
okay that's it for today bye bye