hello hello mr mr ryan are you right
yes
okay so i have a
list of numbers yeah i have this numbers
like uh
3 2
20. literally
and i want you to pick
two numbers if look k numbers k equals
two i only i want you to pick k numbers
and then the difference i want to i want
you to find out the minimum
difference between
the highest and the lowest
of these two numbers
am i clear with this problem
so first of all pick two numbers yeah
from these
how many ways can you pick two numbers
if you're going to
early approve of him yeah if we want to
proof of this problem
then we need to pick two numbers out of
for example this is n numbers right
and numbers
good question it doesn't have to be here
good question you know
so what difference does it make we want
to pick two number k numbers right
we want to pick k numbers out of it and
we want to find out the maximum the
maximum
and minus minimum of these k numbers
yeah k number let's do it uh
if we saw it
good question okay
okay good solution maybe good guess so
look we also pk
okay so look we have to pk numbers and
then they make a
and we want to find out okay so when we
pick the k numbers we know the maximum
the highest
and the lowest
of that array yeah yeah right yeah yeah
let's say this this is the difference
and we want to minimize
minimize the difference
okay
we want to minimize the difference so
what's your approach
you mentioned yeah so look
first of all we can talk about the
profiling how can we put the force there
are n numbers
n numbers and we want to pick two
numbers
how many ways i'm doing like remember
the poc will use the plc
yeah p or c which one
pix p2 num p pick k numbers out of n is
it p or c what's p what's c remember
yeah we are done what's p
permutation
and what's c
combination right
so combination does not have order use
the c p has a
order right complete com combination
means that look if i want to pick n
numbers out of k p
and then
then one and i will i this is the
complexity we pick b c and k numbers out
of n and then we want to find out the
the maximum and the minimum of lowest k
numbers so that's o n times n right
times times times k because they're k
numbers right
so the complexity will be this o c n k
times k what was the mk c n k is picking
k numbers out of n and it would be equal
as well
n factorial
divided by
k bacteria
and n minus k factorial okay so that's
the formula to calculate it you don't
need to remember but you have to know
that it's quite complicated if this yeah
see
picking
one apple out of three how many ways of
doing that
picking one apple after three apples
three picking two apples out of three
first how many ways
three yeah we're done look so let you
remember this here
n n equals c n
n minus m yeah because every time you
pick one apple you also have a way of
picking two levels right because
every time you separate one apple and
then they took that solution for two
years
is this can we do better you mentioned
about sorting yeah how how do you come
up with this clever solution huh
if we saw this original number you can
just look with first thing and then just
drag the left yeah so if we saw the
number
so if we saw this number what's the
order
2 3
10 20. if we if we by the way if we saw
the numbers what's the time complexity
if there are n numbers
[Music]
we're done okay oh and again we can use
the quick solve much solved you know
yeah those solutions are all in logan
but if we go for bubble sorting yeah
simple soaking that will be oh
and square right well usually
so look this number and we only pick two
numbers
pick two numbers so we can go through
this yeah yeah
what's the difference between these two
numbers
the highest in the noise
what's this
one one three seven
ten i can't do it okay what's the
minimum
one one yeah that's it yeah correct why
this solution is working why because why
can you imagine if we solve these
numbers and we pick the lowest and the
highest we want to minimize it right so
if you want to minimize it we want this
number to be 20 is the highest yeah but
i want to find the distance the third is
the minimum the maximum and minimum
minimum maximum and minimum of k numbers
if we pick 10 and 20
the maximum is 20 the minimum is 10 the
difference is 10 right
so if we pick 20 and we pick one what's
the difference
19. you see you see the difference so we
why this solution is working because we
want to we want to make sure these k
numbers
stay as close as possible so how do we
make sure those numbers stay as close as
possible
we sort it right if we sort it
right this number look if we pick two
numbers if we pick three numbers what's
the shortest distance one the thirteen
distance here right
yeah because look ten minus one is
always bigger than three minus one
because we after sorting these numbers
stay close to each other right so look
if we saw this original uh array we use
o and log n
right and then we pick k numbers so we
just need to try
the pairs right the highest right but
every we we divide this certain array
into
groups of k so like that like that like
that and we just try
the the brightness the highest the
maximum and the minimum
we calculate the difference and we keep
doing that we store that we update the
minimum right okay that's it
so let's try the code if you can
you know today's code code is pressing
but if you can implement it you'll be
just two lines
to learn yeah
mean
it has
mean k different yeah different let's
say numbers
and then k right i think
okay so which one the first one we need
to solve the numbers the num stocks what
sort yeah we're done it's going to be
three lines
no not including this line okay this is
the function that we're gonna let's
implementation now we want to find out
look after this
this is a number yeah one two three ten
twenty okay
so this is nums yeah now this is the
number so we now we want to find out
this each group of the difference so
what we can
minimum yeah minimum what num
nums
so if we start with these nums uh
so this this is i and what's what's this
number what's this number
what's this i plus k
minus one right yeah
got it yeah so look numbs i plus k minus
one minus
num square
[Music]
the whole thing is lens and yeah then
numb
minus k
minus k so out this i will be
up to this point right so k is what one
two num lens case one two three four
five
and we want to get this point the last
index will be zero one two three
three yeah
so what five minus two
uh yeah minus k uh minus is minus k
minus k plus one plus plus one we need
to have plus one right
right we need to pass one here
length numbers is five
five minus
uh k is two
plus one
right up to this point because up to
range right so that this will be four so
range up to four so the last index will
be three zero one two three okay okay
that's it so basically look
mean numbs i plus k minus 1 is this one
minus minus num i is this one for i in
range for this i in range from 0 to
this is less numbs minus k plus one but
not including right remember this range
function yes range 10
what's what's what does 1 10 give us
1 2 3 up to
nine nine it doesn't include a ten right
that's why we plus one it doesn't
include the plus one
okay
another way another way look another way
is we can we can use this k here so
you'll be nums i
right
no no no numbs i
numbs i let's say nums is here and then
numbs i
minus k
right i'm nice minus k so i is 1 1 minus
k
we need minus k
plus one right because numbers k plus
one lambda k plus one
and then for i in range
range k minus one up to length number
right because the first first index
would be 0 1
right if this is k
right this will go to the end and then
you you look for the k i minus k plus 1.
does it make sense
yeah okay so can you explain to me
what's the approach what's this approach
so definitely first of all we need to
[Music]
um and then right now
yeah we need to check the every
every group of the k
yeah because we are looking for the
minimum of
this uh
mean maximum
this k array k array minus mean k array
right
if we sort it the maximum of this k
array will be the rightmost yeah open on
the right hand side right yeah
and then the minimum will be on the left
hand side why is that because this array
is already sorted right if k is equal to
three
for example if k equals three
all right
right right n
listen is k equals three
two three ten what's the maximum okay
what's the measurement
what's the minimum
is it very easy yeah because always the
maximum of this sub array is always on
the right most right correct and the
minimum is only on the left most i can
even if this is i the index i and then
this index will be i minus k plus one
yeah easy right
let's that's the that's why we saw this
array because once we saw that we can
find the
maximum and the minimum in constant time
just by looking at the index right
because it's always sorted am right
yeah and then we just need to check
check
check what i times right and n times for
the sub k times for the sub array right
uh
how many so what's that yeah k times
no is this k times no
then
length n minus k times yeah yeah n minus
k times nothing or okay minus one okay
so this is o n log n and this is all n
minus so what's the time complexity of
all
what which one is uh more time consuming
this one or this one
which which is that this aggregate
consists of two steps first of all
sourcing
oh and again the second time it's all
linear yeah because we're just scanning
scanningly away yeah no
salt
this is more time consuming well done so
this is dominating so yeah so what's the
time convexity for all the holy
speculation okay again
oh and okay okay that's it for today
good job
bye bye
bye bye bye bye see you later see you
later bye bye