[Applause]
notation okay
so i'm gonna explain to you
okay come now look
if i want to calculate three you know
the
normal mathematic let's say three plus
two times four what's the answer
um eleven eleven okay so why is either
when we because the multiplication
multiply
yeah takes priority over the plus right
so we calculate multiply first right so
multiply and division takes over
priorities then
plus and minus yeah okay
correct
okay now how about if i want to do this
three plus two times four
okay so we so this reverse polish
notation is basically
uh the purpose of is to get rid of the
brackets
yeah because we are in look we are
introducing the brackets to check that
isn't any times
that's right i'm talking about these two
examples so
three plus two times yes so look we we
are introducing the parentheses to
change the order right sit down sit down
please yeah
so we don't want that right so this
reverse polish notation is is
you know the purpose of is to get rid of
parentheses and then can
can be used to express these two
situations okay so how can we do this
okay so for
is
it's the other people from poland yeah
another polish the country oh i thought
you mean like i'm really rich or
something like making stuff clean
like this notation was invented by
by some polish scientists okay can you
sit down please not just jumping around
okay look so this one
so it'll be two three
two
okay so you'll be two four
times plus okay and then this one will
be one
three two
plus
four
ten okay
so do you see how this is working
so look these two
these will be converted to rpm like that
at least converted by rpm okay can you
can you imagine how how we're going to
how we're going to evaluate this
at least
don't be saying same characters yeah
yeah so this is this one exactly this is
two so yeah but it doesn't have any
parentheses
which is which but we don't we don't
need that's the beauty of reverse so
what's diverse
yeah
but look so every time we we have this
operation
yeah we take the previous two
add it
so two times four
eight yeah don't we we
changed it to eight okay and we'll keep
going plus
we take the previous two
three plus eight you know how about this
one three two okay operation
so what do we need to do yeah take the
previous two three plus two five five
representatives
okay look at five and four
times thing
now we take the previous two look five
twenty
do you see it do you see how this works
yeah but i don't get it why did you do
this one the times but then this on the
plus first
uh i just show you what what do you mean
you don't understand
why do you do the times first on this
one no no no from the left to right when
we meet the operation we take the
previous two that defines that look yeah
but when we start here there was a time
yeah okay so look at this one okay look
look
three two plus four times
right
so you say why why we don't take this
one right yeah
because look we meet we we scan from
left to right the first operator we see
is plus
so what does it mean
we take the previous two
and we press it
so we keep going
we take the previous two so this c the
reverse
notation already defines the order
got it
oh yeah makes sense okay so i'm going to
write another one okay so can you can
you
convert it to reverse polish notation
okay one plus two plus three easy and
one plus two times three
yeah okay so for this one
that's six i know so how can you how can
we
convert it to reverse polish notation
there are two operators we only have one
plus yeah okay so what is it one two
okay we have plus what does it mean we
take the previous two one mistake
so look one two three so it's like that
okay
one
two
plus three plus
okay
so
it's better if you reverse it yeah look
at this is reversing look because
reversing
so plus we take the two and take the one
and then we add it together will be
three and then we keep going
keep going three and uh
and two and three right because three
and then plus
we take the previous two okay and how
about this one
one
is one
yeah one and then
why one
one
but we want to catch it at least two
first yeah
okay two three times and then one plus
one
so where's where's one where is where do
we put the one where to pull up
if you do the one here that will become
two times three plus one but what we
want is one plus two times three
so what do we do
one plus
make sense
look two three
multiply
we change it to six
one six plus
seven yeah you see okay
so so given this given is the first one
okay so
the problem today is easier it's not
asking to convert a mathematic
expression to a reverse polish
notation but instead we are already
given a rpn right
it's already valid and we just want to
evaluate the values of it
evaluate the expression
rpm right
so
how how do we do it
how do we do it um
we given this one two plus
three times okay so how how this is the
uh okay that's this is array okay array
of expression expression equals that
yeah
three two yeah and an operation okay
so how do we evaluate
so we go to the beginning
[Music]
okay this is numbers that's fine if it's
number we push it
to a stack remember what
what's that um
what's the stack first thing
first no
first is lockdown
look stack all right look we put that
when we have numbers we put it in the
stack right
three
one
two oh now we have the operator with no
numbers
now what do we do
we take two numbers
out of the stack yeah
and what do we do
based on the appraiser we can do this
operation right so plus
so let's put a three here right yeah
and then now i keep going
what do we do
times
three before so it's nine so we take two
numbers out yeah and then we do the
operation yeah and then put it put the
put it back nine
okay the last yeah that's what i said
okay so the value will be what the value
will be one
if we
do in this way what's the campaign
[Applause]
[Music]
so
we will have a stack answer let's put an
answer let's put a stack okay stack
equals how do we define a stack in in
in person how do we define a step
well we
um
how do we define define the step
how do we define the stack
how do we define our space list
okay then
okay so let's say for
e
in
a r okay
yeah
okay
so look first of all we want to define
the list of operations we can put it in
a dictionary right so so let's say i
look at operation supporting operation
equals one curry breaks
look at me cut it break and then we can
say add so these right add
minus
the subtract
times
division all right
so this n so we want to define the n key
the keys are operations right
and the values are the actual operation
function which we can define as lambda
which is what is a short function okay
so we can do this
okay i don't know how to spell lambda
a b
okay that's fine
[Music]
function takes two parameters and then
you which you will use a column
to define what it does so which is a
minus b okay so look at a b
what what do we put here a times b
yeah
a b
a
divided by b okay if we only keep the
integer okay yeah so look this operation
will be traditionally the keys will be
the operators we support it which we can
define more we can extend this so far
okay so we only support four plus
subtract multiply and divide what if
there was a divide and i think the y is
harder
yeah it's the same look it's the same
because we divide it by two
yeah
sorry why if you can't divide equals
that's why we use the integer
that's why we have this
integer okay yeah
now we have these operators okay the
keys are the operators
the values are the
corresponding lambda function lambda is
a short function yes the function
now for e look then we say
if e
in operators what does it mean
if e in operators now we need to take
two numbers right yeah okay so number
one num num one num two okay so first of
all we take the number two first okay
num two equals
st dot pop
and num one equals st dot pop right so
we have two numbers so what
what should we do then we can say we
push the value back st append
up the operators yeah operators
operators
operators e
this is a function and we take that n
one and two yeah
okay so this is look
okay look at me operator's e is the
lambda function right the key is the
operator lambda operators e is the
lambda function and then we can call it
giving it two parameters n one and n two
because the first the first number we
take it from the stack is the second
the one plus three the first the first
step
when we push it into the stack is one
and three the first number we take is
three is the second number and two the
second
second time we take it is the first
number so look we're calling this number
function and giving it two parameters
and one and two okay let's see
look as what
yes e is a number so we're just pushing
it to the stack right so st dot append
whatever
[Music]
is this is stack this is fine number if
this is nice
that's st is now has one number how we
can get the line
s t y
another way of doing it wow what should
i put here
st pop is taking it out and return it if
i don't want to take it out i just want
to return the value what what's this
very sty
ft
which number is that value which number
the first number will be the top of the
stack right because it's only one number
okay actually it's not the top of it's
no no actually it's not zero it's minus
one because we are returning the
the last one right the last one right
correct
here
here 60 minimum is the same as st minus
one but the meaning is different right
the minor the thing the meaning is
different st minor one what does mean is
the top of the stack right so that's the
one that's the one we want we want to
retrieve the value of
okay so can you tell me the difference s
t dot probably that's t minus one
if you have this and then you just pop
it it's just gone you just go and return
knight right but it's this one
but what happened to the stack
does it change no that's that's the
difference okay so this one we just
retrieve it you're gonna peek what's
this meaning pink pink and pop what's
the difference between pyongyang pecan
pop pig means
like you pick you just peek by you you
pick you know the value of the top is
nice but you don't change it you don't
pop it but probably is what i take it
out i already know i take it out you see
what the difference
what's the time complexity
i i i
character by character okay
okay okay
yeah okay so i'm going to erase this to
be
[Music]
this is easy operator c okay so what's n
one what's n two n two equals one n one
equals one come on
stop jump up
standard park i done here
easy yeah you just popping two numbers
one with me
yeah easy yeah yeah
that's it for today