[Applause]
okay so let's say
keep going
so let's say
uh you know you're doing the exam and
you've got a score okay so for example
you've got 100
and then yen how much how much how many
strokes
you know 60 okay wow
don't tell mommy okay daddy
got the
90 okay and then what's your friend's
name come on give me your name
tom
[Music]
okay let's see so if we give the ranking
we sort it from the top uh for the
highest to the lowest what are those
100 100 100 150
60 19 16 50.
okay so if we put a ranking for each
score okay so look if the ranking the
top is is zero so we'll put a zero here
at least one should be one right and
then two
three
okay two three that i don't know can you
please not put it we got 1 000.
so the ranking this is the ranking this
is the ranking
this is a special ranking that it does
not take us it does not consider how
many people are
uh before right for example
this 90 is actually in the third place
right because there are two
hundred in front of you know in front of
90.
but we're only considering the
the numbers right so the 100 should be
ranked at zero and then 90 should be the
rank at one
okay
so how do we do this
everywhere any sauce how do we do this
what do you mean
dictionary yeah yeah
but first of all we need to do one thing
before sorting set
what's that
look at
what do we need to do
we need to basically
okay
so basically we want to come up with at
least the score and the ranking paper
right so we want to have a slot uh rank
uh let's go to the ranking table so
hundreds you might be mapped to zero 90
will be mapped to one sixty should be
mapped to two this is so bad and three
no zero means the top
three uh uh
fifty should be ranked two three okay so
in order to do this look at this side
look at this side
i look at the original numbers what's
the difference
what's the difference between these and
this
can you find the difference
here 196 to 50 and 19650 what's the
difference
[Music]
no no no no i'm not looking for the
visual difference i'm looking for the
actual difference 100 195 60.
yeah so first of all we want to do what
we move the duplicates yeah yeah so how
do we remove the dual thing um
okay so now
look
we have this b
which has only the unique numbers but
now we want to
sort it right
yeah what's the term complex to solve
the way
what's the time complexity to sorry all
right
um
this is
oh yeah and what's the
so this number if we saw the numbers
look at if p does soft
so that will give us what
90 100. but we what we want is from the
highest to the smallest
right we don't want to we want to change
the usb order so how do we solve this
already
okay so b
and we put in the reverse keyword right
reverse equals two
and then it will give us a hundred
ninety sixty fifty okay so now this is
160 90 60 50 and how do we get the
ranking which is also the index we use
what kind of function set
you're not saying keep saying that what
dictionary
the is gives you the
the index and the value okay and then
with the index with the matching with
the decimal mapping from the value to
the index which is the ranking then we
can construct the ranking array right i
know that'll be it right okay let's try
the implementation okay so you should be
you shouldn't be able to do it okay
define
leaderboard
num
first of all we want to construct a
unique
array which contains the only the unique
items okay so let's put in the data
theta equals what
we convert the numbers
first of all we construct a set using
the numbers and we can wait to the least
right
list
set
numbers right
and then we want to sort it away from
the largest to the smallest how can can
we write it
data
soft and from largest to the smallest
[Music]
right
now we want to put we want to construct
a ranking
paper mapping so which is a dictionary
or notebook right so we can do this
ranking how do we construct a dictionary
ranking equals one i give you three
options okay you tell me
ranking equals first of all this one
second number this one the third one
this one which one i think this is one
this one yeah because this is the list
this is calling a tuper yeah for the two
part and this one is the dictionary so
yeah
or you can say before this generally in
right
and now we want to use the numerator
right right
for
ranking
for ranking dot score value
numerator
data right
now we're going to do what ranking
ranking one equals one can you tell me
which one is the score
go to cap a
there is no error i only i i is the
index please let's go so ranking one v
equals one r yeah
and then now we want to construct like
rankings are equal answer equals this
and then we also go through the original
numbers right which is for r
in what or which one is the original
number
come on
you pointed at it yeah and then what
answer don't open one
answer
on twitter
[Music]
because this one is the domination yeah
the biggest one this one is our n right
but we have two parts the aggregate has
two parts
don't break my earphones come on you
know anything
yes don't break the table okay no table
cable okay so what's the
the look if look
look at this part okay look at this part
it's ranking we're building a ranking
dictionary and these can be simplified
as one line okay so ranking equal as
what
ranking
equals
we can construct the dictionary here
r
column v
for
r
v
in basically we put these lines yeah we
put put these lines rearrange these in a
single line
in enumerate
enumerate data that's
it uh actually ah it is r is not um
okay okay that's a mistake that i is the
index v is the score so it's the v r v r
right
so this one will be v
because we're gonna make it from the
score to the ranking right so we are
please
and again this one this one we can
construct it in one line okay we turn
answer return
[Music]
ranking
for
r in numbers
ryan
noisy
okay
okay i'm going to erase this there i'm
going to erase i'll please the beat and
at least wait okay can you tell me come
on
[Music]
come
on that's it for today good job bye
[Music]