hello
hello mr eric mr ryan how are you today
have you had a good weekend today okay
sit down
okay so today we are going to talk about
uh you know we want to count the number
of pairs with the as the root difference
equal to k
so you're given a number a raise of the
a list of numbers like one
two
two one okay
a list of numbers let's say
one
and okay let's say equals to one okay so
by the way what's what's the that's the
real difference do you still remember
this function abs
x
mathematics
okay
yeah what's this x
yes
x for x this is the same these two are
same
okay this is mathematics and this is the
way we do the coding we use as
absx let's still remember this
is x
if
x bigger than zero
zero if
x equals zero is minus x if x minus zero
okay so basically it's uh
it's uh the distance
this function returns the distance
between x to the zero right
so let's say this is five so what's the
abs five
what's the abs five five five units
what's the abs
minus two minus two j yeah you see you
got the difference yeah
okay so um
so can you count the number of pairs the
pairs yeah two numbers yeah two numbers
with the difference equals to k
e y which is one can you find two
numbers basically finding two numbers
which has the difference one
one two and two one one two and two one
yeah but we also don't find the pairs we
have a good job
we want to find the pairs
what's pairs
pairs yes pairs
so look one two yeah so if we find two
pairs which are not which has sequence
like uh
uh
you know one two and two one it's the
same right so we only pick
one two the from the big uh smallest and
index to the bigger and you do this yeah
one two yeah of course look so look one
two
one two
two one two one okay so there are four
pairs yeah
but one two two one it's the same okay
we only pick one right yeah so basically
if you pick a
i and j
this is the same as aj you should not
pick it twice yeah this is the same
yeah this is the sense
yeah
it should be easier with the proof of
thing right with the proof version yeah
should we write it
the proof of things thing how to prove
what's the pair so remember what's the
term complexity how to to blue first
appearance
and
square we're down well good job o n
square because we proof was the i right
the index and the proof of the j right
and then we just check the difference if
it's okay then we incrementalize it
right
easy peasy right let me squeeze me
my badge yeah i'm going to find the
i need more oh this one is good okay so
let's do this
all right
define
find a call let's do it
card okay count pairs
that's a and k okay
first of all we need to know the length
of the a length of the pairs
length of the numbers so
how do we get the lens
and equal as well
length of the array the number
length
at the beginning where you guys were
zero
and then we start from the second inner
loop for j
in range
i to n right and then look if
abs
my absolute function at the distance
yeah
i i
minus a j
equal
you see this is very easy yeah simple
easy peasy too for loop starting the
blue forcing let the computer to try the
index from zero to n minus one and then
when we have this i we we need a
computer to try
like uh the j index from i to n minus
one and we check the numbers the
distance between these two numbers if
it's equal scale and we increment our
answer look this is all n and this is o
n
if you're doing one thing you need all
in one step and inside each n step you
need to do another n step so the
condenses to multiply together is o n
square right yeah what's the space
complexity
are we using any space oh well we're
done
okay so
you know oil square
not fast we can come up with better so
look for this one one two two one right
so how about if i have a counter
remember account that the counter the
number of each unique items and their
appearance right so if you count them
what's the out if dc is counter list
so what do we have for this d
one what
the key is one the value is one
okay and that
c is two the unit how many times they
appear
okay so look the one appears two times
the one appears two times i know there
are two ones here and i know there are
two tools here
right two is here
so look
so if i do this one i know it's one
right and what's one plus one
okay so now i'm at the number one so i
know the difference of k is one plus one
right so two is two counts okay so i
have
i have one two times and i have two two
times so how many pairs are they going
to get
two two
this there are two options here and
there are two options here so how many
four yeah two thumbs up so look we just
counted that's it
yeah we use the counter and then we
count it right
okay i'm going to write it and then you
tell me what's the time the rest here
so look first of all we need to see
object c equals counter one
i don't know what we want to count the
number of elements in a so a we're done
and then now i have this answer and the
steel equals zero yeah so for
i
in
c okay for i in c is going to the unique
numbers yeah
all the all you can do for i in c dot
keys is the same yeah for i in c or c
dot p all c
is still the same yeah okay
lambda one answer
plus equal
yeah look
we know i c i appears
this is the number of times c i appears
yeah and we want to find out the i plus
k c i plus k this is the number of times
it appears so what should i do with this
should i put
what what operator should i put here
come on
i have this is one
this is the two
the number of times two appears this is
the number of time one appears
so i should put
what did i talk about what was i talking
about the number of one appears two
times the number of
two appears two times so how many pairs
how many pairs times you multiply
together okay so you also you can do
this as well because it goes through the
c so you can also
make it c minus k is the same yeah
because c minus uh i minus k
has the distance
k to i right the distance okay so it's
the same yeah
and then return what
answer
what's the time complexity for this one
all right yeah it's a single loop c the
keys appears
see
a mouse and items
values yeah oh n what's a space
complexity
yeah okay
yeah so how beautiful is that we use
this we use we trade the space
yeah we trade the time with the space
yeah
so we use the space to make it faster
this is linear this is quadratic
square
make it linear linear
this
okay
okay so look
this one we can use the counter oh oh we
can do this counting one by one yeah we
can count it one by one instead of these
we can do this look this is uh
this is another way of uh doing it but
it's quite similar similar it's similar
yeah we use the default dictionary yeah
look what's definition
integer
and then instead of going through the
dictionary because now dictionaries and
then we go into the original numbers
which is a
and then i just needs to do what
i now i just need to answer
plus
equal the c i
c i minus k okay and then i i also need
to check the answer c i plus k
because d c i minus k and c i plus k are
two numbers on with k
distance on the both sides of the eye
look if this is i right if it is this
side what what two numbers are
have as a root difference k with this
number
which two numbers have difference k
to this i
come on the absolute difference remember
absolute difference okay
i
plus k yeah and what's here i minus k
yeah the k unit yeah this is k unit okay
that's the difference then edit and now
because i'm at least a i so i need to
see i what i need to i have
i have seen one number i so i need to
what ci1
minus
xci is the count plus equal
one yeah and then we can
what's the time complexity for this one
what's the time complexity
yeah what's the time going to say come
on
all right what's the space complexity
yeah it's the same it's the same as the
previous one okay
yeah easy yeah so which one you think is
better oh also
oh and then this one
yeah you understand
yeah so if i erase any two can you can
you write it
that's three
okay so what
the other second one which one you have
three notes maybe that one is easier you
look c equals counter you tell me what
to do okay counter a
for i you're going through this counter
then what answer what
plus equal one and return answer
also plus equals c
i
c i plus k yeah all c i minus k is the
same yeah
in this case because they see we only
counting ones right we're only counting
ones so look if two the k difference we
can count
we can count the pair two three or if k
equals one we can count two three or
two one this is the same we only
counting it once yeah if you count the
two twice then that will be duplicated
and we are saying that we only count it
once and like one two we only count it
one two not two one okay this is the
same pairs okay that's it for today good
job bye bye
bye bye