hello
hello we just played the game on your
chest
and we just knew what okay we're
learning about okay
okay okay
sit down
[Music]
good job okay so today we're going to
talk about
binary tree traversal binary tree
so what's binary two binary three
two three traversal traversal means the
the way
we we travel the tree with
the nose in a particular sequence right
yeah so how many kind of finer tree
do you know for example any examples
what kind of binary tree do you need
yeah the left loads are always smaller
than the root the right notes are always
bigger than the root okay
so let's find a research tree and buy
another one
number two number it doesn't have to be
number one is the loot okay but we'll
talk about that later okay now
we call we talk about the traversal like
we have a route
one and then let's loot two here
the leaf number three and then here
let's call let's let's design a tree
like that okay
one two three four five got it
uh so we we have uh
we we call it this node and we call it
left
left triad left three we call it l and
color right tree right if i i give a
sequence like uh note
air left right yeah this is the
secret one four two five then
three exactly wow we're done it means
the pre-order so we reach it
for a tree we reach the node first and
then we recursively visit the left tree
and then visit the right tree so here
note is one i know which is the left
tree
which is two four five but for the two
four five three we again apply this
principle note
left and right which is two four five
when we finish the left three then we go
to the
right tree which is three okay so let's
call it
pre-order yeah pre-order so this three
means the note here is squeeze beginning
then if i move the end to the middle
and r we call it in order because this
end is in the middle in order so what
does it mean we visit the left tree
first
and then we reach the note and i'll
visit the right okay
so that would be 45 1 3
no no no no people find one three
no no no left to first
for this this one left us is what four
three four two five
one three three what did you say
i said that okay okay sorry how did you
get here okay so let's let's
look at this one first and then one
three but for this one we have to
recursively do it right
yeah so it will be uh so remind me it
will be
four two five one three okay so let's
call it in order right
in order and how about if i move this to
the
to the end let's air ah
and we call it post order right so can
you tell me what
uh what's this
lionel anyone post order
air left right and note
uh four two by three one
left right so left four
five two three one exactly okay
so this is the basic three and we also
have
we also have what uh reversed
uh reverse in order so this is another
yeah we also have a reverse in order
which is
ah and air yeah this operative yeah
okay so that will be and we also have
remember a couple days ago we talked
about breakfast search
preference search breath first search so
what's the preference search order
one two three four five
level by level yeah breakfast search
means that every level i finished one
level finish another
finishing level don't get it this is
another
another special sorry left to right yeah
left to right
every time finish look one you pick the
no current load and i pick its children
i push into the kill which is two three
yeah i take the the first keep
which is two i push the kids for four
and five to the kill right
and then the next tournament is three
you know you see this is level by level
okay we talked about that before now we
let's let's do this
this should be very easy
yeah let's remember we have a three yeah
class three
class three yeah do you still remember
class
and then define in
right the loot and then left and right
right
yeah left and right yeah self dot dot
equals no self dot
left equals left f double y equals right
okay now
we we do this look define
in order let's take an example in order
okay
in order loot
coma okay for the inorder so it's not
left note right right so we need to
we need to
so we first of all we need to do it if
the loser is
numb right if we lose it's numb then we
just return yeah
okay right and then we need to
reach it the left was that dog no it's
not
let's not we need to recursively visit
the left tree right right the left half
look here
so how do we do that in order
look top left okay so we look closely
recording the left
right and now we're visiting the loot
what we want to do is the loop we print
it okay let's print it
okay now we are here right so can you
tell me what's next
just wait and tell me what's that
yeah okay so if i want to make this
pre-order how do you only have to change
one
one thing what about print
value yeah it's print the value so you
print it
that's order right here
we will call yourself itself to because
that's that's okay with because if you
call it the right then when you finish
then
you call this right yeah that's the
because recursion yeah you don't need to
worry about the details you will just
solving that
calling the in order with the right tree
right
to get it yeah okay so now
if i want to change this to pre-order
how do you do it
remember pre-order
you just need to change one thing ryan
do you know
yeah move the printing here yeah and how
about if i want to change this to
close order
do the first order again change
one thing
uh
put the print thingy at the bottom
yeah well done good job yeah that's
exactly do you see it
yeah so this is very clear right so
look again let's do this example one
two three four
five okay let's do like this in order
first okay in order so
in order if root is none it's not long
in order left yeah in order is left
okay when it's in order to finish then
put in the loot
which is one okay so that one is here
but in order
these will be we're printing one
we're printing yeah
left first yeah putting the left first
right so bringing four
to five right and then go back to the
one
and then you know the right that would
be three right
three yes yeah got it so
this is in order and how about if we do
like in order of
binary search tree that's the that's
very interesting like
this is two this is one
this is three this is
this is four here and this is
zero okay so this is the binary circuit
yeah
the left nodes are always smaller than
the root the right notes are always
bigger maybe i put
one more here that's 1.5 and that's
that's
2.5 so what
what if we do a binary in order of the
binary search tree
remember this is the left and now we
visit the loot and we visit the right so
what do you think what we can get
what do you think we can get so can you
do that in order of this financial
street
you want them righty it this one
by in order final research street in
order
l and r oh yeah it will be
l and ah yes
okay yeah you're ten
okay so this is the final search
remember
zero yes we're done and then
one one point one
point five yes okay you finish
this the left and the note is two
wow okay and then two point five
yes and three four wow well done so what
what do you think
that that is what do you think what do
you think
what do you think this is uh
yeah this is in order yeah oh look the
name is in order but the
the result of performing and in order
traversal
on a binary search tree is that we get
the in order
element list right yeah from the
smallest to the largest
and how about if i want to
get from largest to the smallest what
should we do
remember we talked about reverse in
order right
so that would be r
and air right so then if we performing
the r in there reverse in order that we
have a four
three two point five two one point five
one zero okay yeah two point one
two two yeah two one one okay so
for these all these trevor sir what's
the complexity
what's the time complexity of
the what the end yeah
yes oh oh yeah yeah why is
[Music]
we have to visit every node in a tree
that's why
the travelers are different servers they
are all
open right they are all already okay the
time complexity okay
for the space complexity is also om
because we are using this
we we don't have uh we don't allocate
the space
particularly but we are using the
recursion recursion
cost of n right there's a calling stack
okay you don't have to remember
understand now but it's good to know
that the space complexity
for the recursion usually is o n okay
okay thank you that's that's it today
good job
oh yeah oh yeah
oh