hello
hello mr mrwan how are you good okay
today we're going to talk about the old
power gym yeah what's perignon
the word when universes is the same can
you tell me an example race
car and any more i got that bob's place
yeah bob okay i'll pop yeah bob is it
bob okay yeah
how do we check it by the way reverse it
yeah we can reverse it and check it with
the thumb yeah we reverse it
that's one thing oh we can use two
pointer thing and check carry to buy a
character until the meat in the window
yeah yeah
yeah that's one easy way okay so today
we want to talk about oddparent what
does it mean so given a string like uh
you know let's give it a string a b
[Music]
let's just give this a string for
example like a bob
okay bob yay we want to find out the
soft strings the pen interest actually
okay so we uh any
uh what's what's the substring
substrings
what's sub strings both
what's substring sometimes a string
yeah which is what stop sensing how many
substrings can we have for the pop
one two three six
what are those
[Music]
oh
okay including an empty string is the
string is also kind of substring yeah a
special subject so it's a six six
section so among of those what uh which
are the pattern zones the substrings
how many of those are such things
this one is
yeah
okay this one maybe yes this one is yeah
single character
character right this one no right this
one no this one yes right
yeah
a layer any even
parent drums so the the the side the
lens is even are there any even present
here
no there oh yeah this this can tell you
uh
no
[Music]
okay
okay so you understand so we're given a
string okay so our task is to find out
if there are any pendulum which are the
size of
which are all uh you know all the sides
of the
peninsula uh
even
all the soil
okay
uh
okay okay do i make myself clear yeah so
given a string
we want to find
or to check if all
palindrome okay first of all it has to
be plain syndrome paddington
soft strings
uh odd off size okay all size
size so it doesn't make it doesn't mean
that there can't be
any challenges that are even sized okay
for example like what
c
a c okay so
for this one
what's that
can you find any panning drone that that
is uh even size um
yeah
cat and oh yeah that's it
is uh
all size okay so what we want we also
check if all the planets in substring
are all sides
any example any idea
um
any idea the first thing comes to mind
is what a palliative that has
an odd number we want to find out if all
the terms on substring are outside so if
they are even sides we need to say false
otherwise we will say yes
so for this one we said true false
because we find out that
these are even right but for this cac
we find we said yes because all the
subs uh particular substrings are
awesome
and this is even size so it's it's not
right
do i make
so you just need to find the paradigm
that has
an odd number of letters
we want to find out if there are
problems on that are even sides right if
they are even then we just return
immediately right twelves yeah okay so
any idea how can we do this this well
this is clever thing yeah we can prove
always
how do we proof us all the substrings in
what was the term complexity if we put
force all the substances
yeah if we prove us the substring how
what's the time complexity
oh and
4x square yeah because look if
a b c d okay what's the subject if we
have we have a left left pointer when we
make sure the left we we have another
loop to go uh to determine uh the right
pointer right okay okay so let's do it
and now let's
define
oh
odd parent okay
we want to find out all paddington all
the prince's substrings are all sized
okay let's say s
and equals length as well
for
i
in range
and right
right the eye is the left right right
yeah and then the right what should we
start with the right for j in range
whenever
i is the left j is what so it is from i
to n right yeah yeah and then we want to
try how do we check the parameters let's
say we we check the function check
pressure actually we want it here we can
just simply we cannot return this look
[Music]
yeah like i j equals zero zero right
zero
then s minus one and y
i smaller than j
if s i
not equal sj
then we do time false right
okay
otherwise i plus equals one and j minus
equals one right and then return true
got it
doesn't make sense
yeah
all right
look at me what am i doing here what's
this part doing here can you tell me
what's this part doing here
what does this mean
so
technically is
i know you know it i was just checking
if you're paying attention okay
yeah yeah okay
now look if checking and then look look
what's the what's that if the index from
goes from i to j inclusive okay so
what's the string what's the string the
string the substring okay at the same
string equals one s start from i to j
plus one right all right
right
if
if we find the pending jump
if this is a parent drum and it's
offside it's even size right so
how do we check its events as uh outside
uh even sorry
no no no the i to j i to j inclusive how
many sides of this how many sides from i
to j how many characters are there
if j minus i
plus one right then that's how many
characters from i to j
if this end one yeah or modular two yeah
model
equals zero it means this is the even
number and you check this st is the
parent zone we return
we return to return fourth right
return first
and then what what's missing here return
one
turn
what's missing after two yeah whether
what's the time constraint okay what's
the terms number three
what's the time complexity come on
[Applause]
square
this is one double places one loop and
then we need to check out what
we're done because the here
here is another end right
however we can improve this right we can
increase
all right look at me please right
do we actually need to check the go you
know go through the these right we can
get rid of these right because we are
now we need to first of all check if the
length is an even number but instead of
this we can do this look i plus one we
go through the the right would be l is i
plus one to n and then we put a step
here
yeah
what's this two mean
wait i don't see
i plus one to n j and two yeah so every
time we skip two because uh
even number x two is also even number
right yeah
yeah yeah i know we can get rid of which
parts
that one which
we always want to check we don't want to
get rid of this because we already know
this is an even number skipping at 2.
come on so we can get rid of that right
right so it will be easier right
let's all incubate it's not very good
okay so how can we improve it
okay so can you tell me what's the
what's the can you give me a few
patterns which are even sized pink
anymore anymore
anymore
um
any more
a let me think let me see
a race card no okay
what else
hmm let me think let me think let me
think bad this is not this is odd
what else
um
[Music]
anymore
you said this
huh
come on give me one more example which
is pendulum and even
okay
okay so what what's
i got one more okay what's that
already okay
listen to me if it's a peninsula if it's
even side what does it mean we can fold
it right we can fold it so what does it
mean
look we can fold it in the middle yeah
then we can fold it yeah
and then what does this mean
there are two continuous characters
right
yeah isn't just like a mirror it's like
a mineral so that the these two
characters there should be if it's not
like a mirror
at least
everywhere
this is a mirror
okay and then
that's what's in there okay i see what
it means
what i was saying is that if it's a evil
laser even padding drum right
[Music]
i rely on for the last time come on yes
if it's even fair enough
there are two characters which needs to
be the same right yeah
and what does that mean if the original
question if they are original if there
is a string we want to find out if all
the paragraphs us
yeah
parents and substitutes are
er
what does it mean
what does it mean so we want to check
for if they are
if they are too continuous
that
if it is then it's false right
oh yes am i right yes
hurry up
can you repeat what i'm saying
huh can you repeat what i'm saying
what i'm saying is that if they are even
number pendulum if a pendulum is even
number the they they they will be two
continuous consecutive yeah consecutive
consecutive same letters all right
yeah yeah
okay so the original question is can we
find a peninsula
can uh earlier or all the peninsula such
students are outside
so we can check we can check if there
are consecutive send letters if they are
it means that there should be a parent
which is even says am right
okay so we can turn original question
into this this question am i right yeah
okay so how do we check it
um take it like this how do we check it
okay so
i'm going to write it quickly and you
can tell me if if the original question
is yes or no right
a a c b e f g okay original question if
they are or if all the planing
substrings are
numbers okay so what is this one
come on look at it
it's not why why it's not because
because i guess
three three one odd sorry so sorry what
[Music]
one
yeah but we the original question is
that we want to find out if all the
products on such string are all numbers
yeah okay okay another one just to make
sure you understand
c e f g
h i that's enough yes
two of us three
thousand folks
if you say false you need to tell me
which which two are the even size no i
see e f g h i
no no the pentagon needs to be pennies
no i don't think i don't think there is
one
then it's true right yeah yeah okay okay
c e f
so the question is we need to check if
they have two consecutive right because
if they are if i just say if they are
like this yeah there's only one unique
yeah yeah yeah that's that's right if
they are even pending drums what does it
mean
if they are even pendulum what does it
mean it means that it's a
no yeah it's false and then
there must be a two consecutive same
letter right to make up even parents all
right because
got it this is the most important thing
to remember do you understand
yeah yeah no yeah
these two kinds of planning this one is
even this one is all number right
yeah all number there's only one single
in the meter but even size what does it
mean there are two
in the middle
there are two in the middle consecutive
got it
okay let's try this
define
check let's just do a check s
for
i
in
range
land n
minus one huh go n1
look
if what
if s i
equal equal our
s i what next one is one what what's s
what's next next character current
character next character what should i
put here
if equals
because return false because there are
two consecutive letters then there must
be even
turning them right and otherwise we
return true
okay this should go here okay let's go
here
what's the time complexity for this one
what's the original first approach we're
talking about on n squared
yeah as i if i want to
change this s i s minus one what should
i do if i need to check the previous one
how would you like to change this
not plus one
what should i change here
uh we shall change we're changing here
to start with one right yeah up to
length n right
yeah okay
can you listen to us
okay now we can write this in one line
right we can just do this return all of
o means what everything yeah
okay
s i
equal
s i plus one
for
i
in
range
s minus one right because we we
approximate we need to check it plus one
can you put it back please
okay i'm going to erase this and then
you tell me yeah
come on come on just right what just
okay just do this i have
[Music]
have you paid attention to whatever it
says here look if s we want to check if
the two characters are the same right
yeah
so if what come on
if they are the same
yeah
unless we turn red false
okay okay look if i change these two
plus ones what should i check what
should i check check here
can you pay attention come on if i pop
to this first one what should i do here
[Music]
from zero
and minus one right this is the same
thing
and i'm going to write the one liner
again okay o
means everything needs to be the same as
i
equal equal s i plus 1
yeah for
i in range
then you're looking
and i'm looking at this lens s you're
looking this is less sorry let's ask
quick
so what does it mean we want to check if
s i equals the neighboring characters
are the same for the range i is for the
range up to
the length
minus one right and everything all so
this is the same okay the time
complexity is on the space complexity is
what
what's the speed conversely
one because we're not using any space
okay that's it for today good job
bye