okay so today this is uh we're going to
talk about this consecutive duplicate so
can you read this the given string
consistent of x and y's to be the
minimum number of characters such as
there's no consecutive x and no
chemistry y okay
so look at this example like y y y x y y
x x so so basically look at the string
basically we want to remove the
duplicate right now we only keep one in
each group right
yeah
yeah make sense x y x yeah
so how about if i give you another
example like x x y y can you tell me
what should the output be
what's the output for it for this one y
x y x
x y x y yeah and how about another one
okay y y uh x x
y x
can you say one for forever please okay
okay
x
y x
okay all right okay
okay
okay let's see
so what uh one solution can you think of
any solutions like uh how can we how can
we implement this how can we
how can we do this
look there are only two characters yeah
x and y yeah yeah so we can repeatedly
replace x to y x x to x and y
and y to
to yeah we can replace x x to y to y
to x yeah and y to walk
yeah
okay
yeah question please
okay okay let's turn it look
so we can do this while while why is
something happening
and then same for yy in x
x equals x dot replace what
can you
guess
replace two parameters the o string and
a new string so all string will be
x when y yy when we found y y in x so we
want to replace two yy with a single one
x and y
now y y yeah so y replace two y y with a
single
let's run first look we can see it looks
accepted a result and
[Music]
but the thing is that this question uh
can you listen to me
yes so this this only works when the
string consists of x and y it doesn't
work if you have some other characters
like abc right so and another con
another disadvantage of this approach is
that you're looking when we found the
substring in the s it took our n time
right so we will need we we need to find
if a substring is in s normally or in
time and then
and what and
then we need to replace it so in worst
case this will take all n square cubic
oven square and how it will be
first okay okay so i never explain it
now let's say this is always
let's put a comment and then let's do
this
okay so this is the first approach so we
can also we can check if the previous
character so for example like look is x
x y to y y okay so we go through each
character so if x will keep it right the
second x we skip it right because it
equals the previous one and the third
third character we skip it right i'm
right
does it make sense and then why should
we kick it hit it and the second one
should we keep it
okay so then based on this we can do
this so first of all we can put the
answer into a list yeah we keep the
answer
and then for
i let's say for c in s because of each
character if if they are nothing if it's
the first character yeah or
or if the
character
is not equal to what the previous
character how do we
what
would the previous character
in answer so this answer what minus one
right i know what what do we need to do
answer the opponent
okay what c right this is the third
and now what should we do we join we
should join the answer here
let's try this uh to see if well let's
run it okay
is it it works yeah okay
look if we point the answer at this
point it's a list here
if we put the answer and now we can see
if we run it look you see this
you're printed y x y x this is a list
and we need to join remember with the
joint putting this in the string so we
run it it works right
a little bit slower but okay yeah so but
in in series this is all in time
[Music]
time right all in time
does it make sense
a second
[Music]
so it's always very the performance is
very but the most important thing is we
keep the results in the answer and go
through each character in the s
is then answer equal zero what does it
mean it means that
this is the first character we need to
put yeah
or
or if the current character is not equal
to the last character we have right it
means that because if it's equal it
means there's a consecutive characters
right now we append this character into
the answer right okay
okay and do you still remember the group
by function we talked about a few while
ago group by
we can use the google function as well
so how do we use it so look we can say
okay
okay let's say array equals
what x
for x
grew by or maybe x y let's say x y in
it uh i think it's in eta all right
all right
maybe either two or stop goodbye
i'll show you
let's put
it up
okay
let's print this first first to see if
it works okay
yeah because i haven't returned anything
look you pretend you put your results
now look at 20 y x y x right so now a r
look if i print it if if i print it uh
let's print it this one if i print it
quickly x
x and y as a two part right you know eta
two or group by and you see
what is it written
yeah i haven't changed anything look why
is the unique key and then this iterator
this is actually iterator to the group
okay so why are you doing wrong
so we can put a list here we are placed
here to see why what it is okay
look what
can you look at look this is y so the
result the input is yyyy xyx
and now we grouping look we use the x y
in eta to us go by s now when this
happens it has
it has two x axis is the key so it means
y and then it points to yy or x points
to each group right look y
and it has the group and x it has two so
look so we only need to return the first
one which is x is the key
we only need that one and then we we can
we can do what
the same
uh remove the second one right join yeah
we can remove this
and that will be a one-niner right
repeat the one okay so you see
six milliseconds and so this time
complexity is
space space is a one as well space is
the one but this one stays what's the
space let's follow the second approach
what's the space
for this one do we use any space in this
music
no
but we are modifying the original string
because we are replacing this
substring this is the replacement 24
millimeter seconds
can you pay attention to what i'm
talking okay so look
oh string this what's the place what's
the first parameter of the place
x o string and that's the new string to
replace okay
okay so look if i if i do this if i
if i i can do this look replace one here
can you tell me what what what's the
point
if i do
eric
bryan
don't replace
replace
eric with
with with teddy
and then
don't replace
ryan with his mommy so can you can you
tell me what can you tell me what the
result will be
daddy dad
let's do it let's let's let's run this
to see that mom okay because i i said i
want to replace eric here in the
original screen with daddy and then i
want to replace ryan with mommy okay
that's why it is here so look i want to
replace xx with x and then i want to
keep doing this when we find the x axis
i'll keep doing this when we find y to
replace y with y right that's what it is
okay and the second approach yeah we go
through each character yx as long as
it's not equal to the previous one we
push it to the desired
array this then we later we join it and
the third one is the one nano use the
group internal group because it already
does the job and we just need to join it
and putting it okay that's it say bye to
people bye