[Music]
okay
add domain
so what does the email mean so this
domain is like the where where is this
person
[Music]
find me okay so for example yeah
baby
what's daddy's emojis
[Music]
and this is my account
okay this is called email
right
and this microsoft.com is the
is the is the time where it's going to
be delivered right so look
if look your email just eric is eric at
uk
right and if people are sending another
email to eric at like gmail.com do you
think these two becomes the same person
no yeah no obviously no because maybe
but but most of cases know because
eric
at gmail it's like you know there's a
house called gmail.com and there's
another house called happy uk
and you're sending
these two are different different
account email addresses okay
so okay oh and look uh
so these email addresses can have
different formats areas right for
example i can put a stop i can put a top
anywhere right for example i can put the
thought anyway in my account right yeah
this still
still belongs to me it's a different
area and i can put a plus i can put a
plan what does it mean anything after
the plus is the label so i can call
like ad
you know like
monday
microsoft yeah this means
monday okay
this address and
i can have another alias caller friendly
send me email to this address on sunday
okay so then it will be easier for us
for me to categorize those email emails
right
and look email address is a case
insensitive means that after case and no
case don't make a difference right
okay so i i
okay so this is your face
eric right eric at
if i
i will write a few emails can you tell
me
which belongs to ryan is which belongs
to
[Music]
uh
the
class
uh what
good
good okay
good boy another little boy
uh happy young girl is
[Music]
this is not yours this is the time how
about
how about plus
something else
yeah you say yes because everything
after the person is the label yeah you
can have i need
labels of your account right okay i'm
going to give another one okay
e r i
[Music]
yes because i said that if uppercase is
okay it doesn't it doesn't
matter right right okay
okay
look given this
address look input is this right look
and then we want to find out how many
emails this is left right this is
actually received okay how about this
example two
they are all different right they are
different so a a little
[Music]
are they
look at these domain domains can't have
these dots right domain has to be
exactly the same right okay
anything before that you can have areas
but after domain has to be exactly the
same you can't have alias i don't get it
which one is so many you see look like
another one eric
and
happy ukulele.com and
eric
do you think they are the same
they are not the same because i as i
said everything after this domain has to
be the exactly the same you can't have
alias but you can put a dot in front and
that would be
the same these two would be the same
yeah
okay
so so we want to find out how many
unique email addresses considering all
this kind of format what kind of
what's your
data structure
[Music]
what approach are we talking about here
what what's in your mind what you know
what kind of data structure can allow us
to keep it unique yes it said yeah we
use the set key there but first of all
we need to um
now the filter of the the labels the
labels and we get rid of the dots right
yeah
okay so first of all you can have
function right define get simple email
so what does it mean so
let's say this email okay so what does
it return you would return we put a
so you would return you would return
what
return a simple address for example for
example
wait wait
actually i won't need to return this
function with when they tell er i see
that happy okay
okay so
it doesn't make sense we want to at
least get simpler email we want to we
want to return
simplify this email in a simple form
which is get rid of the labels yeah
all right eric get with the labels and
then get rid of the dots okay
yeah
okay so how do we do that first of all
can read the labels oh um um you just
find the plus and then yes now the first
thing we need to find a
what we need to separate our labels
before the
part after the count
[Music]
what are they separated by
i'm not anything yeah that's everything
so after this the name would be anything
everything before
and then domain will be
everything after right okay so now i'm
in a whirlpool now now i want to
i want to
ignore the labels how can i do it
name i want to split by plus sign right
yeah
but i want to i want to keep the first
one only i want to skip i want to ignore
the labor so
what should i put here zero or one what
do you think zero zero zero is the first
part everything before that right it has
a crack in it yeah and then i can do
this replace i can replace the dot with
one i want to remove the top so remove
the one
the people can see the computer too yeah
yeah so look replace the dot with simple
with empty string wait what does it mean
to remove let's do the top right
and then
what's the image
name
plus
[Music]
few examples yeah let's say get simpler
email okay let's just test it for a
little bit e
i don't see class
and uh happy okay
okay so
no i forgot to sign
baby
okay run it
you see yeah you see it removes
everything after that yeah so here we go
okay let's go so let's know
what okay so then we can have a set
right let's do this e let's do this p
dot set right
and then we just need to go through this
math how do we go through emails the
list of emails
exploded
[Music]
emails yeah
yeah
okay and then we we
can you tell me what to do d set and we
want to append what we're going to add
this what how can happen already
um
look we have a set and then this is
email but we want to process it we want
to get the simple email of the email and
put it into the
uh set right and then last we want to do
one last we want to return the length of
the which is the
number of unique email addresses right
yes okay so can you tell me yes
what look look it shows which function
you think it is
come on which function that is
to add something which one
we're going together we're going to call
this one here right
yeah
okay
hello
two yeah the answer is one let's let's
submit
yes
submitted 44 minute seconds
make sense
we can actually do the opposite that we
can what we can do is what
we can uh
[Music]
keep going
okay
[Music]
my keyboard was messed up okay so look
this one i commented now i can do this
name
first of all i can replace i can replace
uh
stock with nothing so what does it what
does it mean
is to what does this mean replace
something to something look i replace
the top we use nothing what is it
actually mean it means that you when you
see a dog you just you link just throw
that away
okay and after throwing away i can split
my
croissant and then you see look at this
look these two you can you notice these
two
just different order right look it's the
same yeah
it's still accepted okay okay yeah it's
faster
now yeah sometimes
yeah
[Music]
unique
we an email address in its simple form
today to the set and then later the
answer will be the length of the set
which contains the number of unique
email addresses right yeah
yeah
okay that's it for today good job bye
bye bye bye bye