okay so today we talk about some um
easy problems mathematics problem okay
so look
if a guy wants to
build a wall but this is the old world
yeah all the wall okay
and then he has this the he wants to
build a rectangular wall
and then look at the tentacle
retainer
and then he has the lens of this lens
this lens
right here is the lens he has to he
wants to use the total lens of 32 this
is nine okay 32
right and then
it has to be a rectangular wall
and what's the maximum we want to
maximum this area
i don't get it
area so look these plus so what
this this old wall and then he has the
length of these three what what do you
call this you want to build the wall of
this
yeah yeah okay so let's that's the
height okay
height and that's the width
okay
so
so what can we do with the 32
h plus h plus w equals 32 right
yeah okay this is 9 right yeah and we
want to maximize what's the area of this
rectangle
it must be h plus h plus w plus
no no no no the area not the length the
length is these three piece
error yeah of anti-clockwise so we want
to maximize this
we want to maximize this okay what do
you mean maximize to make it bigger the
largest yeah that's the one of the
problem in your book right yeah remember
you get your
you know these cheeses
[Music]
hr integer right the pieces you know
that i i don't know what you call it the
bricks
this unit one unit two units so we can
prove first we can prove our switch
either with w the width or h right or
eight what's the minimum width you can
we can try
um
so we can this is the table
right we can this is the table
yeah can we call it this okay it's
bigger than the height
what do you want to eat uh proof what do
you want to try to you can try with edge
or you can try without it up to you
pick one
w okay let's do this
w okay
w and then we have second column h and
then that would be the area okay
area
okay we just need the is the list of
okay but when w is one what's h what's
the value of edge y area
actually equals 32 minus w divided by
two right all right
look yeah yeah
all right
yeah
that's yeah that's okay so
h
so
so what so what's that
so yeah okay so what's the value of
this part
you can do it's fine 31 31 divided by 2
right
yeah what's the area what's the area w
times h would be
right yeah that's the 15.5 right
okay so we can write it as 15 from 5 15
to 0.5 okay let's try to
let's move forward in here both sides
what's the
and what's the area um
okay look yeah i know we can try keep
going man
let's do a few three
three
29 divided by two and then these would
be
i don't know three times 14.5 okay so
it's bigger yeah so
basically we we just want to try this
yeah
try at least w try each w
no no it's not going to take about how
how much
what's the maximum
number we can try
come on
a hundred why is a hundred come on like
given
given condition 32
yeah so all you not even 32 31 up to 31
right because 32 the edge will be zero
you'll be aligned that's not possible
right you're not beating a wall
then it has to be half
i don't know yeah if it's immediate yeah
you can try okay this is this
this is performing we try and we can ask
computers to try that okay let's do this
computer thing and i talk to you about
the mathematic which is
is even better in this case so how do we
move our thing we can prove what in the
wx
w plus 2 times h equals 32 and what we
want is w times h
we want to calculate this the maximum
right we want to get to the maximum size
of this one
right right
yeah
okay so how look the first of all we
want to say the answer equals zero right
yeah
and then we we want to find out we want
to keep the uh we want to go for four
w yeah
alternatively you can go with h right
yes we swipe with the h maybe easier
right for h in
range
we start from one up to up to one after
one right
the thing one is one
look at the all
edge
h uh
i don't know maybe up to up to what up
to 16 right you can't be over than 16
because the oval is 16 then this will be
over 32 and this will be negative right
all right yeah so let's say 16 okay
let's make it
16 and that'll be the maximum will be 15
okay
okay look at h is that and what w equals
minus 2 times h right yeah
am i look here yay
okay totally equal 32 minus 2 times h
and what's the area what's that i don't
you need to check if x
do we need to check uh no we don't need
to check right because look if up to 16
and this will be always bigger than zero
right w will be oh it's bigger than zero
all right
yeah if it's only energy
times h
bigger than answer
right then we keep the answer equals w
times h
yeah
i know we at last we just return the
answer this is the maximum area we can
we can get
you see four is it we're trying the
integer are we only trying integer look
we are only trying the integer because
if it is not integer we we can't try
right because there's so many fraction
numbers like 0.1.2 yeah there's so many
many
numbers right
so you can't actually pull for things
well if we want to brief watching we
have to
we we have to try this limited number of
solutions right like like
this domain has to be limited it can't
be
ultimately large right
and luckily at this case we only tried
16 times like right from 1 to 15 right
it's actually 15 solutions we saw with
this so instead of w h with this h w
right actually equals one
we calculate w we can't get the error h
equals two up to 15 right
only twice 15.
yeah
what's the time complexion for this one
come on
think about it what else the ham
convexity oh and and a little bit more
look this is the concept
actually there's no input right because
all the inputs are known right
the inputs are known
yeah so n no no
there's no input okay so there's no
input there's no meaning of doing this
uh complexity
uh analysis right because
the problem size is fixed and we are
we're only solving this mathematic
problem okay
if we want to keep the if if we want to
know
if we want to know which number which w
or value which w and h when we get the
maximum so we can say look we can have
this and we want to try this h ui so we
have max x equals one and then look if w
times h
bigger than answer we we call the
maximum area and then we at the same
time we remember the max h
which is max h equals yeah that's right
does it make sense yeah yeah okay
okay now i'm going to teach you about
mathematics which is
very cool you you're surprised how how
useful is this okay
i will not say what okay so first of all
i want to introduce a few english words
which one the first one is you might
have heard of this before yeah cool
what's called
quadratic
one two two quadratic okay another
equation and then we have this one
three symmetric symmetric
hx6 what does it mean symmetric the
magic i use is this thing you can fold
it yeah you can fold it okay good job
and how about this okay
oh
[Music]
look it's like when you throw the things
and then
how how how is uh when how it goes right
look how it go
how we go
it's like look look how it goes like you
saw the thing you'll be like that
because of gravity and gravity
gravity you know the gravity if it is an
airplane you will go like new you know
the gravity yeah because the gravity
gravity the earth are pulling us down
right
if there is no gravity what happens
we'll be
[Music]
you went to this botanic garden in
cambridge
why why the apple fall down instead of
flying up and that's why he discovered
gravity yeah yeah the earthquake because
the gravity we have this gravity g and
then we're putting the things
[ __ ] f right okay so
there's a
this is the object this is the object
and then you have f right
and i now have a g and then that's why
you'll be something
okay so okay so
so uh so parabola is is is the
mathematic right like look
remember this x y right this is x
this is y
okay so
okay if i have a function y equals x
squared look square
x times x this is quadratic because it's
8 squared okay
what when x is 0 what's the value of y
come on
[Music]
when x is one what's the value of y
only one one ah this is one here okay
when x is two what's the value of y four
okay so that's one
two
three
four so that's fine
so look one two three four when x is two
y is four right so it should be here
five okay
so if you own actually three
so it's somewhere here so actually if
you connected these points
what does it look like
parabolic you know you know you have to
flip it flip it and look at this way
but look when it's negative when it's
negative you know the negative is
symmetric
yeah negative look
minus one square equals
um
minus one
no no no no
double
[Music]
minus one square inverse
yeah minus two square
two squared
my
minus three square
nine yes you see so what does it even
mean look if it's minus three
it's also nine right yeah
what is minus two it's also four so look
what this means symmetric axis yeah
yeah it can be folded along these so
what does measuring x is in this case y
equals x squared
y equals y equals x squared what's
which one is the symmetric axis
come on so this which one is the
semester x
um
these
symmetric
why are they floating too
y-axis which is x equals zero right
yeah
okay
okay so look
sorry okay so look
so
what value
so this this this function every
function of this y uh so this is
conjecture function okay the quadratic
function can be generalized as what a
times x square plus b
x
plus c
yeah y equals that right
what does it mean a b c are constant
okay so can you tell me y equals x
square what's the value of abc
what's the value of abc if y equals x
squared what's the value of a
um nothing what's the value of a
a a times square what's the value of a
ammo
double x squared no x squared look x
squared so what's the before this a a
what's the value of a a times s squared
equals a squared so what's the value of
a x
no no look this is the same so what a
times x squared equals x squared so
what's a
zero
one one come on yeah what's the value of
b
b times x equals nothing so what's the
value of b b times x
nothing say b is what
yeah and what c equals nothing so what's
the value of z zero okay so let's look
so this and any
any
quadratic equations can be simple
generalized as this a b c okay abc a is
the constant
of the of of the constant that
comes before these quadratic terms right
and b is the linear term c is a constant
right
why is it useful
why is it useful because we control this
we can draw this
like that yeah this this uh
when c is zero what does it mean when c
is zero
this function goes to the zero zero zero
right
yeah look if you put a zero in
this term will be zero p x will be zero
right
i want t is zero y is zero right
yeah yes
okay so if a is positive like a a is one
it will be like that how about a is
negative like minus
y equals minus x square so what does it
look like
can you imagine why what i told you i
you know y equals x square is here and
how about if i put the negative
still
look when x equals one what what's the
you can you can have the value y equals
one minus one right one x equals two
what y equals one
four right yeah so it's on this side
why is mine i literally said that also
can you draw because i'm not sure what
do you mean
okay we're done can you draw
on which side i saw you mean
so when when a is negative it will be
something like that right when a is
positive it will be something like that
right okay that's the first thing so
and if we find a symmetric axis we can
find that we can find the maximum and
mean or we can find the minimum right of
the function
at this point
yeah if a is particular or we can find
the maximum
value of this function if a is negative
right
and okay so what's this part okay
okay this part okay
this is the most important thing here
this axis symmetric axis is
minus look
two times a b okay this is
yeah this is the symmetric
x value
so when x equals these
we have a minimum
or maximum value of this function
okay minus b divided by two times a for
example look
uh
a a and b look b is zero so so
when b is yellow this whole thing is
zero right
yeah and this whole thing is zero so the
symmetric axis is this yeah actually
goes zero correct
okay so look this whole thing can be
shifted right shifted left or right
depending on this lump at least
right got it yeah yeah okay so now we
have this basics then we can come back
to solve the problem very very easy
very very easy okay how can we solve
this
look at this thing last thing again okay
this is like
of the word
and the guy wants to build a new like
new fence okay let's go different this
is h
this is w okay and we know w plus 2
times h equals 32 right
we already know that right
and we want to maximize the function y
equals w times h
right so what's w
w equals 32 minus 2 times h i'm right
yeah
w equals 32 minus 2 times x you moving
this term from left side to the right
side you have to
neglect the sun right yeah
okay so y equals 1 y equals this
32 minus 2 times h times h right
yeah
look at this
okay so how what's this
we can rewrite it as minus 2 h
square
plus 32 h
all right
you see
minus 2 we have this minus 2 we take
this outside right minus 2h squared
plus 32 h right all right this is the
function
okay so what's what's it it's a
quadratic equation remember what's
what's the symmetric axis remember
what's a
a equals one
y is one what is one what what's this
two what's b
what's the constant before the linear
term
what's what's there right
anyway
okay what's c
what's c is there any constant yeah no
so what's that
okay what's what's his axis
what's his axis
this one
what's that this value
minus
one
divided by
minus
minus four right
so we have
two times minus two is minus four we
have a negative
double negative makes positive though
so what's a what's
what's that
what's h
so h when h equals
when h equals a we have a maximum value
am right
why is that because a is negative so the
sign
the sun is
like that right something like that
it's facing down the the
parallel
facing down
facing down we have a maximum value
right here correct
and
when is the x h this is h now s equals a
because it's in the symmetric axis right
good
so h is a we have a maxima so what when
h h is a what's the value of w
w equals one
when h is a
the way what's the value of it
two times a 16.
16 plus something equals 32 what's the
value of what what's what's the area w
16.
what's his size what's his area
w times h what's the area
these two times there 128 right this is
the answer to the question
on your book
you see
it's very cool right
instead of listing the value in the
tables one two three four five six seven
eight until 15.
i i can calculate
when h equals eight
we have the maximum
because look this function is that
yeah so it's facing down when h is
eight okay so
yeah when h is a here
it has the maximum
okay
uh
any questions so far
no
no no
okay so what have we learned yesterday
what have we learned today
to sum up um
we call it
we call it y equals a times x times x to
the look this is calculated all right
plus b times x plus c
where a
is not equal to zero yeah if a if a is
zero then it's it what's b x plus c
if a is zero what happens
[Music]
and what's this this is a line
this is a line okay
and if a is not equal to zero
b c can be zero
so this is a quadratic it's a parabola
right
and it's a symmetric axis you know
floating when you fold it it's magic
axis minus two times a
b right
and when a
a is bigger than zero right
when a is bigger than zero the
is facing
facing up or facing down
facing out come on facing up with
something like when a is smaller than
zero
it's the opposite right
so when a is bigger than zero
and when x is at
this point when x is this one
does this paragraph have a maximum or
minimum value
this one when a is bigger than zero and
one x is at this point there's symmetric
axis so that they have a big a maximum
value on a minimum a
max
this point is maximum minimum come on
you look at this all other points are
bigger than this this is the lower point
so and up how about this when a is
negative and zero maximum yeah when you
are x at this point you will have
maximum weight right is it that's the
important takeaway so you can use these
techniques to solve those
questions mathematic challenge on your
book easily beautifully
today yeah
okay yeah
okay that's it for today good job bye
bye
bye bye