hello
hello mr mr ryan how are you today
okay yeah today we're going to talk
about a nice problem okay um probably no
coding okay just just mathematical
problem uh it's from your book
yeah or for a book math project
so six identical
squares were side lengths of three
centimeters so six squares okay each one
sixth grade each one we say three
we want to put it to form a large
rectangle we only put it into large
rectangle what's the maximum parameter
what's the parameter another parameter
if it's the three what's the perimeter
of b square
parameter the possible rotators from
here what's the parameter
um the outside it's the outside so what
what's the perimeter of this square
it's 12
12 yeah because four times four six
because we're gonna take up and there
are six of it so how can you how can we
rearrange the rectangles into using the
six rectangles
into a rectangle yeah six squares eating
a little
one of these
is you can place ten
what look you can put this yeah
six six squares by ten ten oh like
william said
you can put it side by side so that's
another way of doing this okay
anymore
look at this this one is two two rows
three columns they have two rows three
columns how about three three columns
two rows
how about three columns to those uh
[Music]
still the same as two dollars yeah yeah
these two understand actually you should
rotate though it doesn't change the
parameters here we are looking for that
maximum parameter maximum parameter
my perimeter okay maximum so what's the
perimeter of this one what's the
parameter of this one
kind of like ryan said 10 how do you one
two three four five six seven eight nine
ten
thirty
yeah yeah okay
okay one two three four is one two three
six times three times two six six plus
four ten so ten ten times three yeah we
said that thirty okay the parameter is
thirty yeah i said and this is always
thirteen how about the second one what's
the parameters of this
one two three four five six seven eight
nine ten eleven twelve
fourteen
four four five
four two yeah look one two three four
five six six times two twelve foot plus
two on each side is 14 times 3 is yeah
14 times 3 okay
okay so which one is bigger
yeah
okay so
this is quite simple and how about
how about i tell you if there are
uh eight rectangles and how
what's the maximum we can get uh
that line one two three four five so
what's the what's the strategy of this
yeah
that's seven
when you do like a square like yeah
yeah um you have more in the middle and
you go yeah exactly let's compare the
sixth one look so
if if the unit is each unit
what's how many how many if there are
six rectangles or six squares how many
one two three no no there are more than
that okay they're eight okay okay let's
see yeah if six go
each one is side of three and how many
sides of that four right this is total
number the parameters you can get you
can put it disconnected okay everyone
yeah so that's how many that's 72 right
if you that's a lot no no if you put
these one by one okay
what i'm saying is that if you put it if
you look if you put them disconnected
what's the total parameter all right
what's the total term
so each one yeah three
three times four
that's six yeah
okay so
what happens if i do this to here look
what what's happening what's happening
all right yeah
what's happening from here to here
what's
yes how many joint ages are there um two
four six eight ten
twelve
two
four six eight
ten right yeah i said 10 10 okay so look
so that's perimeter of this one is what
72 minus
times three equals one
equals one
equals 42. yeah that's how we go and how
about this one 72 minus how many ages
are there
um 2 4 6
8 10 12
14 16
yeah 16 yeah 16 times three forty eight
is this sixteen two four oh no
fourteen yeah fourteen two four
six
eight ten twelve fourteen so that's what
thirty yeah that's how we got 30. so
look this number we can calculate it's
always fixed yeah this number is fixed
this number let's say it's t
minus these joint ages the internet ages
like a this is the number we want to
maximize we want to we want to maximize
this number
we want to maximize this number
we want to make minus one this number is
fixed so we have two
so this number has to be
bigger or
smaller if we want this whole thing to
be bigger so we want this number to be
smaller how do we put it smaller what's
the optimal solution
put in the line put it in the line right
so so it doesn't have cost more internal
edges right if i tell you that there are
a million rectangles
squares and how do we arrange it to you
don't need to give me an answer a line
you're just putting one by one yeah
okay
this is
[Music]
what's the maximum parameter you can get
what's the formula if they're n
rectangle what's how many edges two
edges one two
one two three four five there are six
yeah so it will be
six uh will be n minus 1 right n minus 1
times 2 right
and then times m right this is number of
internal edges you can get so the answer
will be y the answer will be what can we
do this and this is the unit times
times one
and minus two times
n minus one right let's say if there are
four
four what's the what's the answer four
one two three
three times two six yeah four yeah okay
so the answer is what answer is this one
uh is it right
[Music]
no no no no
is it like look there's something
there's something
and can
n square right so each one the total one
will be times four okay we forgot the
transform so there will be four n
yeah so that answer will be n times 4 n
minus 2 n
and then plus 2 right so this is 2 n
plus 2 so the answer would be
2 n plus 2
times m ok let's let's use this six if n
is six two times six
twelve plus two fourteen times three
okay so the answer is this one
[Music]
this is greedy okay we call it sweetie
because we know how we we know
the optimum solution okay i'm going to
do that one more time can you can you
listen to me yeah we are
so there and this is the ultimate we
just proved like
and then n so what's the total number of
uh parameters for the n squared okay so
it's n times
and the side is m right this side is m n
times m but each one is they are four
four right this is the total and then
how many edges in the middle
five six n minus one times two right so
this is the answer so look
four n and times m right so we we get
these n common terms yeah so m times the
answer is l
four n minus two n
plus two
and that will be n times
two n plus two
right look yeah if it is eight
let's do this two uh uh
four okay four
to this or this
this is bigger yeah obvious this is
bigger
so look this is what
how many edges if m is one so at two
times four
two times four plus two is ten one two
three four five six seven eight nine ten
got it yes so if we write this define
so we can if we want we can just write
this define
we have maximum
parameters
and now we can say n squares each side
is m and we just written what
we can
n times
two n plus two okay what's the time
complexity for this one oh and
come on don't just scare what what's the
time conversation
[Music]
come on
because there's no we just calculate
this right there
okay
[Music]