hello
hello mr mr rhino are you right
yeah uh remember
what we have talked about is quadratic
equation yeah conjecture what's
conjugated
quadratic equation
what's conjecturing mean it's this um
what what's called you you say it's
false but it's not for
quadratic
so
is this a symmetric thing yeah yeah x
squared plus b x plus c equals zero
right this is conjugated because we only
have one unknown which is x
okay unknown this x is unknown we want
to solve it
a b c are constant where a is not equal
to zero if a is equal to zero then this
whole thing is gone it's b x plus c is
not quadratic okay make sense but b x
plus c
equals zero that's a line
that's a line
line okay if you draw these please
remember parabola yeah parabola yeah
but then the graph you look like
yeah these are yeah pollution yeah yeah
don't get out going down if a is
positive it is going up and it's
negative
going down all right
okay so
yeah that's fine okay so now we talk uh
today we're going to solve this problem
we're going to find the roots
the roots okay
to this equation
given is a b c if they are any right
sometimes they don't uh we don't have
any uh
sometimes this causative equation does
not have any roots right or you could
have a
you know
imaginary which is not real okay
so these are roots
so first of all look
so first of all can you tell me a times
b plus c
can we write it as what
what is the equal
the the addition rule remember
a times b plus a times c right doesn't
make sense yeah
yeah this is this is single right let
that give you an example 10 times
20 plus 5 what does it equal
come on give me an answer a thousand
huh
ten times twenty plus five
i mean uh two hundred fifty two hundred
fifty yeah so what does z equal it
equals ten times twenty
plus you know you see ten times twenty
plus 10 times 5 right this is 200 and
this is 50. and if it's if it's negative
it's the same right if it's minus you
can change the minus right correct this
is called additional right okay so you
we know this and how about this
a plus b
times c plus b
so how can we write this
how can we write this
eh
so the exchange rule will be something
like look look you can
take this whole thing as one one term
okay
take this whole whole thing as one term
right so you'll be
a plus b
times c
plus what
a plus b
times t right yeah this whole thing is a
term right right right you're looking at
right
okay and now if we keep expanding this
right like this it will be ac plus bc
plus a d yeah
a d plus b d right yeah
okay
and then look
if we
look this is the if we can join this
right we're going to join this will be a
c plus d
plus one b
c plus d we join these two terms right
okay and then look this is common terms
like c plus d and then times a plus b
okay it's the same it's the same yeah so
the point i'm doing here is i want to
prove that this
this uh additional rule right so you can
take this
so how look
if
if it's the same a plus b
square
square right so it's actually
what a plus b
if a plus b times a plus b
yeah
a plus b times
a plus b so a is actually a plus b
a plus b squared what does it equal
right we can do this whole thing take
this so a plus b times a right
yeah
and plus
plus one
a plus b times r
times b right and this thing you know
right it's a
a square plus
a b
plus
b square okay so what do we have
a a square plus two times a b
plus b squared okay
so this is very important okay a
a plus b square equals
a squared plus b squared plus two times
a b okay
yeah
make sense
okay ryan are you all right
a squared plus b squared plus two a b
okay
now
now we have no at least okay so let's
let's do this look
a square plus b x plus c equals zero and
how about if i move the c to the right
hand side so what is z equal if i move
the plastic plus term on the other side
of equation we need to do a we need to
change the sign right alright
so what does the ego
so a x square plus b x equals minus c
okay
yeah
yeah it simply move the constant
to the right hand side
and this means we need to give it a
negative to neglect
neglect negat we get
we get the the number
okay and how about if i times
4a
yeah for a to both sides yeah because
they have two left they are the same so
if i multiply both
both sides for a 4 times a
4 times a okay so what does it go
4 a squared
x square
plus 4 a b x
equals minus 4 a c
yeah from here
to here
we multiply both sides for a
right
a is not equal to zero right we know
that
and now
next step is okay now we do this four
times five and then here we are i want
to add a
b square to to both sides right if both
terms are equal
if the values expressions be uh you know
on both sides of the
equation
we can add the same similar terms the
same thing right so we add b squared so
it's 4a squared
x squared plus 4 a b
x plus b squared equals what
b squared
plus four ac right
great okay so this is the magic this is
the magic
so this is the magic so this left hand
left hand side equals one
equals two a
two a x
plus
b
square you see
hey look we have talked about this a
plus b
a plus c square equals 1
a squared plus 2 a b plus b square right
yeah yeah we know that yeah i just
showed you before right and so
we can do we can check if this equals
yeah
this thing squared is 4a squared x
squared
this thing squared is b squared yeah so
we have these two terms here and 2
2 times a b so if i times these times c
times two is two a x
b
times two is four a x b x right four a b
x yeah exactly so look
yeah
so look two a
plus b squared equals b squared minus
4ac
okay if if we square root of both both
sides
yeah if we square root both sides
right so we need to
put a
plus minus because it has two rules
right so look
x square equals 16 what's x
uh four
four and another another root is minus
four remember
yeah four times square four square is
sixteen minus four square is also
sixteen because minus one times minus
one
double negative makes positive right so
that's another so if we square root of
this
so 2a x plus b square root 3
b squared minus 4ac and we need to put
the plus minus sign yeah right that's
what it means
and now
this is easy we want to find the value
of x
by the way you don't need to remember
all these i'm just showing how showing
you how we get the final equation right
yeah
okay now look so 2a x plus b equals that
then b x equals 1
x equals
minus 2a right minus 2a
uh
uh no 2a
if you uh
actually
let's do it one by one okay so it's
confused
minus b to the other side so
b squared minus four ac
plus equal and then minus
plus equal minus minus b
divided by 2a okay
okay so this x is equally
2a
minus b
plus minus
square b
square root of b square minus 4ac okay
this is the final square the final
equation
yes
it's not easy yeah it's not easy to
remember but that's okay you can always
look it up yeah
if you have if we have an equation like
look
2x square plus
uh
let me let me write
x square plus 2 x plus 1
equals 0
okay
so what's x
what's the value of a in this case
what's abc
a is
what's the term before that
one one what's the b
coefficient
b what's the term before the one you
know linear
what's the value before x
what's the value because
two what's the value of c
what's the constant term which one
constant one yeah okay so what's the
rule of it x equals left so x equals one
two times a two times one
minus b is minus two
plus minus
b squared
four
minus four times a with one
yeah okay
so what's this number four minus over
zero
square root of zero
two
minus two
divided by two
minus one right so the root is minus one
there's only one root why is that
because plus minus there are two h
actually two roots but they are still
the same so it's all
it's both minus one
okay let's put it back
minus one
square
plus two times minus one plus one
is it equal to zero
minus one square
one two minus two times minus one
two times minus one
minus two
plus one
what's this
[Music]
yeah you see we find a little is it yeah
okay so what why is that look um
why is that
because look at x this x
it can be written as x minus 1 square
or x plus one square equals zero right
yeah remember we go we know
a plus b square
equals a squared plus two a b plus b
squared right yeah we already know that
this is very important here
now look let's verify if this is x
square
plus a square
plus b square
plus two times of
these terms together yeah you see
so look
x plus one square equals zero what's the
value of x
what's the value of x x plus one
squared equals zero what's the value of
x you take the square root so what's
this
this is zero so what's x zero
x plus one equals zero minus one yeah
you see yeah okay okay another example
another example okay
x minus three times x minus x plus four
equals zero
what's the what's the possible value of
x some of this is easy
x minus three
times x plus 4 equals 0. if two numbers
multiply to 0
what does it mean
one of them is zero right yeah so either
this is zero all this is zero right so
if x is three
this is zero if x equals minus four
this is zero so there are two roots yeah
that's two roots
right look this is true this is easy but
if we convert it to less tender ax
square plus bx plus c equals zero look
what's this
x square plus
four x
minus three x
minus 12 equals zero all right right x
square
plus x minus 12 equals zero
okay so look this is a a is one
b is one
c is minus 12 right
yeah
okay so if we
let's verify that to see if it's correct
okay
uh
[Music]
let's just double check x square plus 4x
minus 3x
minus 12 yeah
so look 2 times a 2
minus b
plus minus
b squared
plus 4 times 12 so 48
yeah
4 48 plus 1 49 what's the square root of
49 um seven yeah so seven this whole
thing is seven so there are two roots
minus one plus seven divided by two or
minus one minus seven divided by two
when it's plus that's three
what is minus is minus four right
yeah you see
yeah you see it's the same yeah you see
it's the same okay
okay so why is this useful okay why is
this reason
okay so sir
sometimes it doesn't have a load for
example
if you write if you plot this in the
graph x and y right right
if you if the graph is like that
there's two roots
yeah when y is you know there's two
roots right yeah two roots
yeah all right but you forgot it's like
that doesn't have a root
it doesn't have any connection back to
the actual axis right but how about this
does it have a root
yeah you have two roots you have two
roots okay so when it doesn't when look
because we have a term b square minus
four ac
if it it only has it only has
roots okay we call it roots real roots
real roots
real roots if and only if b square minus
4ac is bigger or equal than zero right
can you tell me what's the minus
negative
16 square root right there's no real
rules
to get it right yeah
yeah
but we have look
these things square root the real roots
for the square root
right it needs to this term inside is
going to be bigger or equal than zero
right that's what it means so when we
think b square minus 4ac
is bigger or equal than zero then this
this term parallel
here yes parallel bar
has
tested what
intercess with the x-axis we can find
the roots right either one or two
two roots yeah
okay
am i right
look why y equals x square here
the node is yeah connection zero
x squared plus one equals zero
what's x squared plus y zero
is here
it doesn't have connection with x axis
right so it doesn't have any rows but
how about this one what's this it's
minus x square
plus one
is this when x is zero y is one one
right
so look it has two loads right
yes to lose right okay because when a is
when a
is negative this this whole thing is
facing down right this whole thing is
facing down
so when x is yellow it's one
so
it's facing down right so you have two
loops right okay so now today easy
given uh the final thing final thing
before i forget
given this ax square plus bx plus c
equals zero right and we want to find
the real root so define
find
real rule all right let's say real word
because it has
it has another roots but we are focusing
on real notes
a b c okay
give us three numbers nice
so look if a
is zero okay if a0 we will we want to
raise exception okay we can say we
value exception or exception
what's the exception
a is zero
exception means that okay um
there's some errors i i yeah it
it's quite similar to assert yeah a set
yeah
right
yeah i said it's like what's
computed to up to double check yeah if a
is zero then i can't continue right
because it's not what i designed these
arguments all right so let's write the a
yeah uh a
if a equals zero then we return we this
an exception and return okay whatever
if
b square b times times b square minus 4
times a times c
right
if it's smaller than zero what does it
mean
we don't we don't have a blues yeah the
graph doesn't have a connection with the
x-axis right so we can say race
where is exception okay does that have a
root doesn't
uh doesn't have a
yeah i'm just yeah i'm just lazy yeah
raise the extension we don't have any
room real root okay and then now we want
to return to lose yeah so
we can sell we can save this uh this
term so
uh what's this term let's call it
let's call it one ah
equals b square
yeah b square this is b square b squared
you can write b time times one two okay
or
b times b okay or power
b two yeah this three thing same these
three are the same yeah
yeah these three are the same
they are all b square okay
you can already implicitly using this
approach
minus four times a
times c okay
i know
we know at this point we know this thing
is bigger or equal than zero so we want
to get the square root of it so we can
do this s q r t max square the x square
root
yeah how do we go the square root
square root b
we can we can also have use this is this
square root sqrt this function b or we
can do this b
bit times times what
what times one zero point five half
right
this is means half all power
b 0.5 yeah this is the same thing okay
now we have r equals that and another
two roots you have to root
to lose x1 we use x1 the first rule is
x1 x1 equals
yeah let's try this
yeah
all right so the first first rule is
what
minus c
plus r
divided by
2 times a right
x 2 equals 1 minus b minus r
divided by 2 times a and we can return
this as a cube
return q by f what's cuba
x one x two x what's cuba
what's cuba
last question what's the cube
immutable list initially look you can
pronounce what's what's the difference
between this x1
x1 comma x2 these square brackets and x1
x2 what's the difference between these
two in python
you can change this
this is mutable at least this is
immutable we call it jupiter so we
retain two values x1 x2 representing the
two
two real roots right if we don't have
real roots
either if a equals zero is not a
quadratic equation or this term this
b square minus for ac is smaller than
zero we don't have a real root okay
otherwise we have two roots
got it
yeah why is this useful okay so the last
question
last question what's the content space
complexity policy
[Music]
what's the time convexity
come on
what's the timing next to do we need any
space do we need
we don't need any space
what's the
we just give a little calculated do we
need to a one because we
it's not dependent on the scale of the
input right you give me a million abc we
still calculated constant term right
okay
final quiz final quiz this time is the
finals 2 x square plus
minus 3 x plus 5 equals zero can you
find the root of this do you lose
i say a is two b is minus three c is
five right so what's the root
what's the rule what's the rule
two a minus b plus minus
b squared minus 4ac yeah okay we just
have to plug in the value right
a is 2
so this thing is 4
minus 3. so this thing is 3. b square
a b squared nine nine
four times a times c
fourteen forty okay so this one does not
have any
rules right so it should be it could be
something like that
yeah
okay
okay look look
look at this thing look at this thing
remember what's this
what what what's the this is the rule
right this uh
this is lulu
x1 x2
this is the new two route
symmetric remember what's the symmetric
symmetric axis
yeah
so this one is the symmetric axis
remember yeah
okay
okay that's it for today good job bye
bye bye bye bye