okay so today we're going to talk about
a simple problem which is called reshape
the metric okay so what's magic what
metric
uh let's say we're given a list of a way
okay one dimensional array right and
right dimension all right so it's a list
so let's say array equals
one two three four alright listen to me
write this to me look
at this four elements yeah and if you
want to if i tell you that i want to
reshape it
reshape it to two times two two rows two
columns so what does it become so
well what if it you want to shape it
like four times one
good job look two times two is like that
one two you always start feeling the
rose there one two
three four yeah okay so this is yeah so
yeah i know you mean four times one what
do you say four times one so what does
it come to come
ah one two three four easy
yeah so each one is a
it's a two dimensional array how about
one times four
nine it will be the same it'll be the
same
yeah yeah yeah
actually it will be different because
this is one dimension
if we convert it to one time slot you'll
be like that
another list yeah
okay let's just start to be different
okay
so however if i tell you i want to
convert this to
two times the three is it possible
two times no why is that because it
means four
yeah because look we only have five
six we're done whether we have four
elements but now the top is six evidence
so that's not possible so we do ten
scratch empty list
that's it yeah
so
first of all first question is how do we
allocate a
scratch
how do we allocate a three times two
metric with zero with zero
how do we how to allocate look three
times two three rows two columns yeah
three rows two columns so it will be
zero zero
zero zero how do we allocate these they
look like eyes
how do we look accurately a list of
lists yeah a list of these which has a
list which has three read these sublets
and each of these has
two elements there's three rows two
columns
so look if the target then let's say the
target equals one
zero right
for underscore means that we don't
we don't need to use this variable in
range
inventory how many how many elements are
these
three how many elements of each service
two two yeah so this is the columns
first anime you need to put in columns
and then this is a service yeah and then
four
in range invented how many laws
how many rows
uh
three zeros yeah that's the way we
allocate a two dimensional
uh two dimensional
in python okay which is this if we
replace this with the r and with the c
and this is r this is the way to
allocate a
two dimensional which is r times c
metric in person okay and then we can
start following the list one by one and
start feeling it in in you know one by
one in the world yeah look look
one two three four how how do we how do
we
allocate how do we feel it in here
yeah
uh yeah like look at it
so this is the animal in the face so
look one we put it here
two
three
four that's it that's the angle okay all
right so we write it and you'll be easy
quick
define
the keyword we shade
we want to reshape the first dimensional
metric
array to the
metric right we turn that let's say the
array a
we want to reshape it into our
arrow c columns
okay
so first single
first thing we need to check is
can we do this so right so let's
if
length a
not equal not equal one
let's say no equal one
length
this is
length three it's four do that times
tables
i is two c is two so how can we check if
it's equal if it's uh possible to do it
or not to check for times tables so r
times what
c right if it's not equal then return
empty right
okay and then next next we what should
we do we should create an answer
all right right
answer equals
zero for underscore in range one c or r
come on tell me
when you ask
for
underscore in range can you tell me what
should i put here
exactly here c c or r or c r or rc come
on
cr yes yeah first of all you see and
then r i found your nails yeah
okay and then we start from we started
feeling that right let's say the index i
equals yellow right and then we start to
loop into the start to iterate over this
answer
we start to iterate over this answer
metric right and then to fill in the
values so for r uh let's say for
we have used r okay let's let's do it
for
r okay
in range
ah
and then
for
cc
in range c i will go through each
element in the new
metric right
and then
answer we start to fill in the number r
c c equals what
equals one now this index is i so
where's the original a a1
a1
and then what should we do with the i if
we fill it what do we do
we should
move it to
move it to next so a plus equal one
that's not a that's i okay i plus equal
one
okay and then return
after
[Music]
but you didn't say a n is a time c all
right because i need to know what's n i
r n is okay why but you know what is
[Music]
um
come on
it's very obvious hi all right we're
done that's it for today good job bye
bye bye
okay that's it