[Music]
okay so today we're going to go into
these some basic concepts of this hash
hashing yeah hashing
hashing hash table hashing
how do you define a hash table in python
what's the alternative of hash table
like we have been using that for a long
time you know when solving some problems
hashing table like
what
any idea
what's that if you want to look up the
items
in a thingy what do we call it
is the name that i give you you know but
it's not official the inflation name is
the hash table okay
yeah but why we talk koi notebook yeah
because you want to look up the items
you put item in you write a sentence in
a notebook you look it up it's constant
time it's very fast you don't you
actually need to
perform the searches right
so in python we have this dictionary
dictionary so we can we can declare
dictionary like that a equal this is
additional yeah a equals dictionary you
can do this dictionary
yeah dictionary or
the one way first way is the oh you use
this yeah second
yeah this is the what do you call it
curly
and the third way is to what a equals
default dictionary default
edition okay and then you can give a
basic type of integer this is the value
type that's the value what type of a
value type of value
these two
the same
these two just look the same
so what's the difference between these
and these the difference is that when
the key does not exist in the in the
hash table
using this definition the
if the key isn't
in the in the hash table and it will
return the default value for the time
for for example you'll be
zero yeah the different type of integers
you know so look if if uh i can say look
a
something like a
eric okay
if i want to put in the a array without
ever
ever putting the values of eric right so
that will give me the zero unless i do a
array equals nine or whatever
right if if i use the the third approach
the default one but if i use the
first or second approach to declare a
hash table and a area with swallow error
yeah it was all errors i'm saying the
key does not exist like error does not
exist not here like little different but
using these two you know you can always
use this a dot
get yeah
get eric
and then the second value will be the
default which i can give like a
five and then if eric is the key is not
in the table and then you will return
the flag if it's not in the table and
you will look up the table the values
for the key equals errors right
that's that dictionary
so what's the term complexity of all is
like lookup i want to look up a key if
uh if a key is uh in a
dictionary
what's the time complexity there's three
or
few operations right the second one is i
want to update
update update of key value pair right
update
value with key
with the key right
and the third one i want to delete
remove it
today the key right
basically these are the three approaches
the common approaches that are
required for the hash table right like a
notebook if i want to
uh look it up a key if it's everything
in a book right a key value
a one constant right
and i want to update like eric
map area
equals nine
right
and i want to remove it what's the time
complexity for all these three
approaches come on
any anybody right
we own the first terms that's why a one
yeah
that's the
obvious reason that we want to use this
kind of data structure because we want
to achieve the o1 constant right
so um
so we're talking about the hash function
hashing function hashing function
hashing function what's hash function is
that function that to map
map
arbitrary length of data input into a
map arbitrary length of data into a
fixed size of
into a fixed size a table and fixed size
fixed size
so what does it mean
so look if i have a hatching table like
maybe there are only 10 elements right
only 10 elements maybe one two three
four five six seven
eight nine eight nine 10 yeah 10 element
this is a
hash table with size 10
right and i want to put a key
any key any key i want to put uh maybe
10 items any items for example like
something something coming area i want
to put this every thing
yeah and then there's a hash function
data
and then you'll give me
when this data
is
fit into this hash function and it will
give me a key a location to store these
error data so for example you will start
here right and then another one ryan
and then go through this
h function has function ryan
and then you'll give me a key okay maybe
store here right
so now next time i want to look it up
this data eric ryan and i need to call
this hedge function again and it will
tell me where to look for it but this is
the time interview
to look it up to locate locations right
so
if
if these keys i mean if there are many
many data what happened can you can you
imagine like what happened if if this
table is 10 and then if i have like a
hundred a million data
what can you imagine
what can you imagine in this case
so if i have too many datas here and i
want to map it into a fixed size what
happened they are arbitrary ones
it will take for longer and this is not
the most important reason the another
reason is there will be uh collision you
know the collision
collision
what does it mean collision in in
english
collide each other it means the
different different inputs
for example eric and ryan they are
different these keys are different right
but they after the hd calculation they
might point to the same
place
right
one one approach to solve this problem
is to what we can have instead of
solving one item we can do one
we can point it at linkeries or list
right for each each key
each
key here
and i can i
for example eric is here i stole here
and ryan if if if the hashing function
points to this location
and this location
yeah and i can append it to the linked
list right
so i don't overwrite i don't lose the
data this is one way of doing it right
what are we doing so
we want to uh
reduce the chance of collision
right one way of doing is by picking up
a good hashing function
yeah location function so this hashing
function h data
you need it needs to do what it needs to
calculate the key the the values the
the location which is maybe a certified
integer right a location
or
yeah let's say if it's a
32-bit integer
no matter how big is this data maybe a
minion
you always return a fixed size
fixed size fixed size uh location right
so we want we want to we want this
function to be
first of all it has to be very fast
right
this function calculation needs to be
fast if it's slow then there will be
overhead because this hatching function
i need to use it every time
to do what i need i need to use it every
time to calculate the location when i
want to retrieve a element from the
table when i when i want to update it
all right oh i want to remove it these
are free approach yeah three three
operations one
lookup
update yeah for the hashtable update
remote right remove
this last missing these three operations
all require me to
to calculate the hashing table hashing
key i have the key
why so needs to be fast if it's slow
then everything will be slow
the second i want to reduce the
collection
reduce the collection
what does it mean
right if you give me the eric
yeah oh you give me the ryan i don't
want them to point you to a certain
location right because the same location
all these will be falling falling back
into the linear search right look if
these everything just imagine in the
worst case if i xt
always returns zero no matter what data
you give you want to put in a hash table
or
put it in that zero location put it here
right this is intact zero yeah if i put
an array if it's here
i want to i put another right is here
and mommy
daddy right everything you put in here
so this hedge function
is
it's not working you always return a
zero means that location here so what
happened next time i want to
look at through this
this becomes
what what's the time frame let's say if
st is zero what's the timeline where st
oh oh what
what's the operation of looking up i
looking up a key in the list
how do you find an element in the list
from the beginning and then search it
what's the time to listen for that
yeah
update
update is based on the cover first of
all you need to find it and then you
update right
yeah so out there and look up at the
same it's open
remove
again you again if you want to remove it
you first need to find a way if it's in
a
table right
so it's still there right it's not to
mention that if you want to remove a
element from the list like maybe another
one to to shift all the elements right i
will talk about that so
we want to reduce the collision if if
everything is is you know if aaron is
still here ryan's done here mommy stop
here that is
great because they are only separate
places they have no
they have not collected each other so
this all hashing function helps us to
retrieve this r1 constant time because
the hashing function just points to the
location which doesn't doesn't have
other
values
stored right so i can just look it up to
whatever i want
and the third one is we call it
avalanche effect ever larger effect
what does it even mean what does this
mean it's in winter
so what can you explain to me what's an
avalanche event
so if
some people like to go skiing on my
panda i've left for and if they don't
escape they'll be buried
okay so yeah
[Music]
eric what
um so technically snowflake
and then it does a big collapsing it
looks like a big cloud yeah yeah yeah
so in this is what it means but in
computer enhancing effect is like this
one if i want to put this edge
and wait yeah all right
if this tells me is i i want to store
this location at 100 right and how about
h
if i have uppercase okay instead of
lowercase
this needs to be even the key change
slightly
what i mean i slide it could be you know
you know very slight variations from
lowercase to uppercase or vice versa
and then this value needs to be changed
as well it can be changed to maybe zero
or
two thousand yeah to understand
but if if if i change slightly it give
me 101 or 99 this is not good so all i
want this is evaluation which is good
it means that even a slight change in
the key you need to this hashing
function needs to give me something
totally different
do you understand like 2 000 yeah yeah
it's good in the hatching table these
are the these are the three
how do we measure if our hashing taper
high hygiene key is good
we want we want the hashing table to be
fast we want it to be
less
like connection we want it to be having
this evolution effect
right
so
[Music]
um okay so another thing i want to
mention here is that how do we yeah we
mentioned about the list here
how do we remove a list a element from
the list for example like
okay this is a list there one two
three
four
five
i want to remove the element three how
do we remove it
for example
these are the key all the hashing table
hash uh whatever right points to to a
link list to link list remember
remember here we talk about here this is
hyster table okay points to here
heisig table whatever they are pointed
to here this location and this is the
linked list right
so now i want to remove these three yeah
and i go through this list okay i found
the three here i want to remove it all
right yeah i want to remove this tree so
how do you do it
[Music]
yeah but how do we do it
how do we do it
just delete it
yeah
okay
skip it
escape it but we want to remove it yeah
one way of doing is this
okay so you make um
um you make one of these notes three the
same thing yeah yeah exactly so look i
can copy i can copy this value to the
last one i don't care about the order i
put it five and then we moved it
yeah yeah
why why is that because because look at
the list yeah remember the list a equals
this
right this list
what's that what's the time complexity
of this one what's the difference
between this one
what's the difference between these two
can somebody say they don't pull it from
the right and a
okay so like one two three four okay so
there you have it eight to four what
happened
we put the
which one the first one
last one the last one okay and eight
is
first one yeah the time complexity
between these two
removing the last one is
one yeah you just remove it because in
the last you just remove it but pop zero
what's the
why is that because computer needs to
shift it all the elements
yeah
all the elements
so take it out it needs to shift it look
two
five
four yeah whatever this is one way of
doing another way some computers the
computer aggregates sometimes they they
want to allocate another place and copy
over while this is oven as well
but generally speaking
a popping
we're talking about this yeah
we are not talking about the double
ended queue yes double ndq is totally
different it's all
the double ndq with the double nkq the
popping that element from the first and
last one is always a constant right but
for the normal lace if the popping if
we're removing the element from the last
it's a one
if we remove an element from the first
or any anyone in the middle is
right yeah
yeah in general speaking so when in the
middle we it's awareness right right
uh
any questions so far do you understand
what i'm saying
actually
if it's okay you don't understand fully
but
do you understand or which part you
don't quit quite understand
and maybe i can talk a little bit more
it's okay it's okay it's okay yeah okay
so tomorrow
basically is your hygiene table hygiene
table so tomorrow we're going to design
we will not design the hashing table
okay yeah okay do you understand the
haitian key the haitian key look
what did i say today with hashing key is
is to calculate a key
based on arbitrary large data it could
be zero zero it could be nothing or it
could be a one million characters or
maybe a thousand characters so this t
the length of these is arbitrary but the
output the output is always fixed yeah
it could be 32 bit
integer or it could be 122
a bit or 252 bit you know
some crypto currency could the
graphic hashing function and they
produce this 256
sha yes yeah
crypto function
so look because this is one way all
right it's one way right
you don't understand one way or two
do you understand one way or two way one
way
[Music]
do you understand look if i give you a
function h
h all right look can you tell me what
what is one way if hx equals x plus one
it's at least one way or two way
one minute
ah
well come on think about what's one way
one one way is one way is that from left
you can particular to the right and from
the right you can calculate the left
it's this one way or two very obvious
too well because if i give you x equals
two you know it's three if i give you
the right hand side is three you know x
is two right yeah this is two way but
question function you see one way or two
away
remember the left is arbitrary big a
minion characters and the left right is
my 32-bit integer
one one way obviously look a million
characters
it's a little bit but obviously i cannot
do this reverse right yeah there's no
way to reverse one to two from 30 to be
integrated
yeah
so h function is one way okay so this is
zero is one way one way one way function
okay one way function it has to be one
way function all right hashing table
testing
and we're going to
describe how to uh
we're going to implement this hygiene
table design the hashing table tomorrow
okay that's it for today good job bye
bye