hello and hello mr mr how are you today
today uh we uh yesterday we talked about
the hashing function the heisen function
allows to map absolutely large data x
yeah this could be any size into a fixed
size which could be started to be
integer yeah
so why we we use the hashing tag hashing
function because we need a hashing
function to compute the location of the
of the values to be stored so basically
the hash table is the fixed size right
it's a fixed size
and then we
calculate the data question function
hygiene function of the data and it
gives us a value so it tells us where to
put it
if they are conflicts if what is what it
means that if there are two different
kind of data if x e x is not equal to y
and if x h x equal to h y
that means a conflict because we have
different data different inputs but the
hash function give us the same
value and what it means that these two
values these two values x y will be
pointing both to the same location and
we have we can use the linked list or at
least
yeah and we
we generally don't want this to happen
as much as often because when this
happens
it means that it means that it's just it
will be slowed down right there'll be a
performance
degree
yeah because we we take on time linear
time to go through a linked list or list
to find out if the element is in this
right
yeah we want them the data to be
geographically currently distributed
along the
hash table okay
so that's the second part reduce
condition the first part is the the
hashing function needs to be very very
fast so we don't want it to be very
complex right
and i need one way why why do we need it
one way because if it's two-way what
does it mean if it's two-way look
let's say if
hydrogen function is two-way what could
happen
if a hyphen function is two-way
what possibly problems can you think of
right
if hx if you hx equals you'll get the
value v yeah
if if you can come up with some function
fv and that will come up
that will give you the x what does it
mean what what does it say
what what
that's two ways right
then what problem would that
give us so
no it means look if it's two way yeah if
it's one if it's two-way it means that
if if d somehow is leaked the data is
big here
like that the hashing location is late
then i can deduce
the original key will be deduced right
right and there will be a security
security problem right for example like
even the next one you're not sure but
you can try right if it's a you can
deduce it right you can deduce it it
means that it's not it's not safe at all
but because generally
in database yeah when we store the data
we
when we store the password right you
know password is very
secret secret a password
usually they don't store a password in
in a database in which database database
place to store the japanese
stuff yeah
look how do they usually do if you want
[Music]
so in database okay in database usually
you have uh user here user and then you
have a password right
right all right
password
so let's say look
eric
if your password is one two three four
okay this is the very simple password
your password is simple prospective one
okay
so if somehow this information is leaked
right and people can use your password
to do something
yeah
bad right we don't want that we want to
illegal we don't we want to prevent that
happening so
we don't solve the plan password in that
instead we store a hashing function
right we store a hashing from there
usually there's an md5 we usually we can
store md5 or another existing shard
two five six
so what it does this hashing function
with that is you md5 look it give you uh
any password right any password and then
give you
32 bit yeah it's a little bit
something like that here
so look if md5 i hatching i i give a
hashing yeah
hashing so eric you give something
hashing ax p t c
right or orion could be something
different p u
t t one okay something i just come up
so imagine
yeah yeah imagine this invention this
information is leaked
okay what i'm saying is that if this
information is legal
can people directly make use of that
right no right
because maybe
if this look if h actually this password
gives to this column right and they
put one yeah yeah okay i'm just saying
that if this data this encrypted is
hashed it's not included it has the
password it's leaked
then it's less
a big problem right because people
cannot this is not a real
uh original password and people cannot
make use of these these are the
encrypted one and then they know they
cannot be produced
to the original one right got it
yeah they understand yeah
yeah
okay so for example like look this
hashing function the creation what
happened look if based on this if
another way if mommy yeah
mommy
mommy but
mom is encrypted the hashing function
okay so suppose there's a hashing phone
it's also axptc
so what does it mean
so mommy can use the same password all
different but look your password is one
two three four maybe mommy's password is
abcd but but the h hashing function hash
function gives
a b c d
to this asptcf
h1234 he also gives the ax ptc
so what does it mean
there's a connection right because the
different input
the hash to the same output the keys
so in siri right in siri mommy could use
their username and password
you have to log in right but but she
might not right she might not know right
no
yeah
yeah you can do this differently yeah
okay so um today we talk about how to
design a hash table definitely hashtag
no no no it's
very fast
you need a better oh my
yes this is getting
bad
okay so let's say we have a
hash table of 10 10 yeah
let's say we have a test table so
at most ten elements
this is zero one two three four five six
seven
okay
a nine ten okay
yeah so let's make it simpler our keys
are the integers
okay
so we have we have let's say we have uh
we have uh
okay let's say the key this is the hash
table yeah heist table this hash table
so we have a key here we have a key the
value this is integer and let's say if
our values is range from 1 to 20 oh no
no let's say from 1 to yeah from 1 to 20
okay
1 to 20 inclusive yeah 1 to 20. so how
would you map this 1 to 20 to 1 to 10
right
how would you do it
which function we
let's come up with a simple
hash function okay we haven't
we haven't talked about a simple hash
function how do we have how do we map
something into a
into a fixed size table
and
how do we fix it
look at it define
hash hashtag
okay let's say key okay and key this is
key how do we
we know the size is 10 yeah we know this
table size size is 10.
size is 10 okay we know the size system
and how do we map this key the key this
is the integer right so this is the
integer key in
and now we want to return to it
right right yes
okay so i give you a
so we want to come up with a function to
map the integer to an integer but which
is the fixed size
yeah
so how can we do it this side type there
are ten elements in the table and then
our keys are twenty one to twenty so
like i i
i have a few examples you tell me what
what is this function okay it guess okay
look one if it's one i want to i only
store in one if it's two i only need to
store in two
if it's four i wanted to do so far no no
no yet because i if it's 11 i want to
throw in one
it's 15 i want you to store in five
because they only
from zero one two three four five six
seven
eight nine ten right uh okay they're
enough eleven okay let's say nine here's
the nine that's ten ten eleven okay
so it's one
if it's one i want to store in one oh i
know like when you did eleven
because it goes nine and then back to
the start
[Music]
yeah um instead of like 11 is like nine
and then you go back to the start ten
eleven it's one
[Music]
for about ten ten
ten
[Applause]
what key
what what
key
moderators what's this model
um
come on
that's the simplest function look we
have uh
we have a lot of keys to put in the
table right but we can usually these
modulus functions to to restrict it
inside the table right okay
and how about looking
what happened look look at this one goes
to one and ten eleven goes to one so
what happened yeah
all right what happened here
one goes to one so one here
yeah so one i i have one one the first
the two part i remember that yoga yeah
the key on the tuber is the key the
original key the value
is this value okay we can we can
worry about that later the key value
pair because in hash table you have a
key value pair yeah
and then look 11 1
close to 1 here so you put at the end
11 original list is in keys 11 and then
one okay
the value could be anything okay
it doesn't matter anything
anything
okay yes can you sit back please again
we're sitting yes okay
so now today we're going to
design this right so when we
uh we talked about a three operation
right to get a key to get a value right
get a get a value
get a value to update
and update
after a key value pair
and then to remove a key all right
remove a key
okay
these three operations
to get the key
first of all we compute this right
computer h key h function to tell us
where it's going to start and now we go
through this linkage to find out if
there's a key in there if it's their
skill would return the value and the
second value in the triple otherwise if
we can't find it we return to minus one
or whatever or determine okay
update the same thing to go through this
if we found it in a linkage we update
the value
and return otherwise
otherwise what do we do we append it to
the end the link is right
yes
remove
again we find out it's here and now we
find out okay 11 is what we're going to
do
we want to be more how do we remove a
link list from a list
how do we remove an item from this you
just copy it from uh
[Music]
that's a big number okay six okay
okay
zero one one
[Music]
zero one two three four five six okay i
want to remove that three how how do we
do
one two four five um you could be you
make it to six yeah
yeah and then i do more this yeah using
top remember yeah
yeah
if you're linked with what's the time
connection to remove a link
element from
linkedin linkage
and from the beginning no end
yeah yeah yeah but look if linked list
yeah it's an interest we want to remove
this yeah we want to remove this we go
through
we go through the element and until we
found it from this one we want to be
moving
and
when we go through the linked list we
know the previous one right so all we
can do is what
we want to take this out
and we want to re
really modify the previous link to point
it to the next one right yeah
all right instead of copying today to
the end because in a linked list there's
no way
there's no way to get the last value
without going one by one traversing to
the end right
the list provides us with random access
because we can just get it by index
calculating the index
do you understand what was that saying
yeah
what what what did i say you say i'm
like um rather than just copying it from
the other yeah
this is a list english is like look
you're traveling and then you travel by
language
yeah yeah so okay i say it again okay so
look this is the least note i want to
take it off
right i travelling i traveling i found
this link note
and obviously i know the previous one
here because i come from there
and what do i do i modify the previous
one
to point it to it pointed next to its
next one to the current notes next one
right so it's slightly different but a
constant term
when we multiply
when we know where where is the element
we want to remove it's always constant
right if you are given a number to
remove it's constant for example at
least you just copy the last one and you
remove the element for last one for the
link list you know this node is going to
take off right you modify the previous
link next thing to point to the next one
okay
okay then let's do it
yay let's do it
okay so let's write it in a class okay
obviously we have talked about this
before of ob class
class
what class what's this keyword class
a class is
where like here one year to year
it's object oriented thing like a person
right
yeah the object oriented yes like
like glass like class one is the best
okay
like in castle anything like that like
an object hash table so i can use this
the class is you can think of it as a
data container right a container
contains of these data and methods right
like a person class class person right
class person and person has the name age
right this attribute
and it has method like talk thing done
right got it
yeah and then you can use this obj class
to initiate to create different objects
like
i was eric equals
class
he was person name h right something
like that and ryan equals person
name age
so in this case we have created two
objects which is uh
all belongs to the class person right so
a person
the class is like object template okay
the hash table so we could we want to
create a hash table
so first of all we want to initialize
the defined constructor yeah to
understand
underscore in
in it
so let's say we let's say that we want
to install this hash table in a minion
right or maybe
let's say self
dot size
table size equal maybe
so in practically speaking this number
has to be
it's better to be a prime number so to
reduce the
collection so let's say can you give me
a prime number nine
no no no
okay 29 or seven bigger the better okay
i should i i the biggest
three the biggest point number i can
think of is 97 no no no 6 5 5
7.
how do you know that's the prime number
babe
did you okay that up
yeah
but this is
this is a prime number because i know
six five five
three six this is
this is 2 to the power of you know
16 maybe
2 to the power of 16
yeah
and plus 1
2 to the power of 16 plus 1 this is the
prime number
okay
okay we can look we can check later
even
what it's not even our odd number this
is the 2 to the power of 16
right this is obviously not a prime
number
i plus one what does it mean yeah it's a
prime number right
because you cannot find anything
that can be devised
by
any factors between one and itself right
okay so now we want to store this data
in the data save the data
remember how do we store this so each
one look
so look this table has 6 5 5
37 slots export spaces
yeah for each one
first one ryan alright for each one it's
a list there we're going to have a link
list yeah so you'll be at least a list
of elements a list of elements all
linked list it'll be something like that
yeah
and to make it simple we use a list so
here
here we do what
theta equals
at least look
empty this
for
underscore in
actually we end this and then
for
underscore in
range
when you are how many sides so this is
save the data so which is defined here
save the data
the data okay
so the instructor is now we want to come
up with a simple function remember
define get key okay this is get key
let's get key from here if you give a
key a key and then we need to return
we have a key
modulus right modulus
modulus save the size right
okay
pay attention here this hash function
this is the simple the simplest hash
function you don't have to you can put
you can write it
other ways or you can provide your
hash function but we usually want hash
function to be fast this is very fast
right
it reduce the collision yeah maybe or
maybe not right
yeah
and then the third one which is what
ever struck uh
avalanche effect right does it it's not
right because look a different key like
if i give you a value 10.
okay if i give my value 10 in here in
this case it's stored at location 10. if
i give you a
look
slight change is the key
and they they give the similar values of
the hash value right
yeah we don't want that right this is
okay but then for demonstration purpose
this this is okay
okay now let's let's try this okay
define
we want to get key get value
a key right
so this is the key we're going to get
the key so first of all we want to do it
do what key equals what
get key right because we want to find
out where it is
and the first step is find out where
this key a key
is
in the hash table so you'll be get here
right we're calling this function
save the key a key
okay actually look because these are
actually in python you have to put the
first parameter self okay
just remember there will be a first
parameter too because these functions
are defined as the class methods so the
first parameter has to be safe
self what's safe
self destruct
belongs to hash table so you need to put
a hash okay i don't
you just remember that okay
now like this key
now suppose this key is here now we want
to iterate over these yeah
we don't need to uh iterate over this to
see if it
uh if there's a key equals a key right
so what kind of search
are we performing on the link on the
phone here what kind of search are we
performing here
we locate this is a key
linear search yeah we just go through
one by one and there's no better way
right because we're not sure unless
unless what unless you
unless you know this this is sorted in
in that case we can use what
if it's at least something how can we
find anime in the saudis we can use what
kind of agreement are we using remember
the one we always split into tough
binary final research yeah and also
okay good job okay good job good job
both of you good job
come on sit there please
so here we can only use the linear
search so let's go to the
for
i
in
in what
range
maybe now we are we are known save data
dot key right
flying key say self
okay so we go through this element and
we want to find out if i
the first one is the key the second one
is
look at the two part the first one is
the
actual key so if i zero equal or equal a
key right
equals to the original key
then we return
we return the value which is i one is
this value
even after this or you haven't found the
value then we return nothing all written
minus one okay
okay
yeah
doesn't make sense key first of all we
we we want to check the key it's this
place and this here could be every line
or whatever right and i need to follow
you one by one to to find out
it's actually the first one the keyboard
is the the original key
and the value will be the value okay
okay so now we have to get and how about
with update i just change here to update
okay update
update update the key a key and a value
right we need a value yeah
so this is the same we get a key right
okay so what happened here
we go through the original list if laser
element or if this key is already in the
element we just update the value right
otherwise we append it right all right
do you get my point
so this update function
if the key is already existed in a hash
table we update the value yeah if it's
not existing what what do we do
we don't care no no no we put this new
thing at the end of this list right
correct yeah
so look for i insert the key
if i zero equals a key then we don't
return it instead what what do we do
i one
equal equal value we update it and we
return here
okay and if not if
look
if at least here it means that the key
is not in the table so we just put
append it so say
dot data
key
right
a pen a pen can you tell me what what do
i append what do i print
a panorama a tuber what's tuba
a tuber another bracket
what's the key of the tuber
a key right yeah what's the value
value here
yeah you see
if we find it
we change it to the value and we detect
if we don't find it we append one item
to the to the to the end of the list as
a key okay we move the last one remove
how do we remove it
how do we do move it we we don't
actually need to pass the variable here
value here we just remove a key
for i
how do we go for i if we found a key now
we found a key right
now
we we need to
we we need to do what if we found a key
what should we do
um
so i
so actually uh
so look i is actually we we actually
need to copy over right so if we we need
here we for i let's say range range
we're going through the index length
length okay
so now we here would be i
said the data
theta i
zero if i zero is the key
then
we copy over the last one right theta i
what data i
we copy over how do we copy over equals
theta
uh
okay theta k i okay so okay so theta key
i
first of all key i
key minus one yeah minus one is the last
element right
and we we have to use this you know the
the deep copy and shadow yeah see copy
you copy um something from widget
at least b equals a is this the deep
copy of shallow copy
a equals one to b equals a is it deep
copy of zero copy
share because this b is like areas so if
i say b 0 equals 10
so what's the value of a 0
look here
b 0 is 10 you say it's yellow copy and
what's uh what's the area of a0 come on
can you tell me
a quiz
a is one two and b equals a and i said b
0 is 10
so what's the value of a 0.
come on you say shadow what's the
10 yeah exactly it's a 10 because it's
what what it does is here look it's one
two right
a is here right x points to here look
alright
shallow copy what does it mean so b
also points to the same place right if
you change the first element to 10
and you also change the value of a to 10
right
how about shallow deep copy how do you
do this a
yeah deep copy you can you can do
deep copy tip copy is what copy there's
a copy package copy dot d copy yeah you
can do this d copy and then you can say
b equals b equals copy dot d copy a okay
that's the d copy or you can do this b
equals
so in this case if what
what if i said b0 to 10 and what's the
value of a0 come on b zero is to ten and
what's a a zero if it's a d copy b is a
deep copy of a
uh
well
right two
shallow copy is 10 what's the d copy
you're not copy because you're not
actually copying you change one thing
you change for o right
one two and i change the first element
to ten
so what's the b what's the a zero
what's the a zero here is it
is it change
yeah one two it's not changing a0 is one
it's not changed right because b is a
copy of totally a deep copy of a
changing everything to b doesn't affect
a right
yeah it's like you you
eric you are cr no no ryan you are clone
of eric right yeah i'm a small client
yeah smaller acronym so
so
does it make sense yeah if you're
anything i i i
anything you finish your homework does
not mean that everyone finishes some
more right you are too different
independent right okay
make sense
okay so oh we are a little bit far away
ah so look we give copy and now we copy
over the last one so what what's the
next one if i want to delete it
data i data
key
if the key
we go
and we find out
if there's a key and then we remove it
and then we return yeah we do we just
return because we just remove one
that's it i usually know uh key and then
we'll just ignore it and it will be here
and we can
possibly we can say okay raise exception
here yeah raise exception
anyway
key not found okay whatever
right
okay
what have you learned so far today
what what are we trying to do here
hashtag designer hash table right
so in the hash table what's the most
important thing you can think of deep
clean
no
what's the most important thing we
which what's the most important thing
it doesn't change what's this key
hash function structure hash function
allows us to because this is important
if you've given this input key you want
to find out where to put it right we
want it to be
as as far as possible right so they
don't
they don't collide each other yeah so
that will give us the
time complexity how how how cooking
oh what three operations
a one a one and a one all one right this
is the most of our
most big advantage of using hash table
right correct so just one last question
if a hash table is fixed size okay let's
say it's fixed and if there are too many
elements
coming so it's coming to the hash table
what could happen the performance of the
hash table will be
will be decrease or increase
you'll be degree if there are too many
elements in in the hash table can you
imagine that the performance to
to look up
to remove to update
will be slower or faster
come on be confident
the more elements in the hash table
there will be more chance of what faster
more chance of work come on
your fixed size come on
this is a hash table
only three people if another your friend
are coming what happened
too cloudy what happened in hash table
it'd be too cloudy as well slow you'll
be slow because the hashing functions
how do you get loads of traffic lots of
traffic because of the con
like collision yeah what do we talk
about collision because look if too many
elements and there will be all fear yeah
the table will be much much weird
and if any more comes comes in what will
happen
it has to be
put in the hash table right so it could
be somewhere in the link list right all
right
does doesn't make sense right look at me
so look
if this hash table is pretty much filled
then the operation to search
could be very slow because look this bit
could be very large at least yeah this
could be a very large list even you
separate using the h key
but you still have to do this in linear
time yeah to look for these elements
in the linked list so that will slow it
down we don't want to happen right
that's why we we can have a bigger hash
table
yeah bigger hex table a better hash key
to distributing the keys
evenly everywhere in the enhanced in the
table right
so that will give us the o1 constant
nearly impressively very fast one
constant time
okay
yeah you still with me
uh any questions so far
any questions so far any any question
no
any question okay
okay let's see a hash table a type of
class
yeah the vegetable look this is a stable
define a hash table remember hash table
is data structure the notebook thingy we
have talked about right remember
yesterday we talked about this
dictionary yeah
dictionary yeah default dictionary yeah
so i have a notebook i
said i said well key value pair given
the ryan k equals y and value equals
eight right
nine
no seven okay
and i put it over and then later i then
later people people ask how old is ryan
i look it up okay looking up a key very
fast oh one constant time okay retrieve
the value which is eight but you need to
flip on the right page
no no no that's the beauty of hashtag
a key a key a key key
it tells me okay it tells me which page
it is kaki let's let's that's why it's
so fast okay you can yeah good point you
can think of these thoughts as different
pages
yeah different pages got it
okay that's a good way of thinking very
well i haven't saw it that way but it's
a very excellent demonstration of how we
this is different page a book this is a
book
and page one page two page three page
four
right a key get key eric
okay it tells me okay it's in page three
right
so i turn to page three this is instant
time okay i see okay eric key every
value
nine
retrieve it very fast then if if ryan
the key is also on page three what
happened if there are too many items on
page three what happened you still have
to
look through this
yeah you get it you still have to
breathe through the page three right to
find out where it's airing right so that
would slow you down
okay right now slow you down am i right
doesn't make sense
you you now understand the concept of
this yeah hashtag
yeah so how do we make it fast
first of all there are a good a few
things to make it fast first of all you
buy a bigger book so lots of pages so
you don't have a
collection yeah
bigger page less collision right all
right
yeah
okay lots of pages
uh that's it for today good job
bye
[Music]