fine okay so today
we'll talk about the fibonacci number
okay fibonacci number
so the fibonacci number is a sequence
number sequence the first number is one
the second number is
the first number is zero second number
is one and the next numbers is always
equal to the previous two right yeah
so that's one two three five
eight thirteen and that's it okay got it
yeah so if we put it in a mathematic
equation we can say
f function let's say f n
equals f n
minus 1 plus f by n minus 2 i'm right
am right yeah because this f n
if n is here yeah then n minus 1 is here
and n minus 2 is here so f
n equals f of n minus 1
plus m of n minus 2 yeah but we need to
also define the first two cases f 0
is 0 f 1 is what
okay yeah yeah so how can we implement
it
using computer
def f means f means fibonacci numbers
yes yes or f we just use f for sure okay
for quicker
then and but you need brackets
okay yeah they need to work for
all of them okay so look look it's
actually very
very easy because look we have defined
those cases yeah
so we just have to do this if n equals
zero yeah then what should we determine
f equals zero if n equals zero what
should we determine
return one yeah
this return when when the computer
executes return you will return this
value immediately without going further
right
yeah then else will return what
f n minus one plus f
and minus two okay this is f is the
function we know okay because
okay we talked about recursion yesterday
yeah
okay
so it's pretty similar to what have we
we have defined in
math right yeah okay so
we let's let's let's do this
look that's only okay let's let's
for example f5 we want to calculate f5
so what values do we need to calculate
in order to get the value of
f5
so we will do zero one one
two three no no what i mean is here from
here f5
what do we need to calculate in order no
before we calculate the f5
what do we need to know before we
calculate f5
this is f4 right this is
f3 yeah yeah
so what do we need to know before we
calculate f4
f3 and f2 right
yeah what what do we need to know before
we calculate f3
can you tell me
what's the previous two items of f3
f2 and f1 right
yes okay so do you find the problem here
you find the problem here f3 we
calculate
twice all right f2
yeah twice now if you're going to this
way
there will be f2 and f1
okay so f2 is calculated multiple times
as well
yeah so so
is there a way to avoid calculating
again again
yeah so we use uh something called uh
we can save this value right we can save
save this value or put it down on a
notebook
yeah yeah so how can we do this
so we first first first if this key
this value is not calculated we
calculate it
and then we once we have the value we
put it in somewhere in the
notebook yeah so later when we find this
value
we order this value instead of
calculating it again
we get a value from the notebook yeah
okay yeah notebook look and stand for
notebook
no no n is the value we want to
calculate
so we let's modify a little bit f
f f n okay and let's
use it as m b stands for notebook okay
okay yeah okay so what do we do here
so let's first check up these okay so
the notebook okay the notebook notebook
is a dictionary object
in python you use this curly brace
dictionary
curly brace to store the key value pairs
key value pairs
curly brace okay we can work on that
later okay
so so you can initialize is a curly
brace object
so now we have a notebook yeah so let's
see
if this value if this value
n is already in the notebook
right so then now what do we do we
return
we immediately return look it up in the
notebook notebook
with the value end right okay
then we can ask yes this is the
the base case if n equals zero
return zero
if n equals one return
one okay now this is the interesting
part now we don't want to know the
answer yeah
answer equals fn
minus one notebook
plus fn minus two notebook okay
plus this notebook objects around and
then now we know this answer yeah
now we want to save it on the on in the
notebook yeah put it on a notebook
so let's say notebook and yeah
because we are calculating the n equals
answer now then let's return the answer
okay does it make sense
does it make sense look the difference
here this is the one difference look it
up
another difference here to save it to
put it down in the notebook yeah
and this is the notebook object so
you can say notebook notebook equals
these objects
and then you can say notebook like three
equals
one one one one two so that's three is
two
right so we can say three in
notebook these will return true right
like if four in notebook
now we don't know yet let me return
fourth do you get it
do you get it yeah so
after using this notebook each value of
the fibonacci number we only categorize
right
because the first time we don't see in
the notebook
we calculate it but after we get a value
we immediately put it down in the
notebook
and next time we look it up so you're
only in the notebook so we don't
calculate it okay we'll just look it up
right
okay got it yeah and
so we talked about two implementations
yes the first one without the notebook
the second one is the notebook
and we can also have
one method which is probably simpler to
implement it's called iterative
so look define f
and f ryan
four okay so first two items
a equals here let's define the current
two items in a
fibonacci number the first one is a the
second one is b
right right is zero one okay
then we can we want the an integration
for i
in range
and so what do we do
a b equals
b a plus b and then we can return
return a okay so when you know what
necron for that is 55
yeah yeah yeah do you know what happened
here look
zero one zero one okay this is a this is
b
okay let's listen in the table okay
okay zero one
so given an iteration the first one
a will become the value of b b will
become the value of
a plus b okay a becomes the value of b
is one right b
becomes the value of a plus one is one
right a becomes the value of b
is one b becomes the value of a plus b
is two a become the value of
b which is what 3
no no no a become the value of b which
is 2
b become the value of a plus b which is
3.
so you see this is the fibonacci number
here yeah
yeah and the next item is a become the
value of b
three b becomes a value of a plus b
five you see one one one two three five
so we'll return this a is the fibonacci
number b
b is the next item yeah
the next one this is five this is a okay
got it
okay so do you get it so which
all over those three methods which one
do you like best
which one do you like best what one this
is the one
implementation i remember the notebook
one
yeah remember the one without the
notebook because
which one you like the best network
notebook one
and how good how about you input that in
the computer with the notebook one
good