[Music]
hello mr ryan hello mr
erin okay let's see that that we talked
about
so today we're talking we are going to
talk uh
easy okay easy simple mathematics
uh problem which is called buying cars
if we have a
uh list of prices for each car and
and the budget let's let's calculate how
many
maximum number of cars we can get for
example like
10 pasta 5 20
40 35 and even our budget
is 35 so how many cars can we get
how many cars do we get for okay this is
the list of prices
why is this three because you look at
the smallest number then add it by the
next
more than another fifteen and next with
numbers
and what does that make 35. okay 35 okay
so how does it work i mean uh what's the
raise okay okay so you're right your
strategy is to
pick the smallest first and then the
next morning
and the next smallest and here the
amount of the
money we spend is bigger than a budget
right okay so let's let's define a
function
defined by
cost project uh budget yes
yes and prices
yeah so what do we do at the beginning
what would you do we need to
make the prices from the smallest so
to the piggies yeah so in order to know
what we can do
is to salt it yeah salt salt
and and then we salt it so these numbers
are increasing like
two three five seven yeah right this
kind of thing yeah yeah
okay that is 30 then we have a budget
budget then we need to do what we need
to have a
current amount of money right spend
let's call it spend
at the beginning we spend nothing yellow
right
yes now we need to go through the prices
so
for r in
prices yeah all right
so spend the money and then
we also have the number of the cars we
have purchased so far so we have a
number
we call it answer okay answer equals
zero and at the beginning we have
purchasing zero number of cards plus is
nothing
now if if
now we need to say if span if you can't
spend
is bigger
all right yeah maybe maybe not
bigger what why say you raise the please
[Music]
yes please just like this no
so for car each one
maybe we can put it this way look if if
current
uh if current budget yeah current budget
is bigger than the price bigger or equal
than the car
right yeah yeah then we need to
return no no yeah no yeah then we need
it means that we can purchase the car
right
we can purchase car so what do we do if
we want to purchase the car
we first of all we reduce the budget
yeah reduce the budget yeah by car
and then we increase the number we
already yeah
purchase one more car if it's smaller
than a budget it means that we can't
purchase any more car right
yeah now we just return break break you
know the break break the loop
so it exits the loop and we return
answer so we don't need this we don't
need this spent
okay so answer so this is the number of
cars
look look ryan what are you doing
ryan do you get it ryan you're on
youtube
can i have it please okay so look
let's let's say we have a hundred budget
budget equal hundred and then a cost
like uh
20 40 30
50 and 90. okay so can you tell me how
to do it price the salt then you
the price will become 20 30
40 50 and 90 yeah yeah yeah
look after this price to solve and the
price will become easier
okay this one is look and then
look and then we try for car in prices
so about 20
yeah it is budget 100 bigger than 20
yes yes and budget equipment by 20.
so budget is 280 and then answer is one
okay and then now 30 is faster than 80
then 30
yes yes that will become 50 and then
this will become one one more yeah
okay move next is 50 bigger than
40 yes yes plus one
and then this 50 minus 40 that will
become
10. okay is 10 bigger than 50
no no then i break so let's
break and break this loop this great
keyword
is to exit the for loop now
so without going any further so let's
break
yeah break so let's break and then we
return answer which is three
yes break is breaking and can you tell
me what's next continue
what continue mean this is a pen
continue means
okay keep on going to the next one
yeah we allow without if they loop
there's still something at the end but
we're keeping we skipping the
rest of the loop and continue to let
next loop okay
okay so can you tell me the complexity
n is the number of prices
okay number of cars so what's the what
what are we doing here uh
we're adding yeah all of them
not all right so we need to in the worst
case no in the worst case
so there are 10 cars if i have a million
dollars
then i i can have a million class right
yeah i know i can have all the cars
right
yeah so in the worst case that would be
if there is
a cheat like that yeah yeah in the worst
case
so it's this part is o-n right
this part is on because in the worst
case you need to go into
each of the car right but here remember
here is the salting
yeah when we talk about salting is o
and log n okay so look this is a
good example of the so okay so this
is a algorithm but first part we need to
sort it which is o and log n
and now the second part we need to go
through each class to check if it's o
so what's the complexity
why yes it's always look at why
why is not o n because
this part is more dominant yeah yeah
so look if there is if the complexity is
o n log n plus plus
n right yeah we only keep
look we only keep the most important
part this is dominant
because this is more complex than this
part yeah
yeah so we can skip this part yeah
because this is more important
more complex time consuming than n right
together how about if i write another
one o n squared plus
n log n so what what can this be
simplified
[Music]
so what's the answer of this what's the
complexity
o n squared which is bigger
one square is n times n and this n times
log
n n is bigger than log n right
yes so o n square is bigger than z
so we remove the long the trivial path
so like dominating
complexities of n squared do you get it
yes how about o n
cubic plus n square so what's this
what can this be what's the what's the
complexity of that
o and cubic plus n square cubic
yeah yeah because this is dominating so
this is trivial part
yeah so we don't consider this you know
when we talk about complexity we
talk about the most time consuming
component
of the aggregate this acronym contains
stock two parts
sorting the prices number of cars and
then going through each car
to check if they are still budget to buy
it right yeah
okay so there are two parts which which
part is most dominating is the sorting
part
so the complexity is this part which is
o and log n
got it okay the last part say goodbye
bye bye bye
oh yeah