okay so remember a few uh months or
maybe several months ago we talked about
a game jump game right
an array
so each number your position i didn't
remember anything about the jump game
look at this number means that the first
distance you can jump look two you can
jump two one two right
yeah one you can jump one a few months
ago we talked about non-similar problems
which you can jump backwards
right
but now today this problem is a bit
little bit simpler so yeah
at the beginning you are here yes that's
you
i'm naked no naked
with some dress okay
okay so two it means like the next one
the phone is distance you can jump is
here right yeah one hey guys i got some
mayfield
okay so now you're here
so now you can jump one to the
to the front so here
and then you can jump one to the front
so here so the question becomes whether
you can jump from the beginning to the
end okay
yeah does it make sense okay this is not
drawing lesson come on let's not join
the scene what you drawing
what's that a cat cat cat okay what's
this oh that's a nice cute cat
so okay i repeat my question okay so
you're at at the beginning yes and the
number becomes means that the maximum
distance you will jump forward only so
two means that you can jump forward to
here right
yeah yeah one means you can jump here
and one you will jump here so you can
jump from the philippines i can't reach
the end properly you turn me fast or if
you can jump you'll tell me true if you
come jump send me five got it i tell you
two
okay another question another here look
one one zero zero four can you jump from
the beginning to the end
uh two one
it means it stays still right you come
jump forward right okay so let's do
maximum here one here you can only jump
the fullest distance you can jump at at
this point and now you're stuck with
here because you can't jump forward
right
yes i need any idea we are solving this
problem i know quite a lot of
algorithm we can solve we can
you know what kind of algorithm do we
think because we look at this is kind of
like uh what kind of arguments the
search right so what kind of search we
can do
what kind of studies we can do
oh we can do previously we talked
yeah remember a few days a few months
ago the problem becomes that f3 you can
jump forward or backward right two
directions and then i learn time we use
the different search preferences right
this is the simple version of that so
obviously we cannot still use the def
research or we can still use the best
research right
right
yeah
yeah make sense
ryan you're busy are you finished here
what's this that's the electrode and
what's this snorlax what's this tatter
okay i have no idea why these drawers
okay so definitely
search yeah
in this
case how can we test research
how can we develop
and we can um yes
so we we just can move along
something look at here right
here too right
so the next one i can jump is three and
one right yeah so i can jump to the
three or i can jump to the one
right if i jump to the three i can jumps
to the one one four
one
one four
if i jump for one i can jump to one
right
right okay am i right do you get taken
do you get this we expand uh
we explain
three search trees we are different
search right we different search
look and the one next one one okay so do
you notice there's a diff there's a
problem here what what is that
there's some some places we have visited
you know many many times right okay
yeah i know we can do some one simple
solutions to
make sure we don't calculate it over and
over again what keyword is that
okay um
dynamic dynamic programming dynamic
programming and especially we use the
keyword add
cash we're down cash to cash with me
yeah yeah yeah about cash i need you
with cash it's cash okay cash okay okay
let's try this stuff for search okay if
we don't put a cache it becomes like a
backtracking right we jump backtracking
we go
but so we have this we have the kind of
position now which start to jump as
furthest as possible along this way and
then if we come jump we just start
checking to the one and if we put a
cache right look why do we need a cache
look three
three here the next one will be one one
right these two yeah look two
one
so this one look
this one
all right look this one this one here
all right it's the same as this one
right
so what does it mean
so this this substrate
is the same as this substrate
so that's a duplication right if we
don't put the cache the compressive will
be exponential because we're over
calculating repeating repeatedly
calculating the same thing over and over
again that's why we put a cache right
put a cache that means that it's also a
kind of top-down dynamic programming
right top-down
yeah top-down top-down
dynamic programming
it's also we can we can implement with
recursion
with cache which is called minimization
yeah
okay yeah okay
okay let's implement this first okay
preferences we skip it today but
it's quite simple yeah so i just
i just give this idea again okay two
i can go to three and one i travel over
three and one right
three
i can travel one one four right you see
i visited this level by level right yeah
level by level
okay so let's do it
okay i need i need it i need these two
ready
oh okay
i haven't just finished all right that's
you're true
oh my god i need i need a
i need a tissue because it's so
so dry okay excuse me a second okay
excuse me
too noisy come on guys too noisy okay so
daddy is going to draw
the uh
that's it
[Music]
oh sorry can you sit there please
super out can you not touch the camera
it's shaking people will feel dizzy okay
i didn't shake the camera
before i did
if i okay i need probably neither
defect
oh i lost i think i lost it
so define that first yeah you find that
research
so look uh
actually let's jump let's put in the
jump here jump break
jump
okay
what you doing here earthquake
okay jump jump let's say uh we have
numbers here
okay so now
first of all we we know that this uh
there's how many numbers in the lens in
the numbers right and then we do a d
therefore
dfs
now we are in current position current
right
so i will feel i will start feeding this
function look
and all i need to do is return
return d f s zero yeah because we start
at the as a zero right
right
yeah so now look
now look what
what should we do with the default
search so at the beginning what should
we do
so look if this current position is
bigger or equal the n right so it means
that we already we know it's already up
you know we can reach the end right
all right yeah we can reach to the end
so we do turn on
come on we can reach to the end
we return
come on the binary
yes or no
we can reach the end
yes yeah true right
now
we are current right so we can do this
for
i
in
range
range we we start from
we start from one
and to the current current
lam's current right none is current
plus one right because we can jump from
we can
from current position we can jump one
step forward two steps of our anterior
alarms current position right and then
now look what
uh but obviously if this is over the
boundary we need to restrict this and uh
to the to the boundary so we will
replace this with mean
mean n and this number right
and now we can just say if dfs
i right plus
nums
all right look this is a d of s
if we can from this current position
don't work here and there this
this is the current position and
dude
uh actually no actually it's current
because we are current right we are
current okay we are current and if we
can jump
this step and we can jump to the end and
we return one
come on
we can jump to the end by
two and then otherwise if i can't find
the return
this is the default search yeah
okay so what's the time complexity of
this implementation what's the time
constitute of this implementation
what's the time complexity
[Music]
yeah what's the terms and practices of
this implementation come on backtracking
actually this is the best working moment
come on remember
look i'm here
i'm here look
uh please position look
one one one look the worst case yeah the
worst case is all one right yeah so here
i can jump to this
and here i can jump to this right yeah
or two two or two maybe two is better
look one two two from here i can jump to
this point and this one right from here
i can jump here and then here
right from here i can jump here and here
right so every time i jump i look this
is jumping
look every time look here
i can jump here and here
and here i can jump here and here
remember
every time i can expand into two what's
your time convexity
no really
no no no
you need to think not not not i'm
thinking okay okay i'm saying that
at each position i can expand to two and
each partition i can explain it to so
how many of the ways of doing that
[Music]
how many ways until you make there and
there and here yeah so look
each one i can explain look each one i
can explain to two
yeah
so what's how many of these are there
how many of these are there it's
exponential what can you think of
exponential one
oh okay remember
oh that two to the power of one
to the power one come on
yeah
yeah understand so that's that's bad we
want to avoid why is that i i told you
before look because these sub trees we
kept calculating over and over again
look two to the two here
right
and then here from look
do i jump i can you look at me if you
don't look at me you don't understand
look two i can jump from here and here
and two i can jump here and here look at
these two
look at these two
it's
if i calculate from this point
i jump here
but again from this point
again jump here the second time i don't
need to calculate it again it's like
fibonacci number right it's like simple
natural number f5
equals f4
plus f3 right look
f4 equals f4 f3 plus f2
you see the problem f3 equals f2 plus f1
you see the problem
you see the problem f3
repeated calculating right f2
yeah so if we don't put a cash in
in in a fibonacci number the time
complexity is exponential it's the same
here backtracking so what we did how do
we fix it
how do we fix it
dynamic programming the easiest way to
learn the programming how do we fix it
remember the cut the the values top down
remember the value how do we remember
the values
[Music]
brian has said it before what's the
keyword cash cash cash yeah cash we
remember it so
every current every current if you
visited it
we saw it so it doesn't take anything
but
who who can use this value who wants to
use the value that could be
other there could be n values in front
of it needs to use this value so let's
let's overall these time complexes all n
square okay okay we said that when
square without the cash
we can we sketch it's owen square
without the cash is exponential okay
and i understand this is a bit too
difficult to you so now i'm not going to
ask you any complexity time to messy
yeah if you don't understand this right
this is definite search right
how about we we can solve it this is
top-down programming we can solve it we
spotted up dynamic programming right
yeah
but remember what's better
fibonacci number every time we said
about top down and butter out you can
always remind yourself with the
fibonacci number because that's the
easiest problem you can think of using
the top down and bottom of the number
formula right look f3 equals
look fn right equals fn minus 1 plus fm
minus 2 right this is the top down this
is a fibonacci number right yeah top
down you're calculating f of n and you
need to calculate that in
f and minus minus two and then we use
the catch this is expanding to the tree
right look three
two
one and then one zero right
so top down is this way you want to
calculate f3
you want to call it the left side you
need to calculate f2 and f1 if you go to
f2 you need to carry every one zero
right bottom up is this our way this way
around
we to f 0 f 1 f 2 f 3 so right we
calculate this this way so we start with
f 0
f 1 and f 2 this way so this is
top bottom right the same
so look
this dfs
current this is the function to tell if
we can visit it
if we can jump from the current to the
end right
so so
so we can create a
function uh an array and to do this
product feeling the values right
right next to this
probably need a better eraser
so let's say
this dp equals
at the beginning they can't be reached
from the end we set it to false right
and initial state is false right
force times
n
right
but we
and the last point
right and the last location it's true
right actually it's true because you are
already at the last location so you know
pp minus one is true
so what's tp mean dp is the dp vp zero
means that if we can jump
if we can jump from the position zero to
the n to the n right
that's what it means so and
the answer of this question becomes
return
d p zero right db 0 okay
okay so then we can start feeling the
value from the from the right hand side
to the left you know bottom right so we
can do this for
i
in
range start from the last value which is
n minus two because n minus one we know
we already know it's true right minus
two to
zero
every time i decrement one
look this is two zero yeah excuse
excluding the last value which is minor
one okay and then this is a step
and then now we want to just calculate
the reach what's the reach the first is
you can jump which is the minimum
of n
minus one
and then i
i i is the nums
nums i
plus
because you are at i position and then
you can jump from i to num uh to number
i right so we need to minus one here
actually i'm not quite sure let me check
i think uh
yeah you need to minus one because yeah
minus one is the last index i minus nums
i right okay
okay so now look this is the furthest
you can reach and then we can start from
what from
for j
in
range
we start from i plus one right to reach
to reach to reach plus one
and if
if dpj if db trace can reach then tpi
also can reach yeah this is
uh very important right
very important look all right
here
i'm here at this position if dpj
because i i know this dpj this is tpj
here dpi is here i know i can jump to j
so if dpj can reach to the end and dpi
also can reach it to the end am i right
does it make sense
is sure does it make sense
uh
i plus one reach plus one yes exactly
so i mean look dppj
means that if jt is j
if we are standing at j can we reach to
the end
because we know dpi can jump to tpj
right we know i can jump to j so if dbj
is true what does it mean dpi is what
it's true right
so that's what it means and then we'll
determine division what's the time
complexity for this one
then i'll go
just guess because there are two fours
bonus
two flaws
down easy
easy peasy what's the specs unrest
idp
dynamic programming okay because we have
we are bottling up bottom the photo is
on the dp n right pp and not db zero so
this is kind of like a tree uh you know
growing
reversely so tpj is
dpn minus one is the answer we want to
tp zero is the answer we want to know
and then we grow it
we calculating we are not taking them
from dbz and we taking them from the
universe dp
dpj
dbm minus 1 dp n minus 2 dpn minus 3
until we reach the db 0 okay that's the
bottom
top on top down right remember we top
down we return df as zero right pf is
zero so it's this way top down bottom is
this way right okay because we start
putting start feeding this tv minus so
what's tv minus one i mean
uh just very simple what's db minus one
db minus one means the fast
cash first or last come on
last tv zero is the first yeah i keep on
forgetting
0 means the first one computer the array
index star with the first one right
minus 1 the other side yeah minus 1
minus 2 the second to the last right
exactly
okay so now
can we do better because all the
previous two uh definite search safer
search uh backtracking top-down dynamic
programming yeah recursion is the
minimization and then i need spot
dynamic programming is all
n square right in the in the worst case
o n square and we use this minimum
notation to remember the values that we
so so that we don't calculate it over
and over again but if you look at this
problem it's actually we can go through
this greedy what does it mean look i i
look look
i have this max reach we can reach
okay max ratio variable at the beginning
we update the zero so now let's do this
problem three
one
zero two
four
one
five okay can we reach to the end
can we reach to the end yes enough one
two three
one two one yeah we can raise yeah yeah
yeah and how can we do that look
three
what how far we can reach after two one
two three here here right so next range
is here
we don't do
yeah okay that's right we update this
next week yeah
here next switch
we don't need to update matching because
it's look one
is less than next week yeah we ignore it
see hello
make switch updated because look you can
go through to the here right
yeah and then you could go and then go
for
mx switch
update the mac series right
yeah next week here i can go to here and
then one
we don't have data make sure and here
look
when we go to the end we just check if
next stretch can reach the end that's it
simple
let's see another example so the three
cl zero zero one a hundred
two can we reach it
okay three
max reach
to here right yeah
yellow we don't update it zero or maybe
we change it here to one as well you
know we don't have that here 0
we don't update it right
one we don't update it because because
next switch is smaller than the heat
than this point so we don't update it
right
100 we don't update it too
so the max is less than n so we don't
update it right
so there are two things we need to check
once is when we update it we need to
be sure that the current partition is
less or equal to message right if it's
bigger than the message they we don't
update it because
you know we can't jump to from the
beginning to this point so there's no
way to update the max switch right
yeah
so what we do is going through this one
time what's the time complexity
oh when we're done yeah you see just one
time or one right what's the space from
hd
do we use any
a one because we only use one variable
it is not linear to the program scale
max reach mean yeah max region yeah
we're using a variable but it's just one
variable it's not
linear it's not an array that's affected
by n right it's not linear right that's
the difference
one constant doesn't mean it doesn't
mean
it doesn't use any space it means that
you use constant number of space it
means that no matter how big is your
array how big is these
all i need all i use is constant time of
constant thing it doesn't grow
if i need to allocate another array
which is size of n now that's o l right
if you have a million
items in an array and i need to create
another array which is a minion and
that's one right
yeah you see the problem yeah okay now
let's try this this is called greedy
you know what's greedy because you want
to eat them you want to get the biggest
one and you want it
[Music]
length num right
reach
equals zero
i equals zero the current position i
yeah look
y
i smaller than n and also
i is smaller than rich right small equal
rich right
small or equal rich now what should we
do
what should we do
huh what should we do
we are at this position we want to
update the reach which equals max which
one
i plus nums i right this is the first
statement you can jump
i know what i plus equals
one one monster and return how can we
check if
that if we can jump from the beginning
to the end
bigger bigger equal
and
minus one the last incident is mine
make sense what's the time conversion i
just asked you yeah can you answer it
again
[Music]
okay let me let me check if there's
anything i missed
out okay we saw today i think that's it
so
to sum up we have talked about this
problem how many solutions we have
talked about
first one is a tefl search without
minimization which is called
backtracking yeah backtracking
so this complexity is a bit complex
because it's o to n right exponential
just remember the fibonacci number is
quite similar yeah okay and if you put a
cash
that's research with the cash what do
you call it
top
top down dynamic programming yeah
top down dynamic programming recursion
with the minimization
the time connection is all
n square right
and then things we can do top down
sometimes most of case we can do butter
out very easy
up
bottom bottom up
dynamic programming yeah dynamic
programming we use that we fill this
array from the right hand side to the
left hand side right so let's top down
button out is also o n
square
yeah the time the space complexity for
these two is also o n squared okay
and then now we talk about the square
really yeah because we can always update
the furthest distance yeah yeah one
when we
when we current partition is smaller
than rich then we can update it until we
check if the series distance is bigger
or equal than the last last index this
is the comparison oh and the space
complexity is one right we also
mentioned the breakfast search
preference search yeah first of all
search is since it's like this because
we
it's like that yeah
if we put a catch can we focus on
preferences maybe if it's too hard we
can use the we can use the
minimalization table minimum oh yeah
yeah if we use the minimum then the time
conducts t will be reduced to o n square
because each each
each uh
so we will have a a flag like d p i
means that if we can jump from i to the
n so we only take it at least once right
but
it may take other how many times can the
mo in the world can
do do we need to access this dpi is our
end time so all n times n so it's one
square so this breakfast actually test
assertion perfect search is quite
similar it's just different ways of
traversing the tree right trevor
singletary remember
okay
one two three
four
five
six what's the death research in this
case uh
this is four
what's the difference search of these
three if we search these one
two
six three four five what's a boyfriend
search one two three six four five you
see just different ways of traversing
the search the domain the search space
is not it's the same right you still
need to search
you still need to search the entire tree
so it doesn't make a difference it's
just different order of troubles in the
tree the most important thing is cash
because we don't want to tackle anything
again and again and the most
optimal solution for this problem is
greedy because we update we use we just
go through it away once and that's it
okay and that's it we don't go to
another time so it's linear oh and so
which one is the best come on i haven't
asked you which one is the best
well greedy
obviously okay because it's less
complexity well done today okay good job
any questions so far
or you want to show people your drawing
hmm
that's it
right
ryan
okay so i wait for you to finish
you want to say hello thank you bye bye
to people what are you drawing a kitty
or a
pokemon
pikachu okay
show us your drawing skills
come on that's it
you're taking so much time hurry up
this way
bye bye
[Music]