hello hello mr ryan how are you today
okay so today it's a simple mess program
okay so we have at least
numbers like 2 20
70. this is a list of numbers right list
of numbers
y
list of numbers let's say this array
okay
and let's say we want to find out the
first
the first number that is bigger
or equals to
[Music]
let's say 50 yeah
i can equal 50 y
so which one is bigger than or this one
yeah maybe let's try a smaller number
maybe this is 300
okay
okay yeah what did you put in zero yeah
200 310 157 so which number if you go
from left to right
it's bigger or equal than 50
oh yeah okay so okay okay and how about
this
300.
how about this 100
yeah nothing that i need to return minus
one okay
okay
so we need to go through this we need to
find out the first number from left to
right which is bigger or
equal than the target
but 500 figures
oh yeah yeah yeah you were right okay
okay okay okay you're all right okay so
how about this is
five
you know right 70 okay we didn't mean no
yeah okay and then seven
nine
okay okay okay so how can we write this
remember this is quite similar and
looking for a number in uh
array what's the time term next day if
you're wrong to look in a number in that
way
what's the time complexity how how you
how important we've got a weird solution
so
so every
number on the right thing we subtract
with target and then if it's over if
it's a
well that's a very excellent idea so we
subtract so we subtract
we substitute these numbers
and the target we substitute the target
from the least number right and then if
it's negative what does it mean so this
is the number
a minus target is smaller than zero
smaller than zero right
so that means one a smaller or equal
than t right
right yeah
so we want to find out the first number
which is bigger so we need to be bigger
positive than it would be positive if
it's positive then you'll be positive
right yeah it'll be bigger or equal
right all right
yeah positive equal right correct
so it's the same thing okay so i'm going
to write this
define
find
first
bigger or larger bigger large
than topic
let's say this is array and then let's
have it okay so we want to okay let's
repeat this we want to find the numbers
the first number from left to right in
the array which is bigger or equal than
the target right correct if we can't
find it we'll determine
so can you tell me how to draw
if we want to go through from left to
right
what's the thing we want to write we
want to use the ring
red or we can just directly loop into
the
uh loop yeah for
for the number yeah
i
in
a r
if
i is bigger or equal than the target
right then we retire
we are not writing the index we are
retaining the number yeah
we return what
yeah come on give me the answer for i
num array if i bigger than the target
with here
in the worst case we can't find anything
right
yeah then that's minus one that's that's
pretty easy what's the space conversely
one oh
n
are we using any space not just guess
no no one yes i said i won okay i heard
that it's holland okay i said i was okay
i said that one
okay maybe maybe writing confused me
okay yeah
no
i said i one okay look at the video
later
ryan said oh
oh dead oh n dance okay
okay and you said it was 0-1 and we
already said i won in the first place i
see
[Music]
if i'm bigger than t you can just move
the t to the left side then it will be i
minus t bigger than equal to zero right
it's the same yeah yeah yeah
okay
okay so now
not yet today we're going to talk about
a scene of a fancy syntax called next
next what's next name what's next me
next too
next yeah next one is okay daddy
okay next
i need to focus okay what's next okay so
what does it mean next remember you
still remember the iterator yeah yeah
remember the key one yeah
what's what's this q i mean yeah
what's the key word i mean yeah
it means that like you know promise of
something promise yes so so if look
for example like money won't give you
some pokemon right so maybe
the next month is five pounds the the
months of the next ten pounds and the
months after the next fifteen used to be
every week yeah yeah i know five ten
fifteen right
right okay but but mommy doesn't want to
give all the money to all once right so
instead
she was just
yeah
every time you asked for money
she was just year like you know yeah
okay so look that's the money plan okay
15 20 let's say okay and now we want to
put it in the
iterator right iterator alliteration
iterator so this is the list let's say
this is the list
this is the list m equals that i'll
iterate how do we get the iterator for
this
it's a rate so basically iterator what's
the iterator iterator has the next
method so if you ask you for next
element you will tell you what to to to
get it could be 5 10 15 20. so let's say
look the iterator will be i put the
eater
i put the eta i t e r and then i will
have m here that will be iterated right
so this is iterator let's say let's put
it as a
and then now look if i do this next
a
so
can you guess what next a gives us
next day he gave us five right yeah
and then look just imagine next a and
then if i do another next a w
what would you get
huh
next way you you have a
10 and a next day next year look that's
the next a means that look i get the
value from the iterator and internally
internally the iterator will move
there's a pointer inside yeah there was
a move you move to the next one okay so
look how about i have another eat next
so what what could we get
we could get um kai this is five this is
10 this is 15 and okay so what's next
next
next a
20 20 okay
good job you don't know because we're
running out of elements right so minus
one
the the next function the second the
first parameter is the iterator and the
second parameter is the default means
that if you can't get anything if you're
running out of the elements in the
iterator then returns minus one right so
look if i put another x here
next a let's say a hundred what could
you get
i just said what did i just say let's
take the first parameter as a iterator
and the second one is default value if
you are running out of the elements in
the iterator you give you this default
so next i run for aaa let's next next
next and then i have a
i have another next a 100 so what can we
get here
uh we can get the
100 yeah 100 that's 24 value okay so
now so look now we just need to
return okay you should i i'll write this
first okay all right one line
return
next
because i want to find the first next
which is also next first element is
bigger than the target right
yeah
look
look at me look at me
i have this this yeah
x for
x x i want to use x this is x for x in
enough array right
is x bigger or equal than the target
right okay look look
instead of using the
square bracket which is a list
right yeah
look all right
this is this yeah we talked about this
it's a tuple yeah but here here
here it also means the iterator okay
okay
so this you want to convert this list to
the
alright
yeah
what do you guys say ryan if i want to
convert a list to the iterator i need to
use the e-i-t-e-r function
it then you give me the iterator the
iterator will
with the iterator you can ask for the
next element right you could you could
ask the
next element okay
so look if if this one this is the
iterator i can just do this x for x in
array right if x this is the core logic
right because we're looking for the
first element which is bigger than the
target in the array and this is the
iterator and then by d4 you return -1
look simple as that 1
9. make sense
okay what have we learned about today
come on about the room
building
sorry yeah yeah yeah so we what we have
a few numbers and we are trying to find
the first number which is what what
channels which is um bigger than with
big or equal to that
to the target okay what's the time
complexity
that's the linear search yeah
[Music]
and then we're talking about the next
what's the next function can you tell me
what's the first first parameter of the
next function what's it what's the
second parameter of the next term
parameter is the next one what's this
first parameter what's what's a type of
it's kind of what
what type of it
next remember what's the next function
it is
[Music]
a
what's a come on
it's an iterator what did i talk about
what's the iterator
iterator iterator means that there's
something you can ask for the next right
for the next and every time you not ask
for the next one
you'll come
your
the the iterator will move to the next
element right yeah
it's like uh
it's like it's like what
it's like mommy has money i remember i
give you this days of my money mommy has
the money five pound ten pound fifteen
pounds and if you come to mommy for the
money
the first time she will give you five
pounds and the second hand will be 10
pounds the third time with 15 right so
every time mommy now is the iterator
and
if you go to the mommy next next right
yep then mom will give you the
corresponding money and then she will
move the money so she would she will
have a you know pointer to points to the
next one if it right now if she runs out
of money what happened that's the second
parent that means the default yeah
default default
default so the first one is iterator the
second one is the
default parameter if it goes runs out
right so look if we want to another
thing we want to convert the list to the
list look
so listed to the
list we want to convert this to the
iterator we use the i i t r function
right i t e r
i t i
one two three four and then this will
give a it's basically one two three four
yeah it's the iterator okay with the
internet okay
yeah
for
x for x in r a r is x bigger than or
equal t we use this parenthesis instead
of this okay if we use the list
if we use the list we need to turn it
into the iterator okay wow okay that's
it for today
yes maybe
bye