uh
hello mr harry are you ready
yes okay so remember
we talked about how to calculate the sum
between one to n right right
one plus two plus three plus four plus
q10 what's the
answer so n this time 55
sum okay so it's equals to
i equals 1 to n yes this is the sum yeah
and then what
i okay so this is a mathematics symbol
how do you calculate why is it 55
is it 51 yeah
how do it calculate it's 55 1 and 10 and
yeah
okay
so in general if it's it's one plus two
plus three plus here
n what's the answer what's the equation
for that do you still remember it's okay
you don't remember
what's this what's the if f n is the sum
of these so what's happening
what's it do you still remember
how do you generalize this you know this
is one plus ten
times five pairs how how do you get a
five
okay so i think it's n plus the first
one divided by two
times n divided by two okay
yeah
first first item and last item
how many items are then divided by two
okay so we don't have to start with one
right so look if we start with
we if five plus six plus seven plus here
and what's the answer
this one this one yeah
you wanna come in okay okay
okay
so look it's first item plus last item
times how many items are there right so
n plus y and times how many items are
they
yeah divided by two yeah yes yeah okay
so what what's this m plus y
times how many uh items n minus y plus
one
divided by two okay
so in general this is uh
like any integers sum right i was
talking 1 plus 2 plus 3 any numbers yeah
1 plus 2 plus 3 plus 2
plus n is the answer is
the first item plus the last item
comes how many items are left divided by
two okay
another easy way another easy way
another easy way look look
yes 1
plus 2
plus 3
plus 4
okay so
1 plus 2 plus 3 plus 4
equals how many i can do this look how
about if i feel this look
i feel this with the cross all right
look this is the magic
i feel it
and i feel one more
okay so so what do you notice
so these these
circles are equal to the how many
circles are equal how many colors like
and how many of them are together
this is n
this is n this is n plus one right
because we feel like one right so it's n
times n plus one
divided by two got it
yeah
ryan do you understand this yes i need
to understand it
this is how we prove we prove that
we prove what one plus two plus three
plus tier and
uh the sum is is this
okay so now today's question okay let's
coming up today's question
all right
so let's feel the
stairs let's build this if we have uh
n circus okay maybe coins okay we have n
coins yeah these are coins right all
right
these are coins we have n coins
and we want to put the n coins near the
stairs of points like the first one
first of one coin
second two coins third three coins and
so on
so if they are ten coins this is ten
points you need to tell me we can build
four
okay first four stairs
but if i i'm i only have nine right all
right look i only have nine
so you need to tell me i can only be a
three four
first stairs okay
make sense
how about 15
how many how many stairs can we get
fifteen
five five five and how about fourteen
four four yeah
yeah good job good job okay so what's
your song
this is basically the other way yeah you
just go down and just find the
idea you understand the problem we're
talking about
so previously we we
know the end we can calculate this sound
that's easy right but now we know this
um we want to get go back
and then you want to get and then you
want to
accumulate until you reach
that right yeah that's one solution yeah
look let's
translate
that's one solution yeah we're done
let's let's call it simulation and we
we simulate the process how we build it
yeah so look i'm just writing the
pseudocode yeah okay look
uh let's say the answer at the beginning
we have a zero right and we have n right
we haven't so let's say we have uh
okay maybe
this this is the row rows equals zero
okay
right
yeah
and then i let's say i equals the first
one
so wire
i
this this this is the coins we are uh
maybe we name it as current okay current
row current low equals one okay
one is here
so look
why uh why we have coins why we have
coins
covering row okay camera why we have
coins why n is bigger than the
bigger or equal than one then the
current row
right now we need to do what rows we can
fill this row plus equals one right and
then we need to subtract n equals
current right now the current equals the
next row is what plus equals
one right
look
is it another turn rows like this is the
unknown one
yeah okay let's see this is simulation
can we we want to determine the number
of rows we can feel right
and this is the current number of
current of current coins we have to put
in the current node
the first one is first uh first row is
first coin one coin
one
and
when we have coins
and when we
have enough coins for carbon row ro
yeah then we can complete one more row
right and then we
subtract
the coins from the row so from the total
coins
right i know it's
what's the next
how many coins for the next row is
current plus equal one and with the
generals so this is the simulation okay
so if n is very big yeah this is getting
the time complexity uh is getting rough
how how do you calculate bigger
yeah it's getting bigger
no no not really look how many times how
uh how many iterations do you think you
would you will become anywhere become
less than
learn the current
how many iterations actually we can
prove it right look we can prove it we
can prove it look
look
we we know right we know n times n plus
one right divided by two right it needs
to be
it needs to be smaller or equals than uh
actually let's not call it n let's call
it the row okay let's call it
ah okay and resort reserve
ah are rows
this is the number of coins if we can
build our stairs that should be less
than or equal than n right
right
so what's this okay let's write it
what's this what's this
evil times multiply two by two sides so
r times r plus one
small or equal to one right correct
yeah from here i multiply two both sides
and the equation still stands okay
what's this remember remember
what we talked about is a plus b squared
can you tell me what it is
a squared
plus
b squared plus
c
nice new c come on
how many look hey yes two times a b okay
yeah
at least
remember this is very important
yeah okay so now look
r times
this is this is what
r square plus r right plus one
plus one
if i plus two
uh if i trust for
if i add a quarter here right
and i need to subtract a quarter on the
right hand side right
i need to press
the other side right
yes
okay so let's see
r plus two a quarter and a half square
look r square plus a quarter
plus two times this right is smaller or
equal to n plus four a quarter one over
four
okay so if we get a square root of both
sides
if we get the square root of both sides
look okay can you yeah this is the this
is how we deduce it
so look r plus equal uh half
smaller or equal you know because r is
positive right if i is positive so
that's why we can square root on both
sides right so that's 2n plus
a quarter
and then i you know i move this to the
right hand side subtract half
okay so r is smaller or equal than this
and we want the integer part we wanted
the floor look this this symbol look
what's this
what's this no
flaw you know the floor fancy
yes like if it's you just round it
four thirty point five is one four three
[Music]
yes the ceiling is this
this is ceiling look it's quite
quite visually
yeah this is from this ceiling
yeah floor is the largest integer less
less than current number
we see ceiling is the smallest number
which is bigger than 3.5 yeah
yeah okay so we want the list so ah is
this so the current complexity of that
simulation
is this o
right okay
so nothing no no
if you do the simulation right like like
remember the previous one why
why the
we have enough points for the current
role yeah we subtract the coins from the
current uh from the total coins we
increment the coins for the next row
and we we increment the number of rows
we need we can build right let something
like this easy but if i
look if i implement this function i can
just return
you know return two times n plus a
quarter
square root
minus
half what's the time the mass if i just
take a little speed
if i take your list what's the time
conversity
[Music]
expression it's all it's usually i would
say it's usually oh i don't know
if we
don't consider if you if you don't
consider the term complexity calculus
square root so it's one okay
so yes this is the most perfect but we
can also finally search it yeah yeah you
see the final research
okay i'm going to write the binary
search and you'll tell me
you're not a financial white spanish
[Music]
look this is a one to n and i want to
find the number between it and if if i
can have a function to tell me like if
it's bigger or smaller so every time i
can
i can narrow down the search search
space by half right
it's it's like okay so how do you
explain the minor research eric right
any of you can tell that it was final
research
[Music]
yeah so look
one to a hundred i have a number between
one two hundred you guess
yeah
yeah can you guess 50 25 no no no no
okay you guess
i tell you if it's bigger
so i have a number in mind can you guess
it's uh
it's bigger than i the number i thought
75 it's bigger than the number i thought
okay
look you say you asked you said 50. i
said
i said 50 is more than the number i saw
the one
okay it's smaller than another
then i'll go for
yeah okay you know the game yeah so
every time you cut in half right so your
search space is nine without every time
you cut in half cut in half cutting
popcorn so that the time connection of
minor issues is usually usually locked
logan right we'll talk about this in the
very first video
okay so now
let's let's say
let's say look we want to feel
that coin yeah look yeah look at this
let's say the first one and the end roll
right but we are not sure how many rows
we can build right
the
arrow okay
they are totally end coin right
but
look if i i'm guessing if i'm guessing i
can feel
uh three rows so i know how many coins i
like i need to build a three row right
yeah because we just know right n times
n plus one divided by two this is the
number of coins we need to build the n
rows right yeah so depending on this we
can half in the the
search uh search space okay
yeah
[Music]
define okay
beard stairs
of coins
i know we have end coins right
so the beginning left let's say left
equal left
left right left
the minimum we can build is one row
right
yeah
if n is positive then one yeah if n
n is bigger or bigger than zero okay if
it's zero like obviously we compare
anything right if n is bigger than one
bigger or equal than one
the minimum we can build is one row
right the maximum is one
r rows we can put it i n row right yeah
okay so wire
left is smaller than equal than r right
okay
what's the meter meter what's how do we
cut the middle if left is
look
what's the middle
left
right and anybody
left the right what's the middle
um
right divided
okay divided by two you can do this all
you can shift it by one yeah look at 50
50 by one this is also okay right look
50 you don't need to put a bracket
because the plus takes priority over the
15 so it's the same as this okay so 60
and then now how many coins we need
how many coins we need to build the n
rows how many coins we need to build
them
how many coins we need to build and
wrong huh
how many coins we need to build
[Music]
n times
m plus 1
divided by 2 2. this is the formula yeah
we just talked about right
okay
if k equal equals n
so what does this mean we can bear the n
rows right
this is the coins we need and this is
the coins we have
yeah then return return one
reason why
[Music]
what's the what's the law
mid m okay if k is smaller than n
we don't have another coin so we look we
don't have enough coins so we need to
increment the row or we need to
decrement a row come on
if we don't have enough coins
plus
we need to increment so not plus so we
need to do what mid
left
equals one
mid
last one right
yes we have enough coins we need to
reduce them right right equals one
minus one we are done and then we need
to return
return this is a big chicken little
return air minus one right because it's
already power minus one or return ah
yeah return r all return
left to minus one all right yeah left
minus one look because the l eventually
you'll be unplugged when we need to
subtract one ah it's okay right
okay yes nice and what's the time
compression of this one come on
[Music]
so we talk about three solutions okay
let's review a little bit the first one
is simulation yeah
we we start to
to simulate by putting the first coin
from the first row second row third row
and so on that time connecting we
is
that formula right because
the formula
o 1
square root
2 n plus
x comes from a quarter n minus
half right something like that yeah
this is the time the second solution is
mathematic yeah we just if we just
evaluate calculate this formula which is
one right
yeah
the third solution binary search which
is o all logan right
makes sense
okay makes sense
what okay what's the formula of
calculating the first and integer i
equals 1 to n
sum of i what's this what's this what's
the sum of these
what's the sum of these an integer
ryan area
and
n times
n times y and what's
one plus two plus three plus four plus
tier n what's the sum ryan every come on
you know this before
what's the sum
what's the sum come on what's the sum
plus m
plus one divided by two come on it's
here that's the way we know that n rows
and we how many coins
it's the same i'm just using difference
okay
got it
[Music]
divided by two okay
okay good job okay good job today good
job today
bye