hello hello
hello mr alright yes okay so today we
talk about k and n
k and n
okay k a number and nearest neighbors
can you put that down it's quite
dangerous nearest name neighbors
mirrors
neighbors
[Music]
so what does it mean what does it mean
10 so it's like it's a machine learning
you know have you heard the word machine
learning
computer can land right
yeah predict make a prediction
we ask computer to
make predictions to learn from data
learn
from data yeah data
okay or sometimes we call it data
training set yeah so what does this mean
so i'll give you an example so we have
we have a few
uh
you know we know already uh existing
data and then if
you're given a new input what would be
the output
if this data if this fx
this look
okay
the function that takes the input x can
you put it down please question yeah
and then it generates the output yeah
output right output
but we don't know what's fx it's a very
complex model for example right
yeah yeah
for example like uh
it's very very complex for example the
computer predict the weather what's the
weather going to be like tomorrow
right it depends on lots of factors
right the temperature
the the
seasons
right
the the locations right
yeah
and the humidity yeah immediately yeah
and what's the going to what's the
weather going to be like
so
we don't know that the model or we can't
express this model in mathematics like
simple mathematic equation right but
so but we know already from his uh
history data yeah we know already it
happens before right
all right so so for example we have at
least input right
so maybe like like input
uh
temperature
temperature yeah
and what else
what that temperature like humidity
humidity yeah is it how do you spell
this one yeah i don't know what do you
mean
you know
the how wet really the
air right
something like that
and what location
yeah
location
so you we we have uh we have observed
this kind of data in the past right so
something like 25 degree
you know
you know maybe 30 percent yeah and the
weather will be sunny for example sunny
and then something like
something like it will be raining right
raining
okay
so these datas are we collected
we already have this data
right and we want to build a very
complex model yeah to given
uh tomorrow so x could be the
yeah x could be the
input right so we can
we know the location temperature
humidity for now and we want to predict
the weather tomorrow
right
and you'll be very complex and then we
ask computer to predict let's make a
prediction
based on what we know so far let's call
machine learning right so the data the
pc the
computer will work out right work out
the
[Music]
likelihood of the different kind of
weather based on this data
okay basic kind of machine learning
make sense
yeah okay so another example
another example could be it could be
simpler
okay so i have a
i have two two shapes on the only one
space
triangle
square
triangle triangles square
triangles and squares yeah that's true
triangles square
this yes okay
so
can you tell me
so i have a point here
so is it triangle is it
squared
[Music]
no no no i mean if i want to draw a
shape here
right this is the known input for the
computer
right like the weather thingy right we
have known
that at these points it would
a square and now there's a new input the
computer you ask computer to predict
what's the shape here
more likely you know
what's more what's likely to be a shape
here triangular square
um square
square where down why is this square
why is it square yeah it's square why
likely yeah it's likelihood more likely
likelihood okay so machine learning is
it won't solve a prediction problem it
could have at least there
um
you know it's not like 100 accurate it's
it's more like uh
optimum um like heuristic heuristic
heuristic yeah
uh so we also predict here and then the
computer will say it's a square so why
you say it's a square
come on
yeah
the arrow is square why
unless you can say it's a triangle and
you can base another story just explain
your thoughts why is this square here
[Music]
in what you do your instinct why is a
square here
i just guessed
and what based on what why is this
square square
a good guess yeah y is a square guess
how do you guess is the square oh it's
just learning this
it could be look
i'm at this point yeah i'm response
so if i k equals three i want to pick
the three nearest neighbors so at this
point
distance what are the three shortest
distance
to this point
if i put a triangle
what's the three circles distance
[Music]
yeah so these are three shot is decent k
equals here normally can you see
it could be
if there are only two possibilities
triangle and square
and we want to pick a k which is odd
so there is no even vote
yeah because there are two possibilities
and if i have three votes what does it
mean always one wins right yeah
two triangles
one two x square all two squares one
triangle right
yeah it it we don't have this even
though right if you put a k equals four
what could be the even both two square
two triangle you can't pick right so k
equals three so we pick the three nearly
one triangle
two squared
so we will vote for what
square square easy yeah that's how you
get guess let's yeah we will make a
guess based on this case okay easy yeah
this is machine learning let's simplify
this machine learning algorithm right
you ask computer to make a guess
based on what based on the existing data
we know this existing data existing data
existing data and we also call it data
set
training set data set training training
set training data set
yeah because these data are used to
train the computer
right what if you
did
sorry
will it be on the grid or something oh
my goodness
um because what if you don't know um
which one is close uh
okay how do you catch a circus display
right yeah only green yeah the distance
shut it distance you know that distance
you could be there that could be two
times the distance
the
[Music]
the distance yeah look
what kind of distance can you get
well if you have like one square and one
triangle close yeah and x y
what if um you had this um
point and a
is
one square one triangle and and and
there is another one um
called one circle
and then
another one that
also
um triangle and
square but
they're the same
from that point
where they're okay so if okay so that's
a very good choice yeah you have three
things three votes but one of them is
triangle one on one square and
one on and there are two right
in this case you just pick one on it's
it's just fifty fifty
or you could increase the k right to
five
yeah instead of picking three you're
picking five to see more yeah to get
more right got it
they understand what i'm saying yeah
yeah okay very clever very good yeah i
just thought i didn't think of that
before yeah but yeah you make a joke
that's a very special corner case okay
so we talk about distance there are two
kinds of distance you can
maybe you know look this is a point
right
x1
y1 right
x1 y1 okay yeah
so this is x1
this bit yeah
here is y1 okay
and another point here
okay so here
x2
here
y2 okay
what
got it
yeah what's the distance distance look
this sides could be
x1 minus x2 squared
plus y1 minus y2 square and then
square root that's one distance
right because we're only interested this
distance yeah
this distance
what's the distance it's equals to what
so this bit is x2 minus x1 this bit
this bit is what y2 minus y1 right so we
know this a b what's the distance look
we talk about this triangle thingy right
triangle this is a this is b what's this
no c what's the what's c
c what's c c square equals one
remember a square
b
yeah okay and it's all positive
yeah
got it that's that's where it comes from
and there's another distance called
manhattan distance which is just this x1
minus x2
plus
y1 minus y2 look what's this look at
this absolute value right
that's the true value so look if this is
three this is four
if this three this is four the distance
the my hands and distance would be three
three plus four equals seven
but the the first one i don't know what
what's the distance is four yeah this
one will be
three square plus four square
square root equals five okay so now two
distance you can choose any of them yeah
remember we picked the shortest distance
on the previous right yeah okay
so what are we trying to solve here if
this problem is quite complex and we
don't have a deterministic you know
deterministic what's deterministic
we don't have a deterministic way to
predict it so for example this fx the
model could become quite complex you
have you have the input
yeah we want to get the output so what's
the output
what's the output right
right fx right
you have a lot of training data and
we want to know what's the output
okay
so let's let's do this k n so
what's here so we find the k nearest
neighbors to the input and then we get
the average we can do the average of it
right or we pick a medium or we put the
weighted average right so there are lots
of ways but first of all is we need to
find the k
nearest
neighbors to the input right
okay and then we can do the average of
it
yeah
or we do the vote if it's if you want to
labeling right if we want
if there are two choice
okay
signed or square we we count a vote
whoever wins whoever got the major votes
wins right in that previous case
there are two votes of the squares
so we tend to vote
for that that point that's a square
right
yeah
and if if it's a value right if it's
already it could be chosen as a value
for example like look let's do this
x y
if we do have a
graph y equals x square right
yeah
remember we call it called
less thingy i don't know the little
graph yeah
nothing yeah look
look this one yeah y equals x squared is
this one right
yeah when x is zero y is zero what x one
y is one
one x is two four right
three nine yeah
okay
so if
if f x is
x square you know and then we pick a
value like if if it's 1.5
1.5 so let's pick them
k equals three
what are the three closest neighbors to
1.5
if if we have a training data on
integers yeah one
two
could be zero or three right it doesn't
matter we pick one three
okay yeah all right
and then what what's the
so what's the out what's the prediction
so we know these three are the three
nearest neighbors so look what is y this
is one right
f1 equals one f2 equals
4 right f3 equals
s2 equals 1 3 squared equals 1
9 9 okay so what's the average of this
one
1 plus 4 plus 9 divided by 3 equals
about
14 divided by
sorry
is about 5. is it about 5
three
four
uh
so we picked a stream near his neighbor
could be yeah one two three
okay but but this is the difference the
error rate
you know if this is the
uh produce too much error right because
it's e equals to five but
look it's not five right if you if you
pick this if you pick this what happened
if you pick this neighbor
right if you pick one two three you get
the five if you pick zero one two
right i put a zero here so what's the
what's that
what's the
average one plus three one plus four
plus zero divided by three
yeah
five divided by three
one point
roughly 1.7 right
yeah
so you see by picking but the the
correct answer the correct prediction is
1.5 squared will be 2.25 okay so which
one is closer
which one is closer
1.7 right 1.7 instead of
5 right
this one is closer so you see
they they produce a larger difference
depending on how you pick the neighbors
yeah yeah
if we pick if we increase the k
if we increase the k that the
the accuracy might improve
make sense
or if we have too many if we have more
data points around
if we let's say if we have more data
points around the 1.5 right
if i have one more data point around one
and then the accuracy will be very close
to 2.35 it depends on how how these
status so you see that what can you tell
me what's the advantage and disadvantage
of knn
okay based on this the advantage and
disadvantage
advantage
simple yeah we just pick the k nearest
name and make an average am right oh
yeah what's the disadvantage the
accuracy depends on how you pick how
where are the neighbors right
yeah you could produce a very large
difference right you see yeah
and if there are a thousand a million
data sets
data points
it could be very slow to
to evaluate the distance right the
certificate if they acquire a lot of
these data points right if there are n
data points the time complexity will be
o n right
right because you need to go through
this n
to find
to calculate the distance
and also
okay you need to sort it right you need
to sort of find the distance uh find the
shortest distance so if you sort it
you'll be always logged in
right but if you if we're using the hip
hip remember the heat the binary kind of
binary tree right
this is the biggest always speaking if
you don't mean here this is the smallest
of in the binary and then you'll be
reduced the time convexity will be
okay
log n right this is a bit better than
over n again right because k is smaller
than
n right much smaller than n so
a okay looking right
huh makes sense
okay so let's write uh the structure of
o n okay and you tell me okay
define
k and n
okay our input is x yeah
and then n equals let's say equals three
okay
by default yeah we can put a default
value can we put the difference if we
don't pass the default value you'll be
uh you if you don't pass the end you'll
be
uh
you'll be three yeah so we need to
answer first of all we need to answer
and bigger let's say bigger equals three
okay
now we have a data point let's say the
data is here okay it's existing here
okay but we're putting here data is here
and
let's fill the data for example let's
fill the
let's feel the value of x as fx equals s
square okay let's say
this is uh this complex model is f x
here but these theta could be take a
could we already know and so we just
need to follow
i in red let's just fill the data here
but we can move this outside okay let's
let's move this outside for example
maybe we'll put a data here
data here okay down here and equation
okay so for example this data what does
it look like it's a dictionary and for i
in range let's say to minus 100 to 100
minus 1
and then what theta i
equals i times i right i times i squared
okay so when we fill the data yeah we
feel the data the data the keys
okay so now let's let's we have already
we already have this data theta is the
keys theta is like key value pairs right
for example one
one
two four
three nine something that i depending on
on your data it could be
complex this is the given mode uh given
already
historical data historical data we
already know training set
yeah training sets financing
training set
training set okay training set
and now
we want to find uh
we we want to calculate distance to all
the data points in the
uh in the training set okay so now let's
say we want to
get a cost
cost equals what because it's
an array right let's say
i
and then abs the distance yeah we can
calculate the distance right
i x i to the distance i minus x this is
the distance right and that's the tuple
the first value is the
the the the neighbor and the second
value of the tube is the distance is the
cost the
the distance to x right we use the
absolute value
and one for i in theta right
for i in data
okay and now we know we can we now need
to solve it yeah let's use the normal
sword okay
cost
the thought right but we want to sort by
what t
t right
equals x one right
okay
so we want to solve solve the cos array
by by
by by the distance in ascending order
that's what it means number x
x x one because x is the tuple right x0
is the neighbor
x1 is the cost is the distance
yeah why we need to solve the distance
we want to find out the
shortest
k
neighbors am right
are you are you with me
yeah excuse me
what's the terminology of this one if
there are n if that length of the data
is n what's the time that complex if we
sort an array with n numbers
what's the time complexity if we saw the
numbers
[Music]
so if we're using the heap if you're
using the heap the time capacity could
be improved as okay
log n right
yeah
okay
the heap yeah because we need to every
time we maintain a
heap we we insert the number
into a hip it needs to all log in
right and how many times we need to
take uh you know to take a number max
number or shortest number smallest
number from the hip
okay so this hip here
every time we take a
this is smallest hip
i will take it off one time but we need
to rebuild the hip let's look in and how
many times we need to take it do this
k times right because we need to k take
compute the k nearest right
yeah
so you need to okay which is better oh
and okay no okay logan
which is better okay why is that
because
k is
more than n right yeah and could be a
larger meaning if there are a million
data points right
this is obvious this is
much better because k k could be three
okay three compares to a minion
right i do it three times i do it a
million times which is faster
obviously yeah good job
okay now we sort it we saw it we saw
this already now we need to find out the
smallest one okay then we can return now
written what
that is we want to sum it first some
somewhat some
you data
the data
theta y x
uh x y x y x
zero yeah because 0 is the neighbor
right
x in
okay so data now i uh now now the cost
yeah
the cost is the
it's already sorted so cost
up to k
after n right after n is the first the
shortest the shortest season cost n
right so in cost
because up to n right
out to n
yeah because cost is
already sorted right sorted the first
element is that neighbor so we taking
the neighbors
the second one is the distance distance
to the input
right this is the sum and we how do we
get calculate the average how do we
calculate the average
how do we calculate average
we have some we have a how many numbers
what's the sum how many how many numbers
how many elements
are
a layer in in in here
how many numbers how many elements
and yeah so we just need to divide
divide n right this is sum yeah sum
divided by n is the average yeah
yeah
yeah this is average we don't you have
to get it so
overall this is the simplest clear and
uh
demonstration yeah so if
we use the average here but sometimes we
could use the weighted average right or
we could use the medium
or we could use some other functions
yeah this could be changed right this
could be adapted to different needs and
the sorting as i said could be
improved to okay login based on the heap
right
and then this input yeah input could be
different something it would be quite a
complex
you know complex
could be a vector right instead of
singular look this is x is the value
like how about it could be
a
a few variables right you could it could
be a vector and then you need to compute
the distance functions so the distance
function may not be may not be so
obvious because
in this case it's quite obvious yeah
because we're given a number f2 right
three what's the distance between three
and two easy three minus two distance
right absolute value right yeah
but it could be very complex distance
functions like it could be something you
know it could be a few uh
uh uh
a hundred values and what could be
distance by pitching those right
yeah or maybe two two values two values
x y
then you can calculate the distance at
distance yeah look if it's two elements
we could calculate the manhattan
distance we usually talk about right is
is what
absolute value of delta x data yeah data
what data is the difference between two
x values plus
absolute value of delta y okay
yeah or you could use this as a square
root from here square root beta x
square plus theta y
square
yeah the
less the two vector if there are even
input tangents to value and how about
three values so i value five values you
could define different distance
functions right for the input right
okay and data we talk about data data
could be very huge
so if it's very huge then the time the
performance of this kn could be very
slow because at real time you need to
evaluate the cost
of the input to the existing data in the
training set it could be slow right and
if we reduce that
if we reduce the data set
what what could happen accuracy might
might be my degree a lot right
it depends on how you choose the data
generally the more data
the better the higher p
accuracy am i right
yeah
but
as i said
the more data the slower and if we
reduce the number of the training data
we will also degrade the uh
degree the performance
right if only there are only a few data
sets then the prediction will be quite
highly biased right because it could be
it could be you know picking
some actual uh you know some incorrect
data sets data data points from this
data set it produced totally incorrect
prediction right and n equals three is
usually k
and k could be
five
seven you know nine those odd number
which is better right because we don't
we don't we don't want to avoid
we we don't want to you know we don't
want to
so why like n it needs to be odd because
we don't want the even votes right
as i said in the beginning triangle
square if we have
four if n equals four what could happen
two volts belongs to triangle two volts
belong to square and then we can make a
choice right but if it's k equals three
then we always can make a choice right
because there's a majority right that's
the majority
uh okay so that that's the k n that's
the machine learning that's the very
simplest machine learning accurate model
okay any questions so far
is it interesting useful
yeah it's for yeah
you see only one nine two one three nine
three nines implement of knm machine
learning algorithm okay
you see how powerful is that
okay
yeah
okay you want to say bye bye to people
bye
bye bye more update please can you be
more happy please
okay bye