[Music]
okay so we're going to learn some math
today uh probability okay yeah
all about probability probability what's
probability probability
okay
probability what's probability
it describes how likely an even happens
right it's just uh it's just a guess
again like it's going to rain
it probably goes into rain tomorrow
properly you know english earlier
properly
possibly which one is more likely
probably or possibly possibly
i don't know
in english
if you say it's going to be raining
tomorrow it's probably going to be
raining or it's possibly going to be
raining
probably it gives much probability yeah
so it's more challenging it's like
something written
yeah so probability is like it's a
number it's a fraction number between
zero to one okay you can say it's zero
you know this remember zero to one right
this means inclusive right
this means exclusive remember yeah
parentheses exclusive
square bracket
inclusive you can
we can use the numbers fraction number
between 0 and 2 1 and to to denote this
probability or we can use the
integer you know on the number between
zero to 100 but we put a
percentage right a hundred percent is
slow always going to happen right yeah
and tomorrow it's
100 it's going to rain so we know
you know tomorrow is definitely going
away yeah how do you know no i'm just
guessing
there might be something yeah yeah yeah
it's not
you know i'm just using this as an
example 100 100 right yeah so we uh so
we are going to talk about probability
today right like for example like
i give you
uh
you know let's draw a sweet box okay i
give you this three blocks and i tell
you that one of them
one of them has a
coin in that
okay yeah so what's the probability of
the first box has the coin
uh
five three um one over three yes thirty
threes over this okay
okay so now if i tell you okay so this
is called price price aura prior
how to pronounce this word priority
probability i say it's real
okay
it means that before the new information
is given this is the probability we know
so far that the first box
has the coin the probability is one over
and how about if i tell you that okay
if i open the second bar
and if we follow like there's no coins
so what's the probability of the first
coin what stock says the coin
yeah we're done because we already know
that
that we
the new information is given we know
this doesn't have a coin so
the coin must be in the first box or the
third box the least probability is one
over two okay a half okay yes this is
called posterior
posterior probability okay
probability okay probability
yeah makes sense
yeah
okay so now
let's say
let's say okay
let's say what
so okay so
you know the probability you can
multiply together okay so let's say you
have two box okay you have two box
right and each box has a coin but you
know the coin has two sides right yeah
yeah
what's the probability of both blocks
has a coin that
uh is both facing up
both basically what do you mean you're
not coin yeah facing up facing down
right there two sides yeah so what's the
probability of the
let's say what's the probability of
first the box
has a coin you know it has a coin what's
the box what's the coin what's the
probability of a coin facing up
uh
huh hour
what's the second box of the coin facing
up
half another half yeah what's the
probability of two coins facing up
uh
a quarter yeah that's what i mean you
multiply because the first one you have
the second one half you multiply
okay easy all right
now okay so remember on the first few
lessons we talked about van graff right
rain graph
yeah we can use the rain graph to to
study the probability okay
look
this is the event a yeah we put a big
circle
and this is the even b
probability here
what's this bit in the section what's
this bit
both a and b yeah both a and b so yeah
you can use you know if we using the
language as the set you will use these
yeah
a and b but
but again we can use the probability we
use the p right
yeah yeah can we look at this later okay
please
okay now
look what's this pa
what's this
pb
okay and this is p-a-b okay okay and now
i'm going to introduce a new mathematic
symbol which is called p
a
vertical
we call it conditional probability so
this reads as conditional probabilities
of a given b occurs
is in the middle
look what what's this b
conditional of probability a yeah
given b occurs given b occurs where the
b occurs this b yeah
yeah given
b occurs probabilities of a so it's this
b yeah you know yeah okay
right
probability conditional probability of a
given b occurs
yeah so what does z equal let's say look
it's this bit yeah
so okay
so p
a
conditional probability of a given b
occur equals p
a
and b the meter yeah remember the meter
this is the numerator this is a this is
b
this meter yeah
this meter divided by the whole b right
so it's helping
okay yeah
okay
so now look this this one so we can
rewrite this as what p
a and b equals
p
a conditional probability of a given b
times times what
comes up we just rewrite this function
times p b right
yeah
okay
so what does it mean look if we swap a
and b what do we have is we swap a and b
yeah because look at the a and b are two
circles they are in they are you know
exchangeable interchangeable yeah so we
can write it p
b a equals p
b
conditional p
conditional probability of p given a
occurs times p a right
right
yeah
so are these two equal
are these two equal p a and b and p b
and a
using equal
yeah
yeah a and b and b and a is the same
yeah but we are going to prove this
later okay but now look
if we want to prove these two equal we
need to prove these two equal right
yeah these two equal so for now we just
replace this here
right so it equals one p conditional
probability of a given b equals
yeah substitute
over here okay so if p
b conditional probability b even a
times p a
okay so look look at this
look at this what do we have
what do we have here
a rectangle conditional probability of a
given b is equal this is yeah this is
equals to condition conditional
probability of b over given a equals
times probability of a divided by
probability b this is called
naive
what's name
knife
i probably is the name okay this
sounds like in a is language yeah so
this is the equation for this it's just
about calculating the positorial
probability yeah yeah
yeah based on these no one factor need
no probabilities
okay so what do we say we want to com we
want to compute these two if it's equal
okay
yeah we want to compute these two if
to see if they're equal if they're equal
we can substitute let's p a b with ppa
right and then we can put this yeah this
whole thing is based on if these two are
equal right all right
so let's do this
let's do it
okay so if we draw a table right i draw
a table
a draw paper come on
this is the event a and this is a
a dash for meaning the opposite of a so
right maybe the opposite not a okay and
this is b
oh yeah yeah yeah
i'm not waiting for sure but yeah it's
also okay exclamation mark yeah but this
is a dash okay let's say this is a
b
c d a c okay so what's the probability
what's this p a
b
times y
p p-a-v times p
b right yeah
what's this p a
given the probability of b
given probability of b
given even b and what's the probability
of a given b here
yeah
what's the probability of a is a
divided by a plus c right
and what's the probability of b
what's the probability of b look there's
four values what's the probability of
leaf b
look at me come on
what's the probability of b column given
there are a b a plus b plus c plus b
a portion of a a position c right
so it's a plus c
divided by a plus b plus c plus c okay
and this cancel out okay so this b a
condition probability of a given b times
b is a divided by a plus b plus c plus d
okay and what's the probability of p
b
conditional probability of b over a now
given a occurs times p a okay
let's take it at least look what's the
probability of a
here
the first row
the first row okay
i love b
so it's this b so it's a divided by a
plus b okay what's the probability of a
yeah
a plus b
divided by y
all together
a plus b plus c plus b
cancel out
so look a divided by a plus b plus c
plus z look a divided by a plus c b
so what does it mean
equal what does this mean like these two
equal
okay these two are equal okay so what do
we prove
p
a and b
equals p
p and a okay so we can substitute that
formula right
okay
so now
let's let's uh let's do a little
exercise okay you know the apples yeah
apples sometimes they're sweet sometimes
they're not
yeah apples you like apples yeah right
like example yummy yummy
okay
yeah
so i have a table yeah i have a table
like uh
color you know i i i label the colors
yeah like uh
yeah but instead i use the integer to
represent the color is that okay yeah
color
don't put a white or black one in there
why
what kind of effort what kind of
what possibility of the colors of the
apples
red red green green
just different red okay you know for the
red
very very red orange
okay okay
pinky okay
so let's say
we have a few values okay
[Music]
hey what are you looking at
i have my no note
okay so this is the existing so we
already have we already know there are
five apples
right two of them are sweet three of
them are not sweet yeah
yeah
the color the color
the apple with color three and weight
four wait you know how heavy it is let's
say four
grams okay program
the unit program is really light okay so
what's the weight of this one kilo
kilogram is too heavy do you have here
like it's like
yeah okay okay
representative okay
so we want to know we want to ask the
computer to predict that
color three wait three is it swedena is
this reasonable yes or no right remember
yesterday we talked about the k n n
right
k nearly neighbors right yeah
so if we plot
if we plot this number okay
let's let's do this with knn first okay
look let's put this here
three four if this is color this is
weight okay three four is here three
four here yeah
it's one
if it's one we use the triangle okay
okay
two three
two
three yeah triangle okay and then zero
three zero three
is just let's say a square okay
three two
three two square
one four
one four one four
square okay and where's the three three
the square should be here not that okay
so where's the three three
two three is maybe here and here right
okay so
because what's the nearest three
neighbors do we have nearly three
neighbors
these leaves leaves okay so
two yeah it's closest to two triangle
which means it's sweet correct
do you understand yeah it's really
useful yeah do you understand yeah
i don't get it why is it why is what
sweet look
this point here what's the three nearest
neighbor to it
triangle one square
two triangle means the sweet square
means not sweet
okay
so two triangles
two votes there are two votes which vote
for the apple to be sweet one vote to be
not sweet okay so
the probability of being three is higher
right yeah look you know this is machine
learning so machine make a guess you
know what guess it's not a hundred
percent accurate right yeah it's a guess
you ask computer to make a guess yeah
sometimes the guess is all right
sometimes it's not all right so it's
just the best guess so we're talking
about this this really being a sweet
apple is more likely than being not a
sweet pepper okay this is knf okay
got it
now we want to use this probability to
calculate we want to calculate the
probability of this apple being sweet or
not if okay for example if i calculate
that same p this apple being sweet is 50
and being not sweet is like uh
20 so do you think do you think this
airport is sweet or not sweet come on in
this letter i calculate somehow you know
it is example if this effort is
probability of being 3d 50
and not 3d is 30 20
so do you think this app is sweet or not
we pick the
sweet because yeah as i say because more
chance of being sweet right so now we
just need to calculate if this effort
being sweet uh if this happens being
nothing the probability that we compare
both then
let not be yeah
so how do we compute the probability of
apple being okay let's say p3 what's the
probability of least being three apple
two out of five
40 right 0.4 right
yeah
what's the probability of
the apple being sweet and its color
equals three
nine this is posterior probability look
if we already know it's three it's two
there are two vapors being three and
what's the probability of that
of the card effort being color three
among the two apples
there's only one difference look whoever
one of them is three because we already
know fifty percent yeah
what's the probability of the sweet
apple being the weight
equally how is that yeah so p
three this is weight okay this is the
color
okay so what's the probability of the
apple being
sweet also color equals three and weight
equals three
one
and
one point four one point
one four
you times all these together yeah
one zero point one remember the boxes
thing you can multiply together a half
times right so this is 0.4 times 0.5
times 0.5 right because these three we
can multiply together because they're
individual independent yeah being three
apple right
color equal three and
weight equals three so the probability
of this apple being
sweet is what
three three sweet
is 0.1 okay
now let's calculate the other side
all right
what's the probability of all the apples
being not sweet
come on we already know this is 0.5 so
what's the aloha
huh
[Music]
three over five so what's that
yeah three threes what's the
yeah 0.6 look the other way is one minus
2.4 right because look we already know
that three apples are 40 so
not the sweet you know the other what's
what's the neck what's the rest it's 60
which are not sweet okay
and then let's say p
out of these three not three apples and
color equals three equals one
there are three apples here not sweet
and what's the color if it equals three
what's the probability
there's three what's the probability of
this ah
what three one over three i
what's the probability of the weight
equals three and not over
uh not sweet it's also one third right
so you times it together
what
0.6 times
one over nine so this is equals to zero
point zero
i i don't know
six
okay so it's less than zero point one so
what do you think is three or no
[Music]
sweet yeah because look the probability
is less than being nothing is less than
being three okay so look
using this probability you also make a
guess as this apple is sweet right sweet
okay and we use the k n and also to make
a guess as it's being sweet okay so the
chances are
it's sweet okay
make sense
okay so do you understand
yeah
okay so um okay so this is the
probability okay probability probability
is very useful it's very very useful
okay so i'm going to write this uh this
formula again okay
conditional probabilities of a given b
equals conditional probability of b of
given a occurs
right times p a
divided by p b okay that's the formula
let's call
naive
pairs
all right so you if you know these three
values so you can calculate these okay
it's very very useful
naive space players probability
equation okay we call it
that okay that's it for today good job
say bye bye
bye bye
bye bye bye bye