[Music]
so we have talked about the sub array
yeah remember i think
sub erase
what's the
it's a thing it's array like
is it it's a type of array sub array
type of an array continues it's
continuous okay
remember we have a few concepts
subsequence yeah subsequence
yeah and sub array yeah or substring if
you just string substring
subsequence subsequence is that
if you can remove one or more elements
from the original array or string and it
becomes subsequent it does not have to
be continued sub array is continued
right all right yeah right we have to be
continued okay we have talked about i
think we have talked about this in the
max sub array all right we're going to
calculate the max sub array sum right
so what's the next sub array sum what's
the sub rate that has the most sum in
this in the in this array array
everything have a look
another server continues
10 years
how much
you can you can pick this yeah you can
pick this that's six yeah all right all
you gonna pick here is 12. so the most
sub array is two is 12 right yeah
all right oh maybe
six months
what's that what do you mean
the subway doesn't yeah it look three to
one is a sub array two one is the
summary one is the sub right it has to
be continuous nice subsequence okay okay
yeah then why could you just do all of
them oh we're done okay let's see okay
because i i'm not sure i'm just checking
this it's like six minus five is one and
ten two yeah you're all right yeah you
can put all of it yeah okay so let's
what what how how are we solving this
remember we've talked about this before
yeah yeah greedy yeah and then oh the
first approach is what if we're not sure
we can always do this
how do we prove our thing we
what
we can profess the subway or sub
sub uh
sub array or sub
next if we if we determine the left part
you know the starting part of the sub
array and then we can proof us the next
yeah okay okay let's try this okay
this is just a little video and i'm
going to
introduce
a new concept of a new algorithm okay so
let's actually define
max sub array right separate
array sum
and we have the numbers nums
so first of all we want to get a n n
equals length num right
this is the length
and then that's the number the next sum
okay so the maximum is what let's assume
these numbers is not empty okay it's not
empty so assume a third okay i said
remember i said
n is bigger than zero okay
assert anything bigger than zero and at
the beginning we want to assign the
maximum to the max
possible and the negative
so what's the
what's the minimum what's the
smallest number you can think of you can
think of
minus infinity where the mass of
infinity yeah infinity
infinity is not actually not a concrete
number it's it's it's so small that you
can measure it okay
and then now we go
and we fall left we for left in range
range when we start with zero to n right
and then for we proof was the right yeah
if we decide if we already decide the
left path then we go to the right path
for r in range range one
we start with one l plus one right
can we start with the l yes we can
product because the sub array can be a
single number so we start with the l and
up to n right
i know
i don't know what
and now we want to calculate the sum
right we want to calculate some
yeah we want to calculate something they
know this sum equal as well we can do
this sum
somewhat uh
nums
to r plus one right then we calculate
sum and then we want to keep the maximum
so maximum answer equals
max
answer
s right and then return y
very obvious what's the term complexity
it's very tricky okay look what's the
term numerous things
yeah because this one yeah but we can
improve to all square right this is our
nqp right we can input over n square how
do we improve the length square so every
time
so every time we start with the l we put
x equals zero here
and then we just here s plus equals
nums
ah right because every time we start
with air
the sum is zero
right and then we start adding the
the bit the server right now and then we
do this then in this case the term
complexity is our
if we do this optimization the sum is
gone so we accumulate the sum along the
way so what's the terminal
and what
come on
why you said i went free in in the first
place
oh and cupid and now i improve it so
what's the time to make sticks
oh and square we're done okay
so okay so this is the this is not new
okay we have talked about this before
all right this is just the review okay
um and we talk about the dynamic
programming actually
because at the time we didn't know that
dynamic programming is also fancy
there's a it's a fancy name called tadan
agreement
so it's actually an iterative
uh iterated dynamic programming
so what does it mean
so let's use this let's use dp
and dynamic programming i
that means that it
that's the maximum sub array
sum that ends up index i
okay
yeah
max sum max sum
sub array
and
add
index
i okay that's what you mean dpi okay
so what does it equal
is it equals that max
max y max of one
dp
the first previous one i minus one yeah
uh let's do this a little bit closer and
then zero
plus the numbers i
already
can you
understand this what does it mean so
look
i have a lot of few numbers we have 4
minus 10
1 okay
so at this point the max sub array sum
ending at this index
is it equals to the maximum of the
previous previous
previous sum plus this number yeah plus
this number
or if i don't pick the previous one if i
pick only the current current number
right right doesn't make sense so at
this point i can make a choice i can
make a choice
i can
choose to keep the previous separate sum
right
or i can abandon the previous operation
so this is abundant when we abandon it
then we start a new suburbanism is just
this number or we keep the previous
summary some in this case we add the the
current subway summits previous one plus
uh plus the number of this one right
so this is called captain argument it's
also iterated
dynamic programming okay it generated by
dynamic programming
so we can implement it without
keeping this dpi because we always look
because this dvi is an array right but
we can
implement this just using these the two
variables because for every time i
calculate dpi
all i need is dpi minus one right
okay let's do this because this is
called
it's quite similar to the dynamic
programming we have implemented in the
first few lessons right
in a long time ago just a little easier
just make sure you don't forget okay
and then we today we'll give you the
fencing name go kadam
okay negara is the
iterated dynamic programming languages
to a programming agreement to compute
the max
maximum sum of sub array in a one
dimensional array okay
usually if we use the blue force
then that time complexity will be o and
q ln square right on square for the
improved blue force
defined
next sub array
num
okay so now we how can we do this how
can we do this
uh and it goes lens
nums okay this is the same and then we
assert
we have said n is bigger than zero okay
we don't want to compute the separate
layer it doesn't
make any sense if we don't compute the
sub array of the empty array okay
now
i have this answer
answer let's say is max
max infinity right
right and then i have the current sum
okay let's put this as zero and then we
loop over the numbers i in
nums
okay now what
s will be equals to maximum of y um
s
and what
uh actually is maximum of
i we choose the current number or we
choose the s plus i
right and then answer
will be equals max
answer of another current so far okay as
s s will be
actually let's make rename the s to the
the maximum ending that current index so
let's say dp dpi okay let's put a dpi
this is a variable okay dpi equals zero
and dpi
dvi equals
max i this is the current remember we're
talking about the current number ending
the column we can start with canon
number oh we keep the previous sum so
which is dpi
plus i right and the next answer is the
next answer
we're going to we want to keep uh this
is the global maximum okay global
maximum we can do this dpi right dbi
and return
answer
what's the time complexity if you if you
look at these if you look at these
what's the thumbnail that's the can you
tell me
oh n yeah it's all yes
yes it's over
okay so let's go through this a little
bit okay answer global
global maximum at the beginning is max
is the
smallest number we can we can represent
in python is
negative
infinity
dpi is the what is the current
is the maximum sum of the sub array
that ends the index i s and the
current position now we go through these
numbers and we update it so
this this is
kadan angular yeah it's also dp
so it means that
we can choose
we can choose to ignore look alright
three two minus ten okay here
all right look what's the what's the
summary
of ending at
minus ten
what's the
subtle way of ending minus 10
if i if i have
what's the maximum sum of sub ray that
has to end at -10
ten
is it yeah is it minus seven can i
include the before then it would be
smaller right one you'll be infinite no
no no you'll be my five minus ten will
be minus five minus size bigger than
minus 10 that's what i mean yeah yeah
but if this is look if it is if this is
minus 3 minus 2 minus 10 what's the
maximum sum that ends that summaries on
the answer minus 10.
that's -10 right
yeah you see you see the difference yeah
so dpi is the sub is the maximum okay
let's duplicate it max sub array sum
that ends at i index i dpi so
ends at it ends at the index i
okay so and at this point so i need to
compare what i can compare if i keep the
previous sum right
well previous sum keep the previous
number is which is dpi minus one here
right
yeah
this is dynamically if i choose to keep
the previous sound
so that's two possibilities once to keep
it then
then the sum
will be previous dpi minus one plus the
numbers or if i choose to ignore to
abandon the previous sum
then the
sum will be what if i choose to ignore
any one and what what's the sum of the
one end at index like come on it will be
easy
10 it will be least number right so
that's what i mean dbi equals next i
max i is this number
dpi plus i is previous one plus this
number and we are going to choose the
maximum
and answer will be the global answer
right because we want to find out the
maximum sub array sum and then the
summary sum can ends at in in any index
right that's so that's why we keep
updating this group of answers so the
time context is of n what's the space
complexity are we using any space
no
what's a what's a space complexity
oh what
are we using any additional linear space
one a one whether
okay so this is called captain agreement
okay so previously we have talked about
it but we we we didn't know it was
called captain we just
named it that dynamic programming but
it's basically the same thing so today
is basically just the review okay just a
review of the previous lessons okay
uh
any questions
no okay so tomorrow we're going to use
this katanagaran to do something more
because yeah to do something wrong to do
something because this is very useful it
can be used to solve many many similar
problems like
like what
okay so i'll give you a little i give
you a little
uh problem to think about and then we
can talk about it tomorrow okay so given
look you know the price the stock price
yeah all right so i have a price that's
three
four two
one ten this is the price of every day
and you are you you can only buy and
sell
once and what's the maximum profit you
can get for example you can buy a three
and say at 10 the profit you get is what
10 minus 37 or you can sell buy at one
and sell at 10 right the price you know
like a price you've got a price yeah
you've got a toy today is worth worse
than one dollar tomorrow is ten dollars
if you buy it today and if you say
tomorrow how much benefit how much
profit you can make
how much profit
you can make if today you buy
let's say you buy a chocolate
one pound today
but it could you can say 10 pounds
tomorrow how much profit you can drink
come on easy
10. tomorrow you sell it at 10 today you
buy it at one what's the profit you can
nine yeah we're done look because you
pay one today right
you pay one to get it and tomorrow you
say they're ten that's nice so we want
to make find the minimum
minimum you can buy which is one and the
maximum you can say is 10 okay but we
we can talk about this tomorrow and we
can use this captain algorithm okay so
let's say for today good job good job
bye bye
bye