so
hello hello mr everybody
yes
okay so today we talk about a math
problem which mess passes which is
called
no how do you pronounce this i know it
taught
and i
so we have a three only three yeah we
have uh first of all we have three
three rods
so you know what
okay three dots so
this is a
this is b
this is c
so we okay so we have uh
a we call it disk okay we have disk and
disk
if they want this if they play
initially that these antics are placed
on the first
first node okay so if there's only n
equals one how many moves
does it take
to move this a to c given this condition
yeah you only
these these sticks yeah is usually the
smaller place on the larger one so
you'll be like that disc
yeah it'll be smaller or last one
place on the bigger one okay so this
uh
the smaller can only be placed on the
bigger one
and you're only allowed to move one at a
time one at a time
okay you can't take small you can move
one at a time
okay and we are we want to move all the
discs from the left right to left right
most which is from a to c
so if there's only one
then we can just do a just move it yeah
yeah
all right
okay so let's let's if we use the t to
to represent the number of the the
minimum moves okay the minimums t one
equals one is easier if n is one t one
equals one okay
more interesting the
[Music]
how are we moving this can you tell me b
has to be placed on a you know a company
plays on b okay because b is smaller
than a okay
so how can we move this a b to here from
a to c
b
put on b
yeah
a put on c
b
predominantly okay so let's how many
moves
okay let's try again
one
two
three
okay three moves
okay now it's more interesting
see okay there are three three discs
okay come on play again
be
can see put on b yes yes
i
oh i mean c
and then
a
you want to restart you can restart i
think
i think there's something you know the
opposite out there because eventually
you want to put a to c and now at least
taken the place
yeah
so we start
yeah don't worry let's do it again
um
so five plus two seven okay
okay
great job so
okay so if there are n it gets more
complicated right if like four five six
it gets more complicated but the
the essentials are the same
so what are we trying what have we done
here is we want to move
the top layer and if there are any if
there are n here
we're going to move like n minus one
yeah minus one
it's excluding the last one yeah we want
to move these these two
here right
yeah
and i will move through here to here
right
yeah what why do we need to put it on c
because this is the target from a to c
we're moving everything from a yeah yeah
so
we this process is similar we just need
to this f minus we want to move the n
minus one but we don't know how to move
here but we can move this n minus one to
the middle right yeah
and now we move this because it's only
one now right so i only move it to here
and what's next i want to move these two
back to here all right
yeah so now every three step
two step so
so look
tn
equals first of all i want to move these
to here right
let's t a minus one right
yeah
plus here
plus one
then n minus one again
all right
okay so what is the equal t n equals two
times t n minus one plus one okay so can
you tell me what's t4
based on this t n equals two times t and
minus some previous one plus so what's t
four
[Music]
p three is seven t four is two times of
t three plus one
two times seven
yeah so yeah like that
so
so what's this equal okay what's this
equal but let's we can prove it
t one equals one t n equals two times t
n minus one plus one
okay so remember we talked about the
mathematic induction before right
what does it what does it mean is that
it's a message
storage to prove that a phenomena
stands how do we prove it we have a
formula we prove that t the basic case t
one it
uh stands and then we're assuming
t
k
and then we want to prove that t k minus
one also a plus one also exists okay
let's do this and then you understand
okay so actually this t n
is equals two times to the power of n
minus one remember the t one
equals one t two equals three t three
equals seven yeah t four equals
fifteen yeah two to two to the power of
four four sixty minus one fifteen two to
the power of three a minus one seven two
to the power of two
four minus one three two to the power of
1 2 minus 1.
yeah this is the equation but how can we
prove this is all right
t1 we just prove it when n is 1 is 1 t1
equals 1. that's fine if let's say tk
let's say t x yeah t x
t x
was t x equals two to the power of x
minus one right and that was t x plus
one t x plus one
equals one
t x plus one equals one two times this
we have two times t x two times
two t x plus one equals two times t x
two times t
x plus one right so this is 2 times
this bit
2 x minus 1 plus 1 right
yeah
so equals to a 2 2 times 2 x is 2 times
x plus 1 minus 2 plus one what's the
minus two plus one
look if we substitute this t x with
these then we can get this
two times two x plus one minus two plus
one is one
is what is minus two plus one
uh
oh no it's not all two t x is two
two x
is my two minus one right two x plus one
look t x plus one equals two x plus one
minus one okay so you look it also works
yeah because look
all right
x plus one yeah substitute so it also
uh it proves that t n equals two and
minus one because t n
plus one equals two times and two to the
power n plus 1 minus 1 i is the same
it's the same form
okay
uh
yeah
so we can write this simulation okay we
can write this simulation
define move okay let's move
how many disks and disk
we want to move from
source
to
destination yeah and then we have a
another road another road
temp let's call it temp okay
if n equals one what does it mean if we
only have one
we just move yeah we just move if any
goes wrong let's just move it print
okay move
disk
okay i'm just like this one
from
sauce
to
destination yeah because there's only
one right and then we do ten
okay there's only one i thought two's
spell disc is d i s
c
yeah oh that's maybe americans english i
don't know deep
d-i-d-i-s-k-d-i-s-c
yeah similar okay
return okay if not look we move what we
move
okay
if there are more than one so what do we
do what do we do remember what do we do
what do we do
if there are more than one we move the
top and minus one right minus one
from sauce
from sauce to to the term yeah turn the
middle one right
yeah
to the middle one and we use the
destination as a
you know intermediate term yeah and then
we need to do a print
we now we want to move what
move
move disk
and at this end
from
what
from source
and then to this is a normal to
destination
and then now
what's next we need to move this n minus
one yeah
move
n minus one
front
forward front forward
destination to use the destination and
we need to move from because now it's in
a destination right so we need to move
from destination
yeah
to uh
uh
[Music]
so actually it is because now it's in
slot testing is in the temp yeah
this is 10 10 we want to move to
destination yeah
destination right we'll move here 10
because look i already previously moved
enter minus one from source to ten
the middle one is the ten one and i want
to move the from the two one to the
destination
right and i'm using
the
source as the intermediate one as a term
right so let's restart here
okay
i know that's the agreement to solve and
you know arbitrary end you can put 100
here
and the computer will print the step for
you
correct
yeah
so you see so so
if your n equals four it's easy
your recursion look this is the question
yeah because because we are recursioning
solving n minus one right
because we are focusing on one one time
one step at a time we want to move the
end disc
all we want to focus is move the top n
minus one
top n minus one yeah
we want to move the top n minus one from
source to the middle one right
and then i want to move this the second
step move this to the destination and i
want to move these
to here
right yeah that's the question
okay okay so let's say if t
like one test
t
[Music]
five equals how many steps
remember the equation
i just proved before that two to the
power of n minus 1
so 2 to the power of 5
41 31 yes 31 okay got it yeah got it
any questions so far
any questions
okay good job okay that's it for today
good job
do something again if you want
okay that's it