[Music]
so
suppose that you have enough money and
then there's a price for the each you
know the chocolate for example you want
to buy a chocolate yeah you want to buy
a chocolate you want to buy and sell
chocolate so let's say
one two this is the price of the
chocolate on the day yeah
and six
eight nine okay
[Music]
so let's say you have enough money but
the the thing is that you can only sell
it before you can only sell it after you
buy it okay you cannot
you cannot do the opposite so you want
to buy the first and i said right you
can save it after you buy it
so the profit you know the profit for
example today i
i buy like one chocolate using one
dollar
and tomorrow i sell this chocolate
for five dollars how much money i can
make the profit
so today i buy one chocolate using one
corn or what one
dollar
one pound for example like tomorrow i
sell this chocolate
for five pounds four thousand okay four
pounds okay so
in this case
okay
so this is the prices for the coin for
the chocolate
this is the chocolate price and then you
can buy and sell once so what's the
maximum profit you can get one
ten one ten well done yeah
can you get more maybe if i put a 19
here what was there 119. wow okay how
about seven here
uh 219. wow so what's your approach yes
exactly what's your approach you can you
can just see it directly right ryan yeah
you can see it directly what was your
approach
you can prove things so fast
yeah
how how do you preface how do you
improve
how do you do first just minusing the
number note oh wait this is
may work but there's an exception that
look if i leave this 19 i put here
i put it 19 here and i put it
for example 10. so you go look
this is the lowest smallest but this is
the biggest but the biggest comes before
the smaller you come right so what this
is
you can go and then okay so you find the
smallest number yeah okay
and then
you look for
you know almost quite close the biggest
number after this number
yeah yeah yeah so we want to find the
biggest number after tomorrow so i'll
keep checking her
good point good question yeah okay so we
come to this we come to some list later
okay but as you mentioned we can solve
this using proof of thing how can we
prove first how can we prefer
everything of proverbs
still not good still no good okay so can
answer me what what's the approach to
proof of what are we trying to prove uh
checking every possibility of what
last point
but how we how we trying to calculate
the profit i mean
we are trying to
prove our thing that what
what are we trying to prove for thing
here try the what we're trying to bring
try the what on which day we're going to
buy and which day we're going to sell
right this is the thing we could try
okay so if we try to buy this on this
day
then we can try the sale on those day if
you try to buy it on this day we can try
in the days yes we say right ryan
yeah yeah okay
so let's do this defy makes profit
no singing please too noisy
okay the answer will be at the beginning
zero and n will be the days of the
numbers yeah the numbers
prices
so now for
what
let's say bye bye yeah p in range
gradual
strange
[Music]
what we can buy on any day right
yeah yes and okay then for sale for us
in
range what
for each pie day we can sell on what day
we can tell on
on what day if we find sir
[Music]
so answer equals we want to keep the
maximum
perfect answer
okay so how can we write this what's the
profit if we buy on what's the profit if
we buy on day b and sell on day s
what's the problem if you buy on day b
and say on day s
prize
price
s nun
and what plus or minus
[Music]
yeah what's the time come next day
come on you see a four why are you still
saying okay
rn square what's a space complexity i
want one
can you tell me what's a one when i ask
for a time complexity why you always say
one what's the one
sorry
one you like one okay oh n square why is
that because this is going to end and
for you i have n have n possibilities
and for each choice
you have another n possibilities yeah
you got it
yeah so that's always square right
the space complexity one is constant
because we are using only constant
space the answer two variables yeah
answer n b s
okay yes okay can we do better
yes
oh
um
how can we do better
uh let's uh let's buy this okay
my
[Music]
you told me what
what did you tell me before
[Music]
how about this partner prices in
in can you see layout
in a graph okay this is the day
and this is the price okay let's say the
first day
uh
three okay
three
this three two
ten probably here yeah
six probably here yeah
a probably here 10 over here okay
so if you if you put it
yeah
okay yeah you further so what are we
looking for we want to look for uh
we want to look for the lowest peak
flow is this is called the noise yeah
and the largest the top
so that we want to look for the largest
after the lowest right the way it fits
the lowest is at the end
it doesn't matter still if it's the end
look if it's the end
yeah i'm just doing this if it is n okay
it doesn't matter i'm just going to scan
it from the left to the right
okay
so the point is that we keep tracking of
the minimum
minimum we have seen so far yeah but and
now we when we have a maximum we can
subtract it
no no not a maximum we have a bigger
number then we can subtract that minimum
we have seen so far
so look look at this example
three okay let's say we have the minimum
value yeah
i know we have answer okay and then you
tell me if it's all right okay
what's the minimum so far three
okay and
okay then what's the minimum so far two
so we get it
uh so
so so we need to
as well update the answer right yeah so
what's the minimum so far three and the
answer will be the current number minus
three is zero okay because
yeah i don't know i know what's the
minimum number white okay
[Music]
two yeah
two yes there are two
and it's still zero right because the
maximum is the the current number is two
two minus minimum is yeah what's the
minimum silver
two i know what's the current number 10
10 minus two eight
this one max answer we want to find the
maximum and this minimum we're on the
random minimum okay next one what's the
minimum number so far
what's the what's the profit if we use
the current these numbers minus the mean
so is it bigger than a yeah
and this what's the minimum
still so far too right
and
six six
we're not updating yeah about
we're not updating this 10 minus 2 8 is
the same so what's the profit
is that a yeah
okay got it
so the thing is that we keep tracking of
the minimum value we have seen so far
and then we use the current value to
subtract that because we know in the
past we have seen this minimum value and
then if we set it on the day on current
day we can make a profit of a current
number minus that mean number all right
yeah so
in this is one goal what's the time come
back stick
oh and we're down here to jump
so let's try this
define
max profit
prices
so that's n equals length
uh actually we don't need to define the
n okay let's say answer equals zero
the minimum value minimum value equals
equal as well at the beginning the
minimum value will be the
what's the biggest number you can think
of
um
infinity
and now we go through here
for i
in
prices which also use prices now we want
to find the update the minimum value
yeah so how can we update this mean
value equal as well
all right mean
and mean value of nn
i right
right now we're updating the minimum
value and then now what's the profit if
we sell it on the
on on this day what's the profit
answer equals max
answer and then what
i now i value minus one
minus one
[Music]
v min v is the minimum value we have
seen so far yeah
i'm i is the value is the price of today
all right no
i is the price of today and we need to
manage
the price the minimum price we've seen
right mainly yeah i mean that's what i
said
okay good job i only returned
also
what's the tongue honestly um
[Music]
okay so this is this is the we
like you know we keep checking on the
minimum number and we updating the
profit max profit okay okay so remember
we talked about the captain right
yeah
what does it mean
is a algorithm for dynamic programming
it's already dynamic programming
what what does it try to do
uh i forgot you forgot we want to keep
the next step away song right
yeah remember
yeah let's do a little bit review okay
so for example like 3 2
0 10
to 5
what's the what's the maximum sum of the
sub array
sub rate continuous yeah what's the sub
maximum sum sub array
[Music]
which one what's the sum what's the
maximum sum of the summary
[Music]
come on
five to five this is seven this is six
yeah you can't use this because they
you'll make the sum less
right one yeah okay
brand
okay so look so how can we do this we
use the dp array dpi we talk about the
subarray the maximum sub rate sum the
ends the index i and what is the equal
equals max this is the katan yeah it's
actually dynamic programming dpi minus
one yeah
yeah
and then if we
if we choose the previous one or if we
don't choose the previous one i know
plus the current uh the the number
numbers i yeah let's say and i okay
okay so so yeah make sense
all right look
so dpi is that the
maximum okay let me repeat maximum sum
of sub array and the index i
right
so does it so
dpi minus 1 is here
so what does it mean i can choose to
include the previous sum right and then
i can add this then i have a bigger sum
or if i don't choose the previous sum
right because it could be too too small
then i start with the sub array
from the current partition right
yeah
so how can we this is the carbon the
dynamic problem how can we apply these
to these to the the problem of today so
first of all okay first of all it can be
trend
uh transform okay so look
let's say
we have a price today like a a a1
a2
a3
a4
a5 okay let's say this is the
this is the price for the day for each
day
and now we can have another array called
b1
b2
b3
b4 b5 okay so what does it equal so b1
is equal to zero
b2 equals to
a2 minus a1 so it's the difference yeah
difference between these two numbers
yeah so b3 equals a3 minus a2
b4 equals one
a a4 minus a3 yeah and b5 equals one
a5 minus four
okay so this is the difference yeah okay
two
zero three five let's say this is a
array and what's b alright b already was
yellow and one
and wha what's this value
so how is these two
related
so if if i say
if i said okay so the lowest point is a2
and then the the selling point is a5 so
if we want to buy on that a2 and then
sell on the a5 then we got the next
profit all right
yeah
okay
uh
yeah so how can we how can we relate
these to each each other
so if we
okay so if we look if we add these two
uh these b2 b3 plus b4 plus b5
right
yeah if b 3 plus b for b plus d psi what
do we get
a3 minus a3 turns out yeah a4 minus a4
might cancel out yeah so what do we have
a5 minus a4 a2
a5 minus a2 you see
so this is exactly so we are looking for
look this is b3 plus b4 plus b5
is this
and then what is equal it equals a5
minus a2 if i minus 32 so this is the
profit
so what does this mean it means that we
need to calculate the longest
the maximum sum of sub array right
yeah and what you can we already know
use the katan algorithm right to solve
this so as long we transform the
original array to this now we can
calculate it's the same thing as
calculating the sum
maximum sum of a
sub array right
got it yeah are you with me
this is challenging right mathematic
challenge you want a challenge ryan you
say you want a more challenge are you
with me
yeah
it's okay you don't follow but you know
try to understand okay okay let me
repeat again okay this is a bit tricky
to understand okay
the original way the price is
if a2 is the lowest current and a5 is
the
max yeah after this though it's fine and
then profit we can make is 85 minus a2
right yeah example yeah
so if we change from the a to a to array
to b array b array b is the difference
contains the difference yeah difference
of each
price of each days now look what do we
get
b3 equals a3 minus a2
before a4 minus a3 b5 a5 minus a4 if we
added b3 plus b4 plus b5 what do we get
we cancel only in the determined so this
will be equal what b3 plus b4 plus b5
equals a5 minus a4 a2
right this is the profit
so in other words we are looking for
the maximum sum of a sub array because
look this is the sub array of the b
right this is the sub array of b we want
to find out the sub array in this b
array
huh
okay
okay let's try this and we already know
to use this katan algorithm right
the time complexity of categories oh
what
oh and whether okay define
next profit
oh and usually open for the arrays
going once
right that's all that's that's what it
means ryan do you get it
what means that
there's an array and we need to ask
computers to travel
just to go once or two times you know
constant times even when you go go go to
the half it's still aware right okay
doesn't make sense
so this is there are ten ten elements uh
let's say they're ten elements
and your accuracy requires to visit each
element once like from 1 to 10
you know to some to make a computer some
or get the average or whatever
it's all when right okay
max profit
and let's say numbers
first of all we need to prepare okay
let's say n equals length this is the
number of the elements in the array
and answer let's say
at the beginning is zero right
right
yeah and
what do we do for
i
in range we start from the first one
right one to n
right and then what
oh we need to have another current okay
current current equals zero
current
plus
equals
price alarms yeah we want to find the
difference numbers i
minus nums i minus one right this is the
b array right
this is a b right and then if current is
smaller than zero smaller than zero we
set it to zero but so now we can rewrite
this
so what current
equals max
what
makes these plus carbon
zero okay and now we can have answer
equals max
answer currently
and then return answer
okay
so what's
what's the space complexity if we if we
still remember
oh
what's the space are we using any
additional space
no
one or one yeah
look
look answer this is the answer the
maximum profit this is current right
we are looking for the
maximum sub-array right the third result
so the current
current this is the
this is the
sub-array of uh this is the b array
right we calculate difference
calculate difference and we add it
yeah this is the way we take it
calculate difference to plus the current
we use the current value or we don't use
it
okay we use the current value
current value or we don't use here okay
yeah i mean does it make sense eric yeah
so which one do you think is better
they're all over all the three algorithm
the first one is proof of thing the
second one is use one we do
[Music]
remember the lowest point and then
and then the highest point in the future
right
and this one is the transform the
original ratio to the
to another problem
yeah they're using the content so
the second one and the third one is
still exposed away so which one why do
you think i won
the time and space complexity for the
second and the third solution is the
same okay
make sense yeah
current plus the
yeah
which one sorry
okay
any questions so far
ryan any questions
any questions
bye
[Music]