go
hi
hello mr erin is right okay
okay i'm going to write a few rules to
make up a word okay let's say
ah
the legs of r r to i
it means that
the letter
followed by r is i okay
e
eric
oh you're getting this i know i'm not
finished yet because i can see
so we have given the list of we are
given a list of these rules and they
need to return the word lieutenant
and also
impossible
it's it's valid okay whatever it is in
the word
good yeah but
the the thing is it's always valid okay
it's always ready so
and the word doesn't contain the
duplicate letters okay if you if you
give a dad right
it doesn't have these yeah it doesn't
have these it doesn't have cycles here
it doesn't have pointing back because
look if you put this d
to a
i a to d okay
so we don't have the inputs for this so
all the letters
in the world is unique yeah unique my
first word
that's what i'm saying there's no
there's no unique there's no duplicate
letters okay
[Music]
yeah
if it is then
there's no way to use the angle then
there's no way to do it because there
could be there could be a
a different the the result would not be
unique right even though if there's a
duplicate numbers then there could be
different results okay correct
okay let's try again okay i'm not going
to write the ryan this time okay just
guess okay
let's guess
p to
a
okay
they speak spanish
okay s to b that [ __ ] s to p
a to i i to n
uh p to a okay so you got it yeah
okay so given these rules
given these twos we
we want to
restore we want to
cut the original one okay is it clear
yeah
any idea
any idea how do we do this
how do i do it
from these news what what can we get
what can we learn from these news
what can we learn from these these rules
connect to each other next to each other
and apart from that what can we learn
like s p goes to so p was next p a yeah
what's next
yeah yeah yeah oh good so the first
thing of this is
what are you trying to do
yes you follow it but follow from where
good that's a very good starting point
so where where to follow
you're following these yeah p to a a to
i i to n yeah because they lose so the
most important thing is to find out
which one
is the what
which one do we start start okay so
which one is the start
right okay there's one part missing so
we want to find the first letter
from these news how can we tell which
which letter is the question so we check
through all of them if the one who
only appears once is the one is
that yeah where's that yes good job yes
if it appears only once okay look
from s to a r
yeah
p to a all right
okay so look
for example this p
you got s to p
and you also have p to a right
but how about the last one the last one
i to n
oh yeah but that last one is also appear
once
hey almost there almost there nearly a
tray okay that's fine this one i
couldn't do later okay so is it wait i
got a question if if you do like stp
does s have to go fast
the key it means that p is next to s
okay it just means p is next to
s okay so look if you say appeal once n
and s appear only once so how can we
tell if it's
if s is in the first place
if s is the plus how do we know if n is
look
where's as s is in the first n is in the
last okay so we want to find out the
letter which appear only once
if we start from here it does this one
play like um like if it stp does p go
after s
yeah p go after s yes
p is next to x
okay
okay what you're doing what's your right
okay so you understand yeah so look
your solution is it's okay
there are only two letters s and n which
only appears in one yeah but we have to
distinguish between s and n so s
is the beginning and the last one yeah
so this look this is the in degree uh so
if we have this the p the in degree
right we call it in degree and then p to
a this is our degree so we want to find
a letter which doesn't have any indegree
right because it only
it doesn't have we don't have any
letters come going through the s right
okay
yeah and then we follow this s to p p to
a
i you know follow these okay
but you know if you don't yeah this is a
very uh efficient agreement but first of
all we uh if we don't have this if we
don't
uh
we don't have this uh efficient
algorithm we can always prove us how can
we move forward i'm just going to
say this idea proof of thing yeah
proof of thing we first first of all we
find the number of letters from these
rules yeah because we can find out the
letter which is a five s p i i i spam
right spend the five letters five
letters and we can proof of this
yeah this is the set we will compute
this in a set and now we prove forcing
it
using a different permutation and
remember computation one two three
permutation how many permutations are
these
permutations different orders how many
permutations six yeah one two three one
three two
two one three two three three two one
three one two three two one yeah because
you look at the first position you have
three letters three choice the second
partition you have two
right the second choice you have one so
three times two times one is six the
fourth communication if there are five
is five factorial right
so if i learn n letters if the rules
have n letters right so the complexities
o n factorial
once we have one factorial
o and factor this is the number of
possibility permutations their
permutation then we check we need to
check if it is the same rule of least if
it
if it satisfies all the rules right so
this needs to
do another o
n
right
o n right am right
yes you need to go through these rules
one by one
go through this loop
but how do you know doesn't really lose
and then you need to find how do you
check if it satisfies the rule right you
need to use this find
to find out
the number of the characters and then
it's next one so look if if we we have
this expand we need to find out the p
which is at this position and we have to
check its next one
if it's a now if it doesn't if it's not
a
then we return the force
it doesn't satisfy this rule right so
look we have to go through the end rules
for example the anus and for each
character we have to use the find or
index index to find out the
index of the
of this this character that a this
character p
in the permutation is another n so o n
bacteria
times n times n so this is
very very slow okay so we're not going
to
go uh implement this one but we can use
the it's a permutation yeah we can use
the word permutation
the the python yeah the python
has a
gita tool of permutation so what does it
mean
that's a slow
permutation so look we can fly
import
permutation we can use this
communication
yeah and then we can do that if these
letters even all the letters in a in a
set yeah if it's in a sense okay you
need to
calculate we need to process the rules
and put in a set and we can do this for
p
in
permutation permutation
permutation letters
okay now we can need to check if check p
if we need to check if
if satisfied all the rules yeah then
return p we can
return this permutation between p p p is
a two part okay it will return for
example if it's uh
s p
p a uh let's say eric you will return
this e
r
i
c okay we'll return this
[Music]
okay
okay so this is a twofold thing okay but
we're not going to go into the detail
with the check funny but you know what
we're going to check yeah we found first
of all we find out
we find out the index of the first
letter in the rule which is the we use
the index yeah we use the index to
index function will return
the index of first occurrence letter all
right and if it's a string if it's a
string or list we can also use the fine
the difference between the index and
finally is one the index shows raised
exception
if if the the thing you're looking for
does not exist in the list in october
but 5
would return minus 1 if it doesn't exist
and then index only
we can use the index method in for the
tuple but
we can't use the
uh find the method in the tube okay
that's one another difference okay
so
for we can implement the second one
right first of all we
we need to find out the first letter we
need to find out the first step okay
define let's say constructive
constructed reward we have constructed
word
and we have
we have a rules yeah we have a loose
so let's say
let's say we want to find out look we
will not have a little theta d theta
equals a set right
then we can do this for
do
in
lose okay
let's say the loose is like that e to i
e to r let
let's put it in a string okay into r
let's say e
e
bigger than r right that means the i is
next to e so we we first of all a b
equals
rule
does breaks
what's really mean split by this one
by the bigger equal so a is e b
okay
and now what we do
first of all we put all the letters in a
set right let's say data
dot at
this is a hashtag hashtag it will put a
in and then we also put a b in right we
also put a b in right
now the a
finally the data will contain what we
have is a set yeah it's a set of what
e
r
i
c okay
all right this this is the data set and
then now we need to go through the date
the rule again let's go through the loop
again and then let's take it what went
on okay
take one out at a time this is the same
a b equals do
the split this is the same okay
theta dot remover we want to remove this
one look
e to r
r to i
i to c
okay so we want to remove which one
theta doesn't move up
so we we have theta which is eic right
eic we already know eic in the data
there are four characters
and then now we go through the rule
again we want to remove
which key arrows
now we want to remove these or these
from the data so that we can get the
first characters
uh
we need to remove
this yes though we don't remove the b
yeah okay
look
with the move b yeah
and now the first letter is what the
current letter is first letter is one
this is a data it's a list and we
convert it to this
you contain only one characters because
we don't have duplicate numbers we only
have
uh unique numbers and then well the
first character the first depiction
there is only one element so ci cui is
the
is the first character and then we we
have we stole this answer here answer
equals this
uh answer it was cur because this is
first i know what we do
wire
c u r
okay so we we also need the mapping yeah
we also need to making from a to b yeah
so let's say the mapping and
this is a dictionary yeah i know we do
what
m a
equals b so we know
the next character of a is b okay so we
use a decision array look okay then we
look we current why this is current is
still in
in in mapping yeah look look
the last letter
the last letter does not have mapping
yeah because look e-i-c e-i-c
a c doesn't have a next letter right
every other letter has the next letter
the
m e equals r m r equals i m i equals c
so why we still not in the left next
letter for i
no no no no c doesn't have any letter
look it's from a to c c doesn't have
gold
if c goes nowhere okay so for current i
y r current in m means that we are not
reaching the last letter then we build
it we we need to answer
plus equal m current right
and then what current equals m current
right so we are moving to the next one
and return answer
okay
you see
so the time complexity
we're going through the rules
one time two times still linear yeah
and then we'll go through the letters so
the time complexity will be o n right
because look ladies oh n is the number
of characters in the original in the
original world okay
yeah
okay yeah yeah sure
so look we're using a set yeah so data
first of all we put all the characters
in in there well this is this is called
characters in which you have eic and the
second second pass
we are removing the
the next yeah the next characters from
the set so
we remove r i c then i c so
what do we have left is e which is the
the first character now we start
building research in the character yeah
when we are not reaching the end of
character when the mapping
look and be sufficient area dictionary
m a equals b so we can use the key to
look for the next characters and then we
build it
and current is the next characters
and i'm removing the current variations
look if r i'm coming
and i put the answer
i add this append this r to the answer
which is for example i and then i move
it to the next one which is i and i move
it to the next one i'll build it and the
wrong way
yeah let's return the answer
so we are using a set we can also using
the
what
mapping the dictionary yeah dictionary
remember the default uh decision area
from
from corrections input dictionaries and
we can do what we can theta
if it's additional we can tell the data
a
plus equals one and theta
b minus equals one okay so what does
this mean look let's take
this example eic for example okay and
then you know what i'm talking about
theta okay
theta a plus equals one so look e i c f
e i c
e r i
c
data we have these keys this is the keys
key and the value
so look
e to r so e will plus one r minus one
okay r to i
always plus one
i o minus one
i to c
i will plus one
c u n minus one okay so what do we have
all the intermediate characters yeah the
other intermediaries
they will be zero right yeah the first
letter
will be one this last letter will be
minus one right
so we just have to look through these
keys
we just have to loosen the keys
and find out the value which is bigger
than zero okay and we in this way in
this case we can find the first
character the last letter is my
negative yeah okay
makes sense
yeah and then
and then in this case we don't need to
go through the
these second iterations to remove it we
can only just go through one the rules
once right but still we still have to
keep this mapping you know we can we
need to keep the mapping and
like i needs to be equal to c right
right
so the key that this key will be the
current character and then the value
will be its next character right next
characters
make sense
okay can you can you tell me i mean
what's your approach you don't have to
write a quote but you need to tell me
okay i'll give you an example and you
tell me what why okay let's let's see
i'm trying to think of another one okay
i'm trying to think about it you need to
tell me
what it is
okay
let's see
[Music]
okay i need to think about it okay wait
uh
you
[Music]
it doesn't show what i connect to and it
doesn't show what r connects to i i
okay okay
so remember first of all we need to
finally find the first letter yeah
swisher
uh
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
all right yeah and and
yeah
yeah okay good job so can you tell me
what you why you how do you find an s in
the first place
why how do you know this is the first
first one i'm gonna do one
because because we because that's the
first one
okay okay
okay you don't have to stop i mean
remember we talk about going slowly yeah
at least
we don't have any loose that come that
goes to s
yeah you see
yeah this column doesn't have any
letters with s what does it mean so it
means s is the first one okay makes
sense
yeah is how you spell switzerland i i
don't know this
i don't know maybe
it doesn't look like it spelled
correctly okay unless we
i don't know or maybe there's a tea
okay that's it for today good job good
job
bye