and now today
we're going to talk about chess hello
eric
hello ryan you should say what
hello teacher hello teacher okay so
today we're going to talk about an
interesting problem chess problem and
we're going to use
challenge your brain yeah yeah yeah and
we're going to
use um dfs search remember we
we talked about deaf research before to
solve
to solve this problem oh it's just there
yeah
yeah i know come on dfs
it stands for what death
first search yeah
death but that first you
and we're going to apply some uh
interesting techniques to speed up the
searches
and then if we we combine with the
branches to speed up yeah speed up
branches
uh branches cut off
and then you become a backtracking
aggregator so basically this is
backtracking
backtracking yeah yes okay so now okay
this is concept okay so this is
the problem is very simple so you you
know you know the chest yeah
yeah chest the size is eight times a
yeah eight times a square so you have
64 places to place right
um so a squares okay
i'm drawing the squares just roughly
okay
roughly how many squares are there
two four six or more two
four six this is your square
okay are they lovely okay it doesn't
have to be necessary let's go but
i'm saying now it's eight times a yeah
so if i place the queen
you know queen queen q or that queen
i i i want you to place eight
queens eight queens
on this ball so let no
queens no any two queens are attacking
each other so what what i mean by
attacking is that
it can't be on the same row same column
and same type diagonals yeah
yeah so these as well okay so when i
place the queen here
i can't place i can place
okay i probably need to use the red line
okay then
you can put it here or here yeah look at
this this line you can't place you can
place
you can place here you can place your
tangles okay
yeah you can play yeah yeah and i want
you to play
once i put it here then you can play
here
here you see you see what i mean yeah
okay so let's think about this problem
first okay it's eight queens we are
playing planes in equine
and think how many solutions we can
place on the queens on the top
and how about if i make it a little bit
simpler so
let's say you you can play on the
diagonals but not the
same columns some rows same columns and
some nodes
so how many solutions
okay maybe yeah maybe try this uh
uh four by four three by three
okay three by three okay so three by
three queens three queens i want to
place three kings there
so that the loose is simpler that's even
harder yeah
sorry that's even harder no no no
frequency is easier
so because if you put it in the middle
you can't fit anywhere else no no no no
no what i mean is now we only can
considering the rule number one is you
can't place the
queen on the same line horizontal line
or vertical line it's okay to play on
the diagonals
so i want to play three queens there
easy
this one this one this one okay
[Music]
so how many solutions are there
how many four
no no not correct ryan what's your
answer
how many i only play three queens there
and i can play on
i can't play on the uh on the same line
or some
vertical line but i can play on the same
diagonals
diagonally how to pronounce this
three diagonal three three no
no look
no no no no one no of course not
more than one okay look i put it here
yeah yeah
then i can play these here and here yeah
that's one solution yeah
am right yeah okay how about i play
here and then i play five
no no no no i play here and then i play
here and then
i place here yeah that's two right
oh yeah okay and how about seven
oh they're all over all six do you know
how it's very easy to
to think about it so we want to we want
to
we want to play play three queens three
queens yeah now how many columns can we
place
three yeah yeah so if i place the the
first queen here
the second queen here the third queen
here will be simpler right
yeah so how many if i place the in the
first row
if i make a decision here how many
how many when i place the second coin
how many
four no when how many solutions i can
play for the
followers how many places can i place
if i place the first queen
two yes two look i pick one position
here then i have little two more
yeah so i pick one and then what's the
next the only one solution there yeah
so that the answer is three times two
right three
two one okay so same for this eight
queens it will be
a times the first first column i have
a personal position and after i pick the
first one what's the next
the second yeah and what's the third one
uh six and what's the fourth one five
four three two one so what's this what's
this number
a factor right yeah let's only apply
this not the horizontal and not the
vertical right
so you can have a factorial and if i
want to place the end queens on
on the n times and bar
how many solutions uh
but you can still place on the diagonal
yeah okay
but if we want to consider the entire
note then
we can use the mathematics solutions to
to calculate
so how can we do this this is this is
more interesting yeah do you get it
do you get it now because i mean it's
great they are then
a square rooted than a factorial
um no okay oh
that was a perfect idea yeah it's a good
idea
it's a good idea but it's not perfect
enough oh okay
and then i need any sauce any sauce
count how many are they right
then factor it no no no no
[Music]
why this is it's not very time it
up all up to
its number this is
okay so now yeah very interesting idea
okay so
actually we asked computer how to try
how do we try it
so how do you try if the same look how
about we
first of all we we make sure that and
each queen eight queens
okay the first queen only stays here the
first column
the second queen second column third
queen third column
so in this case these eight queens
cannot be the same column right
yeah okay so how about if i place the
one queen first queen here
yeah then i want to place the second
queen yeah
yeah so the second queen here yeah can i
play it here
now right because it's uh i checked
previous one the first one
is on the attack right can i place here
yes
no no no yeah oh then
then can i place it here yes okay okay
then i try the third queen yeah because
i can play place then i play plays on
the second one
look now the third queen uh this is the
second way now i want to try the third
queen
can i place here no because of attack
can i place here
no can i place here no can i place here
can i play here yes yes okay then i
what's what happened i want to try the
fourth king yeah
[Music]
yes yes okay and then the fake skin do
you see it
yeah okay so now when we reach the end
then we know that's the solution yeah
yeah and then now you will go back go
back and you would
because look when one placing the second
queen
this is the first of second grade and i
can play second queen here yeah
and then try solution again don't get it
do you have this rough idea
i i place one queen and then
can i need to check is it valid if i
read it i place here then i try next
screen
right if it's not ready i move to the
next position which is the next yeah
yeah okay so now we do the coating it
should be easy
why not do it yeah you take it off sorry
we need to take it off what i need to
take it oh
click it
what ticket pick it up take it all
what do you mean ticket over left oh
take it
okay look look look
look come on
look listen defy
let's defy a queen decline a queen
and then we take it uh n parameter which
is like
n times n solution and we want to place
n queens how many solutions are there
right
two so then now this is we need to have
a return this return
it turns out now we want to search it
dfs and we take the current solution
current solution and we have take an end
queen okay
now we need to define this define this
uh
define this c you are see you are
current current solution or maybe
uh let's say uh in the current solution
now we need to define this the df as
this
most important search now this is
current solution
and we want to place the aqueous end
queens yeah
right yes now current solution is the
number of rows so if
for example if it's empty it means that
we haven't placed any
queens yet and if it's like zero it
means i want to place the
only i only place one queen so far yeah
which is on the first first zero yeah
this is zero this is one okay so i'm
going to check this
yeah it's okay okay no
no so look
uh wow so look look listen
so now if i have this zero
zero zero and maybe this two
okay so what does it mean zero two it
means that uh
i have placed two queens the first one
in the one
um what does it mean
this is the first queen yeah yeah this
is the second queen
the first queen is from zero so this is
yellow
this is one zero okay two
is what this is yellow one two two is
here do we get it
where's one i can't place on the one
because one and zero will be diagonal
attack yeah okay so that's what it means
okay now
we have a current now we have current
right
so we have to check if right right look
if car if the length of the current
we need to be just is n what does it
mean
if we we already placed n queens what do
you mean we found a solution right yes
then we need to return one yeah return
this now
the answer is one yeah okay yeah because
we already placed that
yeah now now we need to check what
four we have this answer yeah answer
equals zero it's
gonna take forever no no no come on
listen it's very interesting now
look for for now i want to place the row
row
in in range and yeah range n
i can have n so n places for the row
yeah from from zero one to n plus i
minus one right
yes i know i need to check
if i can place it if i can place you can
place
if i can place the cup with the current
solution
and then then row answer plus
equals no no no look if can
i place i can place the next queen as a
row
yes with the current solution then i can
need to
edit x plus equals dfs
right t f s current
one current plus the row
right and with the n
right and then i just need to return
answer
the time queen do you get it this is
definite recursion that first search
yeah because look i can place look look
with current solution i can i want to
place the next queen
in a row yeah row is wrong i can how
many possible solutions i can have from
0 to n
but i need to check if i can place place
on this location if it then
place then i can place on the next slope
and next screen yeah
when i place here then i can place next
one okay
do you get it yes okay now
what's missing here what's missing here
this is complex we haven't implemented
yet
yeah yeah so now we just need to
implement the complaints
okay you need a print but that's
x current is the current solution and
x is the new new position
in yeah look at my nose okay
so look uh for i
y in
right denominator okay what's this what
enumerate i will talk about it
okay
if y equals equals x yeah because
what does it mean it means
[Music]
current minus i equals
abs abs x g of plus y
and minus one and then we do ten fourths
abs
right then as
okay so abs absolute value
so let's see what's the abs that abs
from here
okay abs three
equals three abs minus three
equals three can you get the meaning
what does abs mean so abs is absolute
value so
meaning that look this is the number
yeah this is zero here right
one two three four five times
[Music]
so this number abx x is the distance
between x and zero okay
so what does it mean is the distance
so if it's the positive number abx
x equals x if x equals bigger than zero
right
yeah if it's smaller than zero what does
it mean abs
x equals minus x right look
minus three how many units distance
three
three okay so abs is like that abs
minus two thousand equals one two
thousand
abs um one million one million
abs minus ten trillion
yeah you got it yeah okay okay so now
look this is these we know right
we this is to check we can't place the
the queen on the previous row right yeah
if i
if i place the first queen on the two i
can't place the current king in the two
right and this is to check the diagonals
so look what how do you calculate that
look like if the first one is two
the second one the first one is two
second one
is three it comes right because the tip
the horizontal difference is is what
is length current minus
i i i will talk about it later it's from
zero to one two three four to
n and then what did i talk about
the behavior on the lessons would be
good okay
and then this abs x minus one is just
the value
yeah if you if you place three minus two
values
it's the value uh this is a bit
tricky okay look i'm gonna write it
again
wow
again and again
look current okay u
equals the 1 three five
seven nine four okay okay if this is
current yeah
so what does it mean by if i do this for
i y in
current so what does it do when if i
point
if i print i and y what what can we get
look at this one three
five two four and then here this is the
y value y value will be one three five
two four yeah one three five two four
this is the y value yeah
yeah i value will be what i value will
be
zero one two three four easy it just
give a number from zero
right why we don't need to do that i
now we need to we can know which column
is it
right yes this will be column i i
if i can rename it as column column y
column okay so now we just need to check
so now look look one three five two four
okay let's see
why five sorry five by five
that's okay how about you for just one
three one three here
one two three yeah now
i want to check if the diagonal right if
i place here
i place here this is zero right that's
fine
that's fine look what is right i need to
check now it will be
0 1 and 1 3 yeah 1 3 and then i need to
check if
0 plus 0 minus 1 abs
is it equals to is equals to what
is it equals to zero and what is equals
to
this is second this is zero so this
two minus zero it's not equal right
right it's not equal if it's equal what
does it mean
if it's equal if i put it here zero one
two three yeah yeah
it because the first one and the third
one
is on the diagonal so what can we get
three minus one
the value minus it yeah the value
yeah is two but now
this is the second column this is the
yellow column
two minus zero equals two y so so look
yeah it's equal it means that we cannot
place
do you get it yeah this is basically how
we check these basically we check
these distance this distance
and the least distance yeah
if this distance equals this descent
what does it mean
if it's if it is if this is the square
if this is a square it means it's on the
diagonal right
yeah basically we're just checking that
okay so if you run this solution
you can find out the total number of
solutions to place
on the a times a
queen with a queens yeah eight times a
ball
chess ball with the a queen is 92.
got it okay do you get it
so let the answer the the process how do
we do it so place the first screen
we if we can place on the first screen
we try the next screen
yeah if we can try next screen we try
next swing again
and until we get we place the whole end
queens
and after that after that we added
the answer we found the solution right
because this is recursion yeah because
you so you
keep trying the the first screen i put
the first one second one third one until
eighth one
and when i search all of these solutions
then i don't have any other
more places to uh to pull the queens
right okay so
good job today say bye bye ryan
bye ryan you want to say bye