what's the
binary
[Music]
okay so but
in order to be a binary search tree he
literally does it
so we haven't the left it needs to be
smaller
yeah
than the root
and the right needs to be bigger
and the reach
so this is the virus here violent the
left nose are strictly smaller than the
parents
yeah the right nose are strictly bigger
than their parents okay so there's no
duplicate numbers
okay so if i put look
i tell you okay if this number is six is
this still a final 33 yeah
yeah yeah it is no no it's not because 6
is
bigger than five it should be on the
right right tree you see now that's why
i say street is smaller so
yeah why is that because if it's uh oh
yeah yeah yeah
so what in what order eric can you sit
down but what order
you know in order to traverse the tree
it gives
pre-order yeah
is it free
in order so you know that was another
order left in order
where them left
right
so you visit the left first
okay so say that a famous quote again if
you visit the tree
in order
in order we know that you'll be in order
yeah yeah wow
get it okay
in order so you visit the left tree
first so that's two
and what's next four
two in order three three
four
five
seven eight nine nine
okay seven eight nine okay
okay so what's the third third
what's the third smallest number
the first volume uh four
four okay so today's task very easy
given about research tree and the k we
also try to find the k
k smallest number and you just using
okay we just ordered this and just just
find the third one what's yeah okay one
way would be we we first of all perform
the in order
yeah and then we get we get the numbers
and we put in an array and then we can
just you know
retrieve the case
the case one right yeah
make sense yeah let's buy this
and then think about a time and space
complexity which i'm going to ask you
okay don't guess a one or one okay
okay smallest
another root
so usually we can put this in the data
we put in the data and then we could do
this data search define
yeah define
that was the truth okay first of all we
first want to check what this is very
simple yeah very template if not load we
just return right if not rule just
return
and then whatever nothing i know what we
do we first of all
we
already
first of all the pre-order what's
pre-order we visit the left tree first
right
[Music]
sorry dfs
left yeah and then we visit the note
which you put it in the data
[Music]
okay so that is visiting the right
okay so this this uh yeah yeah this data
is is defined here so we have to
put a long local keyword just to make uh
just to
uh tell it that it's not defined locally
it's it's it's it's outside this
function non-local data
and once we do this data search
root then we can we have this we have
populated the data right then we can
return
theta
k minus one yeah because its style is
one at first if you give a one then the
index will be zero
okay so this is one way of doing this
application the
inorder okay so we don't actually need
to this yeah we don't actually need we
can make it a bit
pretty you know to make it it's the same
but we make it a pretty so we do this
okay so we can just do this
if not is not root
if not root we just return return empty
this
and okay yeah this is look empty empty
this empty yeah otherwise we just
written one
return from search
rule left
read the right no no no plus we because
we want to press together plus
do the value yeah i kind of know yeah
and plus can you guess read or write dfs
do the right yeah
you see and then
we just do this one data
equals definite search
root
and then written data yeah look this is
prettier right because we don't declare
any variables outside this function and
it's it's quite clean look
this function will return a list of the
values
and you know we want to do this in order
so if it's if the root is empty we just
written empty this all right so we just
return we have we return the left left
tree yeah we don't know we recursively
call it and then we append the current
node or value right all right
yeah and then we do this root of right
right
uh and i want to do that what's the type
of space complexity anyone
anyone the time complexity is
if there are unknowns in the past
yeah wear them clothes
you know i feel i should give you this
uh
sticker there for answering the
questions yeah but we don't have
anything okay so i i asked mommy to buy
some okay
what's the space complexity
[Music]
so
do we actually need to visit
orlando ordinary right look because we
are interested in the case
right if we travel if we iterated the
traveler tree in order and after we
reach the cave
do we have to care about the rest
no right we don't have right all right
so what does this mean look let's write
this again
okay so let's say 9
11 12 you know keep going yeah keep
going to your a minion okay
okay that's what i mean this is really
extreme cases we want to find out
that'll take forever no no in this one
you'll close on because there are notes
in the chip but look
if i want you to fight tell me what's
the small what's the first smallest
number
four okay
we can go through here do we have to
visit all the others
that's right because we already know
it's here so why do we need to keep
visiting of all this
what was k
k is one if k is one the smallest yeah
case
k is two means the second smallest okay
so what's the second smallest in this
spanish
five is active you see so how do we do
this
iteratively we want to iterate with
during this in order
right
so first of all
we can have a sec we can what's the step
say stacking stack
first thing that's all yeah first thing
so look at yeah stack
stack yeah stack it goes in this way and
you take out this way yeah this is there
okay so look
we are here we're 7 27 here
we go left as long as we can okay look
look yeah five
four
yeah we can't go to the left right
yeah then we take one out
we take one out when we do we
we reduce this k
is k right if k equals zero then that's
the value we're looking for if not
if you know what
if not what
[Music]
if you know what
so we if we take this out if not then we
go
we we
we
take take one out and we we then we go
to it's right okay we go so it's right
look so we take a four if there's not
right there's no right right there's no
right or four so we don't do it we don't
we keep we keep taking another one which
is five
which is five
now we take a five out
we take a five out and we go to each
right right look because why
because look we go as far as and as left
as we can
and we in the reverse order
in the reverse order
you'll feel a value that's smallest
right
look
okay if there is no four here what's the
smallest number here
uh
[Music]
sorry look we go to the left as as long
as we can and we take it out this is the
smallest number right yeah if there's
four here
then that's the smallest if there are
three here that's the smallest right so
the smallest number is always on the
left right so we go to the left as deep
as as left as we want
we can right when we can't go to the
left we take one out
we can take one out yeah because we take
our line we need to decrement okay if
this is zero that's the number we're
looking for and then we go to each right
right look this is four five yeah we
take 5 out and we need to go to his
right why is that because the right is
bigger than the
camera number it's the next
biggest number which is bigger than the
next bigger number right less bigger
number than five right
yeah and after we we find that k equals
the value then we just return it and we
don't need to traverse all the
next right
right okay
makes sense
okay um let me write it down and then
you probably will understand more okay
so this is a bit tricky but
you know but but it's uh it has a better
performance than the first one the first
approach is very simple yes
straightforward
okay and you both know how to do it the
term complexity is aware right
no matter the no matter the k value is
we still have to traverse all the nodes
in the binary search tree right but for
this second approach we just need to
travel a k
element yeah if k is two one two three
small we don't need to travel the whole
binary search tree right
okay so first of all we have a step how
do we implement a stack
remember we use the what kind of data
structure we use to implement that
sorry
recursion okay no no no stay which one
tell me
which
[Music]
don't change it yeah yeah we don't
change it yeah we immutable this oh it's
we can call it function yeah caller
function
call function parameters okay so we use
the list
okay now why
why loot you know root or the stack is
not is is not empty then what the y
root then we
we keep visiting the left yeah so we put
in the stack we put the root
we put a loop on the left
yeah
and then loot equals to the left right
we keep visiting the left until we come
until we come so look
seven five
four
six
and
uh let's say six okay
yeah
so look we we push this into the stack
so we push the seven here push the five
as long as we can visit it and if not
if not what we take right now pick one
up instead
do
equal how do we take one hour from the
stack
how do we take one out from the stack
what's the message
pop pop yeah pop what does the problem
mean
take away
in english what does it mean
it means it's like a bubble exploding oh
yeah yeah
balloon yeah pop yeah popping okay
exploding
so technically this is popping uh yeah
this is seven
and there was five
[Music]
so look we take one element from the
stack which is the next smallest number
so what do we do with the k remember k
what k equals
k one okay we need to look we take one
out we need to take the k
kind of pop that k k is the number we
what do we do with the k we take one
number out
we already know that number which is a
pen
k is a number
remember so look
we already found the next smallest
number then we take it out so k is the
number we want to make it reduce to zero
so what do we do is okay k equals zero
right okay
minus equal
one one we take one all right and now we
need to check if k equals zero if k
equals zero what does mean that's the
number we want to find so we return to
the value yeah
okay so look we take one now five out
and then what should we do what's the
what's the biggest number then five
the smallest number biggest than five
six so where is it that where is it
right
i said
okay so what's the time complexity
so if it's that long what one is that
long
what's the terminology guess okay
[Music]
k is one of them because we have to
reduce it to k right yeah this is
certainly okay k is there right okay but
at the beginning k plus one
if it's one constant we don't put it you
know when we talk about complexity we
ignore the constant you know 100 200
yeah we don't we don't
do that because okay plus 100
is the same as okay okay
[Music]
make sense okay so look
what's this part let's look what's this
one we're traveling the left yeah
we we need to travel in the left as deep
as we can right so that is if this
spinal tree is balanced yeah it's
balanced right that is o
plus
k power h yeah h in the balance one
would be
log n right there and no in the worst
case it would be n what's in the worst
case can you guess
what's what's the word
yeah well done so it's in the worst case
it's like that yeah it's like that
yeah and then you want to find for
example a minion a minion
yeah a minion that's a 100 a minion
minus one a minimum infinity yeah and
then i want to find a mean a minus one
one you have to push this a million
times and then you have to go back at
least yeah go back so this is really a
worst case right but in a balanced case
in the best case easy actually it would
be
a full binary a balance of a four yeah
so every node would be
you know
a four yeah so that the nodes would be
the the the h height would be log n
right
okay n is the number of nodes okay
make sense we're done eric that's very
well done okay this is the extreme cases
because the remember the binary tree if
it integrated into a
linked list
then there's no point of using binary
because binary you know
why is it useful why is it useful
because sometimes you can go to the left
and then not care about the right or you
go to the right not care about that then
it gives you the performance boost by
by what by ignoring the other half
that's why we have log n right we have
log n half when you see a lot it's half
half half remember the binary search
binary search i have a number in my mind
you guess
between 0 to 100
and
uh you make a guess almost always
guessed in the meter right if
if you guess 50 and my number is 40 i
say it's smaller then
yeah you know it's between 0 to 50 not
between 50 to
100 right look you already abandoned
half
you see every time that that man
oh it's halfway so it takes time so it's
faster faster to look out if
if you okay so i have a number in my
mind
and if you're not having it you always
make a guess from zero one two three in
the worst case how many times you need
to i went
a hundred times right got it but with
the final research
i log in we're done okay
okay so
that's it for today good job yes good
job say bye to people
bye bye bye bye bye bye