[Music]
a triple roman
it could be a final research final tree
or it could be a tree you know with
multiple kids right so let's say three
ninety-nine kids one yeah yeah yeah
five ten
okay
there's only two yeah
but it could be money yeah it could be
that many like i said it could be many
seven and it could be something like
that
and you'll be
uh you know
some it could be many
many many
so let's say if i want to take the five
out and the question is that when you
take the five you need to take all the
notes
uh
yeah good question okay so you have hey
i said
so these notes are unique
so if i want to take the 5 out you need
to tell me how many notes we need to
take it out if
if you're taking the 5 out you need to
take every single note every note in
itself
only child okay so
so
oh children yeah so you need to tell me
it's five and ten okay right five if i
take the fight off take the fight off
let's say kill it okay if i want to
you need to tell me kill it
you need to tell me come on come on okay
5 10. i'm killing it okay
hey five ten or you can return 10
seconds only if i want to take a seven
hour so you need to
[Music]
uh so
but the thing is that you are given the
fine of the tree you know because it
might not be the binary tree you're
given a tree like that you're giving me
for example this tree could be given
these notes as three
one five
seven
ten
four nine eleven right
this is
you're doing it by breakfast
yeah okay wait wait
yeah yeah we're done okay so now look
what's the parent of them if the note is
a root which does not have any parent we
give it the experience yellow okay
that's the zero is especially very means
that look at the
root of three the pattern of three is
zero
right yeah we're gonna kill it okay so
the parent of one is what
parent of one is three
five
three the seventh three ten five
four seven seven seven we're done so you
get it
look with these two information the node
and their parents okay because we only
have distinct numbers yeah we only have
unique numbers
so we need to if this is
what can we do about it what can we do
about it
zero plus three
duplicate it two times uh last two three
five
yeah
okay
so we also take for example we want to
take the five out so what's your
approach
first we want to take a five hour so
what's your approach
so look we can go through this this uh
we can go through this at least yeah
right look we can go through this list
and check which parents
which parents is five
right which parent is five
whose parent is five ten right
ten
look we have to take this out yeah we
want to take this off
okay look at listen we want to take this
out so we go through this
array yeah
to check we go uh we go through this
away to check which which uh which
parent is
five
please look at this one
yeah which one is the time
10 yeah we're here we find here right
and then 10 that's not 10 then it will
be here and then we go
okay and then 10 will be taken right 10
will be taken and
but we also need to take that any note
right yeah suppose there are many many
notes here right so we then we need to
because we call this function to take
the note whose parent is 10 right
nobody's parents can
good question if that nobody's parents
is turned then we just stop right for
example that these knows
leave now there are no parents
yeah these notes
terminal notes we also call it terminal
stuff
because there were no parents
that the these no does not have any kids
okay so in other words no
no no parents is that this note okay
yes make sense so that's a very
straightforward idea
right we want to take the 5r so with
those who list the array to find out
whose parent is this note and then we
add it to the to the answer and now we
recursively recalling
calling the function with the
the id who's whose parent is that right
correct so in this case we
we can we can we compare the answer
right so
so let's try this this is called proof
of proofing
but but it's not very efficient right
why is that because every time we need
to go slowly away to find out
whose parent
is like
who's now whose parent is that right and
we can the other way think about it how
can we speed up this query so basically
we want to find out whose kids so what
what are we doing there we want to find
out whose parent is that the the note
right
look
before we have we know that note
we have given a note we we can know
whose parent is there right because it
only has one parent that's one to one
a man into one yeah so a note
can have only one parent right
we want to find out who's
who's no we want to find out which we go
through this note we want to find out
you know this is n and one
and two could be n3 they are all point
their parents or yeah right we will go
through this array
to find out whose parent is p right
right this is not very efficient every
time we need to go through that again
and again again right so if for example
if a note is like that one two
three four right
yeah we're going to go we want to find
out one right yeah killer one right
yeah but first of all we need to go
through that four notes again
to find out whose parent immediate
parents one right okay i'm gonna find
out too right
okay then i need to go through the list
again to find out whose parent is two
right so i need to
do that again
and then i need to find three yeah four
three and i need to go through the list
again to find out whose parent
is is three years
four plus four yeah you see plus four
percent
what but why but if why do we need to
plus four
i mean no no what i mean is that that's
one note no because because um because
even this
and why is like
like why is like two always having three
always at the end and then like four is
always that we end because
one two three four yeah one two three
four yeah another note would be zero
one
two three right yeah but like when you
get to two it's not overlapping
plus three
i don't get your question
because like uh
three
three four
plus four you need to plus three
but but the thing is yeah okay okay
that's very good observation yeah but we
are talking about uh
complexities okay so so in this case
yeah you're right you it could be m plus
n minus one plus minus two y
and plus n minus two yeah because we
already found it right yeah yeah
yeah but this is still
this is still you know
that that could be n time yeah that
could be and no if there are unknowns
and then you need to do this
n times yeah
plus
and what's the time complexity for this
m plus 1 n plus 1 times
times n divided by two so that's o n
squared right
yeah let's open square that's the terms
of x t okay
okay so so should we write this first
and then think about it how can we speed
up because all we want to do is find out
the list of notes whose pattern is p and
how can we do this opposite
look can we do this opposite
huh
can we do this opposite
so if we do the opposite list that will
be one
all right
[Music]
no
now we are given the data structure
pointing the nodes
yeah p to the now there p to the nodes
will be n one and we can if we can do
this
if we can have this kind of data
structure we can easily do uh traversing
the tree right what kind of algorithm
can you have a sigma tree come on this
is the easy answer for you
so let's let's do this one by one okay
first of all through something
definite search and process search okay
define that let's just say here okay
here and then we have two numbers
numbers current and the number to key
okay okay
okay
so
first of all we need to do what we need
to go through like the answer would be
okay so if k equals
okay and then we need to do one for
in range we need to go through this
right
here
[Music]
ryan you got a question
no
if if p
question if p i so this is the very
parent if parent equals the k current k
to take take away right
then i need to answer
i need to answer plus here
and that will be n p but now i would
need to take that thing which is what
p
[Music]
n i and i
i learned with an answer no p
okay
so this is the profession oh look if k
equals zero that means that that's the
you know
that's the do not the root okay
if k equals zero we determine because
the the zero does not exist
now
obviously we need to
take the kr right to kill the k
right and then we go through this array
we go through this parent array and if
the parent equals the
thing
if the parent equals the thing to take
off
right and i need to take out what i need
to
recursively taking out
the note so what does it mean look
that's one two
three
four right so i want to take the one out
right
and then the answer equals okay all
now so answer i have the at least one
and i need to go through the element to
find out whose parent is one
yeah whose parent is the one here
two and five why
you just grew five yeah i know two and
five so what so look at this pattern two
and size pattern is k
this one so i need to recursively call
this function so take
the note taking the note two and five
out
right
and it's a plus two answer and then i i
return the answer
okay so that time connection that we
discussed
so look if we build this function so
look
look we we have n to p right so we want
to peel p to n p to n so what kind of
data structure can we use to to be an
apparent to the kids
what kind of data structure
the the thingy
you know
yeah the notebook okay so look let's say
cheer try children okay children igor
before
dictionary
and then because the king is the parent
that the what's the type of the kid
a parent can have many many kids right
so it could be at list right
at least yeah
so now i need to go through the
parents okay so let's this one look the
the the triumph
the triad the parents okay in what's
cheap function remember
mp what's deep what's
what's chip remember we talk about a
chip
what's chip
zip is what chip yeah
right so i typically n ends here p is
here i don't have this look at the look
of c
look at n array in the kite come on
look
amazing look at me n and p stick it
together so now c and n will take one
each other so right yeah
so look
and then i need to do what children
children parents right this is parent
right
not a pen
[Music]
i take one element from the notes and
then take one element from the p c and p
from n piece right
okay
so in this case then i can build a
parent to the kids array right the key
is the parent the kit is the
value is the list of the children that
right
am i right
i know with this stair structure i can
just easily do the differences easy okay
yeah i'll do this step define
define
that first search
so let's say the loot
right i know what look
answer at the beginning equals to the
load yeah
but yeah i want to take the loop down of
course the answer has to include the
rules okay yeah and then now i just need
to go through its kid it's a kid what's
the what's the i just need to go to the
kid of the lord right for i
in
children yeah we have these children
yeah children
dude
i know
what what do we do answer plus equal
for search i
and i return you see how easy is that
okay
make sense take a look
we're done cash okay just retain first
of all then we can need to return we can
return dfs to
key all right yeah okay you talk about
cash that's a very good point but
actually it doesn't have much why is
that look i want to keep here one two
three
four
five
six right if i only kill one right
i'm going downwards so i need to go
through two three i just want to release
right
if i kill i catch this doesn't help
because i don't need to visit it again
right
am right just checking if you're correct
do you understand what i'm talking look
why
why when is the cache user because look
if i want to kill one
if i later i want to call this q1 okay
but not for now i don't need to call it
again because look i want to kill one
again and then now i can find from this
standard structure i can find two and
three right so then i need to kill two
and kill three right from ko3 i need to
get kill four and kills here and from
there i'll kill six and kill five right
take six k5 so look for each each
function
for each load i only call one so i don't
need to put a cache
it doesn't help right
but look this is the difference to
understand with this this data structure
am i all right make sense
answer dot
dfs i look at this the return is the
list yeah okay look
listen to me the return this plus equal
is to extend it you can also do this
answer.extend is the same thing yeah
it's ten
what does it mean look if this is one
one plus
two three look this one look a list of
one
plus two three that will become a list
of one two three if this this is a you
can say a dot is ten two three another
list and it still will become this
it's the same okay make sense
okay with this they have solution we can
always use uh preferences okay i'm going
to easily write this okay so what kind
of data uh how can we implement a
preferred search remember we we need to
use uh
we need to use a data structure which is
called what
you know usually type of search is done
is implemented by the recursion
application of the stack
first thing that's all right
and what's the opposite
we need to do the process search
what's the data structure that is not
step
firstly
first thing first now okay that's what i
add
so look let's say 3 2
twelve
thirteen
five
six
seven okay so let's say i want to take a
one out what's the first one search
one
so look one you put one in right
you take the one out and you put it push
it to it alright sit down otherwise
people don't see it
you take one out you push the kids which
is 10 11 12.
in here all right push the baby okay and
then now i take all the kids up
from the queue and i push their kids so
which is thirteen five six seven got it
well kids could have kids
so they were kids
look at this so initiator will be level
by level okay make sense
yeah see there
so look let's say q
equals at the beginning we use the dq i
think you double and dq
and at the beginning we have the k
because that's the thing we are going to
take it out
and the answer would be
of course
with the k right
and then y
q
y y l q or y
length q equals zero it's the same yeah
length skill oh let's get bigger than
zero it's the same why kill then we want
first of all we need to take we can take
one at a time or we can take everything
at the time from throwing q right
we talked about this last lesson yeah
from the cube first search we can take
we can pop pop one at a time or we can
pop everything of the current elements
in the cube right so let's say we want
to take all the elements so t equals
length skill
and then now i need to take everything
out of q for in range
range t
and then i i want to take it out so
which is what current equals
equals what equals q so how can i take
it out
because the queue you know
the queue when you dq you know we know
when we take an animal out of you we
take it at the front when we put the
thing in the queue we put it at the end
which is what
pop left and open right way down okay
let's see it's taking a while taking it
out right
taking it off right so we take it now
then what do we do
so we take it out what to do then we
need to do a
for
i
in children yeah because we have
children
children see
we chosen here then we do what
we do what
we do q dot append
a plan i right
right so so in this case uh
q dot pen right yes
but we need we uh first of all we need
to take it and uh sorry there's a
problem okay
also
so we take it off we take it out and we
need to put it here
the answer needs to append uh because we
already taken out so we append the c
right
apprentice c and then we apply the i and
we 10 return the q return the answer
right so let's go through this again
answer at the beginning we we have
nothing to uh this is the list to store
the number
to store the notes to take out the kill
okay
yes
well while the queue has still has
element then this is the number of
elements in the cube then we go we need
to pop them out all uh at once okay and
then we take one out the c then we put
in a answer
when we take the cr we need to append
its kids right back to the queue so that
that's what you did for i in children
see
yeah
chosen here we appear here the key value
pairs the key is the parent the value is
the list of the children wrongs okay
then we append the i back into the queue
okay
so what's the time complexity of the
different station professors
if there are n nodes in a in a tree
the preference the blue force is always
square we talk about that because every
time we need to go through that thing to
find out
why is it oh n is good because we may
have to go through the list to find out
whose parents whose
which notes the parents has the parent
of them like the target right so that's
n times and for each node it has there
there and there are unknowns so there
will be n square but for this one we
already built it so we can just follow
this
what's the time to max t comma if i take
this out i just need to visit all these
ones
oh and what does what both are this one
right what's the space complexity
are we using any space
[Music]
bye