we're going to talk about the circle
today yeah
because we know this shape for you know
in real life but the tires of the car
right your pizza a pie or you know
whatever the pan whatever
a cup yeah the shape is very common in
real life okay the ball
yeah the ball okay so before that oh you
like a pen yeah
well that is a cylinder
so now let's review our little uh
some shape yeah
this is
square
and
squared square is a special case of uh
rectangle right because look this is a
all sides are equal a but these
is different right a and b right and
then
if we cut this in half we got a right
triangle right yeah i think that's for
the square not rectangle
if you can't square in half it's a right
hand no no no if kali is because the
square is also part of it's very special
for the for the rectangular one if
current is in half right this is the
thing but if you cut this
it's also uh
okay okay i got the meaning okay
this is different if this is any reason
b
okay so this is the shape we already
know yeah these two actually
we can categorize them as this one shape
one time per share okay
what's that what's the parameter we call
it parameter is the what's perimeter
parameter is how
long all the sizes yeah what's the
parameter of these
other parameter is
it is
a times
four times a full time day and what's
this the
a square b squared ah yeah you remember
the formula yeah
when this is a this is b and this is
right right angle this side is a square
plus b squared square root okay
like if this is three this is four
this is eight what's that what's the
next number
come on think about it quick answer
uh it is like if this one is eight this
one what was the question again
yeah we're done yeah because 36 plus 64
is 100 i don't get it what do you mean
okay
a
b look at this is a this is b and we
know this side is a square plus b square
right and if this is three this is four
this is five if this sixty this a this
is ten okay this is just mathematics
okay
okay so now how about the area what's
the area of this square
what's the area of a square
area of a square is four times a yeah
a times a a a squared and what's the
area of these
uh it is
this is a times b divided by 2
why do we need to divide by 2 divided by
2 will be this one right
right this is a times b right it'll be
like
okay
okay okay okay so now this is the base
diameter
so circle
so that we call this
this parameter
we call that circumference
circumference
circumference okay
okay so let's define a mass constant
mathematic constant i okay yes
pi this is pi it's not the constant
is the circumference
circumference
divided by diameter okay what's diameter
yeah diameter diameter is the longest
longest
longest line
passing through
passing the center yeah
this side this is diameter and then half
of it we call it radius okay probably
okay radius ah so we can say d equals
one
d equals one
d equals how many times of r d equals
how many times
d
ah what's the relation between d and
come r very easy how many us
two yeah two times ah way down come on
come on
what'd you do
okay so this pie you know
we don't have to go into the details but
it's the irrational number irrational
number
every lion this is very complicational
okay so what's the opportunity number
obviously is rational number what's
rational
it's a number that can be expressed as a
fraction simple fraction is p divided by
q where q not equals zero
okay
an irrational number is the opposite it
cannot a number cannot be
expressed as a simple fraction what's
simple fraction like 0.5
yeah
half
one over four a quarter you know p can
be divided can be expressed p divided by
q where q will not equal zero p and q
are integer okay
right iteration number is the opposite
right so this number pi is actually
approximation of
you know approximation equals three
point one four one five
nine two six fifty three fifty eight
okay so it never ends it never ends okay
this is the infinity this is going
infinity but it's a best best
approximation would be something like
three point one four one five
nine okay that that would be enough okay
do you get it
so look this pi equals circumference
divided by the diameter right
yeah
okay so now
look we write this here at pi equals c
divided by d and also
we can say d equals 2i this is very
obvious
okay so now using this
how can we prove that the area of the
triangle of
circle
this is a survivor yeah maybe not it
looks like a stone big big egg okay oh
yeah a pizza oh yeah no orange
side view okay so lead this is we want
to get we want to compute the area of
the
of the circle how can we do this
how can we do this there are a few ways
one one way would be to cutting this
this circle like pizza cutting into
slices yeah yeah
you're cutting lots of slices cutting on
lots of slices and you light it up
right and then you can compute it okay
but today we're going to talk about
another one which is very simple to
understand look
very simple to understand that look we
already know c equals 2 times pi i
because pi d yeah this is the ratio
remember
c divided by
d equals pi right right so c equals pi
times t
equals two times pi r okay that's where
we got it okay make sense
c equals two pi okay
what do we do what's what's that
okay we're done okay good job
okay okay
okay now look if we cut it if we if we
if we have lots of rings right right
lots of rings look at what look at that
where i'm going
yeah pizza if i cut the pizza you know
like that that looks like an onion onion
onion
and then look if i cut it this way
just have a big imagination if i cut it
this way and if i line it up
yeah if i line it up unroll it and draw
it a rainbow
unroll it yeah a rainbow okay so look so
what's the what's the center look at
this center is just you know if i
wrongly it will be little little bit
a little bit
uh
square right and then a little bit more
i don't get it how do you make one
look look just imagine look if if i cut
if i have lots and lots of the thin
ring and then if i cut it this way
remember just imagine a piece i
cut it this way
and then if if i unroll this bit so what
look for follow
the external side for this big big one
what's the length
what what's the length how do you roll
it
how do you roll it do you have someone
talking about
kind
[Music]
look
this is a
circle i cut it and i unroll it like a
row
and roll it it's a rainbow frame
just just just imagine okay and then
look this bit
what's the length of the almost
yeah right
yeah
yeah so look if i keep doing that the
most in the inner one will be just a
very tiny bit right yeah
and it's not
when it goes on and the piece the slices
become a little bit bigger bigger and i
can put it
here by here and here by here
and here right here okay i'm going going
this way okay going this way
and this this is the most
outside like this is the external one
and what's the length of this how long
is this
how long is this
this is a c yeah
the the almost one is the circus uh
circumference right
so this side
is two times pi times r all right
we all know that
yeah if we cut the slices look if we
have this
really really thin
just really releasing you you don't have
this stack right then everything would
be like a triangle right you yeah
and what's the size of this look you can
guess what's the size of this uh how big
is this
how big is this
yeah we cut it this way right
so what's this
what's this what's the half of a
diameter what's that
what's half of diameter
what's that
say
this is diameter what's half
half diameter what's called radius ah
yeah so this is r
okay if we cut the slices so thin
that this is a triangle then you
wouldn't observe the stack right and
what's the area of this triangle
we know no no right
what's the base a
ah times
two pi r
we all we need to do what
divided by triangle remember
and what do we get
pi
r squared
okay so
the area of a circle is pi times r times
r okay
r is the radius half of the diameter
so let's do this again look how how do
we get food transform from these two
here
we have lots of lots of the very
releasing rings and we cut it half half
yeah we cut it here so this is high and
we put it one by one from the
smallest to the biggest one the biggest
one which is the outside and the length
will be just the circumference
circumference right
yeah and the smallest will be close to
zero and you put it this way this will
be a triangle
this we know is r this we know is two pi
r it's a circumference and the area will
be this pi r square
okay
make sense
yeah pi r square
okay so now how can we ask computer to
approximate this value because this
value this this this value yeah this
value is not an exact value this is the
approximation yeah this is the best
constant you know in the lens you know
you never like that
the computer now nowadays are trying
very hard you know if you want to
calculate the median positions meaning
digits of the pi you need a very
powerful computer right and they're
calculating the kick ranking
so
so one way of asking computer to
approximate the value of pi
how can we try this how can we ask
computer to to approximate these pi
values
if i draw
if you try i draw a quarter of pi look
this is the
square this is one one one one
one one if i draw a circle half of a
quarter of the circle yeah can you
imagine yeah it would be something like
that a circle
okay circle yeah you'll be a curve yeah
oh
okay
this the radius of a circle is what
come on there the radio status
one one is one this is zero zero this is
one
okay what's the rate what's the ratio
between you know here the circle
this bit
and the square
one
look we already know that uh
this this is a quarter of circle right
so it's a quarter times pi times r i is
one right
yeah r times r is one and what's this
one
yeah no no no no yeah what's this what's
the area of the square
[Music]
one
yeah
so one common one times one one yeah i
said one so what's the the ratio would
be a quarter of pipe
yeah this is a quarterback
okay a quarter of pi this is the answer
yeah is that one
no no no of course this is not one
this is pi look pi is 3.1415 right
divided by four is
okay yeah so
so how about if we ask computer yeah so
look just imagine imagine that there's a
lesser
there's a pizza
paper
okay pizza and we ate no no no look this
center today
this is a table table and i have a slice
of pizza this way
yeah
and i saw lots of chocolates just inside
this area
armenian chocolate yeah remember what if
they actually george you know just run
them randomly you know
just sprinkling
throwing the chocolates onto this table
what's the probability we talk about
probability how likely it's going to
fall in here
uh
25 i know why why is it 25 100
it's less yeah we just talked about
liberation
because this is the area of the of the
of us
why is it 20 25 it's very small come on
25 it's just a quarter a quarter how big
is the quarter it's here
maybe just here it's it's just here you
see the 25 here how about this big
slices here
yeah
so look the probability of of these
coins
falling down on this big pizza
is actually the size of that
is the proportion is proportional to the
side to the
area of this pizza to the table right so
we already know that the area of the
pizza is
this right pi r pi r square divided by
four right because this is just a
quarter
a quarter and the table size is one
times one right one times one is one
yeah so that divided by one that's the
ratio that's the ratio between the pizza
the slice of pizza and the
and the table okay
yeah yeah
so look if we ask computers to do this
many many million million times the uh
the probability would be
we can calculate the probability right
we can calculate that the number of
times we can calculate the number of
times the coins falling into this pizza
and the time the number of times it
smells and that would be the pie
now we can get the approximation of pie
got it
makes sense
yeah
okay i'm going to write the shooter code
okay just write the code okay
and then i'll be it okay
sugar no no
define
pi
p
this this accurate is kind of they said
they give you a fancy name called the
malta
color
what
kind of simulation is that
okay
wait
i think they're trying to spell [ __ ]
color simulation
okay
i think they're trying to so look let's
try look at
this so let's say n n is the number of
times that we want to compute the
smaller coins yeah
the more
the more the better right if you slow
two
then there's no way to get calculated
yeah
am i two so the more coins you throw the
better accuracy
approximation
make sense
see that
so
let's say
total total
equals
and the number of coins inside falling
inside the pizza
inside
okay
at the beginning is zero and then i need
to
try
for underscore in range and then again
i need to generate two random values to
point where it located it could be x y
right this x y
so i can x equals random okay so this is
a function from random what's random
what does it mean
render
when what's random
it can
so it means that you know just by luck
okay it's just good like
i guess like
like
any possibility
yeah so you throw a coin it's a coin
the
the probability of falling
the coin facing upwards is random right
50 right it could be it could be up it
could be down right depending on that
right
make sense yeah okay this is random is
from the random package so you need to
say you need to use in order to use this
function you need to say from random
input random and random is a function
that returns the
probability a number a random number
from
bigger than zero and smaller than one
okay it's a fraction number it could be
0.5 or the next time you call it it
could be 20.75
730.61 okay am i
so if i
generate two random numbers
to generate 200 numbers
right these two numbers so how can we
know look alright how can we know if
this point
how can we know if this point is falling
inside the pizza and not outside the
pizza how can we know
if what
no no no i generate a random point yeah
i generate lots of points here and also
how can i know if this point is inside
the p sign not outside the pizza how do
we check if the
if it's in
look this is the radius
and the distance between this point to
to the center is what
if it's inside it's smaller than
ah if it's out bigger then you'll be
bigger yeah yeah
so how to calculate the distance
look this is x this is y
this is x this is y
what so that's the distance what's that
extension
x squared plus y squared we know this
already right
so look if x squared
plus y square smaller or equal equal
yeah one then
inside
plus equals one right
and look total point total point is
actually n right we don't need to
we don't need to
increment it because we are throwing n
times right inside and now after we
solve all these the pi is what we tend
inside
divided by n times 4 right
y transform because look remember i
talked about this proportional
pi divided by 4 yeah this value inside
divided by n is 5 divided by 4 and if we
times 4 that would be the value of pi
right and if this n is
bigger the more
the larger n we got the better
approximation right if it's like two
times three times you wouldn't get a
very good approximation to the pi
make sense
yeah you are still with me yes ryan this
is mathematics this is is this
challenging to you
yeah
is this channel
[Music]
you want me to repeat
again eric do you want me to repeat this
a bit again
do you get it
to get it so what are we doing here
we're throwing end coins yeah we're
trying like
this
because at random random function return
the value between a random value between
zero to one right so it's always on this
big table right and we are just counting
we're just counting what counting the
number of times when this coin falls
into this pizza
a quarter of a third a quarter of the
circle
and if we fall in the pizza we increment
the counter inside we count the number
of times it falls inside
and then if we divide it the number of
times
we throw
then the value will be approximation of
a quarter of the pie right we times four
that would be a pie
right a little bit of pie
all right
so okay so what have we done what have
we learned so far so today we learned
about the area of pi okay one question
what's the area of pi
what's the area of pi if this is the
radius is r
what's the area of pi come on
what's the parameter of pi
the second
conference
[Music]
circumference please remember
what's pi pi equals c divided
circumference divided by diameter
so the pi
meter divided by
diameter equals two times diameter a
diameter so what's c c was pi times t
what's d b d equals 2 times r so what's
c c equals 2 times pi times r okay
i have two times p times r
yeah and we have shown we have learned
why this is pi r square because we you
know color cut a piece i color pizza and
then
and put it
as a triangle and we calculate the area
right using the triangle right
and then this this
and this one is called mountain carlo
simulation because we randomly throw in
the coins and then we count the number
of times the samples here the number of
samples they falls inside the pizza
and then we can calculate the
approximation of the quarter pi if we
times four that will be the pack
okay so you want to see how we get your
own computers just uh because i have
this so let's see how we get it on
computers okay let's do this
okay i'm going to write you see
is it
yeah
okay so look if we run this uh i'm going
to
erase this bit
look
uh yeah we count the number of we
generally learn the number and we times
if it is smaller than one because that's
the distance if it's smaller than y
means inside and we count it yeah and we
if we do this we run it
you see it's very close to pi but it's
not quite yeah if we increase the least
number
to say
you know make it
make it a hundred times for uh bigger
then it takes more time right it takes
no run but look the result is very close
to pi right you see
make
sense yeah make sense
yeah make sense wow
yeah we don't we don't actually need the
total yeah because we don't need to
choose you know we can just do this
[Music]
yeah we can just do this n because n is
total wow
okay and then let's run this okay one
more time
you see very close yeah very close so
every time it's a different a slightly
different approximation but this it
gives a very good approximation okay
that's it for today bye bye