okay so today we talk about divine
encounter yeah this is this concept is
not new yeah we have talked about this
before right yeah do you still remember
what problems uh have we used this kind
of strategy this is kind of like a
you know strategy that we solve the
problem
remember a few days ago we talked about
uh hanoi tower yeah hanoi tower remember
hanoi tower
yeah
we want to move this
the the
a b the disc from a to c yeah
so what does it include the divide and
conquer so we need to divide this into
three steps first
move the n minus one
this
from a
to
b right and then move the elastics and
from a to
c and then
the third step is moving the n minus one
this from b to c okay let's divide the
concept
so and also we talked about the merge
source remember merge sort yeah so given
a few numbers yeah given a few number
three two five one five
nine ten we want to solve sort of this
how can we imagine multistory
first of all we divide divide the to
sort it to solve the numbers in
ascending order first of all we divide
this into half
and we saw these two yeah
so look this is one two three and then
this is five nine
ten yeah everyone look look at me and
then once we saw the post part we merge
it
right right get it so let's divide uh
divide and conquer so what does it mean
can you from these two uh two examples
what does the meaning divide and conquer
i think it's like you divide it like
this
yeah solve it so they conquered conga
what's the conga mean like i
can't get new stuff i know i mean and
solve stuff
yeah yeah most likely okay so divide and
conquer is that
every time you know uh so divide and
conquer so usually we use the recursion
right so we can
recursively divide this problem into a
few you know not just two maybe a few
sub problems right divide this is the
divisor a big problem a very big problem
we divide it into
more right two or more problems
and then we recursively solve it solve
each part each small part right
and then what's next
once we solve it we use these results
from the smaller part to merge right to
get a bigger path right
right
yeah
okay so
what let's let's take an example okay
let's take a little example so i have a
way i want to get the maximum
of it very simple yeah in in python you
can just do this max
ai
how about i tell you to implement this
one way to
do one
return
yeah i know but
i don't want you to use this function
just implement it define max let's
define this max nums okay
so that letter will be very easy yeah
assuming this num is not empty
then we can do uh
like the answer equals
max
infinity negative infinity and then we
go through each number
yeah
in
num
and an answer equals
max okay so this is not
this uh so we are not using the max
function right so we can say if i bigger
than
answer
then answer equals i right and then
return i this is called the linear
linear we do this linear
linear time
right
very simple yeah we go through this
array first of all the answer is
negative
infinity we go through each number and i
will try to compare the number with the
answer and if it's bigger than an answer
we update it with the answer is the
current number right the time complexity
is o
if there are numbers in these nums oh
oh what's the space homelessly any space
no a one constant okay
constant space
okay so now look if we want to find
these numbers okay let's say
10 20
like one five
nine what's the maximum of this array
all right look what's the maximum of
this
twenty we can go through this yeah one
by one and try to compare with the
answer yeah that's the meaning and how
about we use the divided concept first
of all we divide this into half
or we can divide it into three parts
four parts depending but let's let's
just take one simple
divide
well that's a good question okay i'll
tell you later we first of all if we can
divide it into half okay so that
requires it needs to be at least two
elements right so we can divide it in
half we divide it in half
right so we because we saw this function
for example this one the maximum is nine
this one maximum is 20.
okay so now we compare this yeah how do
you get them
how do we get the it's nine or ten here
oh then we divide this into half right
yeah it might not be equally divided but
we can divide it and this is one number
that that's the thing you can't divide
one number into five
so we just written this number
look four five one divided into two
what's the biggest one five
okay and five and nine which is biggest
nine yeah
okay and nine this way here dividing
into two
this this part ten this far twenty
20 and 20 20
29 20.
okay
make sense
yeah okay so i'm going to implement this
and then you need to tell me what
advantage of using this approach using
this one look at this very simple one
right so i can just implement this why
should i care about using this divide
and conquer
just think about the advantage of using
this one okay
so first of all let's implement
sorry
much more quicker
quicker yeah it's related to cooking why
it's quicker
why it's quicker think about it okay
you're very close to the answer you're
very close defined let's say
let again this is max okay this is
numbers okay and now we need to have a
divide function inside divide
divide
divide and then
what divide
so divide um
maybe we can we don't need to be look
look if
lens
numbers
equal equal one if it's only one number
we just return it yeah return it
numbs zero
okay
now the meter power we want to separate
the meter power so meter power equals
one
length
nums
divided by two right
right and what's the left left max look
left max
equal then we called because we call
this one here max
nums
up to meet yeah up to mid
up to mid and what's the right max enter
me look so i separate this is the middle
part there are total number if there's
only one animal i'll return it right
we can't continue dividing it right
there's got to be somewhere we need to
terminate education meet is length yeah
the number of element divided by two
then max
up to mid right up to mid
right max
okay so if this is two then that two
divided by 2 is 1 right so meat is up to
1 so it's the first one and then y max 1
divided by 2
no sorry 1 divided by 2.
numbs and then a mixed meat
remember this yeah from mid to the end
up to the mid not equal right so look
left max
i divide it into two halves
this is the maximum part of the left
part left array
drive max is the max part
max value of the second half
and i just need to return the maximum
these two right
all right
so if
left max
bigger and right max would we determine
which one
right return
if left max bigger than right max return
and otherwise return
s or you know we don't need to write the
s return you have to explain half
good question we don't
like what i said we can split into three
four or five right but split into tough
is most easy way to implement
right
all right okay
so return right next yeah
make sense look if there's only one
element
yeah we can't separate into half we
determine it right it's the max of that
array right if it's if there's only if
at least it's one what's the max of this
one one is
an emitter
is the number of element divided by two
right that's the meter
left next we do cursory we divide we
divide this problem into two two halves
right the first row
we want to get the maximum left that
part and we're going to get the maximum
second half
right only closely we call this function
maximum
and then after these we get these two
numbers right
and now we need to compare which one is
bigger just return it
so like what i said look one two three
four
five six okay now look
right
into half and then look this into half
this into half
okay one two
into half okay now it's one number
one and two which one is bigger two
two and three which is bigger three
four and five okay now this is four and
five we can divide it into half right
four and five five is bigger
five and six
six is bigger okay now three and six
six is bigger you see
yeah so when we recursively divide this
right and the way you keep recursively
calling this this and here is only one
element and now because one element we
already know it's
the answer then
then what we
we back you know we start building this
recursion
from the bot to the up yeah then going
up
going up going up going up going up this
is like a trick
make sense
so okay so come come back to the
question
why do we have to use this one what's
the advantage of this one instead of you
know linear just going through this
element one by one to compare it
right
the linear one
we can use it on one computer but this
one if there are a million numbers
for one computer you need to go to a
million times
right but if i have two computer i can
divide the list into half million half
million
right and i can use these two computers
to do it
at the same time in parallel
am i right
or maybe a uh a minion computer let's
say a million computers you know just
one extreme cases
okay that makes sense
yeah if look let's let's don't think
about uh let's don't take
uh you know consider the communication
cost between these computers let's just
imagine you know these computers can
communicate
instantly without problems
100 numbers
for a single computer
you need to
go through these 100 numbers let's say i
have 10 computers
each computer take 10 numbers
right
am right
it makes sense so they can each computer
take 10 numbers 10 computers take 10
numbers so
each computer can doing this on the same
time in parallel in another paragraph
parallel what does it mean
it means two lines that go the same way
and then all right look at that what
does it mean so look why this is doing
okay so let's think about this example
okay
let's say eric you have a page of 100
pages
not 100 pages
and i don't care if you finish reading
it or you and write and finish it
together
so how how long does it take if if you
take you if you only you read the 100
pages it may be going to take what an
hour right supposedly it doesn't take a
long time to read okay okay i'm just
giving an example right ryan let's say
your personal reading the same speed and
how about if i say okay for the first 50
pages
you eric
you read it and then at the same time
ryan you can use read the second half
which is from 51 to 100.
so how long does it take for
for this page 100 pages
i don't get it sorry you don't get
anyone okay
so you have one book right a book of
maybe
okay
yeah
let's put this 100 chocolates yeah
easier 100 chocolates
100 chocolates
now
it takes you like an hour to eat one
chocolate
uh a minute to eat one chocolate okay a
minute you want chocolate
how long does it take for all the coins
all the chocolate coins to be eaten
100 minutes right
100 minutes
now ryan
you can hurt girga
right so how long does it take
15 minutes yeah that's what i say look
speed up
why why is it 15 minutes
because you two can eat it at the same
time that's in parallel
but why can't you just like
eat
away how big of a chocolate
i'll make a chocolate okay very very big
maybe this big
okay
okay okay come on come on if it was
really small yeah yeah i know just
example
so so my question my so here's the thing
okay there are a hundred numbers
and then like 10 computers they can do
this in parallel right they can do this
in parallel so let's speed up could be
10 10 times faster all right
i'm right because they can do it at the
same time that's the advantage of using
the divide and conquer because we can
divide this problem into a few sub
problems and they are independent right
they are independent and can be
processed in parallel at the same time
and when we get the result from each
part of the sub problems then we can
merge it yeah we can merge it
right like the maximum uh getting the
maximum right getting the maximum then
we can do what
uh we
we can compare right the maximum of each
part right am right are you right
yeah are you all right
yeah so let's see
let's divide and conquer any other
examples like we have talked about what
much sauce yeah munchie sauce
do you still remember the magic sauce
yeah i'm going to quickly write it okay
come on divide much easier
can you stop
stoplight please
numbs okay now look
if there's only one number
then we return it right return this
return it right because what number one
number is already sorted right what
number is saudi now the meter power the
middle part is what
the middle part is the
nums
divided by two okay and then what's the
left one what's the
right
look
left
equals let's say we want to merge sort
the
the last part that's part numbers area
look at me
nouns up to me right
and can you tell me what to write left
right equals what
start from me to the end right now
okay
yeah i know what's next if i have left
and right what's next
if i have left and right what's next
can you not touch my computer for the
last time okay
all right
i have left part i have right what what
should i do look one two three how do
you how do you make how do we merge one
two three and
four five six
to make it
remember we merged to saute this yeah we
need to merge two saute this remember we
talked about this much saute this then
we just merge this is merged left and
right okay
that's the margin so remember look we
have salty this yet one two five one two
four and
three
four five how do we merge this look we
have two pointers we have one and three
yeah keep moving one and three which one
is smaller one one and then move it two
and three which is smaller two
two then i move it four and three
four three yeah and three i move this
yeah four and four okay it doesn't
matter
and i move this yeah five yeah
okay make sense
make sense
[Music]
okay this is much soft and then
the hanoi tower right we talked about
that and what else what else can we do
this
what else can we do this
we can okay i'm going to talk about
another quick problem okay just very
quick very quick alola another ruler
okay
and then look we have uh
in a meter in the middle and then do
this to this yeah yeah you want to do
this
yeah something like that
oh yeah
yeah lula so you have these different
measurements okay so we can have a
function like define
lula
left
you need left right
and then height height is least high
yeah
hi
okay so first of all meet the meat okay
so look it has to be r minus air has to
be the power of uh you know so basically
let's make this simple so so basically
you want to have a ruler which come
which can be separated recursively right
so in order for this to be
uh be possible to lose we we need to
make sure 2 to the power h equals r
minus l okay so this is the requirement
can i replace it
okay
so first of all the meter one the meter
one equals air plus r
divided by two right
every yn
meter equals a plus one divided by two
we can do this just divided by two okay
all we can do is l plus ah 51 okay let's
draw the same okay
and now look if height is bigger than
zero
if the height is bigger than zero then
we do what what we can do we need to
do lula make the
for the first half which is which which
is what air and the meter
but the height will be five minus one
right
will be height minus one okay yeah what
did i say what did i say high minus one
what does this mean
you're not listening okay should i
repeat again
yeah
i want to i want to make um
to make the markers of the rulers right
so i want to get the middle one this one
this side get the middle one yeah
and then look i want recursively
recursively i want to
mark the left left side yeah this left
side which is this one and then i want
to mark now i want to mark at
here
which is meter and this is h and then i
want to mark what what's missing
what's this part
so what's the parameter what's the first
parameter i want to get
air to meet and now this is what
you really are busy right
what's the speed
it's
air to meet the air to meet and then
what's this b to r right
mid to r good r
right okay and then h minus one right
look this is quite similar to hanoi
tower right first of all there are three
steps we want to we want to complete the
marking of the ruler so what's the step
first of all we want to mark the center
right
and then the second step mark the left
the third step mark on the right
divide and conquer easy
and once we keep marking and when the
height is bigger than zero right if high
is you know if high is always is smaller
than zero height
height look this is the height
how long you want to mark it right
because the lower you know if you keep
doing that you'll be smaller right
always it will be shorter shorter
shorter the length yeah this is
controlled by the height the surf
parameter makes sense this would just be
a dot yeah when it's 0 so then that's
the time we stopped marking okay so
let's say
divide and conquer okay that's the
concept that's the concept that's a very
important concept of the computer
programming we use the divide and
conquer to solve
the a big problem
by dividing it into a smaller problem
and this small problem can be
independently
solved so it means that we can
parallelize you know
what's the advantage of
of the parallelization
parallelizing what why do we need to
parallelize it
what's the advantage what advantage we
can get from parallelizing it
to make it what
i was talking about the coins example so
what's the advantage of making it
parallel
it'll be quicker quicker yeah it'll be
quicker yes the polarization because
this problem can be done in parallel
okay
okay that's it for today good job
bye bye