[Music]
we have talked about divide and conquer
yesterday right divide and conquer so
uh we have a big problem and then we
divide it into smaller chunks of work
and we can distribute them yeah
to solve them individually independently
and
remember
remember we have a few numbers yeah a
few numbers we're dividing the two
halves and then we
we check we get the maximum of the first
half and the maximum the second half
yeah and then we can merge them right
this is the same idea as the merge sort
yeah
so one advantage of this divide and
conquer is that we can do this
small task in parallel so in parallel
what's parallel so i have a task i can
do this in parallel
in parallel yeah i can do this tag i
have a task i can do this in parallel
layer
and then when this task the results for
these tasks completed i can merge it to
a big
uh you know merge it to get this the
solution for the entire big problem
right
so
if we parallelize this we can achieve
this performance speed up right
performance data you know the computers
have calls core they have cpu cpu
central process unit processing unit is
the brand of computer yeah brand
community they have 24 brands yeah my
computer have 24 cores 24 course 24
course cpu course yeah so each course is
like a brain okay when
so look if a task can be done in
parallel right for example if if it's
fully paralyzed but let's say there are
10 tasks 10 tasks
if i have only one brand yeah one core
cpu to do it it takes
it for example if it takes one minute to
complete one task then it needs 10
minutes to complete all these ten tasks
right but if i have a two cores
two cars two computers and these can be
taken in beta and how many minutes there
must be two people okay two people two
coins two cars is the same yeah so how
many
[Music]
okay this is the same assumption okay so
okay if you we if we were the one people
finished five coins another people
finished five five tasks
you know five tasks
uh so how long does it take
it takes four minutes five minutes yeah
exactly so look if i have this do this
in parallel so i can do this
five
yeah two brands two cars whatever yeah
and these are tasks or coins you pick
whatever the time
yeah one minute two minutes three
minutes four minutes five minutes right
because look the time is shortened
because these can be done in parallel
means that once one minute passed and
these can be done in parallel that's one
obvious way yeah one one quickest way is
to speed up yeah to get this performance
speed up right it's easier right so look
if a task is uh you know
if if we if we have a lot of tasks to
complete
and one easy way to make it faster
is to get more calls coming to help
right
right all right yes make sense
okay so look
it
now we introduced this concept called
the speed up okay what's with that
speed up
speedo is defined as the time of one
people one call
to uh finish the task divided by the
time of n calls or n people to have
divided class yeah so let's
is equal to 10 divided by five
exactly look if there are one people is
ten right if two people is five then the
speed up is two what easy and if ten
people this is
ten people that will be
one and speed up will be ten right
so let's speed up so
for this 100 if this class is a hundred
percent parallelizable minimum you know
you can just
you can this this work you can just
distribute it in parallel let's call
paralyzed but yeah and then the maximum
speed up is linear yeah given these n
chords you can achieve the speed up of n
i
that's linear yeah
that's the
number of core number of people number
of course let's speed up yeah and then
you can achieve this this new nino right
this is nina
but in
real life
in real life the the the task
compose sequential path and the
parallelized power what's the sequential
part if if i have a task
if i have a task look
i have tasks
look at these other tasks 10
and if i say okay these five
you can't distribute them in parallel
meaning that you can't have more course
helping to improve these you know
meaning these five needs to be taken
sequentially but these five you can ask
more course or people to come to help
right let's say five people five people
to help and you know
six
wow you quick look because this
needs to fight like one you'll take
five and then you'll eat one and then
the others will eat one one one or
exactly you're just taking one of them
yeah one black very good six wow yes
exactly so look the sequential part will
be one two
three four five and then the
parallelized bar right this is this
takes five five seconds five minutes or
whatever five you need
but now these can be taken by parallel
by five chords right
look at here to here only time equals
one so time would be five plus one
equals six
okay so we want ideally we want this
sequential part to as small as possible
right so we can have more costs to help
uh speed up and we want to
we we want to have these
this bit you know 100 i say now it's
just 50 right because look that ten and
then five of them can be
paralyzed but so this is 50
right so you want this percentage to go
up to 100 to have to utilize the
multi-course technology you have to have
more people to come to help right
so
so we're going to study a formula which
is has this uh sequential path
sequential part b
and then
if this b
this sequential part is b and then the
parabolic
the part which can be paralyzed but is
one minus b right
okay
because all these two added up to one
percent one one hundred percent which is
one okay
okay let's do this look
speed up equals t1 divided by tn right
and i can do this again t1
tn yeah tn equals what i can do is t1
and then it will be equals to the
sequential path plus part plus
the the parallelized path can be divided
by n right because look this is the
power which can be parallelized
which can be paralyzed but and then
they're n process you can
you can help to reduce the time to
one end right
okay so look remember we talked about b
is the sequential path so
so p if p is the what is the percentage
that can be parallelized so b p equals 1
minus b right p plus
p plus p equals 1 right this is the part
that can be parallelized but and this is
the part which cannot be parallelizable
so if we look we can cancel out these
so you'll be 1 divided by b
b let's uh
b will be
b will be 1 minus p right
so y minus p
1 minus b equals p plus p divided by n
right so look this is the formula
the maximum speed up okay i just look
from here to here right but p plus b is
the the percentage that can be needs to
be sequentially
you know
executed and the p is the part that you
can have more people to come to help
this 2 b plus p
b plus p equals 1 right ok so if i
substitute b with one minus
p
one minus p equals p and then we get
this right so this is the maximum we
call it amanda's law
maximum speed up maximum speed up
yeah okay so one p
is one what does it mean so one p is one
let's substitute one p is one means that
all these tasks can be a hundred percent
paralyzed but like like the ten coins
you can have ten people to come right to
half right so what p is one what's the
value one minus one zero
one minus n divided by n so when p is
one that will be becoming
one minus one that's zero plus one
divided by n
i was this value this is zero
yeah
one divided by one divided by n what's
what's this
what's the value of this every line any
one
right what's the value is one over one
over n
yeah
what's this that's n right
this is the linear
linear thing we talked about but if this
p is what zero
what happens if this p is zero
is one divided by one minus zero plus
zero divided n okay so this is easier
can tell me what's this
one and what's this
0 divided by n
n is bigger than 0 of obvious 0 divided
by 100 equals 1
0 this is 0. this is 1 right 1 divided
by 1
1 okay so it means that if no portion of
the word can be paralyzed and this is
sequential let's speed up is one because
these two are the same right
yeah because if you like 10 coins and
you need to eat them you need to
complete them one at a time
you can't have more people more course
to help you to shorten the time of the
of this work
but this time will be the same and the
speed up will be one
right
might make sense yeah so this formula
okay so today's this formula computes
the maximum speed up maximum speed up if
we use n
cos you know c b support or n p bar
to speed up the
the work the p percentage of what
p is the percentage of word that can be
parallelized but right
yeah that's the speed up okay and the
speed up is the time of using one people
to do it one course to do it divide it
by using mp to do it
okay any questions so far
no any question no
okay so to sum up we want to have uh
we want to design the the algorithm you
know to have this uh
p
bigger p
yeah bigger peak of a work that can be
parallelized right right if the work is
like zero percent parallelizable then it
can't be
speed up by using mathematical
technology okay
okay that's it for today bye bye