hello hello how are you today good okay
okay
i'm here so today we're going to talk
about
this
okay
so fluffy icon is a very popular well
known accurate in computer
[Music]
thing so
image pics uh you know we have an image
a picture and now we have some obstacles
here some obstacles
i don't know it's there yeah
now okay so dark
it's not dark it's maybe uh i don't know
okay so now if i drop uh
if i want to start flat filling the
image at this position okay
and then only fluffy we put a little bit
from the inside
so what what does it look like for
example you have a container with
something it looks like a blob with a
brush
so if you have a uh uh
looks like an island a bucket of you
know if you're starting the pouring
pouring pouring the ink glue at this
point you know the water the ink yeah
the ink
you start to put pull it in pour
so the image
will be finally like outside will be
blue yeah you'll be stuck this is the
final stage it's off off here outside
but not normally inside because the wind
cannot go inside the ink will stop okay
when we fly feeling
the flows will stop at the boundary and
the obstacles right all right
okay so
another and
another example is if we start to
fulfill the inside if we put a dot you
know if we start to pull it at the
center what was going to be like
and the inside will be all green yeah
yeah
so
let's let's use a very simple example
with the magic your matrix numbers yeah
numbers with two dimensional metrics
tournament let's say one one one two
three four four two
uh
one one two
two
one zero zero
one
okay so if i
if we are going to start fulfilling and
hit this position
with uh with the color the new color
will be equal to let's say
four okay so what does let's maybe
two
three what do you think it would be like
we can change all the twos to freeze
okay
okay let's hold on
we don't do the one stop all the way
yeah okay
so which which two you think you're
going to be changed with me
this this this this yeah okay so we
change it to
exactly yes
yeah
so the the problem because very simple
so we are starting to fully uh filming
the image with the partition with the
partition with the
with the color with the background with
a new color okay with the new color new
color
new color
so
new colors so we can change we can
change the pixel to the new color as
long as it's next to each other the
neighbor you know four direction the
neighbor yeah this is the neighbor this
is the neighbor this is the neighbor
yeah
to four neighbors as long as the inside
of the image
it's next to the name is the neighbor
and its color is the same as the
starting color right which is we need to
remember the starting color which is two
right as long as it is two then we can
keep doing this yeah and here no more
right until the pixel go out of the
image or it stops
after the other pixel right because we
don't change this one right we don't
change it because it's strong
no no that's a good question you cannot
leave neighbor only
horizontal or vertical right you
[Music]
the bottom one could go with the one
thing
which one which one are you talking
about
which one are you talking about
this one this could go to this
yeah
through the emitter
so you first thought of vertigo in the
horizon okay
what's your uh approach i mean any idea
if we're starting from a position i know
we follow it yeah
search level by level and also
yeah because these two sometimes can be
you know if one can can can be used to
solve the problem the other is also
going to be so conservative right these
two years are just different in the way
they
you know they do research right yeah
so let's do this uh
let's do the test search first okay
okay okay come on
define
let's say fluffier
we have an image yeah image
and we have a star partition starting
rows
uh styling column and then we want to
fill a new card new with the new color
right
yeah with the new color okay sorry about
that
and
okay so
so
what
how how do we do the process uh
we
search
research how to research
in a deficit order so what kind of
implementation usually we use with
okay so first of all we
i see the rows and the columns yeah the
rows will be length of image
and then column will be length of image
zero
okay so one question look if i start to
feel this that look i'm at this position
and i want to
recursively call this
and what happened how does it how do you
how do we prevent it going back to
filling the pictures we already feel
right that's one problem we need to
solve right
how do we look
yeah do you understand what i'm talking
about
okay so look i'm starting to feel this
with the pigs
three
three three three yeah so look i put it
in the three and then we call here
yeah
three
yeah and then see
okay so one way of one way because we
already changed this pixel to three so
it can't go back right when you go back
it's not a color one we're looking for
the color ones to
to to work yeah basically we're working
at the color pixel one and then when we
feel we we start to fill it with the
color three then you can't go back right
and how about this case look
what it means
okay so yeah that's a good question look
how look
usually recursion every question how do
you prevent it going back
so if i go to the if i if i'm in this
position ryan please keep quiet
if i'm in this partition if i go to this
does it hold does it go back
no no right how why is it not back over
because we we already changed this
picture to two what if it's just like
wait what if it's what if it's like
[Music]
this
like that what do you mean like that
on the chain
if if and here we want to change the
picture to one then that's going to be a
problem right because it's already in
one
right if you go here you already change
it this is one and you change it to one
and how about this pixel you think it's
a new pixel but it's not right yeah
so how can we fix this how can we
remember things using computer data
structure what kind of thing can we use
to remember
the thing
okay
okay so we have a different search
differences
and we are currently r c and we want to
just yeah we want to start filling with
the transition rc
right
and then
we first of all we need to have a scene
yeah scene equals
the hashtag yes set
right if
r c
in scene it's always seen if we already
visited this pizza before then we just
return yeah we simply return right i'm
right
yeah and then now if you know if this
pixel is not visited so what's the first
thing we need to do
we need to do what look rc we are
currently a position as if it's in the
notebook
if we have seen this before if we ever
think it would return
if not if we haven't seen it so what
should we do
what should we do
we add it add it to the notebook right
easy that
scene.area and rc okay look we we use
this
look
rc this is a tuber yeah tuber meaning
that we're remembering this position in
uh
in the notebook
and now now this picture is
it's not be immediately so what should
we do we should change the picture to
the new color right so new so the image
okay
image
uh
r
c will be to new color right new color
okay so now i have filled this picture
so i want to try the neighbor right we
want to try four neighbors right
yeah
so we can try
first of all we can try r minus one c
or r plus one c or r c minus one or c r
c plus one yeah this four position right
look this is rc what's this
ah
plus one c uh what's this
r minus one c what's this
ah
r what
r
c minus one
r c plus one
so look this is the oh we can do this in
four for all we can do is for
we can do a loop here dr dc is the
offset of the rows and columns in four
direction so you fold that right
so zero one
one zero
zero minus one
minus one zero yeah this is the four
fold this is the
the offset in on the offset
yeah offset so now the new r
nu r will be r plus p i
nu c will be c plus dc and then first of
all we need to check if this is inside
the image right so we need to check this
even inside if
zero smaller bigger than nr
smaller than r
and
n1 you can guess
zero
smaller or equal than nc
smaller than c if this is inside the
image right and then we do the
search recursively release n r and c y
all right
yeah
yeah checking if this new
neighbor is still inside the image then
we do this at night and see right am i
right
yes
and we just do the needs to call this
dms
dfs
[Music]
srs here
and then we can return the image
okay present the image
so
the most important thing is this one
right because we have to check we have
to
mark the visited pixels otherwise there
will be sometimes there will be infinity
roof especially if that
is what
uh
especially what okay okay there's one
thing missing okay that's one thing you
think
because we only want to mark the pixel
which is the same as the original color
so here
uh
so i have to put the color
color will be equals image
sisc right this is the
the pixel we are going to mark right so
we have to check uh
we have to check here right we have to
check somewhere
we have to check somewhere if here if
the new and
and
if the image
nr and c
equals the color right because we only
want to mark the
the pixel which the value equals to
color which is the star okay that's the
part that's missing okay am i right
yeah
otherwise you otherwise if you don't
have this what will happen you're
feeling every pixel right because it you
would just
go to
four directions without any check and
eventually this pixel will be only one
color which is new color so that's very
important because we only want to
expand we don't we only want to go to
the next neighbor to the neighbor only
if this neighbor has the color with the
same which is the original color right
all right all right that makes sense
and then you know it's definite search
one one problem of definite search is
these the calling depth you know because
look if if this is a very big picture
right a very big picture
and if there's no obstacles if there's
no obstacles it's just a blank picture
if i start feeling the
black color from from one corner right
yeah and then these were calling the
recursion recursion because this is
we're always
uh this is always true and then we're
calling location location equation
indication
and the depth the calling step the
callings as
uh recursion depths will be too much
will be bigger than the
uh you know
because the stack is six size right in
the computer there's a course call step
calling stack
calling stack it's a it's a fixed size
stack
it's a fixed size step okay i'm going to
talk about a little bit about the
corning stack so computer is like a
stack right it's a it's growing
downwards yeah a stack calling step so
every time you call a function right
i will come here you call the function
according that will happen is the
computer will remember push the address
you know push your address of the
current address yeah
kind of address
the location yeah location and i also
will push the parameters
here and we'll push the
uh you know the the local variable
storage of the function right somewhere
here
right and if you could keep calling
calling calling then you'll start
feeling this calling stack
and then once it reaches the maximum
size of the stack what happened boom the
computer just will complain that
stack overflow okay
make sense so stack is a fixed size in
computer because the computer has the
limited memory yeah memory is like a
brand you remember things in computer
right
the computer you remember the things in
ram what's that
random access memory it's like it's a
you know it's a memory thing so computer
can store the data information in the
ram and have a stack right call this
thing so one way to solve this problem
is we can use the
breakfast search we can we can do this
in iteratively yeah using a iterative
one and we can do this using breakfast
and we can even
implement the different search using uh
iterative yeah literally already
so let's do this
make sense every friend you've been
quiet today
okay
yeah
are you still with me yes
okay
so now again r c the same r will be the
number of rows which is length of image
right because the image is a two
dimensional ray and c will be length of
image 0 right because we think it's a
two dimensional array
okay
there's a pixel here if the length if
the image is only i mean if the image is
zero that's not
it is empty then this clock
i mean
this will report errors yeah but we
assert we're assuming the image is the
non-empty it's not empty it has at least
one row and one column okay
and the color this is the starting color
we want to follow we want to follow the
pixel with the color color equals image
image s-i-c-l okay
so in order to implement professors what
kind of data structure okay what kind of
data structure are we using to kill yeah
i mean python we're using the dq double
and the key well okay q equals pq
at the beginning
is the and the partition is srsc right
this is the partition
okay
and now we also need a hash table
notebook to remember the points we have
the pixel we have we've seen so we have
a cn equals one
[Music]
notebook what's number called c
set has said okay
what is that
so now y
q
okay y q
the
r c will be
how do you get the element from the q
how to get the element from q q to y
forward problem yeah
if you want only this is a kill
pop left you're taking one hour from the
left if you just pop what happened
it'll go for right yeah it will go for
all right
now we have this color we have this
color i know we want to mark it right we
want to mark it
we want to mark it with with the image
so image
rc equals new color right in new color
we want to change this color right
i know we need to
we need to do what if check if this is
already visited if rc in
scene we just continue right what's
continue mean
yes continue so continue just just skip
the rest of the loop and goes to the
next okay
and okay so that's the same what's next
if it's not enough no if it's not been
seen so what should have been the first
thing to do
if we're not if you haven't seen this
before what's the first thing
to do
okay so look at this is quite similar in
the differences yeah
except that we are using the q right and
then what should we do now
uh then we need to go through for the
next four four direction fdr dc
in okay look
again the same right okay
zero one
one zero
minus one
zero zero minus one
and then n r and c will be equals r plus
dr
c plus dc and now we need to check if
these two are in the ring right zero
smaller than nr smaller than r
and
zero smaller than equal and nc smaller
than c also
we need to check if this is the new
image yeah image
and uh okay i'm going to write here and
and what and we're going to check the
next piece the neighbor picture if it's
the same color
the color yeah
yeah we only feel the color
even we only feel the neighbor if it has
the same color as color right right
so n
image
and our new color nc equal equals
in this way then we do this q dot how do
we push it to the queue
q dot
q how do we put the element to the queue
a pen yeah look we take one element from
the queue and we we want to expand its
next kids neighbors into the keyword
which is an r and c
okay
and and that will be return image with
an image return image
okay so in this way we're doing this
iteratively without a calling stack so
it won't be you only you won't have this
code problem or stack overflow okay you
won't have this programmer stack
overflow
um
so as i said we are using the q here and
but we again we can use the stack right
we can use the stack
so we can change this dq to us to a list
just to emulate a stack right
it also work right right you also want
it just but when you uh plot it
when you it's just the different orders
of plotting uh fulfilling the pixels
right with the q and step because the
way to
uh you know if push a few elements just
stack and then you only push the same
elements to kill the way to take it out
the dq or this step
the order of the sequence is different
but eventually all the pixel required
pixel are fulfilled right it's just
different order of of feeding uh pixels
make sense
anyway
okay so i'm going to write a image and
then you change it to the
to the final okay
let's say one one two so you're gonna
give it an input and we need to say the
output yeah that's it
it needs to be square doesn't it
no
can be rectangles
or triangles
okay so i'm starting at this position
four and i want to change it to color
five
okay
five five five five five five
[Music]
okay so one more question what's the
what's the data structure i will use how
do we prevent the picture
hotline
now how do we prevent the picture being
visited again
what is the coding in computers set
it only contains the unique elements
okay that's it for today good job
bye-bye