hello
hello mr mr ryan how are you today
okay i guess you're all good yeah um so
you know that was shuffling shuffling
yeah you know snap shuffling what's it
doesn't mean you know you know you're
not the car you're playing the poker
poker games yeah poker cast you shuffle
it pokemon cards yeah your pokemon
shuffle them
yeah shuffle is the way to make a random
permutation it's so it's a random
permutation okay random permanent random
permutation
do you still remember the permutation
this is what yeah
this is p yeah and we talk about a
combination as well right
yeah
combinations okay look let's review a
little bit
all right
i have a
one two three three numbers
what's the possible permutation of it
what's the possible permutation how many
ways of permutation six yeah can you
give us a few examples
one two three yeah definitely of course
it's one of them
one three two
two one three
i said
[Music]
yeah the way how we compute the
permutation for permutation if there are
n numbers how many ways of doing the
permutation remember what's the what's
the answer what's up
if there are n numbers what's the how
many numbers how many commu full
communication of n numbers
if let's n if 3 is 6
yeah f 3 equals 6
if f 4 equals 1
if there are 4 numbers how many ways of
doing it
no of course not
for permutation remember the first one
we have n choice
yeah 24 yes the second one we have y and
minus one choice the third one we have n
minus two and here one and what's this
and
factorial yeah that's the full
computation there we go and combination
combination is not uh with
the order does not matter right if we
pick one two three if we pick two
numbers out of three how how many ways
of doing that
you choose one and three yeah one and
two one
and three why are they you could use two
and three and that's it yeah
picking two numbers out of three is the
same as picking one number out of three
right because look if you pick one two
you left the three you pick one three
you left two you picked two three you
left one right it's the same yeah
all right it corresponds to each other
picking two numbers out of three is the
same as picking one number out of three
correct make sense
so look c
and
picking m numbers out of n
is the same as picking
n minus m numbers out of n okay makes
sense that's the equation here
okay okay our computation okay we talked
about okay we're not talking about
permutation and
computing
combination today we're talking about
shuffling
so
yeah
so look at this one two three one two
three shuffling
we just talked about six possibilities
and we went to shuffling so each
possibility needs to be a probability
yeah we talk about probability
needs to be
one over six yeah all right
okay there's six possibility of three
cards and one shuffling and each one has
to appear one over six this is called
unbiased what's unbiased
and
buyers
what's buyers
what's buyers what's the meaning of
buyers
uh
they're based on
um
is like you know you have preference for
some combination of for some permutation
for example
okay
okay listen to me bias
is means that look there are six
possibilities yeah let's do this again
okay two one three two one one three one
two three two one so look there's six
possibilities i don't want to do the
random shuffling each one has to appear
roughly you know ideally you'll be one
over six probability but if i said okay
i i prefer this one more i want to say i
like this sequence you know so
this is biased you know if you if you
approach to shuffle
has more probability of these
yeah
then it's buyers
make sense
inspires so we don't want that buyer's
permutation we want to
advise three three two one okay good
choice
okay so we uh this is shuffling and then
we could
let's say i have a number i have this
one two three number i want to shuffle
it how can we shuffle it
so one way of checking it is least right
we can choose
yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah okay okay how do we do
this how do we do this how do we do it
okay okay
yeah okay that's enough enough
in order to do shuffling we need to kind
of bring in this randomness in
randomness we talk about a random random
thing uh remember that in the lesson of
uh
what do we call we call this circle yeah
calculus
yeah this is a square and then it's a
quarter of certain we
start to throw the chocolate coins on it
yeah and we count how many coins are
falling inside the circle and if we
divide it by the number of the coins
together coins and we get roughly the
proportion of
a quarter pi right right this is
multi-color randomness and when we use
that randomly we use the random function
random function from the random package
generates a number between
bigger or equal to zero and smaller than
one right
and it also has other function which is
called rand
in
given two numbers a b you will return a
number random okay random
from a to b
inclusive okay
and similarly we have another function
called run range right remember this
range function
running function a b c right
c is the step option a b
random a b
you will come up with the number bigger
than equal and a as smaller than b right
right or if it's rand if you if you
if you just call run age is equal it's
similar it's equivalent to rent range
zero a yeah this is the same yeah
so if we put a random here random range
render range okay i think it's red range
red range so basically you would
generate an integer between this range
yeah
random range okay
makes sense
so why are we using this random function
so we can do this
we can generate the function uh
so you tell me okay
so look if i this is one two three if i
repeat if i repeat three times that if
there are n numbers if i repeat n times
and every time i generate a number
between zero
to three
right zero to two right zero one two
and every time i generate this number
and i swap it
yeah
right
so for example the first time i generate
this is two and i swap what
i will swap uh
zero to i will swap the i
to
repeat n times okay so this is zero to
[Music]
uh let's say
four if i for i in range
and i
right
look if i if i repeat n times and
i generate a number which is in a rent
range
red range
n and i will swap i will swap
so numbers
x and numbers i
yeah and if i look at least n times if i
run the niche
you know pick a number and i sort it
yeah this could be one way of doing but
there's a problem with this why is that
look
if i pick one this number and i swap it
with this
right so that will become
two one three
right
and again i'm here right if i again i
pick this number
and i stop it
you become one two three
again so what's the problem is that one
number could be swapped more than once
but ideally it should be
one time if you repeat n times
so what's the probability of each number
being swapped
come on that's an easy question if it's
a unbiased one
there are numbers and numbers i want to
look i want to swap it i want to perform
this swapping
and one over n right because then if i
do this n times
right so each number needs to be
probability though and one over n's yeah
for it to be swap right
make sense
yeah but if if there's one number which
is smaller than this probability then it
means other number is less than this
probability yeah got it right
right and what could happen if the
one number is more than n
it's being picked and the other number
is unless it's not being picked but it's
not it's not giving you and buyers right
right make sense
so
one way of checking if your solution is
buyers or unbiased is that
it's numbers right if we randomly
shuffling shuffling swapping
if render is as you know perform this
shuffling
and bacterial times
unfortunate sense
so each uh each permutation has to
appear more you know
one time yeah on average right because
this is probability and if we repeat
this shuffling if we we perform this
swapping random shot from uh
n times so each number has to be
picked for swap
once
right if it is if it's not thick it
means it's unfired if it takes more than
once it's
oh sorry it's if it's picked
mono once it's it's buyers
if it's pick
less than once it means it's not picked
at all it's by yourself as well right
yeah i'm not you still with me
do you get what i'm saying yeah
okay yeah okay
okay so
what's your approach if i want to
perform end time swapping what's your
approach
in order to be
to give up unbiased
swapping for each element
any idea
so the problem of this one is that when
this element is swapped
it could be swapped back using this
approach right we don't want it to swap
back now one way of fixing it is what
it's like okay i have one
okay look i have four four numbers
i put it in a hat
i run an empirical number ah i want to
swap it right
so it's swap so it has to be moved here
i this is this is already determined
right pull pull off the numbers and now
i want to pick another number for
swapping
which which
which
three numbers i need to pick okay i
already keep saying three numbers i
randomly pick one number after this
right and that's okay
and again i randomly pick one over
obviously so the numbers when i pick
already
are not for pick in the future right the
previous approach is back then okay i i
picked
i don't even pick one numbers i swap it
i put it back and now again when you
pick three numbers four one number of
these four and i'll empty this one so
one number could be picked more than
once right so we want to solve this
problem by by using these two to place
this once it's clicked it moves to that
and we don't pick it again right that's
that will give this unbiased
uh
when uh shuffling right got it make
sense
yeah
do you think
do you see the problem we're trying to
solve yeah the shuffling it gives the
random permutation
and we want to
be i'm biased it means that each number
if we
do the swapping for n times each number
has to be picked exactly
yeah once
yeah
make sense
okay so then we can implement this yeah
we can implement this
so you the implementation could be just
very simple but you have to understand
the
the principle which is like you know you
can remember this half i think when you
pick the number we'll move it here we're
going to pick one number here over here
okay let's define shuffling
shuffling
numbers
right
now for
i
in
range
length
numbers
so we also repeat this enzyme look this
is one two three four here and right
so let's divide these in into half the
left part is already shuffled the right
part is still in the head yeah still in
the head okay
make sense remember the thing is the
thing i talked about here
yeah
the left this is the left
at least it's still in the head okay
stay in the head okay
sense
so i first of all i will generate the
index so for i
x will be
rent range right render range
red range lens num
uh
so we want to generally start from the i
start from i we want to swap this we
don't start from i i need not pick one
numbers
from here to the right right i
to the lens number
yeah
and then what should we do we just need
to swap it
now
i how do we solve two numbers by the way
how do we solve two numbers by the way
come on this is an easy question for you
how do we solve two numbers if a b how
do we solve a b a b
a wow any for you this is the python way
of doing and how about if we don't
copy
uh
no no how about if i
how about if we want to use the third
variable to do it how do we do this
not deep copy what i'm saying is that i
i won't swap value between a and b how
do we
um
how do we swap it with the half of the
third parameter
look you say a b equals b a f but
ideally what's behind is t equals a
a equals b
yeah yeah a value to copy a
yeah that's d copy right
oh wait that yes it's still copied yeah
because
yeah but what i mean is more specific t
equals a a b and then what what's the
third one uh
b
equal
yeah
if we said b equals a that would not
work right because a is already changed
to b okay make sense
yeah okay so this
uh nums i norms x
equals nums
x
nums
i okay now we're stopping the index at i
and x right
yeah first of all we generate index from
i to the to the end
so here we are i here
we first of all generate index
adjustment why because they're still in
the head
and we're swapping with the i right
so people is that
so so we don't touch the elements before
i because it's already it's already
picked
all right yeah make sense
and next time we move it because we
already have one already swap one more
element
so it becomes in uh in this
this is before i index smaller than i
right
in the smaller so let's let's see
shuffling look easy yeah for i in ranger
learn the range
yeah make sense
make sense any questions so far
okay so one one simple question what's
the probability of
swapping
swapping uh n elements
uh no
what's the what's the
random shuffling probability of each
permit of each permutation
if the n
if the end
items
how many how many ways of full
permutation of permutation of it
i just said at the beginning if not any
items
three items how many ways of doing it
okay so an item how many was doing
each one has the
if it's unbiased what's the probability
of each permutation
if it's unbiased what's the population
yeah easy yeah that's
that's simple max right simple mess
do you understand this part
do you understand
so we are separating this array into two
halves one
is
this bit
the right hand side is still in the half
it's the numbers we are not picking yet
so every time we generate a number at
this range
we want to pick a number at this range
and we swap it with the current one
and then we move it so this number is is
determined okay
why we won't do it because each number
is only swap once yeah once it's swapped
it becomes on the left side
look at me it becomes a left side so
can we say this if the number is swapped
only once
if a number is not only once
and if we perform n
because we are performing n times
right there are n numbers we're
performing n times each each number is
up only once so what does it mean
every number gets the equal prop uh
probability of being each location right
right so there are numbers i have n
slots
okay so n stops
uh listen carefully okay there and there
are n slots
and numbers one to n each number is
being swapped once
and if we swap n times
right
so it means that it means what it means
that each slot each is each number at
each slot right is
it
is what it has this equal probability
right
all right
so it's unbiased it's unbiased
we want the unbiased each number
each number is should be on
each slot
right
we don't want a buyer's one we don't
want to say okay okay we want one
in this slot because we just like it
we can't say that right
it needs to be equally equally
distributed right
if i say okay they are more likely this
chance chance of one in first location
is fifty percent
on all others is fifty percent that's
bad that's bad shuffling
when you should play the render
shuffling car do you want
the top of the car
to be more likely like you know some i
don't know yeah your favorite right
then that's bad right because people
think okay people could guess
all right do you see what i'm saying
if it's randomly shuffling it means that
the top of the car could be anything
if that anchor the top of the the first
position of the uh
of the
sequence random shuffling sequence could
be anything right so we can't guess
because it could be
yeah yeah yeah so yeah
even if people can catch the random
shuffling of uh you know the more likely
then then there's no point of shuffling
yeah right the point of shuffling is
make it
non-guessable right
yeah
so it it could be anything right because
each of each
its permutation is unbiased
it's equally
uh distributed so you can't make a guess
there's no more likely or less likely
okay
okay so i i feel like i talked a lot
today but the point is you understand
yeah you understand yes okay good job
that's for today you can do something
bye bye
okay
hey
okay that's it that's it for today
[Music]