hello hello
hello
and how are you today
okay so we may talk about a compaction
they watch this work complex compress
and decompress impressed
no no decompress what's these two words
in english you press something
uh no compress compress and decompress
convex let's say that's something
i have something some data and i want to
i want to send it over to internet uh
send over the internet internet you know
the internet to your friends yeah that's
what i said
what what
it's pushing into the internet pushing
into internet no not yet
in the internet you have a data like you
have a very big data in a very big data
like a picture yeah a picture of you
right and it's a very big yeah
yeah it's very big maybe one megabyte
you know this is a data set right in
computer one bite yeah
one bite
equals eight bit yeah
and then one kilobyte
one kilobyte equals
this is two to the power of 10 10 bytes
and then 1 megabyte equals
10 24
kb and then what's that 1 gigabyte
equals 10 24
nb okay and then one terabyte yeah this
is the unit yeah it's
it means how big is the data why is it
10 24 because it's 2 to the power of 10
2 to the power 10 right
okay
one bite eight bit what spit
fit
zero five one
you bite no no no no
no no no no no
the basic
information to storing the data zero or
one right because computers
uses the electricity right now the
electricity has this
on off right and the voltage will be
high low so so it's binary yeah that's
why we always talk about binary in
computer science right because zero one
you know you make a
computer a cheap circuit
you can control
the electricity right you can control
the flow zero one
one byte eight bit
array
one gigabyte
or so 1024 byte okay and so on
so look if it's one megabyte if i have
two pictures one
one size is one megabyte and the other
one size is 10 megabytes which one
which one do you think is faster to send
over the internet if you want to send it
to your friend
ryan if you want to send it to your
friend lucas yeah
yeah
and that's ryan
yeah i'm going to send you over the
internet
right which one you think it will be
faster to send 10 mb
one megabyte and 20 megabytes the data
one megabyte why is that because it's
more where down is smaller right yeah
it's smaller
yeah okay so this is uncompressed okay
can i have your attention please keep on
hitting me
okay sit there please
okay so now
how well if i say i have 10 megabytes if
i compress it to let's say i compress it
to one megabyte and before sending
you know i compress it
compress it
and then when lucas receive it he
received one megabyte of data
he doesn't see
it it's great in it he doesn't see the
thing about then on this side he needs
to decompress it decompress the original
data
to become a 10 megabyte and
then he can view the picture right let's
compress and decompress makes sense so
why are we doing this because we want to
shorten the time to send over the large
amount of data because the traveling to
send over the internet it takes time and
generally the less amount of data the
faster right
i'm right
it's it's quicker to send over like one
picture rather than temperature right
all right over the internet because the
computer needs to you know travel the
you know route to the routing cables you
know
going to that city maybe going to
another continent you know in china
right it takes time
let's compress decompress okay compress
so compression has two kinds of
compression one is
lossy
the other one is
so
how does it mean lossy it means you keep
on losing stuff well done i lost this is
the opposite
so why is that sometimes look
okay so the the lossy people
if for example you're making calls yeah
you're making calls
it's a it's a bit maybe a bit okay to
you know to lose some data
the people over the other end can still
hear you
right a picture you compress the picture
right
you know that nowadays the camera right
very high quality you take a picture
like 10 megabytes but it has some
details that human eyes cannot
tell right a big picture if i compress a
little bit your eyes cannot tear so it's
okay it's
lossless
uh it's lossy right
and lossless is the of the opposite like
a data very important you can't lose
anything right
i compress the data and when i do the
compression it needs to be fully
you know
it needs to be exactly like the original
right
okay
okay well this is compressed and
decompressed
okay so one way of doing it can you tell
me how can look let me show you a few
data and i want to send it over the
internet and can you tell me how do we
compress it you know just any idea look
i have this data yeah
a a a a
b b b b b
c c c
c
d okay that's it e e e so we understand
this
what's your approach look there are four
a's five b's and four c's
you get them look there's four plus five
plus nine
four like that's 13 bites you have 13
bytes
one bar is one character yeah
okay
13 points yeah 35 let's that's the
amount of data
that's the amount of storage that
required by a computer to store this
data a character yeah remember we talked
about ascii why ask it remember
american standard
uh i i have no idea what they call me
information exchange or whatever yeah i
think it's
coding coding
interchange inter exchange information
or whatever yeah
look a
97 yeah remember
a
65 right this still remember this
yeah
so look the ascii
is from 0 to 255
what's that that's one bite
why is that one by eight bit
a b two to the power of eight
right that's two hundred fifty six
two hundred fifty six is from zero to
two hundred fifty five okay
so let's let's four bytes five bytes
four bytes that's 13 bytes
okay i have to if i i'm not compressing
this
if i'm not compressing this how many i
need to send certain bytes over the
internet is there a way let you know you
and your friend like your friend daniel
lucas
yeah can decompress on the other side
do not look at this pattern
let's be fair i'll give you one hint if
i have this a minion c
here
armenian sea
are you actually going to send a
ministry over there no then how do we
tell lucas your friend right then your
friend
to decompress
it you know instead of receiving that
amenity alien
can we just tell that
it has
one bite a hair has how many how many
number of c at the end and then lucas
can reconstruct the data
right
so how about if i tell if i
if i compress this using look 4 times a
5 times b
yeah
a million huh i don't know a million how
many zeros
six
six zero see
okay if i hop by if i sending this
over the internet
i will look at the authenticity from the
iron
he may seem exactly a string
but this is the compressed version so he
can compress it decompress it
he can decompress it yeah he said okay i
see it's four i have received a sequence
four a five b and a mean and c so you
will try to a plus a a a a b b b b b and
then b and c okay so which one is
quicker
which one is quicker
um very obvious which one
the second one yeah yeah because look
how many characters we need to see how
many bytes one two three four five six
seven eight nine ten eleven twelve
yeah 12 bytes
and how many bytes here
a minion and
a minion knife wow that's a huge
save right
make sense
yeah
that's complexion that's that's what
this is one of the basic
this is one of the basic techniques okay
there are many many compression
algorithms right and this is one of the
very very basic it's called run lens
run
lens why is called one lens because look
you're running and this is number of
lens yeah one lens
yeah
what is that you say round length yeah
this is kind of oneness
okay and then let's do this if we have a
data you know which is that encoded
version of the rundowns yeah for example
like what do we just say 4a
2b
3c
and then only there's only
only the lowercase characters okay if it
does if it doesn't contain the
the numbers yeah because if content
number there's no way to tell if it's
one or part of the
yeah
there's no long way to tell if it's part
of the lens or it's part of the data
okay so given this data we want to come
what's the
uh what's the decal version of the
original data 4a to b3c
we're done so that's it today's task
yeah
so we can just go through that let me
see i created
so we just go through these past this
string character by a character if it's
a digit if it's a digit we remember it
and if it's a character we we remember
it yeah and then
at the end we can use these remember we
can use in the pricing yeah in the past
and look
what's this four times
a impression right that will give
a a a right everybody
okay how about zero times
a b c what's the b
d l times a b c in pi zero
zero
it's nothing nothing empty string
so
we can use
look can you go let's see please all
right oh yeah see there
yes so we can have a data array right so
first this is array so look look at me
how i ins how i go through this
algorithm look
okay if it's a
if it's a number
i i remember it is four right
okay the next one is the letter a letter
a
then i push the number and
a in in the in this
and then number two again i remember
this and b
right
i look and i push it again two and b so
and then again three c actually see we
see the class okay so eventually we have
this data array which is like that okay
how about the digits could be multiple
right it could be more than 10 so if i
have 33c
if i have a 33c
if i have a 33c right
so we have first first of all we
remember the number three but the second
time
is also a digit so we need to update the
number with uh 233 and then until we
meet a character
a data
so we put it here we just put every time
we push a pair which is the number of
times the data has occurred right once
we have this data we can just return so
you'll become see
return
remember
john
so you want to join these two right
we're going to join these two
so theta
i
times
theta a prime a plus one right
theta i times i
for
i in
range
length data
right and the step is two right because
every time we we we go two step it's
four and then two and then thirty two so
we every time we we we construct this
piece
construct this piece and we join it
together okay but let's let's implement
this okay
let's implement it
what do you what did you do you just
said get it implemented yeah
defined define
players
or whether we have these what the string
s
first of all we need to account for c
equals zero and we put this answer in
the
line
and then go through this number for i
for we go through this string and
remember this 2 a 3 b
3 a 33 b
2 c okay
we go through this number
and then if if how do we check if this i
is an integer it's a number
it's a letter it's a digit from zero to
nine nine is a is a number so we can do
this if i dot is digit yeah
python has this function to check if
it's digit so this is the same same
thing as if i is bigger than 0 smaller
than
9 right or you can do this all right
this thing remember over the i
ord
is what 40 a right
is it for t n yes
okay
if i is it this digit
if it's digit then i want to update a
number which i can say c equals c times
right look i i'm currently at 3 and i
want to make 3 to 33 how can i do this 3
times ten
plus the second three yeah
a hundred twenty twenty eight if i'm fc
is a hundred is twelve and how can i
make c
c to be 128
c times ten plus a right got it that's
how we get the number c equals c times
10 plus the i is a digit so one way of
doing when we convert it
convert the digit to the integer or we
can do this we can do this over the i
and minus for the area this is the same
thing because the ascii code of the
ascii code of zero is 48 and we just
need to minus that
if it's a number we just we just update
the c and if it's not a number
we need to append it to the data i have
to answer answer the append
append c right and what's the next i
need to append remember i remember i
have this 2 and an a i need to append
this yeah 33 and bi
so what's this
one
i just pointed
i have the wrong letter
yeah
so once we look once this i
we push it then we need to update the
counter to what
we have to update the c to what we have
used it so we have to update prepare for
the next iteration which is to be set to
what the counter how many
c is the number of characters
you know
enough for the following characters so
what should i update c2
idea
c equals y come on
remember we have used this two twenty
two twenty two b and then before we want
to process the next pair so what's c
equals to at the beginning two now the
two is the next one one is zero nothing
nothing what's nothing in in numbers
list what's the matter what's the right
yellow come on okay i'm a football
player okay now look
now look hey
okay can you tell me what's the answer
after this right if the if the s is
2a
32b
7c
so can you tell me what the answer is
what does the answer contain
a
no no no the answer is the list remember
from c and i to it
we append c and i to it so what's the
what's the answer that's going to be
like
it's a list of pairs c and i see the
number
come on
it's a pair of uh he puts the you print
the c and he puts the i so what's c for
the first pair
um come on what's that next
and then
come on
33 and then
be
seven
yeah okay so that was that's what this
piece of work does to convert this s
into this bit yeah
but this is not a final answer we need
to
remember we need to
use the times this together yeah 2 times
a a 32 times
33 times b you know 32 b's together
seven c c c then we need to join them
together so we just pretend yeah i've
written this before right
join
answer
i
times answer
i plus one yeah answer i times i plus
one
four
i
in range
how many of these
lengths theta
okay it's actually it should be zero
let's theta two right because start from
zero and up to length theta and the step
is two
the step is two
okay
okay so uh make sense
yeah so what's this week can you tell me
what's this
it's doing great so what does this mean
this time this understands this like
this and i put it all together right yes
this time this is
yeah
okay what's the term complexity
n is the number of string characters
yeah what's the space complexity
um are we using this space
yeah
okay
okay that's it for today bye bye
bye