go
hello mister mister ryan how are you
today good okay so today we talked about
mass
you know concept it's called golden
ratio
golden ratio
what does it mean golden ratio
come on come on okay that's it
so if look
okay yes
so let's say if i have a
you know i have a mirror here somehow
what so if i let you undertand your
mirror okay and if i tell you like to
put a line
put a line a vertical line somewhere
where do would you like to put the
vertical line
in the middle
i love you
do you think in the middle is the most
elegant beautiful there's no right or
wrong answer you know
okay what's that
my answer okay okay that's it okay and
ryan what do you think you're going to
put a vertical line
vertical line just vertical and not much
horizontal
okay so what's this other personally
what's this
you don't know
just guess a rough guess
okay okay okay
yeah okay so not even a third no what's
that it's not
a fraction
no not equal
what's this bit how the
error says half i don't what's this
what do you determine this vertical line
is going to be
uh or you just let them guess random gas
okay
okay there's no right or wrong answer
come on
okay so man yeah
let's do this okay
look at my line
okay let's dash line okay so
how about if i tell you that okay if i
tell you listen if i tell you that okay
so there's a line separating that yeah
and then that would be
let's say this is a
and this is a this is b
okay
so this side is b this is size
a
this is size a this is size a plus b
okay why are you going to go with the
station again
okay and then
[Music]
if we have what if we only have one
all right if we have a plus b
which is this side okay a plus b which
is that the longer side
divided by the bigger side yeah bigger
side hey
if it's equal to what a a divided by b
okay
let's call this line
golden ratio listen have high resolution
if if this
so let's learn
you know two
two things the sum
of the two things
the ratio between and the sum to the
larger one it's the glacier simulation
with the larger one and the smaller one
so
in other words i have a line
okay and i have at least this is a
this is b
and if i can say a plus b the whole
thing divided by a
is the same as a divided by b now we
call this a golden ratio
the bigger side a let's a divided by b
are good and ratio
that's mathematics why is it golden
ratio it's golden so it means that okay
no you know ideally you put a line there
it's it's most beautiful right okay
i only say it's most beautiful but you
know it's it's more like you know good
it's not beautiful sorry no beautiful i
don't get
what
okay so you'll be like okay so let's say
it's golden ratio it's just the one
ideal way to put to to set
you know to divide the segment into two
okay
what's that
okay okay so look
mathematically okay mathematically yeah
mathematically huh
we use this with symbol
together
this is greek uh greek greek greek
letters greek another quick
that looks like a vagabond yeah yeah
these are these yeah
these are these we call we call we
pronounce this as five
five p h i how do you pronounce this phi
five five okay
okay so now look if we rearrange this
look if we have this equation and we
want to rearrange it so how can we
arrange this one
okay
look i think
a divided by 4 equals four divided by
two right yeah
yeah all right
this is two this is two yeah
so how can we arrange this
eight times two
eight times two sixteen four times four
okay so same here same here
a square
equals a times b
plus a divided by 4 equal to 4. okay
what's this look what's
this what's this look if i said a square
minus b square
minus a b equals zero okay
okay i'm just okay so given this
equation how do you
you know put it together so you can put
it together
i'm just example okay so this is z is
two no no it's not no we want to find
out the value of b and a
right and now we're given this equation
and how can we
uh and you know
to make it a quadratic equation
make sense
so if it's on the other side of the
equation if we move to the right
left-hand side we need to put the
negative sign all right we talked about
this before right
yeah okay on the right-hand side is b
square if we move to the left-hand side
of the equation we need to put negative
right all right
yeah and this is the sense
so look if let's say if b equals one
okay
if let's say b equals one we want to
calculate a right because the golden
ratio is a divided by b
right will be the same a divided by b
equals a plus b the sum divided divided
by the larger sum okay that's the goal
generation okay
maybe yeah when i was
rephrasing it as a beautiful one maybe i
was not correct right it's just the
golden ratio
okay let's just remember this
okay so look if b equals one then we can
we can do one
x a squared minus y
minus a
minus one equals zero what's this
causative equation we talked about this
do you remember that the thing is yeah
the thing remember remember
the thingy what's going to call this
polar bear
okay okay
so this look at us
all right come on
go press it okay so this let's let's
solve this equation okay let me switch
the number how do we solve this equation
so we can use the five
to get it okay we can use the five the
phi
right
yeah fine
minus one
so this is the equation we're going to
solve all right remember we got a
quadratic equation
can i have your attention please
yeah okay we're listening come on come
back okay so how do we zone this
i haven't been doing anything yeah i'm
not i'm talking to eric what what's this
project equation yeah y
remember this do you still remember this
because every equation there are two
roots there are two rules of it
yeah
and you remind me 2 times a
minus b
plus minus
b squared minus 4 times ac and this is
the numerator we prove this in one of
the previous
video yeah
there are two roots of these so what's a
of this what's what's the a of this
equation
what's the a of this equation
what's the a
it is uh
what's the a of this equation x squared
minus x minus one equals zero
okay what's the equation what's the
value of a
the value of a is
x squared
now x squared here what's the value of a
come on it's there x squared x squared
what's the value of a
x
squared
x squared what's the value of a x
squared x squared times what equals x
square
one what's the value of a
one
what's the value of b
plus b x minus x plus b
zero
plus zl times x will be zero the whole
thing will become what's the value of x
one
one is plus x this is minus x what's the
value of x
um what's the value of b sorry
b b
plus b
plus b equals one what's this what's
this term minus
so what's the value of b
what's the value
minus
minus one minus one
what's the value of c
so
let's convert this yeah equals one 2
times a
minus b would be one
plus equal plus minus okay b square
b square one
one minus minus four equals one
one minus
minus four what's this what's the value
of this one minus minus four
one minus minus four
huh come on less
it's minus three
one minus minus four one minus four this
is minus three
i said minus three one minus minus y
equal
one minus one four equals five equals
five yeah you know that yeah if you say
one is minus is equal to plus yeah yeah
yeah five okay so there are no two loops
okay so
let's say two
1 plus
these and
1 plus 1 minus
square root of 5 divided by 2. do we
know the value of
this mommy teaches me that
yeah okay so what's the value of this
okay square root of five you know we
talked about how to estimate using one
method before right 3.1
2.1 now
it's quite close how about you
what's the value of this very close it's
okay
because this is the irrational number
yeah remember you made one i don't know
how to spell this investigation
oh i saw that in the match station yeah
yeah
what's going on
okay very close but not yet okay
equation number is the fraction that
cannot be represented by p divided by q
where p and q are integer and q is not
zero okay and simp
rational number is the opposite it's the
why isn't it
okay okay let's use it
okay i use a calculator okay because
i use the calculator well i want to get
the see that password that's okay that's
okay come on can you sit by 11. oh yeah
okay 2.25 times 2.25 equals five
five point zero
five
times 2.23
okay so any
4.9729
no 2.232
times
2.232
equals
yeah
so it's roughly two point two
three
two maybe yeah
i don't know i i need to check okay 3.33
how about two points
okay two point two three six okay the
answer is two point two three six here
two point two three six okay let's say
two point two six six because look at
this number two point two three six
times two point two three six
equals four point nine nine nine nine
it's very close to five right
so this is number it's very close to
five okay okay let's see so
so look this is the we talk about
fraction number yeah because look at 100
divided by a this is a simple fraction
number yeah and then there's some number
which is irrational but we talked about
easier pi remember
this is irrational number and then look
this equal
approximately equal to 2.236 and we want
to
calculate this yeah we want to check
your list so let's pack this value in
equals
2.266 and this whole thing is equal
3.236 divided by 2. what's this
what's this
3.236 divided by 2. come on what's this
1.618 right
yeah
am i right
yes
[Music]
3.236 divided by 2 equals 1.618 yeah i
just show you right
okay 1.68 okay this is approaching the
golden ratio okay this is the value
remember
1.618 yeah how we get it remember how we
get it
x square minus x minus one equals this
one rule yeah two one
and the other rule yeah the other root
is one
one minus
this well this is the two root and this
is equals to minus
0.618 okay this is minus
okay
okay so look how do we estimate this
yeah remember we talked about fibonacci
number yeah yeah what's fibonacci number
come on give me a few seconds one one
two
three five five hey eight
no no no 56 and what's next
uh i'm so just 91. okay yeah it's 91.
yes why you say just kidding it's 91
okay
okay so why are we starting this again
look if this is the value the first
value is b the second value is a
what's the next value
what's the next video p-a
it's 147. yeah p-a and the next one is b
plus a yeah a plus b okay am i
okay
okay that's it that's it look
b a a a plus b okay right this is the
consecutive uh three terms okay the
ratio okay let's say if this is going
big you know because this sequence is
going infinity right it's going infinity
right i'm right so the ratio between
these two will be converged will
converge to a value let's look
look
look look a plus b
divided by a equals a divided by b what
have you noticed what have you noticed
look at this what have you noticed look
it's b the the fibonacci sequence b a
and the next items a plus b
yeah come on
because this this a and b is going
infinity yeah it's going to
infinity so we can say it's converge we
have the ratio of converge and look the
ratio between a plus b divided by a is
the same as a divided b b so what are we
talking about here remember
what's this
this is a this is b
the whole thing
come on the whole thing a plus b divided
by a equals a divided by b so what's
this binary search what's this
what have we talked about is the word
here we what is
yeah
that's what we study okay so if we
ideally if we we uh
we printed out the uh so if we keep
going this fibonacci number
so we will find the golden ratio okay
look so we can say okay n equal a
thousand maybe then we can say a equals
one b equals one
four
for underscore
in
range
and then look at a b and what's the next
item it will be b and then a plus b
right and if the understand we bring
if we find the value final value which
what's the value of it b is bigger yeah
b
times one point zero we want to convert
it this integer to the floating number
divided by a
and you will see you will see the
numbers
golden ratio converts yeah so then
finally the coordination will be this
number b times 1.0 divided by at least
is the golden ratio five five
okay
so
let's do this what's the one 147 divided
by 91 okay
what's 66
no you see one one four seven are you
sure
divided by
1.615 right you see
it's very close to
1.618 this is the golden ratio we just
talked about okay so let's try next item
next new item what's in the next few
items next few items is one
what's this what's this one divided by
no no no 147 plus
91 equals one two three eight
okay and now what's next what's next
number
plus one four seven
three eight five and and then
last two three eight
two three yeah okay so let's let's let's
calculate this ratio yeah this this
value divided by this okay
six two three divided by three a five
equals look look look we got the
children ratio yeah you see 1.618
you see
so that's the beauty fibonacci number
when it goes infinity
the next item the ratio between the next
item and the current item will be
converging to 1.618.
yeah let's go
you can find many many
uh instances many many things you know
the the nature yeah or mathematics you
know many many things they obtain this
golden ratio
law
all right look this is at b this is a
the next item is a plus b okay
yeah so a plus b
divided by a equals a divided by b okay
so this is the relation okay
all right makes sense
so we have what have we learned so far
today the golden ratio and what's that
what's that can you explain to me what's
going on
so look if there is a segment and this
is a this is b and what's the golden
ratio how confidently
what's happening
so what's the golden ratio a and b
[Music]
what the last sum always the sum
divided by which one a or b the larger
sum yeah
all right one
equals one
a plus b times b equals a square right
and this is a b plus b square equals a
squared
okay this is look if this is b if b is
one then we can say
a plus one equals a squared right and
then we go to let's go to what a square
minus a minus one equals zero and we
already know how to solve this using
causative equation yeah
yeah two a's
the root will be one plus there are two
roots yeah one plus square root of five
and one
uh 1 minus square root of 5 divided by 2
and then we talk about how to estimate
the square root of 5 right yeah the
other way of estimating the square root
of 5 how can we extend it look
what square root of 5. let's say what's
the biggest square root let's say that
gives us you know
what's the biggest square root integer
part
is it going to be three
three point something or two point
something
which which one square root of five
six point something yeah because three
point something would be nine right over
nine right two point something is less
than five right yeah okay so let's say
two plus this is two point something x
squared
equals 5 right yeah this is the small
part okay and then look
remember
a plus b
square equals a squared plus b squared
plus 2 a b right all right
so we we know this x square
this s squared because this is a
fraction it's very small we can just
abandon it for for now then let's say
2 squared plus 2 times
a b that'll be four x equals five
yeah because there's a less s square
here right
let's say s square here but it's too
small let's forget it about now so four
plus four x equals five what's x
uh
a quarter right
0.25 okay so now we have the good
estimation we're plugging back so that's
2.25 plus x
yeah so that's the
eric look
yeah 2.25 you get 2.95 right at the
beginning right yes yeah that's how we
get get it
you know
you get it and then 2.25 plus x
squared square equals five and we keep
doing this until we get a very good
estimation okay yeah
okay let's say for today i feel like
talk too much today
bye bye bye
bye bye