[Music]
okay so today we're going to talk about
the sum of the first and
numbers okay some we already know this
oh
first you're right now
easy
okay okay wait wait wait wait no you
have no yeah let's talk
please if you want to release okay so
look the first one number the sum
is what one the first four
all numbers four you just
square it wow how do you know
that's nine right and what's next
you see obviously you can have this one
less one square not two numbers two
squares three number three square
four number is four squared so that's
the trick yeah
[Music]
moving too right and then we what what
was here
[Music]
we want to add the number so what's what
okay so what's the time complexity of
this algorithm
do we need the extra space to store this
what's the space complexity
no we don't need any space a one or one
constant okay now if i
have another function g to calculate two
less than c
we tan n times n
so what's the time complexity yeah
what's the time complexity
what's the space complexity
and one one or one as well because we
don't need any space so which one is
better
it's um it's quicker because if i if the
n
is one million then you have to get one
three
five seven that's this approach with o n
but before this one we don't need it
right yes
[Music]
please please keep quiet keep quiet
please now we want to
prove that the formula is correct by
using the mathematic induction remember
a few days ago we talked about
mathematic induction yeah
induction this is going to take forever
you say that every time
okay now so the formula is f of
n equals n times n right yeah yes
and what's the base case f1 equals one
walking around
[Music]
f k plus one is still correct so this
is f k plus one equals f k
and then we just need to one more add
one more
uh one more number yeah the second
the first k odd no k
is one two three it's basically the
first so let's k
k plus one uh k plus one
k plus one odd number will be two times
k
plus 1 right right look if k is 1
and the next k next whole number is what
if k is 1 the next whole number will be
if k is 2 the next whole number is
the second let's if k
is two so the third odd number will be
one
five yes five right
right yeah because the 8k is two then
the first
one second will be one third and the
third one will be right right
so we now have length sorry
fk equals k times k right yeah plus 2k
plus one
[Music]
ym so this
is what this is actually k plus one
square right why are we doing why
because i want to prove letter
f k look look can you get it and again
look
look k times k plus 2 k plus 1 is
actually this is k
so look at a plus b square what does it
equal
equals a squared plus b
squared plus what can you guess
c c what's c c square
there's no c k two times
a b okay a squared plus b square
equals two okay let's try this number
three times
three plus four square right
equals three square plus four squared
plus
two times three times one that's okay
seven plus four equals seven as three
plus four equals seven
seven square equals forty nine right
yeah three square
nine four square sixteen
two times three times four
twenty-four
twenty-five yeah plus twenty-four
uh 49. you see yeah
[Music]
yeah yeah yeah it's it's easier look so
a square plus
a plus b squared equals a squared plus
squared plus 2a b
so look k square k squared
1 2 times k 1 so look so what we have
done
is that we prove that f k plus 1 equals
k plus 1 square so this formula stands
yeah
so we have to prove that the first all n
all numbers the sum
is is what n times n
all right yes so any questions
no no questions no no
bye-bye okay that's it today say goodbye
so tomorrow we're going to talk about
first and
even numbers it's going to be fun okay
we'll see you tomorrow
see you tomorrow