go
hello
so we have a you know the computer we
have keyboards yeah we have this control
c okay
ctrl c yeah okay so what's that ctrl c a
copy copy copy where
copy what and then ctrl v
paste it we want to paste why wouldn't
control p
that's a good question control p is for
print very very good question okay
control plus p is usually print you know
ctrl v i don't know why is it called v
but it's actually paste control
so when we control c so if we have a
test like eric and ryan yeah
if we select you know we select we stand
the text
press ctrl c
and
the selected text or image or file
whatever you selected
is paste is it store one copy in a clip
clipboard
paper okay so in the buffer we have this
error right
okay
and then i control v again and then
we will have it
right here and if i keep practicing
you'll have multiple copies of that
right okay let's just control
sequentially
okay make sense
that's it
so today we there's a very simple uh you
know very interesting math problem so if
we have a keyboard right if we have a
keyboard like can you go back if we have
a keyboard like only have one character
which is a
right if we have a unless
at the beginning there's only one a in
the screen
so for each operation you can
do this you can select
you can
control
control c
or
current a's or a's yeah in a screen
or you can control v
control v to paste whatever in the
buffer yeah paste paste whatever you
copied last time
right so let's give an example we want
to find out the minimum number operation
to get the number uh to get n a for
example if i want to have a
sorry if i want to have
two a's
how can we do it so at the beginning we
only have one egg how can we make using
these two operations to make two days
come on quite easy yeah
a control c you have to start with one
name control c yeah yeah it's easier
control c and control v where done
because control c you copy this a and
then console v you put an a in there
right
okay how about
if it's only one a do we need to do
anything else no no because there's only
one okay so for that one a input one a
we need a zero operation two a's we need
a two because copy and paste three a's
you need
three three
copy
paste paste right
copy paste place three
four eight three
three or four come on easy three
three four three
minimum the better you say four you said
three
oh
yeah
that's the thing look so first of all
so first of all you copy you copy one a
yeah yeah you paste it
two a's twice
then you copy again oh copy again and
then paste it again so that's that's
four right is the four yeah yeah
okay so it's the same thing as copy
paste paste paste right
it's full copy paste space paste so you
can have copy face paste space or you
can have copy
paste paste copy paste paste copy paste
all fours yes
okay
five okay a a
a
can we do better no
there's no other way right
because it's five right it's fine
fine okay this is comes with interesting
ones six you will have six
how can we do this one two copy
copy
paste
and then copy
paste paste
right all you can do is copy paste
paste
copy
paste right which one is cluster copy
paste
copy
paste yeah you see or
paste paste
paste paste space space
or copy
paste
copy
okay seems fine yeah it seems fine yeah
you see
did you get it yeah so that goes on yeah
yeah
all right
so we can do this profile so yeah of
course we can try because for each
operation we can keep trying for each
one we can say it's copy or paste we can
keep trying this until we get it but
this is quite uh quite slow right
because there are lots of possibilities
for each operation there are two right
we can for each one we can say we can
choose copy or we can choose space why
does it need to be a
sorry why are there any a is there's
only one characters well why does it
have to be a
oh it could be b b whatever then the
point is that we need n we need these
two operations to come up with n exactly
n
times
a okay or whatever letter you choose
okay so this problem is quite clear okay
so how can what how can we minimize this
one how do we minimize this
so look if i have
look look if i have nine a's
so what's how do we quickly come up with
9 8
if we have three characters three a's in
the buffer we can press copy paste paste
three times right yeah all right okay so
another example if i have uh
if i have 99 a's
one obvious way you can copy one and
press paste 98 times right
yeah
that's that's obviously you can for n a
if n bigger than or e bigger than one
then that's the most the slowest method
you can say is end and anyway exactly
because you copy one a and you press
press
and minus one time right
yeah hold it so what's about me holding
it
hold it yeah yeah hold it
you get it right 1998 one slowest way i
can think of is i copy one a because i
already have one a right i copy one a
that takes one time
and i put press paste 80 98 times right
yeah
right or i can i can do what i can copy
i can copy three uh i can copy one
i can copy three a's
right
copy paste paste
and i copy these
yeah then i have three a's and i press
32 times
right
like make sense because each time i
press ctrl v
that would be 3 8 am right
makes sense
makes sense so obviously this is quicker
because look copy
paste paste
copy paste paste and copy
four times and then i need to press how
many of v
32 times right 32 times 30 times of v so
all together that will be 34 32 plus 4
which is less than
99 we're talking about right
99 we're talking about okay
make sense right yeah it was
98 because you need to chris knight
19 i want the 99 99 a right
i want to 99 8 so now i have uh
oh yeah you are right 32
because all together is 33 nine
33 times of a and i already have three
a's so i need to press another 32 times
to cut paste three a's 32 times right
okay
okay so this is interesting yeah because
we look if so we can
as we talk about the blue force is too
slow yeah we're not going to do the full
first thing here because it's so slow
right
so how about if i have an s function
a function f n
yeah
if n if i if it's you know if it's the
number the minimum number of uh
if it's the minimum number operations to
get n right
and i can send them it's equals to mean
mean of what medium
because i want to try
try to try all possibilities try all the
factors yeah factors
fine
like for example like 10 what's the
factor of 10
five right i want to try two and five
right because if f2 can be
if f2
yeah i can i can copy i can copy the f2
two characters in the buffer and i can
play page five times or i can copy five
characters into the buffer and press the
ctrl v two times right and i want to
compare the minimum of these
right i want to compare minimum please
make sense
[Music]
it doesn't make sense yeah it makes
sense yeah how about 20
what's the factor of 20
20 keys what's the fact that 2
10 yeah up to half right so now
now if this is f another function and i
can i can see if this is from another
sub problem right sub problem then i can
say okay
if i have i know the answer of
if this is a time this is b times this c
times this c times and then the minimum
will be what
means
a
plus
20 and two divided by two right it needs
another ten times right
all right place ten times right
and then mean and then what b
plus how many twenty divided by four
five times
c
twenty c plus twenty divided by five
four times
ten 20 divided by 10 to plus d to the
potential right so i want to get these
four numbers and
get the minimum
what's this up what's this kind of thing
well we talked about the thingy you know
what's this we talk about the thingy
what's this
yeah dynamic programming we have two
ways of doing it which is what
what
yeah the fibonacci number remember
yeah number
yeah
all right
uh fibonacci number yeah
ff f7 equals f6 plus f5
s6 plus equals f5 plus f4
okay about it yeah typical nice number
if you're going this way that will be
top down if you're going that way
starting from f1 s2
to fn that's butter up right
it's going this way uh that would be
when using the top down right make sense
right
so let's quickly implement uh top down
okay because top down gives the most
intuitive way of solving this problem
okay
define
n
obviously if n smaller or equals one
then we return zero right because we
already have one characters
yeah we don't need to continue right
there's only one characters then that's
it
now let's say answer equals what let's
say what's the slowness remember we
talked about the slowest way to come up
with n character what's the slowest way
how many answer equals one
what's your opinion
the very big number or what
[Music]
right we talk about this is the slowest
way right if left and a
i can copy one a and press nine times
place place nine times right so one plus
nine equals ten right this is zero yeah
and then i fall i
in range
i start with the second yeah and up two
and divided by 2 plus 1 yeah because up
to n divided by 2 and we give a plus 1
because this gives the inclusive this
number is increasing and divided by 2.
so now if
n
modulus i equal equals zero right look
look look i want to get the f10
all right f10 and then i fi
so what's the factor this is together
factor yeah two five right yeah
i know what should we do answer
equals mean
answer
and so what look
f
f what f i
f y y come on plus what
what
x y plus one
x y plus one come on think about it
what's the f5 f5 as well
and then return obviously
f2
plus one plus one five times yeah so now
what's b i
i is two so what's what's this
and
divided by
i right because you need that term right
look n is ten i is two twenty divided by
five
all right
yeah all right
one thing is missing if i don't put that
cash well done yeah because look this is
expand you know exponentially
you need to put a cash to remember the
fn because we don't want to repeatedly
take away fl right this is the same
thing as the fibonacci number right
yeah
top down top down and actually what's
the time complexity if it is
[Music]
don't worry about the complexity
remember the square
yeah yeah yeah
we can always verify the the tom come
next using butter up okay let's try the
butter
up
[Music]
let's say i convert it to
range range and plus one yeah because we
want to return
everything ryan can i have your
attention from the last time please let
me go backstage
[Music]
return dp this is the value i want to
store the number uh to store the value
so which which value should i return
okay right
dp which value dpi stores the number of
uh
stores of the answer for so what's the
dptpu
[Music]
and yeah dp and the last value of tp
minus one yeah this is the same
so now look i have what i have uh four
i
in range
i start from the second yeah because i
already know the first one and then up
to m plus one
and i can start from another for loop
for j
in range
start from the two i up to i plus one
well i divided by 2 plus 1
right
and then now we can try if
if i modulus j equal equal 0 right
dp
i equals mean of dpi okay so tell me
what's right here it's quite similar dpi
what
what if i found j is the one of the
factor of i
and dpi is the number the minimum number
of operations to come up with i
a's yeah
ias
so what's the value of dpi we want to
get the minimum all right you just you
was just saying if that 10 10 if i found
the 10
and then i is two and what's the value
dpi because um two and five are more
closer to each other and one on ten is
more
okay that's a very interesting point but
look here i have i call i a yeah i want
to come up with i
i want to come up with i and i know j
j yeah is the one of the factor of i so
it equals what dp j
plus 1 plus 1
plus 1 i
look dpi plus i y
i need to divide
divided by because j time man i have
already i i i already have j
i already have j in the clipboard in a
buffer and i need to press how many
times i divided by j times right i have
two in the buffer i have two in the
buffer right so i have to have to place
five times yeah four times yeah because
i have to copy one and uh press four
times so it's one plus four equals five
right
all right
repeating zero okay so what's the time
complexity if you're looking this this
is quite obvious alright
everyone come on what's the
what's the time conversation if you look
at this
come on hurry up
why is the one square can you tell me
[Music]
so remember the previous one
top down here
there is only one four but inside the
four you need to do cushion two
different cushions to get the other
values so this is actually another four
right so it's actually the same o n
square and this one this one is bottom
right which one you think is better
which one is this one this one this one
because there's no recursion right
there's no recursion and you can just
implement but this needs to
you need to do it the in a reverse order
from the bottom to the up right and you
need to create we need to create an dp
array yeah dpi dpi at the beginning
equals i right because they have the
slope right
all right yeah okay so there are 10 a's
what's the what's the number of uh ways
you can do it okay if i want to have 10
8 come on one last question
how can we do it
come on think about it give me answer
let me let me check what's the 10 a yeah
how many how many
five
two five six six six six i'll turn it to
the sixth one
what six so we've won yeah
copy copy
okay so you try look okay
first of all copy
second place
you have two a's yeah an hour and paste
paste paste paste how many one two three
four five six
is it
because um because you know the practice
thing um
um and you do the one which is closer to
each other
why why is there one
[Music]
one time is it six really
copy
copy paste
and then
paste paste paste paste place paste
paper paste
copy paste
facebook
copy say copy
so copy
paste and then you need to copy again
you need to copy again look ryan yeah
here's one one missing
yeah you need to copy again because
otherwise the password is only one a
copy paste right
and i need to copy to make a two a's and
then copy paste space spaces one two
three four five six seven yeah that's
seven okay
that's the other how about we do these
five
look at copy
paste paste
paste paste and copy
paste how many one two three four five
six seven it's also okay
both ways okay okay
why copy let's know is what let's not
say copy
copy copy
good job