so it's a package so usually we say from
by set
we can import two functions
import two function which is bisect left
and bisect right okay we're going to
talk about this today
by set finally finally search finally
yeah remember if we have a
if we have a sorted array right
certainly one two three four five
however if it's the salty
if it if this array at least is sorted
we can find uh element which is pick uh
you know
if it's in in array which is pretty fast
right yeah and the time complexity if
that n element is oh
you should know this if there are n
low levels
because every time we can do this final
research yeah half yeah but if it's not
salted
if it's not salted we need
oh and lock the end to sort it yeah this
is sorting
and if we do this linear swatch
like if we are performing the search
checking india
if we're doing this linear search
from the beginning to the end yeah one
two three and the time complexity will
be what in the worst case if we're going
to each element one by one what's the
time complexity anyone
you know oh what the worst case this is
super easy
oh and yeah because in the worst case
it's you need to check an element okay
that's pretty big spacey
so bicep okay so if i have a
if i have a
array sorted array like one two two
three three three four five okay
so bisect left and backs and right
returns the the
instruction
position okay so isaac left it one two
two and okay
four five five if look if it binds left
the first if this is array the first one
the first parameter is the
the list so we give list and the second
parameter is the number the x
the x yeah so you can say x equals
let's say three
so you will return a position
right so you you will return here
uh here right
so you will return a partition in this
insertion point you will return the
insertion point
what's insertion
insertion point i
right so
a up to i
for e
in
so any elements in up to i element i is
all
smaller
smaller than
never than x uh
smaller than x
right so i i insert
so the insertion point will be here
because all the elements up to these
three look look
here it's all smaller than three right
and all the
all the elements at
i from index i afterwards is all bigger
or equal
x okay
and then the opposite the opposite bicep
right
bicep right
a3 okay so
it's different it will be returning the
insertion point here
right
all right
so what does it mean here it's quite
similar except that
a i
e in a i and e is smaller or equal x
right or this is smaller equal x because
i pass 3 here so all these are smaller
or equal to x
and all the elements start from i
is bigger than x
okay
make sense
so let's
do this and i'm going to test it give
you a small test
yeah
so and every element up to this
insertion point will be smaller what
question are you gonna give
i'm going to give another another one so
or maybe this one and i'm going to
change this to two so you tell me what's
the insertion of the left and what's the
interesting i don't understand what's
going
on
i'm just explaining here so bison that
returns insertion point so we're going
to put the element three in this sorted
array
to the left
so
so if i have a three here right
and i put it here so to all the elements
so the new three will be here right
there's already three i know but okay so
i can put that yeah but why is it there
why is that what do you mean
so this is the new insertion point
you don't get it
then why does definitely go down
that that would be returning that's what
i'm saying that would return the
insertion point i
where to put the element x this is x x
equals three
so you need to put it here right because
all the elements up before after this
point are smaller than the x right
because all the other they need to be
bigger
yeah
but this right is slightly different is
that you need
the insertion point left the same but
it's at the right yeah okay so let's
just say but just at the right
side
yeah yeah yeah most likely so because
this is smaller or equal x and this is
smaller than an x right because i happen
to three
in all the left to the left everything
to the left of the insertion point needs
to be strictly smaller but bisect right
it's all the elements on the left hand
side yeah this this one yeah look
it's smaller or equal too right got it
okay so if i have two here bisect left
two where's where do you think you're
going to be
can you point to me
here or here come on let's buy set left
two if it's two
where
yeah this one too and if it's bisected
right two what where is it going to be
here
right because all the elements need to
yeah it's the same as three okay
you know we can implement this using
linear search look look for yeah look so
how can we implement this let's let's
implement bicep left using the linear
search
okay
let's just just quickly write it define
bisect
left
sometimes biset is equals to by the left
okay
a
x okay
i need
by default it has two parameters by
default x equal uh it has the lower
index equals zero right by default
default parameter and the high equals
none if high is none then
then high is the length of the
a
yeah so we can just do this for
power for i in range
length a
right
then we can say if a i
i
if a i a i is the right book if a i is
look on the bicep left is strictly
smaller than x right so if i a i
okay one two two three three three four
five
so if i said left two by the left
three you give me
here right so if this element is is what
bison left
okay i'm i'm ready to
so look bison left yeah question left
he's here bison right
three
is here right
so the left if if 3 is bigger
it's bigger or equal right it's bigger
it should be bigger or equal right
x then we return i am right
make sense
and otherwise i will return the first
one right return if if what happened if
what happened what happened if there's
this element is
right
if this element x is 100 and the first
element to add is at the end right
if the element is zero
okay so this element is bigger than that
then
big or equal
it's bigger equal than every 10 i right
so let's let's give an example like if i
want to input x equals 0 look at me
yellow
a i
1 is bigger or equal than 0 so i return
here that's correct
how about one
one is bigger or less than i written
here correct if it's two
one is smaller than two no and then two
is bigger or equal than two so always i
return that right so that's correct
so otherwise i return the length of a
right
all right so what's the time context if
you look at this one
[Music]
we're gonna strongly start to the end
what's the time domestic
all right right we are not making we are
not using the uh advantage of you we are
not getting this advantage of using this
uh
sorted right so we are not using that
why
good question that's what i'm going to
do next okay so look present right so
for example if i said right so this one
needs to be so we just have to change
this equal to bigger right so if it's
equal then i keep going
right
and if it's bigger look four is bigger
than three then i less the insertion
point right so the difference between
bison left and bison right in if it's a
linear search the difference is just
this sign
right because all the bison left
by the left is everything needs to
strictly smaller than x right
basically like this
it's not because we have this equals
and as we said this is the slope because
we're not using this uh set that the
array is sorted
why
good question then i'm going to
implement this
okay
now let's implement this
define
by set
left
a
x
low equals zero
high equals
equals num okay now let's do this
okay first of all if low is smaller than
zero yeah we can't support it that we
can just raise
raised very well or whatever you said
you know very well
okay okay you can put a custom error
message here right
this is this is for computer to screen
that okay you give me a value low which
is negative which i can't handle i'm not
happy
raise exception
or essentially a third is quite similar
okay
then how then look if high
is none
then i high will be equal to length of
the a right
now we can say
wire
low smaller than high
right
what mid
how do i get the middle if i have lower
and half upper
[Music]
lower
divided by two right
[Music]
okay right
so look and now look if
i check the middle yeah if a meat
is smaller than x
if the middle one is smaller than left
then what should we do if the middle one
is smaller than legs then
the waist is going to be if it if the
middle one is smaller than x what what
what's it going to be
look
look this is
meat here because it's salty right low
this is high i don't like it
look if the middle one
even the middle one
yeah yeah
if
if the middle one
if the middle one is more if the element
a middle one is smaller than the element
we're looking for so which half is going
to be
where's the element going to be
it's in which side
the left
look like it's the middle one it's the
smaller than what are we looking all
right yeah so okay so then we say what
so we move it to the
to the right low equals meat plus one
right that's my high spell line
yeah yeah okay that's fine
from the left side so we can say what
pi
[Music]
shorter is better yeah but i'll say he
returned
okay let me just check a little bit yeah
return
[Music]
okay so actually because the parameter
is low okay
sometimes look
sometimes there's another actual
parameter which default is key so you
can specify how to compute the key so
you can put a key here right and if key
isn't it's not empty you can just say
key like
i'm calling the key function
yeah sometimes you can pass the customer
key function in there
uh what's the time complexity for this
one this is biceps
on everyone
what's the time complexity if it is if
we are fine
okay let's try to change this to
look
listen to me listen to me why this is
this is okay because every time we check
this case here
includes the equal sign right so when
it's equal
then we want to move it to the left as
as much as we can right so you
eventually you will be at the first
insertion point right
so
so look if we try to do this bicep right
everything would stay the same but
but i just need to change this to bigger
than x and then i will swap it to
high equals mid
as this is equal sign
slow equals mid plus one
right so when it's equal then i will i
want to move this insertion point to the
right so that's why lower i will move it
to upper upper bound all right towards
the right
everywhere are you all right yes what's
the timing of next for this one as well
five cent right
okay so can you explain to me what's the
difference between pisces that's the
best advice
[Music]
writing is different yeah i'm sorry well
the insertion point is different right
followed by them let's let's do and this
thing is different come on come on come
on come on last time yeah
and a line just okay but not
[Music]
okay so what's the bite look at this
where's the bison left four you mean not
on the right no no no look this is still
why is the left four
where it's going to be where do you want
to put the four in the second two
four i want to put a four in this
thought to the right so where it's going
to be
where come on
four
three five three five so it's in
here right
right here pointing to five yeah yeah
because let's go where the four is going
to be
okay and bisect right four is it the
same one is it the same three no no no
where is going fork on the big one
it's the same it's the center so lonely
difference the only difference is what
the bicep is that duplicate any man
right look let's try another one pisces
left there's two cheese two okay where's
spicer left one okay yeah what's right
left two which one is going to be the
first time
first two yeah because yeah i said two
the second two
the right okay this is before where
yeah three
okay so why because right on the left
all the left will be
smaller or equal right but for the left
you will be only the left half will be
only smaller right because if you put a
two here
everything up to the two should be
up to the two only one super yeah i know
it's strictly smaller but for the right
bicep right this is
treated or is smaller or equal right so
it's here right don't make sense
yeah i know it's two sorry if it can be
equal why isn't it two
what do you mean which one the bison
right two right
yeah but it's the right two so we put it
here because everything after this point
is three said it can be you make me two
yeah that's why it's equal to two yeah
you want to expand
these not equal to two that's why we put
it here we input it here all right
okay
okay uh
so let's try this let's emulate this one
a little
bit high
meat
[Music]
if this point this this meat is bigger
than what we are looking for where is it
going to be that's all right
if the middle one is bigger than the
element we're going to look for so where
is this going to be left or right come
on
it's here what's this high equals middle
is it left or right
high high equals mid right
left
not just guessing why look middle
this meter thing a meter bigger than x
right
and then high equals mid so it's left
i said that yeah left okay yes low
equals me high so you basically moving
this low to the middle yeah
yeah
okay that's it for today good job
say bye bye
bye bye
bye