go
hello hello mr mr ryan how are you today
we have talked about air is longest
increasing subsequence longest
increasing what's subsequent yeah
subsequence
what's the difference between
subsequence and supplement array or
sub-list
which one is continuum okay so look
third one three two four one seven
okay ten
sub list continues so it has to continue
yeah
yeah and usually we start sub this
program we can we can proof us in o and
square time right because you always we
can try every possibility of a of sub
list
by determining the left point
and then profiling the right point
that's o n squared but for subsequence
what's the subsequence
each subsequence you take
arbitrary number of elements from the
original way you delete it yeah and then
the remaining is the subsequence for
example it does not have to be continued
like three four
seven or
three two four yeah two seven six okay
two seven six is this the subsequence or
something
with subsequence
yeah okay you're listening okay okay so
long what's the longest subsequence in
this case what's the longest subsequence
what's the longest subsequence
everywhere what's the longest subsequent
three two four one seven takes ten
longest increasing subsequent okay
increasing substance
[Music]
but you're right about subsequent i
didn't say increasing yeah
it's the whole thing yeah
great job
and increasing
sorry increasing increasing one
uh all i can find is pen
two for
increasing subsequence you know it does
not have to continue the longest
like
the longest subsequent which one you
don't get it
long um like long it's increasing
increasing like two four seven this is
increasing always increasing subsequence
uh one two three four
[Music]
you pick it longest including subsequent
remember we talk about subsequence
okay
okay okay
[Music]
so it's all four yeah the longest will
be of four lengths of four
one
two
one one
three
yeah
yes four yeah
okay
okay okay
so
previously
do you remember we talked about this
we have we talked about this using what
kind of agreement you know if if we use
the tp what's db dynamic programming
okay if i use dpi
representing the longest length
of subsequence the longest increasing
subsequent that ends at index i right
okay
so that longest
increasing subsequence
ends
at index i
index i okay so for example like here
that's index
look so dp value at here will be 2 right
because longest ending at index it will
be 3 4 will be 2 right yeah and how
about look 7 is bigger than 4 right
look 7 is bigger than four right yeah
so what does it mean so what's the vp
value here
four seven
four
so look
dp2 here is two
because i found that longest increasing
subsequent and the index 2 is 2 right
and i know 7 is bigger than 4 so what
does it mean
so the dpi dp here at this value
will be
here plus one right because look seven
is bigger than four what i need to do is
i put a seven at the end of the previous
longest subsequent and it will have
another more one more right
right
right so
so dp right so let's dp
i will be maximum
dpi
and dp j plus one to j
plus
one right
for
j smaller than
i
n
and what's nums
num nums i
bigger than number three okay so that's
the tp function right
listen to me one more time okay
so dpi is the longest increasing
subsequence the length of the longest
increasing subsequent and the index i
and what is the equal i just have to
keep updating this for j smaller than i
if none sign bigger than j okay
make sense
no that's no no no this is okay let's do
the curve yeah but you're right yeah
so why why this is working why because
because i just said look
if i know
db what's the d what's the advantage of
us using dp we want to avoid repeatedly
calculating the values right so i have
dpi meaning that the longest the length
of longest subsequence
increasing subsequent that's an index i
right
and
if i found another value
right which is bigger than the current
value so i want all i all we can do
is put a one append one because we
already found one more subsequence that
has the
one more length right has one more has a
size of one more right look
look there we go whatever comes here
right because the longest increasing
subsequence ends here is four right and
then i found seven is bigger than four
so what does
mean what does it mean
[Music]
what does it mean it means we plus one
plus one yeah plus one because look this
is the longest subsequent we have five
so far and then we know seven is bigger
than four so all we have to do is put a
seven as a previous subsequence i know
we have a
longer subsequence
we size one more right less the less the
dp less the dynamic programming yeah
because we already save here so we
already keep updating here and for this
one yeah
the times of next is o n square right
because we for each eye we need to go
through the j
uh smaller than i okay let's just
quickly implement this
let's just quickly implement define lis
array okay they would need to be capital
there is no capital okay
if not array just make it
uh
yellow that's r
okay
and then n equals length means of a r
and then we need the dp value yeah at
the beginning will be one right
make sense
because each individual element is a
subsequent it's the longest increasing
subsequent right
and now for
i
in
range
n right and then
for look for j any every other element
every and every element every index js
in is smaller than i right in range
up to i
if
if array
i right if array i is bigger than array
drag j
so then with dp
i right
we have dpi will be what equals maximum
dpi
and then dp
j plus one right this is all we talked
about right yeah
return what
that's the interest now what do we
return dp dpy we want to return the
longest increasing subsequent
max of one db
yeah good guy down
i did say dp why is that because dpi is
the longest the length of longest
subsequent increasing subsequent ending
the index line and we want to find the
length of longest increasing subsequent
that could end at any index right so
let's that's why we got the max dp
what's the time complexity
ten
[Music]
seven
eight
ten he said we're gonna do it for ten
minutes okay already nearly done okay
okay come on listen to me
listen to me
now ten minutes
what's the what's the longest increasing
subsequence here
what's the longest increasing subsequent
the length of longest increasing
substance 3 7 8 10 3 7 8 and 4 okay
so we can
we have another agreement right so we
can have at least longest increasing
subsequence right at least
and then we can build it
yeah we can build it along the way so
look how can i build it look look how
competitive so at the beginning we don't
we we have nothing right so how are we
doing three
so where to so let's see this is
increasing subsequent it should be
sorted right
this will be sorted
yeah it's salty right because it's salty
right the longest
increasing subsequent increasing
substitution what does it mean it's
sorted
so three if i'm going to put it in a
longer subsequent way it's going to be
it's empty now so i can just put it
there right so longest subsequence will
be
three
okay
two
we're going to put it here in the salted
is
it should be before three yeah
remember yesterday we talked about what
buy
buy sell collect and buy right
left if we buy send here so where to put
it we should place here yeah yeah this
is the place to put put a two in so i
replace it in two
why is that
why is that because if
i don't know what's happening afterwards
but all i can i know is that if i change
the three to two
it will only make a result better
am right because three is two i'm
changing the sequence of
a big number to a smaller number so it
doesn't make the these are bad words
right
but what
because three
can you put like three three
three there's only one sweet here yeah
what if there's like two or the same one
can you put them together
good question very good question like
they're two tens no because long is
increasing increasing three three is not
increasing
right it's not included
it's we only have one three because if
there are two three you can put you this
is not increasing this this is not
increasing right
right so look so what well
what did i say so
previously long is increasing something
like three now i have two right i mean
two so i can change these to two
three to two
and this doesn't make the result worse
right because i'm changing a sequence i
don't know what's up after but all i
know is that i change a big number to a
smaller number
yeah you will not make the result worse
you will only make the result better
yeah because there's some for example
there's another number 2.5 here
previously 3 is decreasing but now i
change it to 2 in my increasing right i
might pick this in the future
right so let's quit it so i change this
i use the bicep left yeah bisect that
to find out the place there are three
and i change it to two okay
ten where it's going to put in the
saltine here at the end at the end so
i'm putting it here
seven where are they gonna put five six
left ten ten yeah so i replace this
again i replace these two seven yeah
because i changed ten to seven what does
it mean
yeah the result could only get better
right
hey where's the looper
after seven then i put it
what's the time come back to your face
i've logged in
logan so all together o n logan which is
better
this is better or all square which is
better i look l and go again this is
better yeah we find the better ever yeah
makes sense you understand your answer
yeah perfect let's let's do this
define longest increasing subsequent all
right
and we need to have our air
and empty this yeah
[Music]
no no no no for the variables it's okay
it's okay
then we thought we'd also list four i
in
a r okay then we call this x equals
bisect remember bicep
what's the five cent left yeah why is
the left
the first parameter would be the
ar
and the secondary
no no no we're going to buy in the list
yeah in the list
and then i yeah
if
what
s equal or equal length
the position is the at the end right it
means that we can put it at the end
we can put it at the end right
we can put it how can we put the element
i in the end of this
this
dot what's the method we put up we put
we put this i we want to put this i in
the list
a pen yeah
apparent i i oh you can do this a i s
plus equal i this is also okay this is
the same thing okay this is the same
thing
otherwise we just need to change what a
is one
y equals one
okay so what look
what did i just just say 7 10
and if i have a value a i want to
replace this with a
anybody
uh we uh change the time
so x equals what
so the x is bicep yeah we got this
position in the position and equals to
the number yeah which is i
right and we just need to return what we
can
say come on listen easy
return what's the length of the longest
increasing subsequently
length of
less
this yeah this this okay
make sense
make
sense yeah let's just double check
yeah i think it's uh
all right yeah it's all right
okay so
so this one we call ingredient because
we quit it every time we
we find a smaller number
yeah we find a small number we replace
the one in the list with that position
because always keep this maintaining a
sorted ais right so we replace it we
place it we created the place and i know
give us the result
yeah
all right yeah
what's the time complexity for this one
again
what's the space capacity for this one
[Music]
in the worst case is one everything is
increasing one two three four five so
this you know the list will contain this
one two three four five okay this
longest increasing subsequence
makes sense
so the first one dynamic programming
yeah
programming you understand yeah and this
one is greedy no no no no let me program
it on square
remember and space complexity
okay that's it for today good job
bye bye