go hello
hello mr mr ryan how are you today good
okay
because we have a very great superhero
okay so today we talk about uh you know
the
linear equation linear equation
linear equation okay so what's linear
linear
one unknown even linear equation in
one unknown
one unknown for example three times
three times x
plus
three equals six this is one linear
equation with one unknown right linear
means the unknown here
yeah it's only one time linear minor
yeah remember this linear
linear single yeah nothing
all right x
what's what's causative if it's even
here it's two it's graduated from here
remember this is non-linear right or
cubic
right so this x to the power of one is
indeed linear x to the power of 2
this is projected and x to the power of
3 that's cubic you know you can have
more right as long as this unknown has
one which is x we call it linear linear
equation and there's only one equa one
another one here x so what's x here
what's the value of x three times
something plus three equals six so
what's this x can you make a guess
three times something
plus three one yeah we're done okay so
how how do we solve this easy we move
this constant to the right hand side and
change the sign
minus three
so three times x equals three and then
we can divide it three from both sides
right so we we got it
yeah we got it so we go to x equals
one okay easy
quadratic yeah a x squared plus b bx
plus c equals zero remember we talked
about this graduated because this is
2 2 times 2 x to the power of 2
a b c are constant and then look we got
one unknown unknown right on a linear
equation in two unknowns
so if we have two unknowns and then if
we we with one unknown we can have one
equation and we know how to solve it
with two unknowns how many questions do
we need
can we
sorry
[Music]
one equation solves one unknown right
yes
can we solve two equations two can we
solve two unknowns with one equation
yeah for example a plus b equals ten
can you solve this a can you solve this
no because look a and b could be
hundreds of you know millions of
possibilities a equals one b equals 9 a
equals to b equals 8 right
however if i say a minus b
equals
okay four
what are ifs
uh it's gonna be uh
so look we have two unknowns okay
it's gonna be uh
it's gonna it's
gonna be can you try it three and seven
where down three and seven look two
unknowns two equations we can solve it
yeah yeah yeah so let's let's linear
equation in two unknowns so how can we
solve this how do you know it's three
and uh seven and three it's just guess
blue four thing something yeah yeah
one one one trick look plus b minus b
look
how about look because look these
how about if we add the left side and
add the right side together
ten plus four right
fourteen
a plus b plus a minus b
fourteen two a 2a oh sorry so what's a
seven yeah and if a is seven then we can
just plug in the values that would be
three yeah easy huh
yeah two
for anymore
a seven and b u b is three right three
plus seven eight so why don't they need
to be seven because look a plus b equals
ten a minus b equals four it needs to
satisfy these two equations that's what
i'm saying
two unknowns needs two equations to to
to be able to be uh solvable right
okay so
if you know how to solve this linear
equation into unknowns that we can solve
many many applications like like rugby
and chicken chicken rabbit problem right
right
home
repeat and chicken
yeah if i have uh
you know look if i have a cage right i
have a cage and there are some chickens
some chicken i don't know how many i
know some rabbit
yeah
some rabbit
okay so listen to me
i have some chicken and how about if i
tell you that they are
okay listen to me okay
okay no no no no no what's that okay
okay listen if if they are
they are eleven heads
eleven heads
okay you know my head listen okay and
how many legs does the rabbit have four
four legs so already has four legs right
four legs how many chickens does that
how many chickens are there
how many legs does the chicken have
two two
legs okay why are you talking about legs
and talking about heads
so all i know is that there are some
chickens and rabbits in the cage
and they're all over all 11
pets including the chicken and rabbit
and they are why why
why are you talking about legs and then
suddenly talking about heads
because it needs two equations to solve
it okay so look r plus c equals 11 right
okay
i'm
that's what i'm saying okay so let's say
if if they are
okay
if they are what if they are 32 legs
so 32 legs together so how many 32 legs
all together and how many rabbits how
many chickens so look for legs
[Music]
okay
and one two three four five five rabbits
you've counted but no look six chicken
yeah
six chicken i'm talking about yeah
six chickens
six chicken how many how many legs two
plus but you yeah yeah yeah i know five
times four what's this
okay it's 32. yeah you're all right yes
yeah that was
10 but
it's still legs
okay so what's i see look 10 heads and
then
all legs this is 10 head
and here is legs
[Music]
okay so what's i see come on how can we
solve this problem
so look how can we say
[Music]
ryan do you understand what i'm talking
about
yeah
[Music]
so how can can we solve this or not
proof of thing can we just solve
[Music]
how do you know it's too late wow so
quick because i breathe
blue falls in your head so quickly
yay
okay okay so one way of doing this okay
you can't prove us for any
every other input right for this because
these two are inputs right yeah but
because if i see something really small
yeah really
yeah because this is more than our
possibility how many possibilities are
those uh i think there's five
five ten that'll be ten because i and c
pair yeah one co 10
no no no that would be there will be 11
11 possibilities the r will be from 0 to
10.
but what if there are it might be five
and c in my v5 and there's no point of
doing
two numbers two letters i mean
yeah yeah yeah look because i could how
many possibilities of ah
10 11 right r would be zero to any
number between zero ten so okay so look
how can we solve this one way of doing
it look here what's r r b equals ten
minus c right you can do this yeah
all right look from here
r equals 10 minus c
all right
okay then if we plug in this to here
so what 4 times 10 minus c plus 2c
equals 24. right and look
look what's this error look 40 minus 4c
plus 2c equals 24. okay 4t
minus 2c plus
minus 4c plus c equals one
minus four plus two equals one
minus zero
what's this
that is minus one
minus two c equals twenty 24
40 minus
something equals 24.
so 2c will be equals 6x
so c equals 8. so we know
look we plug in the c here
this is a so i is two right another way
of doing it look at this is c this is if
we times two
two r plus two c equals twenty right all
right
if you subtract these from here
four minus 2r to r
2c cancel out right
24 minus 20
for
r will be equals 2.
got it
right do you understand you're drawing
all the time do you understand
do you understand right
yeah make sense
yeah okay
okay one
i give you one example and then you tell
me if it's a
two
uh
linear equation with two unknowns okay
so x plus y equals 10
and i'm looking look at this
x times y equals 25 is this
is this the linear equation with 2 and 9
is it you don't need to solve it but if
you can solve it it will be good is it
x plus y equals 10 to two equations of
two equations two
[Music]
yeah it's five
but what's the point of doing two
variables even though they're the same
letter
the same number because i'm not telling
you i'm asking to solve it you need to
find out the value of xy but my question
is that is this a linear equation
is this
linear equation in two unknowns
you don't know okay this is
no okay why is that this time look x
plus y equals 10 and then we can do this
x equals 10 minus y right yeah
yeah if we plug in the value here look
what what do we have look
10 minus y
times y equals 25
10 y
minus y squared equals 25. do you still
think this is the linear
because this yeah this is nonlinear
right
okay so this is the before okay another
example
another example okay
look yeah look x divided by y is not
also no right it's not 0 because look x
plus y equals 10
x divided by y equals one is this a
linear equation
is a linear equation into unknowns
you say
no yeah because look if
if one this is the same as
x
yeah look
if y is not equal to zero right then we
can do uh maybe we can just do this
again look
x will be 10 minus y right
right and 10 minus y divided by y equals
1.
is it the equation is it a linear
equation
maybe look
then we can times y on both sides so
it's 10 minus y equals
equals y
equals to y
okay and i'm going to solve for y equals
five okay so the thing is this one is
very tricky because y cannot be
zero right cannot be z equal to zero
right
so
what
so i'm not sure if this is still called
the linear equation okay maybe not maybe
yes okay i most likely it's not a linear
equation
okay
but okay let's do this um
okay let's do this
okay can you go backseat please please
okay how about this x plus y equals 10
and then 2x plus 2y equals 20 is this
linear equation into
linear equation into unknowns i mean
is it can you solve this no why is that
why is that come on
not linear it's linear but you cannot
solve it why is that
because
because if x is one and
that is nine and two of it is
is
two one is it and then
eighteen
yeah
twenty
pluses
can you solve this equation
how many how many rules are how many
possibilities for this
can you solve it no
no no
lots of answers yeah look what because
the first equation is the same as the
second equation right because we just
times two
if we times two it's the same
so even though there are two equations
it's actually one right all right
yeah
okay
okay can we can we go can we focus not
drawing okay come on you throw it up
that sounds good
okay so now today
today we
okay so
okay so no no no no no
what's your
next problem remember
s and a yeah s has
how many numbers
three quarters three quarters three
three quarters of s is the same as two
fifths of a
a okay let's and then
a
more than s is what
490 okay so look
how do you come up with these two
equations you just read the problem
statement right and then you just
express the idea
in mathematics right i like look what's
this
two unknowns
two equations
right so we can solve it right
yeah okay so how do we solve it look
how can we solve it one way
one way is what a will be equals s plus
490 right look if we move the s to the
other side we need to change the size
right negative to positive positive to
negative right
and then now look
a we got a if we plug in
here
right so look
what do we have 3
4 s equals 2 5 and then we substitute
substitute a with s with s plus 460 90.
okay look
yeah so look now
we have one equation one unknown i know
we can solve it right
all right
we have one equation one and another and
ryan
can you leave to do that
all right how can we solve this
look here is four here is five so we
want to multiply both sides by a number
which is the least common multiple 20
yes we multiply 20 so that would be five
here
multiply 20 that will be four here right
right
how many of these
15x
a
s plus 490 right
yes
all right
okay so what's this a times s
plus a times 490 right
right if we move this to the left side
how many s do we have
15x minus a s is 7s
equals 8 times 490. so what's s what's s
let's divide the both sides by seven
right
i was this number eight times 490
divided by seven
this is 70.
yeah
so it's 560.
s is 560.
and i'll park in here 560 plus 490
equals
10.50 right
this is how we solve this equation okay
okay
so
look
we coming back to the nothing chicken
problem okay so let's say if we have uh
we want to solve this problem you know
we use heads we have heads and now we
have next
so you need to tell me
the number of the rapid and number of
chicken you know with edge and air right
yeah if it if there's no such answer we
just written none okay so one way how
can computers solve this
by
looking forward yeah proofreading all
the equations okay look look uh four
times r plus
2 times
c
that's the length right let's select
and then r plus c equals 1 that's the
head
yeah
right
we can solve this equation
and then solve this and then ask
computer just to return this how can we
solve this look
come on all right so r equals h minus c
right and then we plug in here
so four times h minus c plus 2c equals l
look
4 times h minus 4c
plus 2c equals a
this is familiar because for c and l we
already know it
four times h minus four two c equals l
right so two c
equals four times h minus
l right
right if we move this to the right hand
side and move this to the left side
so c equals
4 times h minus l divided by 2
right up
now
so look c will be equal as four times h
minus air divided by two divided divided
by two okay divided by two
divided by two divided by two
right and then air
r
r will be what r will be h minus here h
h is given minus c
okay so there's one before
if this is not uh
if this is not a
even number yeah you divided by two that
will give incorrect answer right
right
so
one way of doing this is what we can
verify these two numbers yeah we got a c
and r now we can just say
if
r plus c equal equals
h
and
yeah
i i don't think we need it because this
r plus h
is always equal right
this is all this condition is always
true the problem is this one
e4 times r plus two times c
equal equal air
then we can return
okay return a top ten okay all
how do you pronounce this word t-u-p-i-e
actually it's tough
because i i google it
it's called temple okay stop him
he said it's people yeah
my mistake okay c and ah
it's tougher okay
we just turn the tupper okay
we return the top of can you not play
with these come on what did that you
just say
the chicken and rabbit
okay and otherwise we just return okay
oh we don't need we don't by default we
don't need to write it okay we can now
what why is this can you can you explain
to me that if i calculate cnr why do i
need to
do this
check
what did you say what's the prefer of
this one
sorry what's the preference
okay let me repeat one more time right
because four times h minus f could be an
odd number you cannot divide it by two
because for the chicken and rabbit there
is no half right there's no such thing
as half chicken
or half rabbit
yeah good what's that
but if you times it by four that means
it could divide it by two but air the
problem the point is air
why is that why
in what case is the air b these whole
thing can be look four times h is a
even number that's a very good point so
this whole thing when c
when four times h minus air is an odd
number
so
in what cases it could be a odd number
why don't you just steve
sorry let me repeat my question
for
four times h minus air
in what cases this is going to be all
numbers
this whole thing is an even number and
at least if it's air what's the air
what's the air
the legs
why
if it's all number of legs can you solve
it no no because chicken two legs rabbit
four legs how come it could be
five
odd number right
all right
okay so one way of doing this that if
you can say if air is odd you know
divided by 2 equals 1 is all that will
be 10 because there's no such solution
or the other way is you you calculate
this number yeah you remember you have
this divided by 2. and then you double
check the legs
yeah double check and then you make sure
we already have we know it's a valid
solution otherwise we just written that
what's the time complexity for this one
oh
that's your that's the one you should
guess one a one why is that because i
like it
why is that because we just use
mathematics to solve this no matter how
big is actually an air
instantly we just solve this equation
instantly the computer just solve it
instantly we don't use any additional
linears
in a space yeah so time and space
complexity is a one
yeah this is the case
one we just solve the mathematic
equation but if you're using the for
loop what's the time complexity
okay okay let's use something for how
can we grow first
how can we perform if we have a head we
can prove us either chicken or rabbit
right we can try right
so how can we prove us that
please let's
let's proof of the weapon okay yeah
all right
so for
rabbit
in
star wars in what in in range
range
range h plus 1 right h plus 1 means the
range this
plane so we are we are guessing we are
trying we are guessing the rapid is from
0 to h inclusive right we have a r so
what's c here if we guess r now what's
the c
c
r plus the c equals h right yeah
so i know ah so what's that what's c i
know r i know h what's c
come on this is easy
[Music]
easy yeah okay so now we want to double
check the air the legs
if how many legs of rabbit
rub it what
what
how many how many necks
times four plus how many how many legs
of chicken
two
three times four equal equal
three times four
equals one
because uh
well already
actually we don't need to write it
it will be automatically written now
it just
really what's the time to max t what is
that how would it just return
because when it reached here at this
point it means there is no solution in
here there is no such thing look we are
working
doesn't it just do excuse things
excuse me excuse me like screaming oh no
no no no look the computer just saw here
and here this one right and then you
clicked because if you haven't told the
computer what to return at this point so
it's you you will soon return nothing
none
right so what are we doing we are trying
every possibility of r from zero to h
all right and now we calculate the
chicken
and then we check yeah this is to check
if if the next
set is fine then we return we found a
very solution and that's it
blue forcing what's the term complexity
[Music]
what's n how many in the worst case
what's the m how many iterations here
and
what's n
[Music]
in how many iterations we need to check
how many possibilities for the r
for a rabbit
given h hat
yeah
come on
how many iterations of this
yeah
oh h plus one but we dropped the
constant yeah
yeah they're all the possibilities from
zero to h
and that will be h plus one and with o h
so the time time next is o h what's the
space complexity
oh okay yeah that's o
what's a space complexity
so which one is better
the one before
why is that because
because we are
because of the capacity
is quicker yeah it's it's it's
it's not depending on the size of h no
matter if h is a minion
this needs to take a linear iteration
but for the previous one we just do the
calculation yeah with human do the math
calculation and then we translate the
calculation to computer code and the
computer to go and just work it out by
doing some math computation it's linear
it's not it's not in its instant right
correct
today so to sum up
what we have done today
chicken graphic and then linear equation
with two unknowns yeah how do we solve
the linear equation with two unknowns we
look if x plus y equals something so we
we plug in the values of one variable
into another equation so then we can
make it one linear equation with one
unknown am right
okay okay that's it for today that's it
for the bye bye
bye bye