so ah hello mr mr right now you're right
yeah yeah okay
so we talked about uh linguists okay
english
how many types of linguists do we have
linked this
another note tingly
yeah i think the tablet too
this is what what's this
this is
fingerli right and how what's doubly
what's w
it has a cycle
it has a side not not quite
what's singly means single direction
what doubling
direction
now now this is this is still singly the
doctor is that it has another additional
link from the
current node linked to the previous okay
okay
this is probably okay
yeah
so these are the data structure this is
the data structure to store the data
right it's one kind of data structure
and
how does it differ between the
the list you know normally we have a
list yeah a equals list
one two three four okay
the list is quite simple yeah it holds
the element right and then these
elements are put one by one next to each
other right so we can have this
randomness if we want to achieve the
third number we can just do a
a1
the first index the first number is a0
right the third number is one
anyone
what how can i retrieve this number i
don't next this is the list a1 how many
alright four
four
how many what's the what's this number
a1
if i put one number here what's this
three
two two yeah because it start with zero
like a0 a1 a2 a3 okay make sense good
job
okay so
now the thing is we're talking about the
thing clip here okay so we have head
here
and i'll come to the next we point to
the next okay so this is one two three
four
right
so
if we want to retrieve the number in the
second in the third now we can't we
can't just do this like the list why we
have to travel from the head head
and the next hit the next and the next
right so the traveling term is it's
linear right it's all what
if the previous one the eight of these
yeah it is one two three we want to get
these the term complexity so one yeah
because we know we know this address of
the a and we can based on the type of
element we can calculate the address of
any numbers in the array right
and then if look
because the array is quite simple right
we only we don't store any additional
overhead right but for this one
we also need to store one more one more
thing which is the point that points to
the next right so if we look there are
four numbers here one two three four we
need to store eight units of thing
because these four numbers
and each node we also have this
pointer to the next one
so yeah do you get it
um but for this one for the linked list
the the the only uh the advantage of
using english is that it does not have
to be continuous right so these and
these nodes could be separate it could
be separate apart in memory
but for this one the linked list for the
list it has to be continuous
so you know the computer ram is limited
the ram yeah like a table yeah if a
table is limited
so if i want to store like uh
you know sometimes i want to store
minion data right for example if this
this thing
uh
like a thousand a thousand elements
right and i want to allocate i can't
sometimes i cannot find a continuous
space for the hundred elements
right but for the language i can
because this linkage can be separate in
the notes i it could be separate in
different parts of the table yeah
overall right so i can do it
okay this is the one difference
okay so let's let's
let's do a very good
easy problem which is to find the length
of english right so let's say
i have a hat
i want to find the length of the linkage
how can i do this
how can we do this the length of
learning is head how can we do this
any idea
you want to travel
why you head
by your head
okay
y head is not the end yeah what do we do
but before that we need to declare a
number right answer
and why ahead what
what's next return
return
answer where do you put the channel why
your head what what what do we do with
the y hat come on you can do it
answer
uh
equals one okay and then what should we
do with the head
we should go with the hair moving to the
next head or next
hair equal as well head dot next okay
return answer
we're done what's the time to let's see
for this one
the n is the number of nodes in the
degrees right now this is iterated we
have iterative we can also do that do it
in recursion
so what how can we solve this purple
recursion look this is head right this
is head
so the the entire linked list the length
of entire linkage is what
is the thing this is what this is what
this whole thing here is what
start here what's this what's this note
hector next
we're done so look the link list
the length of the entire language is one
note here plus the notes i'm not sure
how many nodes are here but i know this
has next so i can use the recursion to
call itself to solve the problem
a smaller problem right
okay so define the terminal terminal
condition is that when the node is empty
yeah
lens head i don't know what should we do
what should we do
if okay if not head even head is numb or
not head okay then we return
num zero okay and then otherwise we
return one
yeah
head no no no how many notes are you
i don't know
yeah the question this is the question
calling itself this this
this calling itself right calling
yourself
why not because look we want to
calculate how many nodes are in entire
language
it's equals to one node here i know it's
one over here
and then use header next is this this is
something yeah this linkage and i call
itself to solve this and then return it
yeah
make sense
yeah yeah
so this because this recursion every
question has one problem uh it's called
step over from stack overflow because
every time we want to
uh call call a recursion calling we said
we need to push
you know push the address of the
corner and then we need to put a push
the parameters in the stack stack is the
fixed size in computer science in
computer right
in the computer
so once
once the number of elements it says the
stack size then you will cause that
overflow right if the linkage is or has
a minion element it probably will
will have this problem right so the best
approach would be the previous one which
is iterative okay for and for this
the question we can write it in white
line right look return one plus nine
head not hat or next
if
what if hat
[Music]
yellow yeah we can just remove this yeah
yeah
return yeah look at one nine return one
person then head down next right right
yeah
let's get ready
okay
okay so yeah that will be today
bye-bye