hello
hello mr hello mr ryan how are you today
good no way answering yeah
so we have sorted this yeah we have
sorted this but they might contain
duplicates
like one one two two two three four four
okay
okay so first of all three is in the
teeth okay that's why let's write salted
salted array
okay saute it away
so we have a sorted array with some
duplicates okay and we want to make
remove the
duplicates so we want to make it like
that you have to be
what oh yeah we want to make it work
like that
one two three four easy
okay and then whatever because look
there are two four six eight element and
there are four uniques right
one two three four and then whatever
comes after it doesn't matter
so you need to return these
what do you mean by it doesn't matter
what comes next
so this is an array we want to modify
the array in place what's in place
which means that we don't need we we
don't want to return another separate
array yeah we just want to return this
array
with all the duplicates removed
yeah so whenever you can store something
else it doesn't matter right
like you can store like 100 or whatever
it doesn't matter
so
so all i need is to remove the
duplicates from this socket remember i
started this is very important
in place so
so eventually a will become this so it's
not a separate array like b or c it's a
it's the original way and then you need
to make sure we need to make sure the
first
you know you need to tell me you need to
leave they can be also this uh you need
to tell me okay so the first four
elements stores the unique right unique
numbers in the sorted array right so you
need to tell me okay this is there are
four four elements here
make sense
is it clear
but you need to return the list or just
four
good question because this look yeah
that's a very nice question okay defy
okay so let's say remove duplicate
remove duplicate
so this is the
duplicate so this is a okay
yeah because originally i was looking
explaining where and you need to ask for
you know explanation clarification yeah
and that's what you're doing now
remove duplicate a
and then these functions
return
it return uh integer
okay so integer returns that the number
okay the number of the elements
in the
you know which content which are unique
right
yeah it's not returning at least because
we are all we are modifying the list
yeah
all right so in this case this function
returns four and the first four elements
is one two three four
easy and even now five
five five
so
what i need it will be five and
it doesn't matter what what's uh
yeah what's come after it doesn't matter
underneath you need to tell me it's five
this one's your return five
right make sense
okay
so
if
okay so um
what's your approach like what kind of
data structure can we use to store
we just
um
there's a one and then we get a next one
that's the same and we just delete it
did it and hopefully
yeah oh yeah
you can think about the most obvious way
of what kind of data structure you want
we're done set yeah we're using a set we
can use the set so first of all we use
the set and then these look if we use a
set one hand
if we use the set set a what's the a
this will become a set set of what
one two three four five unique yeah this
is only unique so the set is actually
using this curly brace
okay
and then now if i convert it further
convert it to list
actually we need to make it because that
does not have order right
set does not have order
so before we convert into this we need
to convert it to sorted using the sorted
sorted
set a
and then these will give me
what give me uh
40 is the iterator that you'll give me
uh one two three four five
in in ascending order because it's
already started
right and then i have this list
converted to list so it will become a
list
okay so this is the exactly the numbers
i want to return
right so all i have to do is copy this
over to a
and return the length of it right
all right yeah so what's the term
complexity if we're going for this
remember that
if we see
the salted
what's the term consistency
yeah
and this is the p4 origin so so
basically
we are not making use of the fact that
the array is sorted right and because we
somehow use a set this is all in space
and we
we use the one space to to
retrieve these unique right
to retrieve only one one for each
element even it's duplicate
and then we need to convert it
to
sorted okay and then this is taking o
and logan
okay so let's do this again uh let's do
this
but this is obviously not not in place
right this is obviously not in place
the multiple case a
okay so now look what what should i do
uh let's say b okay b equals
list
sorted
set you see i
right
okay
yeah
so
so what does it mean it means that first
of all i converted an a into a set which
only contains the one for each duplicate
number sorry one two three four five
right and then i i make it sorted so
you'll be one two three four five
convert that to this
and then now look
so i just need to go through this for i
in range
length b right
right
and now i just need to assign copy b to
a right so a i
equals b i right
and i don't i don't need to
change anything after a
after you know afterwards right so
return return
length of what come on
right
yeah look a is the original we want to
determine something
right makes sense
a is the input
makes sense yes
okay
yeah
this time complexity is o and of n
space complexities o
l one
what's the space university
[Music]
and
okay
yeah uh we can do better
yeah because we're not making use of the
set then this is sorted and then we we
are not doing this in place
okay so how can we do this look i i
write it again there
okay let's see so these
will become
one two three four and i don't care what
what's after okay
look look at me
look at me yes
so look look if i draw this and can you
make can you tell me the difference uh
the
can you tell me what
what's obvious here right this this one
two
three
four okay
can you tell me can you observe that
what
um um
[Music]
this one is the first one
the first one is quite unique yeah
okay so let's look at these two three
four
what are you name in common in common
what are those in common look
what are those in common the first
the first of what the unique number okay
one how come they they're unique
how do you know it's the first you need
because
no you just visited
and yes and how how do they compare to
the previous one um they're different
way down that's the one they are
different if they are different than the
previous one i put it there right
yeah look these are different than that
yeah it's the same look this is the same
so i skip
yeah this different right and the first
one is always because we always need it
right
yeah okay
so this is a beautiful algorithm
beautiful approach
remove
you dupe
array just a okay
so
um
so what
so let's say i equals one right yeah
i equals one
right four
uh let's put it maybe x x equals one for
i
in range we start from the second one
ah one right
to
length a
okay now we want to check look
if one
a i
not equal
a
can you tell me
and then what now we return what
we don't want can you tell me so if this
current element from the second animal
even it's different than the previous
one so what do we do
what do we do we add it
so how do we add it
how do we read it look if this this
element is not equal to i minus all
right yeah
now what should we do what should we do
first of all we need to x plus equals
one nine because we already found
another one element to put
and then we need to assign assign these
assign is what a
a what a x
actually
here x plus equals one a x equals
a i right am i right
make sense
look x is the
okay let me just quickly try
okay
and i want to to convert it one two
three four
right and then look
these here yeah
so x x is these x controls the progress
of the
elements we're going to put yeah x is
here x
right and a x at the beginning a x is
one
here
a x is not is put to
a i i a i minus one is the one we
already put before
right
ax equals ai
x plus equal and return y
less than one x newton x because that's
the final x is the number of elements in
the target array right
yes
what's the time complexity
what's the time capacity
right
what's the time
this is n is the number of length length
a right yeah going to end
one time which is better
this one on the previous one this one
why is that because it's quicker it's
quicker all right and we're doing this
in place and we're not using any space
what's the space convexity yeah i just
said we are not using any space and
what's the specs from chesty
you know what i'm talking about yeah
yeah
okay do you really understand
do you want me to erase one of these and
then
i'm going to try to do this at x equals
one yeah x equals one that's easier
all right
so x is here look look
x6 here
the beginning yeah the beginning a this
is a still a the first one that we don't
touch look at me x is here
x is here yeah
and then we start what i i start from
here
a i not equals a minus one
yeah it's not equal right so i send
these to ai which is two and i put
points to the next one
yeah i
move it
a i equals
is it equal right yes so i skip i don't
go to the if
a is not equal as a minus one right yes
so i set ax to three
and points to next
i
okay
equal
skip
not the same not the same set these two
here four
and then go ahead yeah easy okay
okay
you're using your understanding using
your understand okay so i'm going to
remove this and remove it so you tell me
which one
come on i just see grace in front of you
come on
yeah x look x
all right
that's it that's it for today good job
bye