hello mr mr ryan how are you today
okay so you know how to multiply two
numbers yeah yeah
okay okay one two three four five six
how do you do it
okay okay how do we do it
one two we do this number times yeah
this number times this and then this
number times this and we put it in like
one and then okay number here
oh you're so lazy just give me how to
you know just teach me how to do it but
without giving me the example okay but i
understand what you mean yeah these
numbers are eight yeah
and then
seventy
three right and i please
hear something something and i i learned
together right you're lazy yeah yeah
yeah yeah you're lazy
okay so in python actually if we give
given two string and then these could be
you know very
huge abstract length right so you can
just directly if these are given two
strings and then you can just do you
know convert it to you can use this in a
and then convert the string to integer
times
in
b you know right and then you can
convert the result back to the string
right
yeah this would be it but we want to
understand how do we
let the computer do the math
do the multiplication because in some
other language right not in person like
in java in the
the integer
has a fixed size so you cannot store
you know for example in c c or in in c
plus plus
another problem in language and if you
declare in right
yeah if you declare the in integer a
right it can only store
stop a number which is four bytes so
this is for byte right
okay this is the highest sign but if
we're talking about you unsigned
individual which means that none
negative it will be a will be belongs to
you know 0
and 2 to 2 to the power of 32
to -1 right because it's 32-bit so this
is the maximum number that unsigned okay
and then
and signed
four by integer four by integer
yeah remember
what's by
32 bit yeah four by 32 bits yeah
right okay
computer
let's review this data uh
data unit right
what speed
a bit is a bit it is
a picture thing
yeah yeah well there are only two
possibilities
zero and one
okay so it's zero all one right let's
pick
and next one is byte the computer stores
the unit the basically uh storing data
units spiked
is eight bit
yeah
a bit what's a bit
it's like
so you have a b like zero
so that's binary okay so how what if if
this one one one one what's this
remember this binary what's this oh i'm
buying that
two
one plus two plus four plus eight right
that's one fifteen right and then one
one one one one one one one maximum is
one three i don't know
one plus two one plus two
plus 4 plus a plus 16 plus 32 plus 64
plus 128. so if you put all the nodes
together it's 255 okay so 8 by 8 bit a
byte is from 0 to 100 to 25 okay
similarly
what's what's the next one
kb kit bike
killer bike yeah it's a 10 24.
yeah look 10
24 bytes why is it 10 24 because 10 24
is 2 to the power of
1 10 right
yeah
okay
and what's next unit
10 24 kilobyte would be megabyte
10 24
kilobytes
what's next
gigabyte
what does that equal
what is equal that equals um 10 24 can
you guess 1024
[Music]
okay
integer is 32 bit so it
it represents the number from 0 to 232
to the power 32 minus 1 right so this is
a very big number but still not very
big enough right
so
um so
we have to know that how we do it uh
you know how how are we helping the
computers to do the math so one easy way
would be what
let's do this example again
okay so if if there are
three this is that a is three three
digit b is three digits so what's the
result what's the maximum
result what's the length of that result
how many digits of the a times b
how many digits
if if this is n this is m how many
maximum i mean how many digits
four
no wait no no
let me do the
how many digits i mean just the maximum
it looks like it might be a three digit
three digit yeah if it times one it'll
be four of three digits but if it times
this one
will be oh four digits
three five digits it's five six oaa okay
five six away
so what i'm saying is that if a
is n digit
b is mdg what's the maximum
of the result you can guess for example
like nine
yeah that's what i'm saying okay you
times these together
well
999 times 99
equals
998001 alright so six digits okay let's
try another example this is the maximum
you can get there so what what do it
what's that nine nine nine four digit
times three digit what's the maximum
digit
is is
this one is nine nine eight
zero one so seven digit okay so if you
like n digits of a mdg dot b so they're
term together the maximum is n plus and
digit right
yeah makes sense yeah the maximum is
nine right you can you can't put more
than nine right yeah
okay
so if we have this result then let's
start this without an answer answer all
right my answer will be the digit yeah
every every time you have a zero zero
zero at the beginning is zero
so if if i say
if i say i want to translate and times
this where do you
what does it put okay if we do this this
is from here to from right to the left
this is index zero this is index one so
if the index i
in index i
times index j
so where are we going to put
so two times six where where is it going
to be
where it's going to be
it's gonna be
so is it going to be i plus j right if
you look yeah all right
yeah
okay look let's try this again okay
let's try this again look what two six
times six times two is this is six is
twenty right this is twenty so it
actually is one twenty
right one twenty so we're going to put
twelve we want to put 12 where
we're going to put the 12 is i plus j
right look because because this j equals
zero yeah we're looking from the right
or left one
uh i equals one right zero one
so
one plus zero is one so we're going to
put this 120
at starting at a position
one right i plus three
right so if we're going to do this if
we're going to
if we're going to multiply each digit
yeah from each number and then we can
put it in corresponding
position right
yeah
now we can do this right
this is the way to do the uh
okay
okay so look all right
these numbers are they are represent
from the
most uh significant to the least
significant from the left what we call
the left side is the most significant
and and the right move side is least
significant right
so if if we can reverse the digit right
then we can do it in
using the index yeah why are we going to
do this so we make it simpler right
if we reverse the a that would be three
to one right look
but it's actually one two three if we do
by the way how do we reverse this if a i
want to make it reverse how do we
reverse it yes
how do you reverse it
2.0 yeah we can do foreign use the quick
one which is what
minus one test uh column
four four five six okay let's let's do
the reverse thing that'll be six five
four so yeah actually okay so this is
representing a this is b this is b
this is our way okay and this array is
three represents the number the universe
order is one two three times
four five six and then we have a result
your answer
at the beginning we have uh how many
digits
there are three digits there are three
digits the most will be the sixth digit
so i put a six yellow here
okay
okay so now
if i go from here the i digit
yeah that's three three i equals three i
equals zero i i equals zero for this one
and j equals
let's just start from here j for and
call this
three times six eighteen right
yeah
i equals zero j equals zero so the
result will be put in i plus j right
okay
so it's zero so eighteen look but it's
eighteen yeah we don't we ideally we
want to store only one digit in one
place right so 18 let's put it 18 and
here right because this is 18 right but
now we need to do what we need to spread
yeah we need to carry over 18 carry over
to this
so what what does it become all right
this is 18. even digit is 18 i don't
want to start more than 10 here then you
need to go
yeah so what does it become
yeah that's what i mean yeah so look
let's try another example three times
five here so where are we going to put
so let's put this a here okay one here
okay so we're going to put the 15 right
yes and the result will be in
in three i plus j so you'll be here
right
15 plus one is 16 right
yeah
but i need to carry over so what's that
um
six one yes six one you see
so if we're doing this
i and doing with j we keep going and
then we can get this result and we just
can after all we can just what reverse
this answer
yeah make sense
okay let's write it to you i think you
understand okay can you tell me the most
important takeaway is what if the digit
from i
a i l a i times b j
we're going to put the answer
where you're going to put the answer
we need to carry over to i plus j plus
one right because we don't want to store
a two digit or three digits we don't
want we only want to store one digit
yeah and we won't carry over
to the next one and
we can reverse it
yeah
okay for simplicity we don't consider
the negative numbers yeah so the numbers
a and b does not contain the negative
the minus sign right yeah but you can
handle it if if
two negatives
multiplied together they will be
positive yeah
if one of them is negative the result
will be one what
negative negative yeah exactly so we
don't have the
in for the simplicity we don't have the
uh
you know the a and b with the negative
number okay define
multiply
b okay
a b okay
and then look
and m equals length a
length b right and now we want to store
the answer in answer equal and the
beginning will be zero times one how
many digits the answer will be how many
digits
we just talk about how many digits it
will be
i
am
okay now we just need to reverse first
of all we need to reverse this a and b
right right
a equals a
plus dash current minus one b equals
b yeah this is the simple way python
right yeah otherwise you have to
implement a two-pointer thing to swap
yeah at two points
and then now we just need to go through
for i
in
range
n right
then
for
j
in
rent
okay by looking at these two number two
fours what's the time complexity
because these two are nested for loop
for each n for each eye you need to do j
times right so that's item straight so
it's 10 times
length for the two right for the two
numbers
by the way the a and b are given as a
stringer if you
one two three and then p will be four
five six
you need to give me a string str right
give me a string
now look
now i answer
i plus j right equals and i want to
times n a i times bi right so ai is the
ai is a string right it's a character
yeah we want to convert it how can we
convert this one to one
easy question this is string this is
integer how can we do this
one way is to leave in yeah
or remember the old function
odd one what does it give us
what does it give us
all the zero
all the zero give us 48 right so all the
y you just need to minus
40 a and that's another same thing
so here let's just do this a i
let's let's let's just do alt
a i
minus 40 a and then we need to times
what
times over d
a j
minus 40 a okay so
we but remember we need to carry over
right carry over
yeah so we pass
sorry
so actually this is not equal it's plus
equal right because the multiplier is
plus equals
and then answer
i plus j
plus one right plus one
plus one will be what
will be one so the next digit will be
the previous digit
plus equal previous this is the answer
i plus j
divided by 10 right carry over and then
we need to carry over the next one look
this 18 right 18 we want to carry over
to one and
to a and one right
so that's two steps first step is this
digit the i plus one plus j plus one
needs to carry over plus equal leasing
divided by ten and the second second
step is to do this 18 and do the modulus
so i plus j
modulus what
10.
yeah
what did i just say 18.
two steps first one is two one to carry
the one over to the next digit the
second step is make 18 a right by
modulus 10 right yeah so this can
carry over to a1 okay
now answer will return the number
okay
a number of number of these yeah so we
want to remove the
we remove the
[Music]
the leading zeros right
we all know that zeros okay
so first of all
if i do this dot join
john answer yeah my answer is uh array
of uh digits we want to make this answer
a array of
array of what array of
characters so what do we do
wait
okay so
array of
so this is this is array of uh digits
right array of digits
one for example the result is read as
210 right yes 210. well we want to join
that we want to join that
numbers together so how do we join the
numbers together
these days
remember we want first of all we want to
make it work make it this one
so first of all we want to make it this
yeah how to how to become how to convert
from a to here
yeah but this is the array
before that we need to do this map
maxing map
to star
the first one is the function and the
second one is the list which is a yeah
yeah so i met please and then i can join
it right
yeah and then join
but before i met him i need to reverse
it right reverse it look
reverse it first of all reverse it
convert it each one to the string and
join it right
if i tune it and i i will have something
like zero zero zero one two three i want
to remove this leading zero right yeah
yeah i want to remove this leading zeros
so we can use two functions to do one
function which is called
airstrip
by default air strip is stripping left
and by default if you don't give any
parameters you strip the white space
right the space white space
yeah
so look
look
anything here i put every
okay anyway here
there's a lot of space and i can say
airstrike
you you'll give me you remove anything
in front you'll give me one array
all right
and a lot of space will be after because
we don't remove it yet and we can call
another one called r strip
this is to remove the space white space
at the end so you'll become eric
okay
and then if you want to do both you can
just do call one string
and a parameter you can give a parameter
to it so for example if i give a
parameter to it so you will only
retrieve
what you will only remove the zeros
leading zero on the left side
so this one
i can remove this
dust air strip yeah
yeah
and then
look if if the result is zero times zero
what's what's the outcome of zero times
zero
it will be all zero and if i do the l
strip it'll be nothing so i have this is
the special case i have to check if it's
nothing then i'll return zero right
otherwise return x
makes sense
make sense everyone
yeah okay so what's the important thing
you learned today
come on give me one second
how
so
a i
times b j
okay first of all we reverse it and a i
times d where are we going to put answer
with your friends
put it in one
a i plus
j okay and then we need to carry over to
the next digit
okay
okay make sense
look we are reversing the actually this
is answer not the result okay and answer
we're reversing the result realize that
result is the list of
digits
it's an integer and now we convert it
using the map convert it to
list of
string
when it's list of string i can join it i
can join as a string and then i want to
remove the
leading zero okay and i want to check if
it's after removing the leading zero if
it is empty it means the result is
yellow right otherwise we return this
right
make sense
yeah make sense
happy
okay you can say bye bye bye
bye bye
[Music]