hello
hello mr all right yeah good
okay so
so given an array of numbers numbers
one two three four five
okay so we want to able to implement two
functions one is to update
defined update
with the index to the value yeah
so these will change the number at index
to value right this is to be very easier
and another function would be to
sum to compute the sum
of a range
and from index to index right
so
basically we want to support these two
functions
what's the naive way of implementing it
for this one
if we want to update the index with num
with the value if this is numb
what's the what's your approach
come on this will be easy
you can
numbs
index equal
what's the time complexity for this
one oh one yeah perfect we're done and
now i want to sum the range from index
to index both are inclusive so it's from
two
by the way this means inclusive okay and
the exclusive is this yeah
a parenthesis okay
so example like
what's the number given this range the
integer
what's the number in this ignorance
integer uh
one two three and one two yeah and
what's the uh what's what's like
these
what's the numbers between integer
between this range
[Music]
so basically we want to sum the range
some of the range
what's your approach for this one we
want to sum up the range given the range
from two yeah this is wrong so how can
we stop it
you tell me you don't need to write i'll
write it for you so what's your punch
sorry
how how do you usually sum it
you know just something
yeah yeah yeah so you can write the loop
all right
so okay tell me answer equals one okay
you feel the brown
four
for
index
yeah in one
okay so what's that
come on
okay you feel the blank you must know
okay come on
and this is the answer okay what's this
what's what well you want to come
calculate the sum
so at the beginning at the beginning
what's the zero okay and the range in
well for index in one
red yes all right and then what's the
front index from yeah
what's the two index okay this is a bit
tricky so i put two or two plus one
yeah
what are we going to sum up with the
numbers here
what are we putting what are we doing
here get the number what's this number
what's this number
if the index in if we if it is index
yeah so what's that index
index is index and what's the value
what's that what's the value how do we
do how do we call it
[Music]
okay you know either why you say you
don't know you know it
makes sense what's the time complexity
for this one
oh and
so we can actually we can rewrite this
using the sum function yeah the
person has list we can just return some
somewhat uh num
okay you tell me
what should i put in there
and there's a column here so what should
i put here
come on return some numbers what
what are we doing here
we want to sum the range sum the numbers
from the from the full from two right so
some lumps
what should we put here
from
and
yeah
we're done okay
so the time of next is all in okay
okay so
so given this number right so given this
uh approach let's let's quickly
put a table here
for the table okay
so that's the space complexity and then
let's
update
update and then there's the
sum
the space complexity for okay maybe the
space complexity for the update
and let's space complexity for uh
sum okay
and the first one our pro we just talked
about the first approach let's do it n1
which is naive okay the update
we will update is on one right the time
is what a one right we just say r1
and then what's what's uh yeah okay okay
and what's this what's that when we sum
up the
sum so what's the times unless you just
said
you just said what
what's the terms of message value
number okay what's the sample message
[Music]
okay what's the space in mexico we're
using any space yeah a one okay okay
this is the pro okay
uh
okay so let the space come and let's
okay
okay so look if they are n
n updates so ideally if there are n
updates and end sum
and operation of sum and one of these
will be o n square which is too slow
right
yeah
yeah i want to get
i was always
owens square right how do you pronounce
this o n
l n square o n square and how do you
pronounce these
squared
o sql all square
any other ways we can do this
any other ways we come up with a data
structure before remember how can we
come so look this is too slow right we
want to
get the sum of a range but this is too
slow so
what kind of data structure can we use
to make it faster
make it faster we
[Music]
okay so what's that called
start with the p what's that called
well what what what what are you doing
here you calculate the sum and then you
minus that what so what's that called
what's good
in the beginning what's that called
prefix prefix sum yeah prefix sum so we
change this to prefix okay so prefix
will be the numbers can you write the
prefix sum here
[Music]
okay so look if we want to calculate the
numbers between
uh two and four so i would need to get
the sum of these four numbers that will
be ten minus one right so that will be
so that time complexity for this one is
what if we given this
one yeah obviously because this just
involves the mathematic the subtraction
so look this is a one right
right
but okay so now what's the update look
how do we update it
so this is the
prefix sum yeah prefix
and then how about if i change this
three to four what would you do
first of all obviously i need to update
the num noms using one but what happened
to this prefix exam
what happened
how do we change this if i we just do
the previous one
yeah i know i know but do we need to do
that again or from the beginning
so what what number
i know i know but what i'm saying is now
i want to change the number three yeah
because we also have this update
function we want to change the number
three to four
right so does it affect anything any
numbers how do we changing the numbers
here we
put this
yeah
the difference yeah seven and i'm
changing
incrementing
all others yeah we're done okay so
what's the time complexity for this one
obviously you know you can do multiple
numbers what's that
yeah you just need to plus one for
everything else yeah
everything on the right okay that's
where done okay so what's the time to
place for this one
[Music]
oh n because this is a one this is one
plus together it's one because
if i change the number here what happens
if i change the first number what
happened
i need to change all the numbers yeah
because they all it's all affected right
so this is alright
look so look it seems that either you
have one or one here or o and a one here
right so if there are n operations here
any operation yeah one of them will be
two so right yeah make sense yeah so
today our task is to to
make one of these quicker than om okay
make sense yeah yeah okay by the way the
space complexity for uh for these two is
all you know oh ln okay
it's the other one smaller than oh n
yeah smaller than that okay so look
because we are using the prefix sum so
the space complexity yeah space
complexity is not
uh
you know it it's not constant anymore
right the update we need to update it
and then prefix okay
actually we can just use the uh yeah we
can just use one column to represent the
space complexity okay
okay so look
if from two so we can just do this
return
if it's all inclusive you want to
calculate the sum between this range
inclusive we can just look at prefix
prefix
uh two
minus
prefix
from minus one right yeah
from minus one yeah there is minus one
but but if front is zero then this will
be negative right we don't want that so
one way is to add a zero at the
beginning right so if we add a zero at
the beginning then
we don't have this problem so we can
just do this wrong and then we can plus
one here right make sense
yeah okay
so when we change the numbers so look if
i want to change these numbers to value
right yeah
or and all i want i need to do is to
what this is not the value and i just
need to increment the difference
differences value
minus nums
index okay
we call this data yeah data
different i know i want to
change the values
to
the all the values on the right to you
know cross this data plus this data yeah
make sense
that's what you did yeah
okay
okay now um
yeah okay let's find so that's the
second option
still to
a bit slow because look this is this one
sum o n this one update on i
look i have nine numbers
but you said to get a time call next to
see
and then this is
oh one yeah yeah that's less than
yeah yeah i know but look this is slow
so base we won't have these two we we
have these two functions and then each
one has n and time we want to call it
center of this has to be
n
yeah less than one yes no no not the
space complexity okay don't worry just
the time conducted okay so these two are
the time
yeah these two columns come next if let
your times end what happens
there will be n square right
yeah b
look o n is this
this is o n o n square
yeah
remote is going up very quickly when n
is a hundred is what
a hundred hundred what's that
ten thousand right
yeah it's very slow right yeah you need
to iterate a thousand uh uh ten thousand
times right
so we ideally we want to find something
you know under the end right underneath
maybe here look at log n right what do
you need to try
let's say even
if i want to call this function n times
right
makes sense
i want to call this function n times
because i say so i just want you know
let's make it faster yeah because look
the problem is is that i want to call
this function n times and n times this n
times the update n times the sum
and look if this one of them is n then
will be you're making the complexity of
n square right yeah without a d okay or
n square yeah
makes sense okay so let's look at these
nine numbers how about if i tell you
that
i want to group them into threes
yeah
and i want to have a blocks a blocks
a block which contains the
the sum of this block yeah
on the sum of this block
so you'll be aware of three yeah
okay so there are n numbers so i want
the block size with n okay block side
will be square and how many blocks are
there
three
which is the same as
the number will be square root of n i
make sense because look square root of n
times square root of n
is 10 right
makes sense 3 times 3 is 9. okay so
what's the sum of these these three
blocks
six
fifteen
and uh
okay so yeah
look sometimes sometimes this square
root n is not integer right for example
if there are only eight numbers you
can't find you can't separate it right
into
into three or right make sense it's just
a rough estimation we can
we can
allocate the block size of square root
of n
so why are these useful
so look
if they ask they are in a square root of
n blocks right so if i want to
if i want to
[Music]
if i want to work if i want to
accumulate to do the sum range in the
worst case how many blocks i need to
cover
in the worst case all of them all of
them so which is how many blocks
this one no no no nine blocks square
root of nine three blocks right
yeah so when we calculate it it will be
square root of n
the time conduction right and when we
update it so however if i want to update
look
look now if i want to change this number
the five to six what happened
if i want to change this five to six
what should we do first of all we need
to change this to six and what happened
here we have changes six and what number
should i change it yes
yeah look i just changed this i don't
need to worry about the rest right
yeah
okay so the time complexity for for this
uh let's say this is the square root
that decomposes uh decomposed
decomposition okay okay
so square root
d how do you pronounce this one
decomposition
how do you
think
don't go wrong and wrong make it easy
okay so
what's how do you compo pronounce the
composition yeah and put a d means that
the opposite yeah
decomposition square root of taken
position so
so look at the the time compresses o
square rule
nude square root of n
sum will be square root of n as well
right
no no no okay i make a mistake this is
to be one right and because we just
update the blocks right one block
yeah yeah look so if i times
all n times
so the time convexity if i multiply this
is you'll be all n times square root of
n right this is better than o and
square right make sense
when we update it we just uh
do what we just update it so you'll be
01 right
yeah
make sense
okay so um
uh
okay so the space complexity for for
this approach would be what how many
blocks there you'll be the how many
blocks are we using so what's the space
complexity what's the space complexity
what's a space complexity yes
[Music]
what's the spectrum how many it depends
it means how many blocks are we using
yeah how many blocks for the space ones
squared okay so it's base convexity i've
just put it here okay one square okay so
basically we just need one okay
and then it'll be one
okay
okay so now uh how how do we map look
this is suppose this index index will be
zero one two
and three four five six seven eight
right right and how do we map these to
index here how do we map these to index
one how to map this to index two if the
m
the block size is three how do we
map these original index to the block
index
very simple
okay
though it
any idea
how do we make zero one two to zero and
three four five two one six seven
eight two two
what what's the comment about it we need
to just do what
what happened if i divide it three four
zero one two all becomes zero right
yes divide it by three three four five
all become one the integer part right
it's not yet two right
yeah six seven eight divided by three
two right two or two point something
and what's this what what's the flaw and
do you still remember yes floor this is
floor this is ceiling right
yes mathematic this is wrong
three point five four equals one
three point
five ceiling
okay that's it so we just need to flow
the original index divided by
block size
okay
the floor then your map to the floor
right
make sense
okay so let's try this
let's try this
so first of all you know at the
beginning i just need to
okay that's the init function yeah init
function and we're taking the numbers
thinking around so first of all the n
okay
n will be equals to the length of the
numbers
all right and then m this is the block
size okay m block size would be the
square root yeah
square root
we if we want to use the square root we
have to import the mass yeah mass of
square root from mass import
square root okay yeah
square root of n and we want to change
it we want to
we want to convert it to integer pi
integer part so we can just do this in
that that's basically the flow function
right and now we also converted the uh
allocated blocks at the beginning the
block sum for each block at the
beginning
what does it equal
i'll be giving initialize to zero yes
times n plus one let's make it extra
space because sometimes it's not evenly
uh allocated right because i just said
that integer the square root of n might
not be an integer
and we have to allocate maybe one or two
yeah one or two yeah i like beginning
and then i just need to go through for i
in range
range n right this is the original index
and i want to put it in the blocks
blocks i
okay so tell me tell me
okay so plus what plus equals they are
the numbers
numbers i right so basically i want to
put the numbers at the numbers in each
block right so what did i just say so
the index i goes between
yeah and
plus
divide divided by okay two two forward
slash means the integer divide and you
get the integer which is this flaw okay
divided by the block size okay which
which one which variable is the box size
and um where that okay
and now we have this block set okay so
this is
this is any function the preparation
yeah preparation and now we want to
update after it's simply update
update
i want to update with the index with the
value first of all
first of all i want to find out which
index which in okay so the index look
so i need to do what i need to blocks
index divided by m this is the index
converting the index to the block id
right needs to pass the difference
what's the difference the current value
is value and i need to minus the
previous the previous value which is
nums
index right this is the difference right
yeah if you changing the five to six
this would be one right and i want to
update the block sum yeah
with
with one more right make sense and then
i just need to update the values again
so nums
index
equals value
look these two lines what's the time
complexity it's right on it's written on
the ball what's the time conversion for
the update
which one is it
look at this one
come on yes it's all one
okay
i need to this population is all
o n right because we're going through
the n
all right space complexity o n square
that okay n squared yeah o n plus one o
m okay which is square root of n okay
now the most uh
key part is to
sum the range
define summary okay come on this is the
last part okay some range let's say from
i to index j we want to sum the range
given this range i to j inclusive okay
okay at the beginning let's put the put
the sum in here in the answer variable
right
yeah
okay
and then now let's do this x this is the
point x okay let's this is the position
let's put it in the p okay p equals the
position and i
why
why it's not reaching the
j it when
when we are currently not summing up to
the we're not reaching the right the the
right most part okay okay so now here
again
this is the number and we have some
we have some which is 6
24 here
now if i tell you look look at me if i
tell you i want to sum this range i will
i want to sum up the range here
okay what would you do
what would you do
no no i want to sum the range three i
want to get the sum between three to
seven inclusive three four five six
seven what would you do what would you
sum up the sum what would you get the
sum
[Music]
no no we're given these whole numbers
and i tell you this is block sound
yeah there are three numbers would you
calculate some
how would you calculate some
um i would
just
now what's the difference than the
previous the the first one remember we
have this bros told you somewhere
making make use of this how do we make
use of it we just use that use that and
then we use that to to get the sum of
this block and then just proceed yeah
exactly yeah don't make it faster right
make sense
yeah because look
because
because these two yeah
yeah and most we we are traversing
one block the blocks the entire block we
don't need to go over
each animal in each block and for the
rest yeah these two rest
the animals
and most will be
roughly
square root of n
times two right
yeah let's make it the most and once you
release so the time constant will be
like that okay
the time conducts t why is that
because they are
square root of square root of n blocks
right
roughly okay
and then
for the rest which is not inside which
which is not covered in the entire block
i can just do this
sum yeah by individual number and that
let's say in the worst case it's two
times the square root but it's less
so this time complexity would be o
square root of n that's why we have here
right so look
now we just how do we check if how do we
check if it's currently if x is here
and then x plus plus the m size
is smaller than j right it's smaller
than the j then we can use the block sum
right we don't need to go through each
number
in the blocks because we already
pre-calculated the blocks
uh the sum in the block right okay
while p smaller than j then we say if
if p materials block size
equal equal zero
and
its cover it's covered this block is
totally covered so p plus m smaller
equals j
then we can just add the sum right
answer
plus equal the block size the sum will
be blocks
the block sum of current is p right p p
will be converted to the block size so
this is the box and then we need to jump
jump up the entire block right because
because look we already here we know
this number is 15 and covers three
numbers and once i calculate i added the
sum i need to jump to the next block
right make sense i don't need to jump
one by one i can jump to the next block
so
p
plus equal
jump by m unit yeah
plus even else okay else is that it's
not covered then i have to add it
i have to edit the column number right
so answer plus equal the current number
is nums
nums
uh p right times p and then p plus
equal one yeah we move by one by one
right right am right
return reason why
yes
okay do you really understand do you
want me to test you for a little bit
give you a little bit challenge okay
come come on okay that's easy so can you
explain to me what's this part
and what's this part i know
oh man okay so answer plus equals
yeah okay so look i want to calculate
the sum from three to seven from three
here and i look
otherwise if it's not covered by entire
block
then i have to add a
sum three and seven so so basically the
sum would be three plus fifteen plus
seven okay the 15 part is here the three
and seven part is here got it
make sense
yeah is it clear is it clear so the
individual if this individual is not
covered by this block
yeah it's not covered by the block like
in the range all right because look we
want to calculate the sum between these
two right
and it only covers one entire block
right
it covers the entire block then i can
edit
i can speed up the process i don't need
to add the numbers here right because i
already know like yeah make sense
i'm gonna release level over individual
i just get here i just edit
right
so the times complexity i just said
because they're at most square root of n
blocks so the worst case is square root
of n plus an individual yeah really this
individual cannot be more than
2 times square root of n right so all
together you'll be
o square root of n let's let's keep
let's this part the sum of this part
okay update we have to cover this okay
so now
the very last bit
okay so look oh
which one is bigger which one is bigger
sometimes we have these yeah log n
which one is bigger but they're tricky
okay because look this is square root of
the decomposition and we
in the future we're going to talk about
some other trees
some other techniques like segmentation
tree
sandwich tree which is all which has the
old lock end
lock and impulse method yeah
up there and sum okay so can you tell me
which one is bigger
if you don't know
we can always plug in a value let's say
let's let's factor n equals 100
what square root 100 10
okay so what's this number
log
2 to the 100 to the power of 100 2 to
the power of what
is roughly 100
power how many twos do you need
how many tools do you need come on
how many tools you need
one two three four five six seven
seven every seven is what two to the
power seven is one
okay two to the power of five
two to the power five four sixteen
thirty two
or a 62 yeah so it's between
64. it's between 64 to 128 so the number
is 2 to the power of 6000 something yeah
six so it's roughly six point something
so which is
which is faster
which is faster yeah slower than slow is
faster so but still this is quite good
okay okay
my sense today we complexities of square
root of n
and if you if we plot it this is o n
this will be
all log n
roughly of n square
and oh
uh
these will be more a little bit more
than these between yeah got it yeah
these will be square root of n okay
make sense
okay that's it for today good job
bye bye bye