hello mr mr ryan ry
okay
so okay so we're going to talk about the
binary tree converting the binary to
undirectional graph okay so remember
all these are graphs
right but only the first one only the
first one is the
tree okay and it's specifically spinal
cheese
so the final trees first of all it's a
graph it's a subset of glass right and
it doesn't have these arrows okay it
doesn't have error it's an directional
graph okay
but
some people think it's a direction it's
dag why is that because the parents
from the trees we cannot from the if
we're given a root of tree under the
root of the tree we can only visit from
parents to kids yeah we can't go back
right if you're given two you don't know
where the parent is you only know it's
kids right so
sometimes we can think of trees as
directive directive directive
from parents to kids
and a cyclist yeah a cyclist
what does it mean exactly
what does this mean
[Music]
so look this is not not a tree because
it has a graph oh yes a cycle right we
don't have a cycle in the tree at least
it's not because it's not connected
it's not connected right these two are
separate this is not connected these
this is kind of forest right foreign
this is not right if if we okay so this
is the directive graph yeah
undirectional undulation graph means
that
you know you just uh
it doesn't have errors errors
just like that right
so it means three completed four or four
can also visit three okay
all right so we are going to convert the
binary trees okay convert the final
trees
the final dream it means that a parent
can only have two maximum two maximum
two yeah if it doesn't have any kid it's
a leaf now we also we call it terminal
okay terminal
terminal
terminal now okay leave
this please
okay so um usually
how can we represent a tree
class three yeah we cover three
and then well define
usually we define a
a tree using this kind of structure yeah
and the value and the left and right
right
okay
yeah so self
dot value equals value that means the
value of the note
the radial note and then it has two
two things pointing to the left and
right right
left
self
the right
equals okay so this is the three
definition one of the three definitions
in object oriented programming in python
right because we have three we have a
node we have value and we point to the
left and the points to the right okay
yeah make sense
yeah
and also some sometimes we can define
the tree
like we defined a graph which is what we
should for example like this one look
one two
three
four five so we can define it as the
list of
at least
from parents to the kid
a list of the edges right
we can define it as a list of edges so
what what what log 3 is defined look
it's one to two
okay a list of this yeah and then what
one two three
three two four
and three to five right you see
this is another way of defining a tree
right and
we can also use this to define a graph
right because the tree is a graph right
all right
okay so how do we define the graph
remember
define how do we represent the graph for
example like uh
you know how do we represent this in in
in a graph
okay how do we represent this in a block
one two three
any idea i mean we talked about this
before yeah how do we define
what did i just say
[Music]
if we're using this how do we define
we just list the number of edges
one two yeah
another one one three yeah if it's the
undirectional power
and then
two three okay
okay this is our direction if we hit the
direction then this we can also use this
to use the dimension here directly okay
and sometimes if there are
numbers over the edges we call it weight
right because for example if two from
two travel to three it costs like five
pounds yeah i put a five here five
pounds yeah something like that yeah if
it's one to two cost three pounds okay
so look three this is directional
weighted directional weighted edge
weighted edges weighted
directional weighted
graph okay
if a number if edge has the
numbers on it it means the weight
weighted weight and the one to three
yeah what about one to three i don't
know maybe it's three okay let's make
that so look we can use this there from
two and we possibly we can we can have a
another value called edge uh one two two
is three constraints sometimes something
like that right the list of edges
uh alternatively we can we can use uh we
can have this kind of data structure
which cause the adjacent list adjacent
adjacent list
okay what does that mean it means that
look at that
uh taking this for example yeah one to
two
two to three and maybe one two three
okay
so look the first
let's say the first graph okay the first
the first that we can use the dictionary
graph yeah dictionary okay this channel
g default dictionary yeah another the
key is the note the vertex yeah this is
converted
remember the vertex
vertex okay
vertex the graph is the collection of
vertex and edges okay so g equals a
connection of v and e okay so g
collection of v v is the key
key which is one
and then we can point to a list of if
the
vertex it points to in this case is two
and then
three right and
and then if two uh because we have a
weight only if this is uh
i'm waiting we can just do this a list
of vertex and if it's weighted then we
can put a couple yeah remember the top
two it points to the two the weight is
three
it points to the three it weighs as
three okay
okay so look the second
the second vertex
it points to three yeah it points to
three
it points to three the weight is five
okay and any other
vertex it points to it no right and then
vertical three
look at the vertex three points to
nothing right so we do this just empty
this
so this is the adjacent disk
okay
and we also can represent the graph
using the
adjacent metric so what does it mean
look
if if these are one two three okay let's
make it zero one three one two okay
and zero one two so we can just save
space on the magic so look
so we can do we cannot let metric yeah
so the rows
this is the rows
this is the columns
so for each node look this is g g if g i
j right
g i j means that the vertex i to vertex
j right this look and the weight only if
it's weighted so we can do this
g
zero to one is three so we put it zero
so let's just put it because look there
are three three notes so there will be
three three right
nine values
so what's the diagonal what's this
what does
what does it mean
it means gi what does it mean the
vertices i to vertical side right
yeah so usually it would be
the values that you know okay so the
value zero to zero so you'll be zero
right okay let's fill this zero to one
which is three
zero one so i put this into three change
this to three
okay and then zero to two
from zero to two is three so look
zero to two here i change it to two
right
okay and then
one to two is five
so one
yeah
two zero one two
is five
okay and one s see that to two is three
so where do i put it
where do i put the three zero to three
zero zero to two
zero
zero uh
okay okay wait wait wait that's a
mistake five five one
one to
one to two right one to two and
two uh three is zero to two zero to two
i put it already okay
i know
if but if one two two one two two then
what zero
so it start with zero okay one to two
yeah one to two yeah
so look zero one
yeah
zero one two five okay so that's three
values
yeah yeah because look at the metric the
the away the least in the computer style
is zero
zero to two is three yeah
zero
ah so okay zero one two okay generator
two is three yeah you're all right yeah
okay so what's three
zero two one is three okay so there's no
two here right because there are three
edges three three five okay so easy five
right now we're done yeah
you see adjacent magic this is how we
represent the graph using adjective
mention
okay so this is just the basic okay and
today task very simple
okay
so today we will give you a binary to
you especially but you can we can extend
this to
to n
to a general it doesn't have to be
binary it could be n three
how do you say the tree which has the
three maximum three notes
i think ten arrays we always
[Music]
maybe i don't know means three yeah
okay i don't know okay so look at the
balance tree okay one two three
four okay let's let's say this finally
yeah let's find the thing look
let's find energy
we want to convert it yeah we want to
convert it
to
a graph
like what the adjacent list for example
adjacent is right g equals the graph
okay additionally yeah this is called
using this and then you need to tell me
which is what
one the key the one points to
two and three okay
yeah
but again two
two points to one right because look
look look look
the graph that the tree only one point
is two by one graph is undirectional
okay so two means needs to point to one
again right yeah
so if you take these if you consider
this as a graph as a graph it's not a
tree look two is connected to one as i
like
okay so now three you tell me what
should i put here
three what should i put here
put it in the list what should i put uh
you should put
no way
how many how many vertex
does the three connect to
one
[Music]
yeah
okay but let's go into what's the
pokemon card yeah if i get it yeah
okay
and then four
four is
three
okay and then five
you see
so look we converted these to
undirectional graph because it yeah one
connected to three we also connected one
right
yeah and directional graph final three
final trick you can use this
uh the the thing we just said three each
three note
uh has the value
has a left
that's the right okay
okay
yeah
but before we do this
this is one kind of three structure and
how about an edges you know let's say we
have edges from
two edges this is edges
edges this is the added list of edges
yeah
list of edges from two from two
from two okay
yeah
okay so
that makes sense so do we how do we do
it remember
for this one it'll be simple yeah we'll
go through the list i know we can just
assign it right
yeah
but for this one
for this one what
it's not given the tree is not given by
edges it's given by the notes
by a lute note
right
right so so we need we can we need to
travel as a tree so what kind of
equilibrium in your mind can you know
can we use to travel
where down backwards
let's do this okay that will be easy
okay
i'm going to try i'm going to i'm going
i'm going to keep this okay this is the
graph this is the
the adjacent matching adjacent
no adjacent list okay adjusting this
yeah because the keys are the vertex the
least is the list of the
vertex it connects to right
so
um
okay so let's let's let's write this
okay define
uh
let's say convert
a tree if like three is given uh edges
okay let's write this version first of
all we need to define this g equals
default additional yeah because because
by default is the dictionary
and then the default value this the
value is the what what what type of the
value is this
dictionary what's this
what's this
what's this what's it called
yeah but what's this what's type of
these
yeah at least
yeah
you see yeah if it's an integer we'll
put it in right if it's a string we'll
put a str right
and now it just goes through the digit
for
a the edge is given a to b a b in edges
[Music]
then i can say g
a
well
list of edges g a dot
append
b right
and can you write this g what a pen one
because a to b that means there's an
edge from b to there because we're
trying to
convert the trees into undirectional
graph okay yeah undirectional means both
ways both ways
yeah
uh so this is the
given list will be very similar we just
go through the list and how about if the
if we are given this as uh loot right
we're going to root
right and this we can't use this anymore
but
as we said different search processes
right
but
so look if i want to travel
like that okay
point for search what's the possible
search uh let's say here
what's the process search order for this
one
okay what's the preference search uh for
search
[Music]
if it's a pre-order
no no if it's one
if it's in order
it's one
two
[Music]
three four five six yeah oh is that uh
no no no at least it's not dinosaurs to
you because look oh yeah it's not but
but look if
we order what's pre-order
note left to right right we visit the no
first
and we visit the left and we'll visit
the right okay so
note so we visit the no first place one
okay one two
three
and this is the right why which is four
five six yeah note that that's us okay
okay so but we visit these so whenever
we reach the note we want to add an edge
from the kids to the parent what does it
mean
what does it mean
look we're traversing the tree but we
want to add a edge between the kids to
the parents so what does it mean do we
but we don't know the parent yeah but we
know where it comes from right yeah so
what does it mean the difference search
we need to pass down the parents right
yeah
define
that for such first of all
and i know the parent yes parents
what you're doing what you
you're busy
dude and parents
okay eric
why do we need a parent and what did i
just say
because um
because the parent
is
yeah why we need a parent in in
different states
because we stopped
yeah and then we will go down we want to
add the edge from parent to current
right yeah that's right okay
okay it's not good
if we originally empty air we just
returned right
okay
and then if apparently if they ask
parents if we have parents because we
have to check why is that because
because a parent could be
numb in what cases the parent would be
nothing it would be enough
right the loot
the route doesn't have parents right
yeah yeah if
if parents if there's parent then we can
just say
g
parent
not a pen and you can write this as a
plus equal okay this is the same thing
dude all right
okay can you tell me what's next g what
plus e for one
okay
i'm adding a h from parent to the root
and what's next
anyway come on you're listening if i add
edges from parent to the load what does
it mean do i
um do i need to add the edges what
i have already added from parent to root
so what do i need to add next
[Music]
okay i already add the edge from one to
two
so what should i do next
what's your ad
okay so what the other part is
[Music]
there's
yeah it's easier
and now we just have to travel the black
tree and right three right so can you
tell me
dfs one
left what's the parent of rudolph come
on i asked you the question before yes
and
another one dms
and then what's the parent
and then we just call the beginning
dfs loot what's the parent upload
beautifully yeah we traverse on a tree
in different manner recursions
and but we need to pass down the parents
right
because because we need to add edge from
a parent to the root if the parent if
there's a parent yeah in the special
case is the root doesn't have a parent
so we pass with none if personal number
say the parent is numb and then
it doesn't add an edge here
okay so there's a problem
why is that look i need to
i need to put it here right because look
even apparently if the root if there's a
rule lou still needs to add
do i need to add that look
i passed the
pass download
okay g root um
root adding the
kit
no no no okay wait wait wait
d pattern if parent and parent has the
to the lord okay and then the loot dude
needs to add the parent no uh
maybe not
that's okay because
in this case apparently it's nothing
yeah do you add
you don't add the edge right so that's
right yeah because the
if it's the root you only add the edge
you only go down to the kids to other
edge right so you come to the left and
you add edge from two to the one or one
one to the two okay if apparently it's
nothing then we don't
execute so this is correct this is
correct that's the default search
and the preference search and what kind
of
how do we implement a processor do we
still remember what kind of data
structure are we used uh are we using to
implement a breakfast search
what's cue
[Music]
first thing
first thing what up
first thing first of all yeah it's like
a queue right you you you you wait in
the queue right first come first serve
yeah first first thing first one okay
in python we use the
how do we implement how do we declare a
queue
how do we take care of you
what and i need to put a
loop
yeah yeah loot an apparent
the parent is numb right
uh
the first parameter is the note the
second parameter is the
the second
value in the coupler yeah we're using
the parentheses is the tuple is the
parent it's parents and the dq dq means
double ndq
then wire q okay
so now we take an element out so we take
the carbon
we take the current and then we take the
parent and then that will be the same
yeah q how do we get the element how do
we get the elements on the queue how do
we take it out
dq how do we take it out take it take an
element of the
left where down top from the left hand
left hand side yeah if the stack is the
the other side it pops right
yeah remember the step first thing
that's alright you put this in and you
take it out on one side
but q q is different yeah you dq you
enqueue it means putting an element into
the cube
on one side and you take it out from the
other side this is pop left this is
apparent
right why we're using the
dq
if we put it on the left side we
if we probably then on the other side we
this is a pen left
right and then this is the
append left top left
a pen
and then this is what pop okay
double ndq means two ways you can do it
so the way one advantage of using double
ndq is that the
the operation these four operations are
all constant time right it's not like at
least in python look impressive if you
declare a kill using this simple list
right you can stop pop
zero remember but prob zero
is ninten it's called ninja time right
all right
make sense
yeah what did i just say
okay so now we're getting the element
from the queue
and then again this is the samurai it's
parent you kind of what should we do
apparent
g
parent
a pen
current okay can you tell me what's next
this is the same like before definition
gui
what i added edge from parent to current
and what you are adding next
if lays the left kid
we need to push it into the kill yeah
apparently
can you tell me a penalty apparently
yeah attacker
so i playing card on the left and then
what's the card what's the new parent of
curry in the left
what's the parent of the car in the left
and what do i do next is what
if what i push the left key what should
i do with the right kid
[Music]
what's the pattern of current the right
current yeah okay
okay
okay so
what did i just talk about
to sum up
finally
no no no
you need to tell people that what what
have you learned today about trees
and what species what's the problem
we're trying to solve here
uh we're talking and we're trying to
uh
come to
[Music]
and this is adjacent list okay it's all
on the board okay
okay
okay well done that's it for today good
job bye bye
bye bye
bye
sure happy face
let's not happy smiling
one more time
okay that's better thank you bye finally
[Laughter]