[Music]
even numbers
okay okay two four six
eight and ten and
that one yeah okay okay yeah as you said
hello mr eric hello mr rice hello
hello yo okay so today
our job is to sum the first and even
numbers yeah
remember uh yesterday we talked about
the sum of the first
and odd numbers and now equation is one
n times n right yeah squared okay
n times n n squared and right now
it's gonna be n times
and at n
okay what why is that okay so i'm going
to teach you
yeah this is the correct formula to sum
up the first uh
and even numbers for example they are
five right so the sum
is five times five plus five that's
thirteen
am right 10
20 30. okay so yeah good question
why okay so why okay so
so remember the first n numbers yeah
we're talking about the first n number
six properties first n numbers
yeah the sum you know in mathematics we
use this
this is this symbol yeah like e every n
yeah that's e e r e and then you can say
i
equals 1 to n yeah
and then you can sum i so let means
that means i equals 1 plus 2
2 plus 3 plus t of n okay
so basically this is a mathematic
symbol to say okay i want the sum
i i equals from one to n sometimes you
can
just say one to n okay so let's okay
let's look
like a sum okay sum from one to n
some i so let's read okay so what's this
equation
uh remember how what's the equation for
this
okay so that's a quick way to understand
it okay so this sum
is that the first item what's the first
item of this
we call it one number progression yeah
we call it all
these are three how how do you spell
this automatic
mathematic asthmatic progression
okay i don't know how to spell it so the
first item
is an experiment one first
item last item okay
so let me equation yeah yeah first item
plus
last item comes and how many items
how many how many
and then divided by two okay so if you
do this the first item is
one yeah the last item is
how many items divided by two
okay so this is the number for example
one two
[Music]
yeah from one look one to a hundred is
one plus a hundred
times a hundred divided by two so that's
what
that's 50 50. okay
yes 50 50. yeah you got it you have to
sum the numbers from from one to 100
okay
so now we know this yeah uh actually
we can we can use the mathematic
induction to do this
as well right right and don't touch it
we can do this mathematic equation now
we're gonna
teach you about now
[Music]
no no no look okay so one n
base case mathematic induction when base
case when n is one
so let's sum i is one next plane will be
one right because the first
first one number yeah okay so let's say
f k equals this is the one times uh
k times one plus one times k
divided by two okay yeah and now we want
to add one more item so fk
k plus one equals this yeah fk
plus one plus what plus
this is the k because this is sum from
the first k numbers and
we want to plus one more yeah okay
so look if we we substitute this
in so k plus one times k divided by two
plus k plus one right
yes and then if i put a two here that
needs
these to be two right yeah so this
this thing so it's equals to k
times k k square plus k plus
two k plus two okay
k squared okay yeah k times k is k
squared 1 2
okay so how do we simplify this so
look k remember k plus 1 square equals k
square plus 2 k plus 1 right yeah
so look k 2 2 and then i can
these 2 will be 1 plus 1 right yes
i take away so this is k plus one square
and then pick k plus one so what does
this mean this thing
equals k plus one square
yeah plus k plus one
okay and divided by two and if i
do the k plus one so that will be k
k plus one times k plus one plus one
okay so what does it mean this is this
is
n this is n and two so it's the same
form as k
plus one times uh n plus one times
n divided by two by two okay so that
means that this formula is correct okay
so now yesterday we already proved so we
don't need to prove it again so this
remember this is the sum of the first n
numbers right
yes and we have we know the sum of the
first and
all numbers yes which is squared
n squared right n times n yeah so it
means that
if if i do this
this is the sum of all n numbers yes and
i
one minus the first and
even all numbers
and what's these what's this
that will be the first and even numbers
right because i
this is total numbers and i remove i
detect the
even number or number and that would be
the even numbers right yeah
yeah yeah yeah okay so we this is the
formula we want to
we want to know okay so this is this
what i just told you is this right
yeah yeah okay so what's this
look that equals two n squared
plus n minus two n square right
yeah what are you doing with this sorry
what you're doing is
oh i think there's a problem and n
plus n plus 1 plus n divided by 2
minus is it n square first and even
numbers
no no no okay so that that will be up
there's a problem
because because how uh there's a
slightly problem here okay
can you notice because look
um keep crying ryan you're making it
easy
so please spinning around makes you
dizzy
so let's first end numbers yes
yeah so how many even numbers
[Music]
okay let's let's put it this way because
lee look
because this n could be all or could be
even right yeah so
so how about let's say i i want
uh the first and the first and
all numbers yeah all numbers
sum is n square right
yeah and then n square
plus the first uh let x we are not we
want we want to know the first and even
numbers yeah
right and then equals it will be equals
to 2n not
n right because look there are n numbers
and then n numbers there will be two
ends
not an n okay yeah so
that will be n will be 2 n so that will
be 2 n
times 2 n plus 1 divided by 2 right
yeah because there are two numbers not
numbers yeah
yeah this is all sum of e
all numbers yeah and n all numbers
plus n even numbers how many numbers are
there
n n and n there are n numbers
n all numbers and n even numbers so how
many numbers are there
m two n to one because they're n
and nano p two n right yeah so that's
two n
you will not see the one that's the sum
of the if this i put this is
making this into 2n so that would be 2 n
and 2n plus 1 yeah divided by y
okay so the two even numbers plus two
odd numbers so how many numbers are
there
is a
um one two
two two numbers two even numbers that
would be two four right
yeah two out numbers that will be one
three so how many numbers are there
what do you mean one three and two four
two two oh uh there are two even numbers
that will be
two and four and then two all numbers
there will be one and three so how many
numbers are there four yeah easy so
that's four numbers so
so the sum of these n is two right so
the sum of one plus two plus three plus
four would be
uh this formula this formula
but what but we need to choose this n as
2n yeah because there are four numbers
yeah
got it okay easy yeah
okay so now we just need to x x
equals one so if i divide b two so that
would be two right
so that would be what two n square
plus n minus n square okay
so can you simplify this two n squared
minus
n square n
square plus n yes so this is the formula
yeah we just move here yeah
that's the sum of the first
even right first sum you might notice
yeah i'm going to do the coding
yeah yeah wait wait
n times n plus n when n is one
the sum is two right the sum should be
two right
yeah all right the first
one even number that would be two right
yes okay so let's say fk again
k times k plus k and then f k
k plus one equals f k plus one
so what's the next next what's the name
one uh
no only because this is the look if k is
one right
f1 is one right and f2 will be
f1 plus the second
the second even number that would be
four right
yes so this four is what
two times k plus one right am right
k is one k is two uh
take k is one and k plus one would be k
plus one so that would be
uh two times k plus one right
let's try another one f two equals
exactly one
f three equals f2 plus what
3 will be 2 4 6 yeah so k is 2
2 2 times 2 plus 1 so
i want to add a 6 okay so it should be
adding this 2 k plus 1
okay so that equals what k squared plus
k
plus 2k plus 2 right
yes yes all right
is it right
oh you're touching that thing okay
okay don't touch it okay now next thing
we're gonna do is recording pause no no
no we haven't pulled
it yet so that that would be uh
we want to prove is the same form of
this right so so so that would be
k uh plus one
k plus one square this will be k
plus k square plus 2 k plus 1 right
so how many will be left if i take away
this from here
then what that would be another k plus
one right you see
you see we just prove f k plus 1 is k
plus 1 square plus k plus 1 so if we
take this is k
this is k so it's the same form of this
n right so it's
correct okay so now i'm going to
do a coding two implementation again so
you tell me
you tell me which one is better okay
defined
f yeah one answer
yeah because yellow four i in
branch french
[Music]
last last even number will be
two times n plus one right
then i need to check
answer one plus equal one plus equal
i i
[Music]
i haven't implemented here how do you
know okay so the other implementation f
and return
n times n plus n okay oh
this one is
it doesn't matter which input how big is
your input i can always calculate it
in constant time yeah
n times n plus n okay in python
in python we have a phone you know from
mass you can throw math
import import as a
import power i i believe is power
believe
maybe not maybe not maybe there's a
function
no no no i don't think this okay i would
double check this
maybe it's power power and then i can
write power n2 right so let me use
n to the power of two right pow okay so
remember in person yeah if you want to
write
a to the top power of b yes
you can write this way a guess what
guess what
that's okay one pie yeah yeah but i have
to put another multiply b
so that's imperson you can do it this
way right times
time it means a to the power of b okay
so if i do this
a 2 power power
3 what's the answer
okay let's verify look look here look
here
look two ten times d you see
you see can you see hey okay
yeah okay yes okay um
okay the last thing good job today
bye bye bye bye bye
bye bye bye bye okay i'm gonna show
surely little times times three okay
look look
this is the one i talked about okay
maybe
can you hold it can you hold it can you
hold it hold it hold on let me check
something okay
from mess import power
yeah yeah yeah look at this power
function look at this power function
yeah
yeah you can totally do it this way
power two
two three it's the same thing yeah it's
the same thing you see
yeah it's the same thing yeah okay thank
you bye