hello mystery are you right
okay
okay good thank you for doing that okay
so today we're going to talk about a
little mess problem
and square plus 19 times n minus and
what's this factorial factorial okay
what's factorial
factorial is
what's factoring
n
times
n minus one
n minus two
until one
okay and what's zero factorial you
missed n minus
yeah
okay oh yeah yeah all right yes
okay okay what's the and what's yellow
factor
one okay what's one factor
uh one okay we're done okay good and how
do we implement this unfortunate thing
remember we talked about this in the
first lesson right
yeah what's the first thing in essence
the first implication
okay so let's look if n is zero
return we we define the base case which
is
yeah which is one otherwise it would be
returned
n times what can you write a location
here
f1
minus one we have done wow you remember
i know you can also turn this into
factor uh because
uh yeah you're bigger
iterative so which is what answer equals
one and then we
we went for i in letter for n in range
let's say for i in range and
range m plus y because we're going to
multiply two
actually we can start from the two right
because multiply one
changes nothing right
okay answer
times equal
i
and then return what
three one
come on
there's no n answer equals one return
one come on
yeah this answer keeps the result of the
factory right and then start from two to
n
every time i times this i right do you
get it
what what did i just say your pc drawing
leave
he said it times and
now i yeah i is the yeah the thing with
intertime okay i'm so smart
okay
[Music]
so look
we want to solve this equation so what's
n n
is n what's the range of n
what's n if look we're looking at this
yeah i know so in order for n factorial
to make sense and it should be bigger
and equal zero non-negative right and n
should be
should be y should be the type of
integer right it can't be a real number
right it can't be three point five
because three point five factorial makes
no sense it can't be negative number
minus one factorial makes no sense okay
yeah is it possible
no no no no we don't define that yeah
okay so look
can n be zero
zero zero minus zero factorial minus one
is not equal to zero okay okay so
no it's too big i don't know 1960 is a
big number okay so
so i mean what if we want to ask
computer to solve it what kind of
equilibrium are you thinking do you
think
what kind of ergon
can we use to
try different values
try every possibilities
what's that called simcoe how do we ask
computers to solve this problem to try
every value
try the possible values
what's the angle and cost
beautiful thing
but look we know that the minimum that
possible value is zero right
but we don't know the upper bound right
the lower bound is zero the upper bound
could be
we don't know yet we don't know which
number right so we can in this case we
can ask computers to keep trying and
they found it it may not find its answer
okay we know we don't know i don't think
there's a possible one yeah that's the
problem okay if there's no such answer
then computer will keep trying or we
never end right because they just keep
trying and how do we do this
okay
why are true right why assume is okay
this is always true
enter this loop if this is always true
then we keep trying this right and at
the beginning the first number we're
going to try is zero and if n times n
okay n times n squared n squared we can
implement n times n
and all what n times times remember one
two okay we're done all we use the math
function where is the power
and
what what's the second perimeter um
yeah there's three ways these three a's
are equivalent okay if n times n plus
19 times and
minus n factorial right we can we
already define it
or look we don't need to reinvent the
wheel in order to be inventory we are
we don't need to implement this we can
just import
from
mass
import
factorial yeah because we already
defined this factorial factorial
factory and we just can say factorial
factorial n right if equal equal zero
then grade we just return
n okay otherwise m plus equal one right
right
look
we don't define the outer part so what
does it mean if laser there is no such
solutions and the computer will just
keep trying keep trying keep trying keep
trying keep trying and you never end
right that's that's the
one this uh pitfall that they're using
these profiles to try because we just
ask computers just to
you know
naively trying right without thinking
uh okay so
we want to find out these yeah but the
thing is that
this function this is a quadratic
function and this is the factorial
function we don't know how you know
that the growth they grow like the
trends
[Music]
is
but
let's understand this a little bit more
okay this is look
this this is a quadratic function and
it's not easy to analyze it because the
projective function remember if it is n
squared plus 19 and if n is zero is zero
right if n is one it's 20 right so it
could be something like that right the
continuity function right remember
yeah yeah
unless it's n factorial we don't know
yet yeah so it's really hard to compare
these two right without plugging in some
value but we can make it a simple right
look
let's move this thing to the right right
side okay
okay so n squared plus 19 and equals
answer right yeah
yeah just move relation to the right and
change the sign
okay so now 25
so n bacteria equals what n times
n minus one factorial right
makes sense
yes and we know n is not zero right
yeah we just prove the n is not zero
right
if n is not zero we can divide
both sides
some right yeah
so we can get rid of these
uh let's try this
look look n square plus is is n plus 19
right this is the same thing n times n
n times
19 right and now we can divide it by n
uh
in both sides so we get rid of this
because out right n plus 19.
yeah
okay
okay so
let's let's rewrite let's use a k k
equals n minus one okay let's let's just
just substitute the variable
n minus one is k
so what's this so n equals k plus one
right
k plus 1 plus 19 with the left side and
the right side becomes what
k factorial right
right makes sense
what did i just do
e is k factorial what's k
k is
k plus 1 plus 19.
it's k yeah i i just substitute the
variable okay another k plus 20 equals k
factorial right
it
says okay so look this is a lot simpler
than the original one this is conjecture
this is the line linear k plus 20 equals
k what's k plus here k plus 30 is a line
right so how do we plot this line k
factorial all right
when k is zero
is it uh it's 20 here right
okay so one k is one is 21 so it would
be something like i thought the answer
is
m minus one equals k okay
like this is this question yeah yeah i i
just substitute the n minus one with k
okay
yeah yeah
because i don't like this and minus one
thing so i substitute with k
and then up
so n is k plus one so look
if i can solve the k
if i can solve the k so i know the n
right it's the same thing all right
yeah
so k plus 2 this is a line right you'll
be something like that right
and k factorial
calculator is each the trend should be
growing much much lower 0 factorial is
one it's somewhere here one factorial is
also one
right that's tiny yeah because this is
twenty and then two factorial is two
right
three factorial is
six
four factorial two
thirty four
this is th this is one this is twenty
yeah yeah so you'll be here right and
five factorial
they which one grows faster which one
you think is grow faster
this one yeah this one so what does it
mean after five right because when k is
five
this line is 25 and then that's 4 plus
20.
1k is 5. the left side is
uh
but i thought
oh yeah yeah okay
yeah yeah yeah yeah so when k is four
should be four yeah when k is four
when k is four okay so this is when k is
four
uh this is five one k is four k is uh
this line is twenty four and four factor
is also 24 right so what happened is 5
5 this is 25 here right
but this thing 10 0 is here
so
the more after 5 right faster four
anything on the right
this case the case material thing going
faster growing faster right
growing a lot faster and then these two
lines what does it mean
you never cross again
right am right
the only thing it costs is here k equals
12 right
makes sense
okay so if k then we can solve this then
we can just solve this we know
that there's only one solution right
that we just proved like we know it's
only the one solution is k equals four
which is n equals five
there's no such solution right
there's no other solution right because
we already know the land this is how we
prove that we only have this one
solution make sense
yeah so coming back to the original we
blue force we don't know yeah because
even you find a solution for k uh n
equals five how do you know how do you
know there's no such other solution
right you the computer
can't prove
but we human we just prove because we
plot the graph
this is only the correspond
and when it goes further when the k when
the k becomes bigger
the difference
becomes larger
make sense
yes
okay so we just proved that k equals 4
and n equals 5 this is the only solution
right because we can proof of this bit
the domain is here and we don't know
because there are lots of numbers here
but we know they are not solutions
okay any questions
okay what did you learn today come on
learn about that math
math okay and how did you come up with
five as in first okay
how many numbers have you proved for us
before you get to five
[Music]
six
six and you find it too big
yeah
six numbers
i guess so yeah okay so we tried zero
you try one you try two you try three
you try for five open you got it right
yeah okay by you but you
but you have an answer then there's
other solutions yeah
okay so this is to tell you that five is
the only right answer okay yeah okay
good job today that's it for today
bye bye