hello mr are you all right
yes
okay so we talk about the golden ratio
golden ratio
gold
and ratio
and it's represented by a greek letter
which is uh like that yeah five
d
yeah five okay five something like that
five
so it is defined as look if we have a
line segment and the bigger one is a the
smaller one is b
right and the sum is a plus b the ratio
between the big the sum to the bigger
one
is equals the bigger one
divided by the smaller one right
right this is generation if we if we set
p equals 1 and a is the goal generation
okay
so let's try to solve this then we can
multiply this yeah so a square
a square
equals
a plus b times b
right and this is what a b plus b
squared right
because we said b equals one so a square
equals a plus one right
if we move these two to the other side
so what a square minus a minus one
equals zero
quadratic function we know there are
there are two roots right two roots for
each cognitive function
equation and look if so the quadratic
function is what
if uh for ax squared plus bx plus c
equals zero we have two roots which is
two times a
minus b
plus minus
b square minus 4ac
okay
yeah
okay so look if we substitute look at
this a is 1 right if a is what so that's
2 times minus d which is 1
plus minus b square which is 1 minus
from negative 4 which is 5.
right and then
because we want the positive we are
positive the value so we could just plug
in these values that would be
this is the
golden ratio which is approximately this
one this value again 1.618
yeah that's
this one uh
so last time we talked about fibonacci
number yeah
the first two numbers zero one and the
next few numbers is
what is the sum of the previous two
terms
right
56 91
and what's that 147
okay and then we add one more which is
okay
so look if this one is b this is a and
this is what b plus a
right if this is b this is a this is b
plus a right
so if because this fibonacci number goes
infinity right so when this goes
forever forever forever the ratio
between two terms consecutive two terms
right is a
a divided by b would be y
a plus b divided by a okay look what's
there
golden ratio yeah we just define it
so let us try to just try a few terms
okay let's try to calculate this number
okay and then this number
okay i'm going to use the calculator
okay
let me use the calculator
divided by 91
is
1.615 okay
1.615 and then this one
238 divided by
147 is
1.618 okay it's very close to 1.618
right
remember this golden ratio is 1.618
it's a irrational number equation
the
rational number
a relation amount is a fraction that
cannot be represented by
by p divided by q where p and q are
integer right
like this square root of 2
pi this is all these are all irrational
numbers but like
20 divided by 3 this is a
rational number right because these two
are integer
so we can write the
we can introduce another mathematics
way to write the limit
to to calculate
the number which has uh you know
infinitive
right
uh look we can do this limit
when n
approach
how do you write the infinity
write down
lie down a okay
by the way another facebook yeah
facebook changed the logo to meta you
know facebook yeah
the change is located to this
yeah
so look we can say f n plus 1 divided by
f n
all right because this is important
number the next term n plus n plus one
and
a fibonacci number divided by its
previous term this will be equal to 5
equals to 5
and which is approximately
1.618 okay
make sense
okay and then we we also talked about uh
different ways of calculating the
fibonacci number right at least you know
two right one is using the recursion
if if n equals zero return one
and return zero if n equals one return
one
else return f n minus one plus f n minus
two right and we are using the cache
function
to avoid repeating calculating the
intermediate numbers and we can also use
it using iterative number right for i
uh we can just for
for i in range
n
a b equals b
a plus b okay
so this golden ratio we just talked
about because look is is x square minus
is basically the root of x s square
minus x plus uh minus one equals zero
okay it's the least and how about if i
say if okay if i put a two here
okay so we're going to introduce a new
sequence which is is called another
golden golden
golden and what's next to golden
the matter the matter here
method what's matter
yeah we're done good and silver
so today siwa ratio
so mata yeah and golden shiva what's
next
bones or copper yeah sometimes copper
you know the copper
yeah so that's silver silver so when
this is two
and copper are grounds
when this is three so look s square
minus n x minus one equals zero
this is called meta meta ratio equation
method ratio equation so when n equals
one then let's do it will be golden
when n is two that will be c one
when n equals three i don't know cooper
or bronze okay
yeah
yeah we already start a lot right or is
it golden this is fibonacci number
yeah so look it's very beautiful right
because fibonacci number contains the
golden ratio right
make sense
how about this receiver if we if we have
these two so
so look
f square
minus 2 x minus 1 so what's the root of
it
2 times a
which is 1 2 2 minus b
which is what
okay maybe we can just solve this look
if x squared minus n x minus one equals
zero what's the root
what's the root two times a what's a
what's the height yeah
is
one right one
two times a
minus b minus b which is n right
plus
minus
one
b squared b squared is n squared
minus 4 times a so plus 1 y
right this is a so basically for this
equation
a is 1
b is
minus and
c is minus one okay
and now we can just substitute remember
that the formula two times
a minus b plus minus
b squared minus four ac okay this is
very important to the quadratic equation
right we have to lose what's this
this is the root two roots two roots two
roots
to this equation
yeah quadratic equation a b c are
constant and we want to find the value
of x and this is the formula yeah there
are two roots
okay
make sense
okay so this okay so look we're coming
back to this
so when n is one
n is one so is when n is one is one plus
five right this is golden ratio already
and when n is two
one nine is two two times uh two
fraction two uh two over
two plus equal
e minus 2 square
4 plus 4 a yeah so plus 4.
okay so we can substitute we can do this
a little bit so
plus minus
four
two right four times two divided by two
so that's one plus
minus
what's that well if i take these four
outside that would be two right yeah
so i turn to all right cancel all these
two those will be like that okay if then
we keep the positive one because this
one
uh is bigger than one so we keep it
perfect so simulation is this one
one plus two squared
2 squared so squared so what's this
value we don't know yeah yeah what's
one point something one point
do you still remember
so okay first of all how do we how do we
estimate this square root of 2 what's
this value how do we estimate it
remember how do we estimate it
[Music]
how do we estimate it there are a few
ways we can estimate it
so look the integer bar is between 1 to
2 right right
yeah
because 1 squared is 1 2 square is 4
right
all
right so is it um
it's
so this square this square is two right
so it's less than two all right
yeah
do you get it
so look let's assume it's one yeah
because the integer pi is one so one
plus something the fraction number x
square equals
two right
all right
this is at one point x this is square
root of two right if i square it
okay so this becomes two on the right
hand side right
x x is a number x is number between zero
to one right
it's a fraction number
it's like 0.5
0.2 right so look
remember a plus b
square what's this how do i roll this
this is a square plus b square
plus what
this is the number
two times a times b yeah
okay so but look
this this one because x is so small yeah
it's a small number it's a small number
so let's just do this look
then this is one square plus s square
plus two times one times x right two x
equals 2. okay look x is a number b
smaller than one
all right
so let's just consider it at the moment
so look at x 1 plus 2 x equals 2 what's
x
1 plus 2 x equals 2 so 2x equals i move
these two
so x equals 1.
okay so now we have a good estimation
0.5 okay so x is 0.5 i think it's
something like zero point
okay okay look look now it is not 1.5
right because look 1.5 squared
square is 2.25 it's not too right so we
can keep doing this look 1.5 plus x
yeah one point thirty three no no one
point five x
let's do it square equals two and then
we can keep doing this
look
2.25 plus
s square plus two times two times a
x that will be 3x equals 2 right
all right so we abandon this for a
moment because it's too small okay so 3
times x equals minus 0.25
so x is what
x equals x is 1
minus
1 over 12 right
this is a quarter divided by 3
is
12.
okay so look we have this is x basically
x is the
adjustment term
adjustment term okay so we keep keep
amending the result so the previously is
1.5 right and then i can just minus what
1 over 12. so what's this number
1 over 12.
1 over 12
is
0.083 okay if we use 1.5 to to subtract
that will be what 1.41
[Music]
seven yeah
all right
so look this number if we square this
number what happened one point
four one seven times one point four one
seven
is two point zero zero seven eight eight
nine you see very close right so we can
keep doing this look we already know
this number and we can plus x and then
square equals 2. and then we can keep
doing it by appending the x squared
because it's so small right and then we
can solve this linear equation and get
the x term next adjustment and put it
back
together this is the way to estimate it
properly
make sense
yeah okay
so uh okay where are we
well we talked about a lot and forgot
the original topic
so
yeah this is the civilization like civil
rights so how is that useful right how
is the user
remember uh so look the first first few
terms the first two term yeah
b a
okay
how about look how about if i say the
next term is what two times a plus b
yeah remember
all right the fibonacci number is what
fibonacci number let's say fibonacci
number we can do this if the first one
zero if n equals zero
is one
if n equals one and then what
if n is bigger than two is f i b
n minus one plus f i b
n minus two right
yeah
equation yeah
left how about if i say okay if i times
n here if i times two here
so look if i i have a function that f n
equals what and then i can say
2 times f n minus 1 plus f n minus 2
if n bigger equal than 2. okay
so what's this look all right
if look what what's the difference
between this one and the fibonacci
number look at this
there's only one difference here which
is what
if and
bigger
or you wouldn't so what's the difference
what's it what is how is the difference
between this one and fibonacci number
because because in fibonacci number is
there is no two right i put the two so
okay so let's try this and
so look okay
zero one okay so what's next term
what's my next term
no no not the fibonacci number the one
like times two two times two
two okay what's the next one six
huh two times plus one oh two times
look
f n equals 2 times f n minus 1 plus f n
minus 2 okay
you said this is the difference between
fibonacci numbers with all these two now
i have these two so the next one is two
times f two times y plus two
twelve
two times twelve plus five
is nine
two times this plus this
70 70 okay this keep going right yeah
you see you'll see 169.
yeah 169. okay and keep going okay
so we call this this
remember this is the name we call it
pair number
pair numbers okay this is the term for
the 10 numbers so each one is the two
times the previous one plus the one
before
right this is complete numbers
yeah
so we can also use it using uh it's
quite similar to the fibonacci number we
can just do this define
pair
n okay
and if n equal equals zero return
zero
if n equal equal one
return
one
else return one return
two times
air n minus 1
plus pair
minus 2 okay
and what's the one we're missing
cash right because we don't want yeah
yeah
okay so another iterative method okay
it's a rating number
it's a rating number define
pair
and yeah we can say okay a b equals zero
one and then four
in branch
and i know can say two a and
a b
equals one a will become the new b right
and then b will become
the two times uh
two times b
cosine b plus a right two times the
previous one plus a right
okay let's let's walk b and a okay so
make it better b and a
so b
a
b will become the new a
right and then that would be two times a
plus b
okay and then we can just return return
b okay
whatever this is the paired number
okay so c variation is related to pair
number
and golden ratio is to relate it to
fibonacci number okay just to make it
clear
so
so why is it useful how do we use the
silver ratio
remember that the civil rights is 1 plus
square root of 2 right if we're not sure
what's the value of leave yeah we can
calculate the parallel uh the the one
stupid way would be to calculate this
zero one
x zero one
what
two times this plus two 5
70 116 24
29 yeah 29 and then
70 yeah okay i know this keeps going
wrong right because what because look
this is b this is a this is 2 times a
plus b right so the similar ratio will
be 2 times a plus b
divided by 1 divided by a equals a
divided by b yeah if we if we look
if we said that b equals one
right if b said set it to one and this
is zero ratio and we use this greek
letter which is what data i don't know
how to write the data
data s
data s to to represent the zero ratio
okay p equals one then we can say two a
plus one
times one equals a square
a square minus two a minus one equals
zero remember yeah you see
this we
just changing from the golden ratio
where this is one to two
right
so let's solve this equation let's look
at this
so 2a
minus b look it's the same we have the
humanity plus minus square root of a
right
okay so this is 1 plus minus square root
of 2.
okay so the last way we could get this
the silver ratio is
where where the c one is from okay
um
okay look let's write look
look
remember the consumer concentration uh
consumed can continue fraction
a plus b divided by a equals a divided
by b right
look at this then we can we can unknow
this look
that will become what
1 plus b divided by a equals a divided
by b
right this is the golden ratio which is
uh five right
five
yeah
a divided by b equals gold generation
what's the b divided by a
what's b divided by a a
is the golden ratio
one over golden ratio
yeah so we can say one plus one over
golden ratio equals gold generation
right
yeah
all right this is how we can get it from
here
and and the same as look two a plus b
receiver ratio
c one ratio right and that'll be two
times two
plus
2 plus 1
2 plus b divided by a equals a divided
by b this is the delta s theta s i don't
know how to write it
delta s
so look this is theta as this is 1 over
delta s so 2 times 2 plus
1 over
delta s
equals delta s
okay so this is a serial ratio
okay
so look let's take this golden ratio for
example right so this one
golden ratio equals this one okay how
about if i replace these with the
definition of golden ratio
so you'll be 1 plus 1 over this equal
generation is this every question is
that's only 1 plus 1 over
this right look
what just happened
yeah does it make sense
[Music]
yeah
what did i just do
you just
go the right side okay so i can keep
doing this yeah
so i can keep doing this yeah so one
plus one plus one plus one plus
yeah
this is the continue this is another way
of writing the code generation and
similarly we can do this with the
uh with this watch which is the silver
ratio okay so let's say
2 plus 1 over look this
this is what
this is what 2 plus this 2 plus 1 over 2
plus 1 over 2 plus 1 over two plus
right zero ratio
and as you can imagine if we want to
change this evaluation to bronze
and we just change this number to n to
three yeah
three three zero
and
basic container uh continuation fraction
so if these
uh let's wait to read yeah there's a way
to write it look if a 0 plus 1 over a 1
plus 1 over a 2 plus 1 over a3 plus
and we can write it as a list so a0
semicolon
a1 a2
a3
okay so for golden ratio the value is
one
one one one
for the silver ratio is two
two two
and for the bronze is three
three okay
makes sense
so
so um
so what's the silver ratio one one plus
square root of two that's equals to two
point four one four right something like
that and how about
this if this blue rules will be what
remember that equation two two uh x
square minus n x minus one equals zero
when n is three two
two a
minus three with b three
yeah come on look at me
plus
b squared
nine minus four plus four right so this
is two
this is the bones
okay so this is the value for the bronze
bronze ratio
when n is three okay
when n is three this is the rule
remember
remember this
yeah i keep i keep talking about this
yeah this is very important equation
okay can you remember this
you can
okay so what what's the
how do we can you write the conjugated
equation
what's quadratic equation
a x squared
plus b x
plus
c
equals zero right
okay so look a b c are known constant
are the values so we can plug in here
right
and this gives the solution
so the x equals this two we have plus
equal so there are two
to this equation so quadratic equation
yeah remember we talked about this
there are two roots
this is one this is one right
max's
f
there are two roots
quadratic equation these are these yeah
it could be something like that when a
is smaller than zero it's pointing down
one a is bigger than zero is turning up
okay
make sense
yeah
okay so to sum up what have we learned
today
silver ratio and then
how can we estimate the civil ratio
how can we estimate the signal ratio
remember the pair number right yes
so look the pair number if is p so limit
when n
approximately to
infinity
look
p n plus 1 divided by p n
that would be silver ratio which is
that data how do you write the data i
can
delta s which is
equals one plus square root of two
right
and this is approximately
two point four one four i we spent some
time to estimate this value
okay and then
the fibonacci number let's do generation
similarly limit
and approximately
infinity
yeah when n
approximately approach infinity right
f
n plus one divided by f n the ratio
between the
consecutive two terms is equal to
five right
and which is equal to what
which is equal to one come on
[Music]
what is equal to
zero one one two three
the next term divided by the previous
time leave as well
[Music]
golden ratio which is
this yeah
1.618 okay
yeah
and how about
limit
when n over approximately
to infinity right and then we want to
calculate this value
1 over n
so what was this
come on
think about it just simple example
when n goes very large what's 100
what's the value of it one way
[Music]
small and which is what if
really really small small
too close to one
when n goes to infinite infinity 1 over
it you say it's very small i know what's
the value
what's
what's the value
zero yeah yeah you see a median one over
a minute very very small very close to
zero okay so that's what it means when n
goes infinity
this value becomes zero right but in
fact you can't find a value very
there's no such thing as infinity right
so this the
this my next equation name name stands
for limit
okay so let me
think about any other things
so
um we talk about a pair number yeah okay
so let's one last thing okay you can you
don't need to remember okay so look the
pair number the first two items is zero
one right
okay if we can change this to two two
if the first two number is two two is
called pair
pair lucas number okay how long
okay
just
and then
the pair locus number is all uh
except the first two numbers are
different the next term is always two
times the previous term and plus the one
before right it's the same
okay so this is another small thing okay
okay so that's it for today good job
bye