hello mr mr wright how are you
okay so we talked about a graph and the
graph is the collection of vertex and
edges right the vertices and edges
yeah yeah
so
so for example like this
a
vertex to b
c
and then let's say i have a d here okay
let's say and then look if
this is the connected un-directional
graph connected means that there is no
you can travel from any vertex to any
other vertex right
this is not connected right if i have an
e here this is not connected
so we're talking about a
connected graph and
un-directional okay sorry un-directional
it doesn't have the direction so and i
can put a weight on it so let's say 1
two
okay let's put it cycle here like three
four five
so i have a weight
associated for each edges
yeah edges
[Music]
these are the weights okay
so this one has a cycle right because
look abc you can cycle and
bcd is also exactly
so look a tree we know it's a subset
right a tree the tree is a subset
right three doesn't have a cycle
remember with two for two it doesn't
know cycle yeah
and then three we want to make a tree
out of these graph
and it has to be connected right if it's
not connected if you if you don't have a
if if
you you pick these you know if you pick
these
right that's weight one that's way three
this is not connected but this is a
for it so we foreign to
pick the single tree one tree so
one tree another three trees with the
forest yeah
and also we want to
pick the edges that the sum of the
weight in the numbers on it are then
minimized are the smallest there are
five edges
mean
mean weight okay mean total weight
okay so these are the requirements
and we call this three what minimum
spending tree mst
minimum spending tree okay spending
spending
make sense
so how would you how do you pick how
would you draw a tree out of picking the
vertex and edges
how how would you do it
how would you do it
okay so first of all you have to pick
all uh vertex here
pick it always see but these isn't in a
circle yeah
okay okay so how which which energy
would you pick 24.
wow one
two
four yeah this is the smallest
okay i hope look for if there are n
vertices
oh yeah yeah one two three okay one two
three actually yeah this is better yeah
yeah yeah
so if there are other things how many
edges would you pick
[Music]
why is that
if i pick an a minus one i'll make it
connected and no cycle if i put one more
edges what happened
that would be all right so
so we want we don't want the cycle right
so for n
vertex graph
so that will be n minus one edges right
am i right look
one one vertex no edges yellow two
vertices you can only put one make it
connected one edges three
two right
yeah yeah you can pick these all these
or all these
but if you add one more
there will be a cycle differently right
so everybody takes n minus one edges to
make it no cycle a tree no cycle tree
and then you'll be making all the vertex
connected right and then we wanted the
spelling the the total minimum weight
the minimum weight
so
how did you find out is these the
one two three
[Music]
okay how about if i change this to ten
people one two four all right
yeah easier
okay so the weight okay we want to find
the weight minimum weight of three sub
tree t is a subset of graph okay
and then these would be the weight of u
to v
the vertex yeah u and v
u to v belongs to the edges okay so we
want to minimize this right we don't
minimize this one way of doing this okay
let's bring it bring the topic today
which is called couscou
item okay so it's quite similar to
how how did you peel it how how did you
feel it
addition
nothing okay so this this one
yeah what abcd
so first of all the first step is to
what to create uh
to to create the
you know the the we call forest for each
forest and each one has no edge uh has
no edge so there will be four trees in
the flower is that
so
f f then let's say f at the beginning f
belongs to an empty set empty set
and then i i need to
to add a
at
each
tree individual tree the vertex single
vertex right so i will have add
add
each
each v
belongs to
v
to f okay this is the c dot
this is zero okay now look
so i would pick a smallest weight first
of all i would saw and then i was i
would salt salt the edges saw edges okay
so edges e belongs to e edges okay
i will show the edges so how many edges
will be one a to b which is one okay
which is one
and then what what's what's the smallest
b to c yeah b to c
two i i sorted the edges
and b to d
for
a to c
five
and what's next c to d
ten okay so these are the edges
sorting by the way smallest to the
biggest
make sense if there are e edges how
what's the time complexity to sort it by
the way salting
sultan
and then e logan
there's no n common there are e edges
you have to say which n is what n is e
okay
or maybe o eric
love log l okay oh area
okay so now look we started we haven't
resorted and now
why
why the graph f is not connected why o
f is is not connected yeah connected
connected
now what what we do we remove first of
all we do move the smallest edge in this
case which is one right right
one
if it doesn't form the cycle in this f
okay this is f if this is not in the
cycle
then we we connect it so one yeah
for the one right
so the next one is b
uh bc2 right we have picked this edge
already and i will pick this
bc2 we put it here
okay and then the next one pd4 easy okay
so next one is a bit tricky
i need to pick one more edges
ac5
right
look for this ac5 uh
look i pick one
i pick these
i pick this cd
okay so now if i pick ac that we'll have
a cycle we have a cycle here right
and that will be because we say we don't
want the cycle so we can't pick this so
we skip this we skip this
we skip it so what's the next one
oh actually we uh
actually we already uh finished yeah
because there are four four vertices we
only pick three right
okay so maybe this is not a good example
maybe let's do another one okay
okay let's use this example okay
one two four two
and wow
okay maybe you're right let's try okay
let's try
oh
um
i need to change the
value to a little bit maybe this i will
put a
four here okay and then this will be
three oh man okay
so
so let's say this is a
b
c the biggest one that you get is seven
three ten five two four three four
two four okay okay so how about
now let's let's try this aggregate to
see if
two four three four so what let's start
with the edges solid edges what's the
sp to c
b to c
is two and then what's next b3 yeah b to
e e3
what's next for b to d is right
or a to b is also four right it doesn't
matter
which one comes first
and then what
then what's next a to c five right we
sorted the edges
and what's next seven right b to e
all right and what's next
c to d
okay
so first of all we we start with these
individual trees as far as we pick the
smallest edge which is b to c two right
b to c
two
okay b to c
so i pick the b for c here
i know what's next b to e
i pick d to e which is what three
yeah
i know what's next p to t right it
doesn't still have uh it doesn't fall on
the cycle yet four
yeah so this edge this edge
okay next one a to b for
and b4
and oh it still doesn't form cycle so
okay so maybe i need to find a better
algorithm i'll find a better example
right because you already find because
we already find it right
huh
okay maybe maybe i will change this to
40.
oh
so you don't pick these
[Music]
okay so a to b 40 will be here a to b
and you have to drop this
okay so again look at ascent bc i pick a
b c
b e
and b d okay so the next one
next one i will pick a to c right you
see it still works right so
so the idea is that we don't pick an n
if it's a
if this edge is already forming a cycle
we skip it okay i need to find an
example which which does that okay maybe
i i i do this one more okay so
so you see a better example okay
a
be
c
b
i pick a big better example it doesn't
have a cycle
s
so i picked a one
two
i got two
three
four
five six seven okay so for this one
for this one
one two one i picked one here all right
one and the next one the smallest will
be two
four
but now look the next one is three but
it has a cycle so i skipped
one two four six four
six
and then five five no no i have a cider
six six
six
and i'll be here because how many
vertices one two three four five five
vertex i need to pick four edges one two
three four got
yeah
okay look okay so look this one is
easier i just said a to b
a to b one
b to c is two
and
a to c is 3
c 3
is 4
b to d is 5
and then c to e c to f is six
a to f is seven
okay so look we pick these we pick this
we pick this
but we don't pick this this is a cycle
right we don't pick this
four we pick this
five we don't pick this because we have
a cycle c f six
c f uh six we pick this and then
another way because we already pick uh
that's one two three four five six we
don't need to pick six edges
uh no no no no
uh one two three four we
need to pick four edges
one two three four okay
yeah make sense yeah
so
tick tick cross stick
so what every time we pick
uh pick the edges we merge two
components into one right right yeah
so how how this is kind of greedy right
so
why is this
why how how can we prove this by this
approach is uh
it's the minimum spending chain
how do you prove it how how does this
work basically just trying to get the
smallest number yeah smallest number
with no cycle there's no sign yeah look
every time we merge we have a merge two
thing we pick the smallest a uh edge for
example this is e we pick it look if we
don't pick it
if we don't pick it there will be some
other
some other edge which will have the side
to this one right right
so look this is the edge we are trying
to pick if we don't pick this smallest
edge there will be some other edge going
to pick
to connect these two components right
and if that edge is not it's going to
pick they will have a cycle and if it
has a cycle why not we just pick this
edge all right don't get it so this is
this proves that this is a smaller
minimum spanning tree okay
okay and we can use the what kind of
data structure can we use to to find if
two two vertex
belongs to the same parent
same group
remember we have used we have learned a
data structure remember
destroying that well done yeah look we
have a look at we have a group a b c d a
b c d and we for the disjoint set we can
check
we can merge these to any two or we can
check if two parent uh if two components
belongs to the same group yeah we can
check how many uh components connected
how many uh number of connected
components right so this is done by this
joint set this june set okay john said
okay
so
when we uh so what's the time complexity
for this cousco
remember
what's the what's the approach
yeah saltine yeah first of all we're
sorting and then we need to find uh we
we need to find the smallest edge from
the
formula we need to go through the
smallest uh
edges from the smallest to the biggest
right and then fine if these so there's
another operation
we need to find out the
if two components if two vertex belongs
to the same edge and we can use this
using the disjoint set okay the time
complexity for left beat to check if two
vertex belongs to the same right uh in a
disturbance set is trivial compared to
the
uh
you know
compare comparing to going through the
edges okay so the time complexity will
be this one for the cool stuff okay
make sense
okay i'm going to give you another
example and then you tell me what's the
spending tree and i'll be for today okay
you both okay you both do it right
[Music]
okay so these are three
one
two
three four
five six seven okay
are you ready come on
you want to try
no please you want to try
okay so listen
no no no you're telling me
what hey okay you tell me how hard you
write it
hey
a yeah a okay and then what's next
and then
to b
to b okay this one two
and then what's this three
sorry like that yeah
okay okay i know what's next i'm then
don't pick four nine don't take five
nine can we pick six yeah yeah
oh what's next
do we need to pick again nine
how many how many what is one two three
four five
so we need to pick four edges how many
edges are we got we have to get yeah
that's it okay we have one no no no
so look one two three four okay okay
yeah makes sense okay that's it for
today
bye bye