okay
so we talked about the minimum spanning
tree yesterday and then the agreement we
uh we teaching is what
what what can i what what's the name of
the acura we talk about crosstalk
because okay
yeah okay
so okay so meaning expanding three okay
so let's review a little bit okay let's
review a little bit
so we have lisa
[Music]
that looks like a diamond or something
yeah yeah yeah so one two five
four so
wait so what are we doing uh so we have
a four uh four vertex and then how many
edges we need to bear to for this
minimum spending trees so one two five
so how many edges
so far
one two four two one four okay two one
four two one four
two one is two one point two one four
so let us
so first of all we pick we have all the
vertices which is has
uh n doesn't matter
[Music]
what doesn't matter about the order you
say in
what do you mean like
like that is two one four so can you say
one two four it's okay it's okay but
first of all
first of all look we have n vertex four
vertices so we have uh we need to build
a minimum spanning tree with the four
trees yeah each one we separate uh no
edges just verticals and then we start
picking the edges that does not form the
cycle so the first one we notice in peak
is one and then the second one will pick
up two
and then now look three three because it
has form a cycle so that's why we don't
pick it i will skip it so the next one
is four right
yeah easy peasy so this is the minimum
expense
okay so that's a question with n vertex
uh what's the n minus one
okay n minus one yes and minus one edges
okay
okay so this one is that we start by
adding the edges right look we we have
this vertex and we start by adding the
edges
okay adding my edges
so the time connection as we talked
about we need to solve these edges by
the ascending order of the weight right
so we this is e
o
e log e right remember
the edges
let's just say both the time complexion
yeah the term complexity okay you can
just say what's the sound complexity
instead of just telling us
oh you want me to ask you the questions
okay
okay so what's the
because we are using what kind of data
structure will you need
no no with all kind of data structure
data structure you use to this joint set
this is john cena yeah okay
okay
this question especially for you yeah
because you answered
[Music]
and how many edges are there and minus
one no no i mean the maximum like for
example like if there are four
look
there's a cycle though yeah yeah i mean
the graph okay i like the graph if it's
the graph if there's a graph okay if
there's a graph
with n
m vertex yeah and vertex
and how many maximum number of edges can
you think about
think about it look it could be crossed
how many of these look
lots yeah i know infinity
how is that infinity look for each one
you have the edges to n minus one right
so for each one you have the edges to m
minus n times three
now look at four this is how is that n
times two look at these three edges how
many of them are three
so three edges that's the
next one two plus one right so it's n
minus one plus
n minus two plus tier one right so for
example n edges uh and vertex i the
first the first vertex has connections
to the n minus one right so it's n minus
one so for the second one
it has the edges to
n minus two right so you probably plus
one right okay so that's the total
number of edges
okay so it's in a scale of uh n
square right it's in the scale it's not
exactly the same
you get it
so
well why this is not working okay
because you missed the part which is
stuck to the board
so okay so
maybe okay so
what i'm trying to say here is this
you've got this dumb thing
yeah that's okay there we go
okay
let's
need to put numbers though no no i don't
for example this one let's consider the
first vertex right
this is
vertex so you can have the edges to
how many
how many vertices are five yeah but if
this is the n there are n vertices
and minus one okay so n minus
no no no
no no no okay next one because i'm
trying to
you can okay
when i said the questions then you it
answered okay so now so for the second
one how many edges you can have two
a minus one but we already count this so
we don't count it again yeah it's
literally set anymore n minus one
and one is one
minus two yeah and then the next one and
one is three
yeah and my why is that minus three
because it has two and one is three
how many
no look at you because i already have
two so you can't count these these right
so it's n minus three yeah
and minus one minus two okay so
i said n minus three okay and then after
a minus four yeah after one right so
what's this what's this sum n square
uh i don't know yet look so the first
first item is uh the sum will be n minus
one plus one how many items are there
times n minus one divided by two y yeah
so this is this is the equation to sum
the
uh
the you know aromatic
sequence right
so 1 plus 2 plus 3 plus 2 n minus 1 the
first item the last item how many items
online divided by two so it's n times n
minus one divided by two right so this
this is the number this is the possible
number of edges for a graph with n
vertex okay so because we because we
know this o e log e right
yeah and if this e edges is the v square
right because look this is a v square
so if we say o e
log v square okay
yeah
so look
this one we have say log a
log uh
a
a uh to the power b actually you can put
a b look look at this is magic you can
put a b to the before so it becomes b
times log a
okay so this is a logarithmic uh
transformation for example like
log
two to the base of a right a is two to
the power of three right two to the
power of three is a right so that equals
three times
log
two we're down three times left so e to
the seven
we can also say look we move it to
before
right so now we drop the constant
okay so now let's come into the today's
topic with more questions okay
today we're going to talk about
another aquarium to compute the minimum
spending tree which is called prince
prince okay
all right okay so the previous thing
the previous thing we picked up away we
picked the edges and we added to the
forest right and now this time we want
to
what we want to pick the vertex instead
so for example like
okay so you
so let's see what we can get okay
c
b
maybe here
okay let's say one two three four five
so
one two three before we pick the
smallest but now this time it's
different we can pick first of all which
letter which vertex you're going to pick
no no it doesn't matter pick one abcd or
e
okay because because why is it doesn't
matter because eventually all these
vertex will be in the minimum spanning
tree right right it's connected right
so we just pick a
okay so from a how many edges how many
edges
to one and two okay so now
now this is easy it's on board now we
can we have one it's not on a board okay
so then we pick the smallest one which
is
a to b
this is one okay
now
we have these yeah we have these three
now a or b how many veggies connect to a
now i have i have this one yeah i have
two this one
and how many edges you connect to the b
how many edges
so look i have one ap right so there are
two two out of it so first of all i pick
this one right pick a and then
there are two edges one and two because
i pick the smallest one so which is one
okay
so now i already have these yeah so how
many edges connected to these these one
right
this one and this one and this one yeah
so i pick the smallest which is two
right two three four i picked
the smallest one so i took this which is
d
two i yeah
then i
then that's the
the three i have built for now is this
included right
so now how many edges connected to
these a b or d
three
so no no i already know i already know
the tree minimum staining tree has abc
and how many edges which we haven't
added
connects to that vertex here one
what was one c
c c and then okay how many edges
okay how many one
what one how many vertex one how many
edges
two
so we pick four or five four four so we
pick four
uh four let's
uh let's see do you get it do you
understand this process so first of all
we randomly pick okay so the step one we
pick a vertex it doesn't have to it it's
it could be random pick the vertex
pick a vertex
v-e-r-t-x pick a vertex
and then
we we we need to separate these two uh
to this uh pick a vertex we want to put
it in these three i pick vertex and put
it in a tree
and then we have s equals all the
vertices
all the vertex and then we need to find
a vert a vertex
okay we need to find the vertex in s
right connecting to the existing tree
with the minimum edges edges
right so what i will try what are we
doing here look
uh
so if we have ap
right then then h is connected to a or b
is this a d
b d or b c
and then we just need to pick the
smallest of them and then try to and
then try to include these new
vertex new edges
in the tree make sense
okay let me write the step okay
let me know the steps
okay so now the first one we want to
field is that t will be equals to the
empty set right empty set
empty set this is the tree we are going
to
build define
prince
we have we have a graph right
so first of all we have a t equals m t
right and then no no no no
so we want to fill the vertex which is
vertical
let's say the vertex will be
e
and then
v
we will be let's say we start from the
beginning of the first node okay zero
okay
or
no no we don't need this why v in
different place what do you mean
different place
no no no this is the same i'm just
writing y v is not equal to
y v is not equal
to
right because we're going to
include
all the vertices anyway the minimum
spanning tree is is contains all the
vertex right all the vertex of the
original graph and it's connected right
because we're talking about a connective
it's just the edges is the
n minus one edges right right come on
see that
why v not equals the
uh gw why we haven't built enough vertex
we haven't included enough vertex in in
a minimum spanning tree now we need to
find the edges we need to find the
energy m n right the m and
m and n is the vertex number need to
find the edges five edges
find edges
okay so let's say we want to find what
we want to find the energy this this
function will return
the m
m it belongs to
belongs to existing v right existing v
and then
n belongs to
uh
g dot v minus m and minus v
this is look this is the vertex we have
included in a minimum spanning tree and
this is the vertex that we haven't
included
and we want to find out m n in these m
belongs to v and m belongs to v minus v
and also this edge is the smallest okay
and this is the smallest
smallest
and then after that then we can do what
we can include the graph t
equals t
including the graph right
with m to n
and then our v
will be equal to v
including the vertex vertex is
n right this is the the vertex
we want to include it right and a little
bit
a little bit
so the time complexity for this one okay
this is a bit tricky okay it is uh is o
uh e times the log e
log v
plus v times log of v okay
no no because we're going to use the
heap remember the heap
what's the hit by the way
anyone this is this first impression no
no no no no
but not quite
the hip remember is the binary tree with
the top data structure data structure
okay so the third data structure
priority two yeah the one that you said
is prior to q so every time when you
take the element out it's always with
the priority right the smaller smallest
yeah with the smallest okay so then that
takes all because we have vert v vertex
so that requires log of v okay and we
need to traverse all the edges
but because because the verb look at the
vertex the vertical number is smaller
equal to the edge number right
am i right
don't write it on the floor come on
okay so the term convexity can also be o
e
log log of v because this one is trivial
right it's e plus v log v so it's
trivial
okay
uh
so
the space complexity is of v you know
because we need the data structure to
store
right we need to store these yeah we
need to store the
number of the
vertex
and okay so i'm going to write a
tree a graph
okay and then you tell me okay
you tell me how we how we're going to
build the minimum spanning tree using
this uh you know using this queen's
algorithm
but first of all let me give you a one
question what's the difference between
prince and crisco
they start from different places
you
what's the difference between couscous
and
prince
what are we doing in the couscous we
start adding what we start adding the
minimum
okay so
one
two
two three
four five six seven
okay so i'm
for the couscous we are picking the
smallest edges and add it to the forest
right we adding the edges but for the
prince prince we're adding the vertex
right
yeah makes sense
so
so okay so for now
you want to try with the prince again
how are we building this
that was two pokemon cards
you can work together let each one see
as well
remember what did i tell you about
randomly pick one pick one
okay so pick up a oh slowly yeah hey and
then okay so for me and then we move to
the smallest one okay one b okay here
okay
okay so now now what happened what's
next
you start from
how many edges connected to these
okay
yeah okay yeah that makes that's okay
yes okay and i know how many edges
connected to these and then
yeah so can you tell me how did you do
it come on i just need to explanation
because we we just we just looked at
people this morning
what does it connect to and we cloud it
yeah okay
okay so look you pick a then
how many edges connected
to one and three you pick one right yes
and now you have a b how many edges
connected to a and b
uh
one
how many edges this one this one this
one right
and i pick the smallest which is two
right how many edges connected to one a
b c
seven four
six yeah then i pick four right
all right
and how many edges
how many edges i pick uh
connects to
a b c d
a b c d so look so how how do you do
that
so how many h is connected to a b c d
you just
do this how many edges will be easier
huh
how many edges connected to abcd come on
how many edges left
one which one is that one two two yeah
come on five and six you pick up did you
get it yes
yeah yes i feel like
not quite not quite no no no okay so for
example how can i give you one two okay
okay
together
you did you decide we work together
you decide
okay
but you need to tell me exactly not not
just write it you need to tell me
okay
do you understand you need to tell me
you're still in the same way
yeah same way because i i'm
because you might think about you know
it's uh
it's different right
one two three
two
three
four
five
and then five
one
one okay come on that's it
okay
so first of all so we start with a
thumbs up
okay
yeah yeah yeah no no no you can't do all
that ask you need to tell me
how did you make the decision because
you because you got d because it has two
connections um
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah three or
two and two is the smallest no no
actually you can just mark it here okay
so it'll be easier okay that's why
you'll choose okay now you have all uh
how many vertices you've got
and how many vertices you got uh you got
one
two a and d okay and then what's next um
we choose we choose this
how many
how many because you have one two three
oh i haven't put it here
so okay so so what
[Music]
and now three four yeah okay and then we
will pick up
the smallest smallest yeah
okay we're done
and we're not definitely not going up so
our only choice is down the reason why
we're not going up because we don't want
cycling
okay so what's next what's next how many
edges can enter a b is three uh
this is this
and then g is and then you choose the
smallest one one okay maybe i put a four
here okay i do
okay okay okay and then
i'm thinking of way different and then
how many edges connects to these
please
yeah this yeah yeah yeah
and then this is
definitely the smallest okay okay and
then and then this is the yeah yeah
yeah and how many edges connected
because look you have a b d c there and
then you get to pick one of them it's
okay because they are all five
no no no
because this one is already included
right
don't get in yeah yeah
okay so to sum up you have uh these
three right because look what what have
you done so far is pick an a
and then you pick up
d you pick a b you pick a g you pick
uh e i don't know yeah
you start building the vertex
right you start building the vertex by
choosing the smallest edge
okay okay that's it for today good job
bye