hello miss how are you today
okay so you play chess right oh yeah
okay well not really not really okay
that's fine so we have a chessboard
chess ball you know with the
empty stairs and with the
knight and one king let's say we have
one king here okay only one team
only one king okay but there could be
many many
many nights
okay uh night yeah you know the night
you know what's nice
it's like a soldier or something
and riding on a horse right
yeah yeah yeah yeah so tonight yeah like
that
the whole horse
okay i don't know how to draw yeah with
the salt okay
okay
so let's let's use the
edge
yeah because it would be horse h
at g so it could be
2h
3h here
okay
wow okay okay that's very abstract blah
blah blah okay
okay
yeah yeah yeah yeah
you call it horse come on
okay okay
yeah yeah yeah okay
so you know the horse
in chinese chest how do we move the
horse
where can this jump
we're done okay so basically the
if this is x
this is y right the offset
of x to be one
y could be two or x equals two y could
be one right so it could be like you
know in one step
to the right and two step
right to that to the north right
okay
so
they hope they have
three
and how many moves what's the minimum
number of moves in order for any of the
horses to capture the king one
yeah wear them okay and how about if i
don't have this
how many what's the minimum move
yeah too yeah
yeah okay you got it yeah because look
this one in order to capture these it's
how many moves it requires
[Music]
one two
now one two three okay four moves okay
four moves for this one is one two
okay make sense
yeah so today's task we only we have one
king on the board
yeah
this is a lego metric we can represent
this as a matrix two dimensional metric
in python and where zero is empty
okay
one is king
two is the knight okay nine or horse egg
knight
or hot
so we want to find out the task is that
we want to find out the minimum number
of moves for some knights to capture the
king
the horse cannot jump on the horse for
example if there
is a knight here for this one you cannot
jump here
right make sense yeah because this
this place is already occupied by
another
knight another horse right makes sense
what's your question yeah you've got a
question
sorry
you don't have a question okay that's
why you understand what i'm talking
about right
so we want to find out the minimum
number of moves for some horse to
capture the king
okay so that's pretty simple
if there's only one horse
yeah if there's only one horse let's
don't look at this
what's your approach to capture a king
if there's only one horse if we want to
find out the minimum
we can do what kind of search
what kind of search can we do come on
breakfast search weather why is the
breakfast search look look
here you have your house here right your
horse here and then the next move you
can jump another to here here
how many how many
how many notes are there for the second
for the next move for the in ideally how
many of these what's the maximum number
of move for the next move where down
eight okay a move yeah because if you
are here you could have a direction okay
so so like if any of these is
the move will be capturing the king
then we find a
shortcase yeah well
for the preference search you use
usually can be used to solve the
shortest right because that's the way i
travel the tree
level by level
right
am i right
so when i reached the
note for a number here
at least it's the king
if i found here and i already know like
like two moves right
because i always explain the levels by
level and when i visit it when i visit
the king
it's always the guarantee the shortest
make sense
but definite search may not give the
idea right because look if devastate
could be somewhere here this came over
here
right when you get the king
it may not be the optimum right you
could maybe take 10 moves
you need to travel all the trees and
compare this
the moves to get the minimum but for the
preferred search is when i found the
first king
it's it's already the shortest because
i'll travel the trees level by level
it's guaranteed that's your taste the
different search
not the ultimate you have to travel the
entire tree because look yeah you may
find a king
yeah by the by following this path
somehow
yeah you might have a king here
but you don't know there may be some
shorties cars here right this is the
optimal when you find a king
you have to remember it okay so i take
10 moves here okay i take three moves
here so the strategy is three months
that's two minutes okay one two okay
yeah make sense
so look there are many many edge many
many edge yeah you know you already we
already know how to solve this problem
using preferences if there's one edge
one horse but how about many many edge
we can repeat this
as many times as possible right
yeah even our energy we can do it look
we can do this one one solution blue
force yeah
is that we try for each edge we
calculate the minimum number of moves to
add k and we get the
minimum
number yeah so you'll be like four
h in all hot in all asia
and in order as this is on edge now we
do this answer equals mean
answer and then prefer search okay
question search
i start with this edge right
and then return answer okay this is one
way to prove something yeah make sense
make sense
yeah look because we already know how to
solve the one problem what one king from
one horse to one king
the source to the destination and we can
repeat this
h times if there are n
n horses we can repeat this n times
but this this is not optimal why is that
because look uh
let's take a
complexity for example if these the how
do what's the complexity travel from
source to king
yeah it's n
it's and if they are look if
um
if there are n
n rows and columns yeah if this is the
n rows and columns
okay so ideally n rows and columns and
we can visualize this as a graph right
we can visualize this as well so this
edge
uh you know can points to
the vertex this is the vertex this is
the vertex at different this is edge
edge
f and different vertices yeah they are n
times n square
vertex and square vertices
right then how how many edges are there
i don't know
how many edges
how many edges for three inverted how
many edges for
the four vertex do you still remember
this
this still remember this
now let's
so if there are n vertices what's that
if there are vertex and vertex
how many how many edges possible
look remember a few days ago we talked
about if that the first vertex
has edges to n minus one
a minus one times n minus two y
times n minus two yeah
one yeah okay so let's not let's
let's consider they are n cells okay not
n rows and columns they are n
and s and vertex and possible partitions
and the number of vertex is
n times
uh because the first one is n minus one
n times uh n minus one times n minus two
times minus three times one right so
you'll be n
minus one
plus one times n minus one
divided by 2. this is the number of
possible edges so this is n so
the number of possible edges is and and
yeah this this one is linear in the
order of n squared right in the order of
square if there are n cells and possible
partitions there and
square
edges right so that means that because
we only travel the same
we can use the hash map to hash side to
remember the
possible partition we travel right so if
i travel from here to here the next time
if i come back look
if i come back i don't travel again
again right because this has been
visited yeah we use the notebook
map
yeah so the time complexity to travel
from a source a source a pair of source
to the destination is n square right
because only they are possible n square
n square
n square n to the power of two edges and
then we travel
use n square and if they are if they
n
horses the time term lets you n times n
square right
at least m yeah could be
filled in these so the time in order of
the possible partition so the time
complexity is actually and qb right the
time complexity we're using we're using
the queue we're using the hashmap
so it's all in order of our n right
got it but can we do better can we do
better
maybe
look we in in order to
shorten the term we don't need to repeat
this
m time right we can put these m sources
together at the beginning into the
preference search so look the
preferences usually start with a
position right but we can start a set in
a set of positions
right we can look if there are five five
h here right i can put this five edge in
the queue first
right this this is the
takeaway today
yeah what did i just say this is the
takeaway today yeah what's the previous
one
what did i do
if i have five edges i just put it in
the same in a queue right remember we
use the wndq
we put it in a queue in on the right
hand side nq in q we take it all right
yeah we take it out so
instead of doing this
five times
i can put these five partitions into the
queue
and then this is not like a tree anymore
this is like uh
what the least i can travel these
so and each one is a right possibly a
yeah
so it's still the same
if i found the king here
what does it mean i still find the shot
is smooth right
all right
okay so this is one optimization right
what's your motivation okay so as i said
i have many nice one king can you think
reversely you know what's the university
yeah yeah so look instead of instead of
going from a course i can go from one
i can go from where
yeah look because there's only one king
right so i can go from one king and if i
catch any horses
yeah you'll be yeah
yeah yeah you'll be you'll be the
shortest yeah because the direction the
edges
the graph remember the graph
if there is no direction what would you
call it
if like in a graph we don't have a
direction what do you call it
what's this graph
and directional graph yeah underneath
it's the same if you can capture the
king
from this partition to here
surely the king can come can jump
backwards right the king can
yeah we we just reverse it it's the
problem is the same yeah we can just
reverse these horses as the king
and k
is the
horses uh it's a horses okay
makes sense
so because we have online kings so the
term complexity will be just o n square
right instead of o m times n because
this could be in order of n
makes sense so we are reducing the time
complexity for o and q b to o n square
right
yeah
yeah make sense
okay so but as i said look we can we if
if we don't do that we can still if we
can still append
a plan of horses many horses together to
the kid to the king uh to the queue
right and this is called the marty sauce
breakfast search
do you get it multi-source pressure such
make sense any question
what did i just say
what's my this preference can you tell
it's me you use um
lots of lots of starting point yeah
previously we only had one king one one
horse and that's just single sauce
breakfast
but now i have many many plates and i
can just do it
okay i will just uh i will just
implement this preference search okay
it'll be easy on we use the wnbq and how
do you define wndq in python
uh
pq
and what's q first thing
[Music]
define let's say
minimum main move let me move and we
have a
a board okay at the board
we want the chest bar
right
so
q q equal d q
yeah because we we using double ended q
but we are not sure what to put
usually you put a load in binary search
in a binary but we are not sure what to
put here so let's just initialize with
nothing so it's an empty cube
so now let's say the row
columns is we just get the dimension of
the board yeah the number of rows and
the number of columns
yeah
[Music]
zero and um zero
so yeah
and
and then we need to go through the ball
to put the
let's start with the king
for
r
in
range
rows
for
c in
range
what
what do i play the rows and what what
are these
columns
and then look if
both
are c
is is okay let's define a
constant king equals let's say one
uh empty could be zero okay
and then the horse on that nine horse
would be
two okay something like that yeah
if ball equals king yeah because we are
capturing the king king there's only one
king okay king and then we just append
it kill the apparent
apparent
rc
okay look we push
to coordinate what are these
what do you declare with these
parentheses what are those keyboards
tuple is called tuple okay
okay now
now this is the initialization
initialization we put
put uh we put a
king
into the queue yeah into the queue
yeah because we're putting the sources
right if you change because there's only
one king we're putting english one king
if there's only one thing we can break
it here right you can just break
but if you try to
append the horses yeah and then you try
to you can change this to horses and do
it reverse way
now this is called multi-source
breakfast search okay multiple surveys
research
so after we we do this after we do this
what should what should we do after we
do this what should we do
and we we can do this breakfast yeah
right so first of all we need to
remember the number of the
remember the positions we have visited
so what kind of data structure can we
use to remember that moves
uh what what was the thing we could see
in equal set yeah
okay and then we can say while q is not
empty yeah why the q is not empty now we
uh okay so because we want to remove
remember the how many uh look eric
yeah
look we want to remember when we visit
this uh
when we visit this is the king and then
we want to visit here horses we also do
we want to return
two moves yeah we want to pretend the
shortest
number of moves
so we can because
if we want to remember it there are two
ways of doing it because we can append
the number of moves in a tuple right
that's one way because every time you
you can expand you can expand the one
node now by node and then you can
remember the number of moves here now
all we
as we talked about before we can always
what we all we can also always take all
the existing numbers uh the nodes in the
queue and then append their children
right we can take we can take these
three notes all at once and push their
children back to the queue so in this
case
every time i visited all the numbers all
the elements all the positions in the
queue it's all belong to the same level
it's the same distance make sense
yeah so let's do the y q and we need to
have the answer here answer is the level
your answer equals zero
uh let's put the minus one so we we can
increment it immediately so they'll
become a zero
okay
so now we can do this we can do the move
yeah
four uh we can do the current current is
rc equals
q dot pop left right
we take it take one uh
actually we want to take n element out
of q because
there's number n equals length q less
as i said we are taking everything in
the queue dq we are taking everything in
the queue we popping out right
and then we need to do this for
underscore in
range
and we're taking everything out r c
equals
q dot problem right we're taking
these out
right
okay so now look we we take this rc out
then we need to check if it's then
if it's the destination and we can
return answer right
so if bought
rc
equal equal one we are starting on kings
king so where are we going to
end terminate
all right we are starting on king so if
the ball is what
if
the ball is what we starting from king
and then if we visited
if we visited what
night or horse yeah the night
let's let's do a horse okay if we if we
ended the horse then we can just return
answer yeah
all right okay now i i want to visit
look i'm an rc i'm at this position as
as you know yeah as we know there are a
position yeah we know how to visit all a
position right yeah
from here we know possibly the maximum a
children right we want to push
okay i'm going to push these eight kids
if they are
if it's still
inside this ball yeah if it's not
outside and if it's empty right because
it's not empty
then we don't need right
i'm right make sense
so
for
let's say dr dc this is data in a
position we can use the list of the
coordinates yeah or we can use the array
of continuous use of two parts
okay one two yeah this is offset yeah
one two
one minus two
minus one two okay you can think about
it there there are eight of them okay
i'm not going to write over there you
know the a position this is the
continuing and then i need to say n r
and c
equals
r plus
d r
c plus dc this is the
next this is the position of the next
node right and then look if this knows n
r and c are in the range okay in the
range
how do you say in the range i'm running
up space
so look you can say zero smaller than nr
smaller than rows
yeah zero smaller than nc smaller than
columns if we're in a range
also
the bot and r and c needs to be what
come on you can answer this
and i and c needs to be what i said
look
if i i'm here i want to jump to the next
position if only if what
not to condition eva
i want to jump into the next position
yeah yeah
so obviously we need to find out if the
e this n r and c is not in a yeah it's
not in uh
sin yeah obviously we can say
n r and c
not in c yeah not in c if we're not in
scene i know we need to add it somewhere
i've seen.add
an rnc
okay
so do we need to check if the board is
empty or not
do we need to check
if we don't check uh
no we don't need to check why is that
because if we check is empty then you
will never find uh
yeah look you will never find the horse
yeah because yeah do you get it if we
check is empty and then this if it's
empty we append it right we append it
and then you'll never find the heart
right because that
we need to append its kit only if it's
inside the box if it's the next booth is
an airport and if it's not visited right
if it's not visited
make sense and then return if we can
find it we determine minus one right
okay
this is called marty sauce mutty sauce
if we're starting for the horse then
that's monty so if we start a king start
from the king that's only let's see a
single source okay
let's stay a single source
sin dot n r and c and then q need to
append and i is here q little
next move okay
okay so
one question for you eric can i exchange
these
can i swap these two
this is the king this is the horse can i
swap these two
and if yes
why
this is the
this is the what we are talking about in
this lesson
we start from king
yeah oh we can start from horse can we
yeah
come on say it loud
yeah yeah we can obviously we start
because we know it's only one king so we
start from king it's better
right the term times x t will be o n
square because they are if they are n
cells then they are n square
edges and we visiting each vertex
exactly once we're using the hash
scene
right but if we start from horse i know
we need to find a king
so let's marty sauce right hey listen to
me
we start from the horse because there
will be many many horses so at the
beginning and here if we start from a
horse then these will be executed
there could be multiple horses put
appendix in a cure right and when we
start at the beginning it's instead of
continuing the single king we will have
many many horses here many many horses
at the beginning right
these could be many many horses right
many many horses
and then we can each for each one we can
expand uh it's eight kids yeah possibly
eight kids right and we find a king
right so look there could be n
forces so the time complexity will be
o
n times
squared right but this m
could be in the order of n right because
look
they are n position on the board and
then could be m m is smaller or equal
than n right
yeah okay
so this time complexity which one is
better o n times n square or over n
squared which is better
yeah obviously because it's great okay
and you you reverse it yeah you reverse
it m you pick one right because we start
from the single key the time the space
compacts the water spectrum basically
are we using any space here
c
and k cube so what's the space for my
city
oh and because look yes there are n
vertices yeah and vertices
and vertices
so
because we have only we're using the
c set to visit to store the number of
vertex we have we i have seen so that
almost the time complexity is
there there could be n vertex in the
scene in the hashtag okay and the cube
as well
uh
any questions over
what's the subject we talked about today
sorry yes
and what's the agreement we're using
and we also talked about what what kind
of breakfast
martis machi sauce multi stocks
multi-source preference search
previously we have focused on the single
source purposes right look at the final
research we push the loop there's only
one load
yeah
level by level yeah what's a perfect
search of this order
this travels
yeah that's it and if now we basically
today
no difference it's just actual one we
have another five here
and what's the preference of this one
five two three four six well done that's
it that's the takeaway today okay and
instead of doing that we just push
instead of pushing one note here we just
push
the multiple notes in the queue right we
push the one five and the q
yeah look we push one five in the kill
right and then we take one out
push all its kids two three five four
here and we take the fire out we push
the kid six here you see it's the same
yeah
it's the same yeah
okay that's it for today bye bye
goodbye
can you say bye bye again
bye-bye