hello mr mr ryan how are you today
good day what's this
binary tree
what's the test right what's the test of
it
one two and then one two four
that's
one
two three three three levels three one
is the fourth one okay
go back away
so the binary trees are kind of uh fine
and cheese kind of black right and
for final three has for each note has
all mouse two kids and for each note it
has only you have uh one parent and
which note does not have parent and we
what do we call it
uh
doesn't have a parent i know the notes
which don't have these
children we call it leaves leaves or
terminal no okay that's easy so
previously we talked about these
different search purposes to count
number two in the depths yeah so do you
still remember
uh
so
first of all the final three let's try
this final three definition class three
class three
class three define the constructor
you need
so we will have what we have value
and we will have a left
equals num
and right
equals num right so this is basic
definition of binary three three node
okay and then say we can say self.value
equals value so look this value here
and self top
left left note where he points to here
he points to the left and he points to
the right right
and he could be numb at the beginning if
we knock and so parents to left
and then self
downright
equals right
and then let's do this this is this okay
so this is the
object that's the class three object
oriented programming we talked about
that yeah it has three properties value
left and right
so with this definition we can easily do
this different search easier so define
we want to get a depth
next steps yeah that's root with the
load
okay so if not root will return zero
for empty node it has the zero
very easy and now we just need to return
the maximum of our
depth
to the right to the left
and because we do the left and that's
wha
right right easy
look at the trees the noodle name to the
right plus one right because look if you
have a tree
if you know this tree the left you know
it's for example like three and you plus
one that's the depth and then if there
is right if this is four plus one is
five
so we are recursive we call this
recursive recursion and this is the same
function recursion to call to solve this
problem with the smaller size okay look
the left and then plus one because we
have to transfer the newton number makes
sense
i'm all we can do use the process search
you have to push the note up to a
visitor now what's the perfect search of
these orders one two three four
five yeah level by level and we use the
queue right we still double ndq remember
we use this this is a pen
we append the loot first
and then we take the no every time we
take it out we push its kick back to the
queue
right and for each node we have to
append we we can take everything out of
the queue and then append their children
so in this case we guarantee we can
guarantee that all the notes in the
queue belongs to the same level for
example like look
okay this one yeah
first of all i put the one up in right
that's the initial route i take it out
take everything in the queue off i push
the kids
which is two and three because two and
three are being on the same level yeah
or i can take then like 10 everything
out two three and push its kids five six
four five yeah
five six four five so look
at the same time
at any time the key the notes in the
queue belongs to the same level right
all right
so in this case we can have a single
variable to increment the depth where
every time we take everything out of a
queue we have a variable
alternatively
when we push the node into a queue we
can also remember the depth at a time
for example if instead we put a one atop
one and zero right
and now we take it off
we put the kit two and three but two
with the one
and the level zero plus one is two one
and then three one right so we have a
topper the second
second value in the tuple is the level
the first value is the note
right okay so let's see the little
review we have talked about this
previously
so today's task
we talked about these
similar but we are not talking about
binary tree we're talking about energy
so what's energy is that it has more
than two um two kids easy yeah
one it could be
two three
four
five right something like that and then
it could be
six
seven yeah up to
maximum you know it doesn't have to be
there's no fixed number it could be a
list of the children so let's define
this first
class 3 this is the same
and then define
init this is the reserved
constructor function means that whenever
we create a tree now this function will
be called constructor we call it
initializer okay
you need
some self
and then we have a value of course and
then we have a children we just have a
children
okay
at the beginning is the list of nothing
okay or you can put it now let's at
least this is the list of notes the list
of trees three notes okay three notes
for example trinomial
and now this is the same yeah
value equals value
theft of children
equals children okay
this is the template template for
for us to create a tree with the energy
and
not retrieve okay and language
so
simple we want to look at the maximum
depth
yeah so what's your approach
come on
is it the same as the financing
can we apply the same agreement to in
english
yeah of course that's a search professor
right easy but instead of left and right
we need to visit these this is the list
of children we just have to go through
the list of children
let me let me write it okay it should be
very very easy
and then then
uh for search preferences let's try with
the difference first okay
try with the temperature with the type
of search usually we implement within
our location right so it's very
recursion we don't have to worry about
uh maintaining the stack
because the computer just maintained the
stack for us and we can just with the
recursion it's easier for us to
uh
to implement it
it's usually almost intuitive way right
because we just call okay we want to get
the
depth of the left for example like
parachute left left
left substrate and then we're going to
get the depth of the right substrate and
we can just recursively call it because
it's already defined right
define
depth
and then this is the loop okay
so at the beginning it's the same we
want to check if it's empty right if
it's empty we'll return what
nothing okay you should not do it or if
you lose it's not okay
yeah look if
this if root is numb
or if not or
not no it's the same thing okay
return return zero yeah
within zero because we don't get the
depth yeah and now we have we want to
verif
kid is children right
yeah this children has a list of this is
the list of notes yeah list of notes
it's the list of three notes yeah three
three notes
this is the type of list of trainer
so answer equals zero now we just need
to go through for kids
and then for
and then we have we want to now what's
next we have a kit and then we want to
do what we don't call this function
because we need to get the test yeah all
right what's the death of a kid
that's kid yeah so now we want to
compare it that's the answer
equals next
answer
steps
kid yeah easy yeah
and then we tell what
answer
plus one
equals
answer plus one plus written answer look
we have we have a note yeah this is a
few notes this is the kid yeah this is a
kid
no doubt kid a lot of children list of
kids and i will get the notes
yeah plus one because we have to add
these
got it yeah make sense ryan you're with
me
okay so
this we can turn this into one nine yeah
into into one line let's just say
we're gonna say one oh yeah
return
okay this is one we can determine max we
can use this maximum here okay okay
next one
and then we need to give it a default
default let's parameter default zero
yeah why is it why we need to put it
before like that
and then plus one right this is the same
thing max function look what's next one
here this is the python inbuilt function
max123 what's the value
sorry yeah easy yeah and if you give a
max nothing
your
your complaint your screen the computer
will screen
so if you give that nothing at this time
nothing your skin you will say okay this
is not what i want but you can put the
second parameter default
equals zero
then this is okay right because look if
this is now if the evil children look if
load of children is numb terminal no the
leaf node
i need return zero here if you don't
give a return before zero
the computer says okay i don't know what
to do
makes sense because you asking me you're
asking me to get compute the maximum
of nothing
what's maximum if you compute the
maximum it has to compare right one what
number what's the maximum one one what's
the maximum one two two what's the
maximum of nothing i don't know but you
need to tell me
it's nothing
you have to say before equals zero okay
so let's case and then plus one we have
to press one okay so let's start test
research easier
okay let's talk about question search
a little bit
for the preferred search we can keep
these yeah obviously right right
so question search we use the q
obviously yeah with the q double n d
cube q equals p q
so at the beginning we want to push what
into the queue
we're going to push the word in a queue
children
to implement a perfect search at the
beginning we need to put something here
we need to put something into the queue
right node
i literally third
okay you said chosen i didn't hear it
okay
okay you have to be more confident
loot
so at the beginning
if we put a single loop right then every
time we need to take everything out of
the road okay
okay
so now
we have this answer at the beginning is
zero and then while
why are q
now what we need to do every time we
take a note out of q we need to
increment the answer the level right
make sense look
one
two
three
four
five
six what's the perfect search order of
these come on that's easy right
easy but how do we immunize it this is a
queue at the beginning we put a one here
right
one here the level the answer will be
zero and then here
okay answer will be zero now we take it
out we take everything off
take everything now we increment it to
one
i will push its key the kit of one is
two three four we push it in
okay and now every time we take it out
look we take two three four hour
everything in the key out
we need to increment the answer
what's the what's the kit what's the
children of two three and four
five six five six because these two does
not have to get i know we take this five
six
yeah and then we take everything out and
push it it has nothing okay so
science is three so that's it so why q
then answer plus equal one yeah as i
just said and i need to take everything
out so how many kids are there in the
queue which is length q right
and i have just to say four
in range and
i take it out current equals
q dot pop pop one for popular flow for
life
both left yes problem we want to take it
out from the left side right
there is no pop right down it's pop okay
pop is popped right top left is popular
okay okay
i will take it out right we take it out
then what do we need to do we need to
push it to kids yeah for kids
indoor dog children do the children
do the children and then we just killed
a pen
apparently that's it you know
you notice that the the breakfast search
and definition for the tree
is much easier than the graph we
remember a few days ago we talked about
the definition of professor jibber graph
right because the graph is
bi-directional so look if you
if you add travel from one to two
the binary tree you can't go back right
or the trees you there is no way for you
to go back but for the graph
if this if this is the identity graph
then if you visit what you visit from
one to two
and the next time you may travel back
and there will be cycle that's why we
need to use the hash set to remember the
nodes right the vertex so we don't visit
it again but for the
for the trees it's easier we don't we
don't need to define such thing right
well we can just go to follow the
children and they will go through
go from the root to the kids until it
hits the terminal node which that is
enough
and i will just return answer yeah we
can answer
levy so i was also talking about there's
another way of writing this question
search which is to append a
note and its level at the time right at
the time
so instead of instead of pushing the
single loop i push the tuple
i push the tempo so which is at the
beginner loop is one okay
yeah
so now i don't have i don't need to
write this answer right i don't need to
uh actually answer is zero let's say
answer input
so instead of taking n notes at the time
i take one note i always take one note
yeah i take one note
so i said carbon equal current and the
depth t equals
uh q dot uh poplar
right and i have these steps then i can
say answer equals max answer
answer b right and then
i don't need to i just need to oh yeah i
just need to do this for kid in
uh
okay so previously this is not good okay
this is carbon okay
yeah
for kids in current or children okay
previously the one is current there are
vietnamese i i
put a mistake there for kids in current
children and i killed a 10 kid
that's a topper and i put a second
variable which is the
uh what d plus one right
because the
current depth is d and then i push it to
kit the level with d plus one make sense
yeah that's a tougher and what every
next time i take one note out and i
compare them
compare with the maximum answer so in
this case i will get the maximum depth
so in all the cases there are
definitions we
definitely searching perfect search the
time complexity is over what if we there
are n nodes in a tree
oh and yeah what's a space complexity
n o and yeah because we're using the
queue right and then for recursion using
the stack right
okay
so so look to sum up this is quite
similar to
uh this is quite similar to uh
to getting the maximum depth of the
um
of the final tree the only difference is
with the children instead of two left
and right we need to get it from the
list of children and from the location
we're using that
for the deficient recursion to computers
maximum deaths after each and each
child each kid
and the maximum the the depth of this
entire tree
is the maximum depth of each kid
plus one right because it comes from the
current children okay
and then for the breakfast search we
just expanded level by level
okay that's it for today good job
bye-bye
bye bye