hello
hello mr ariel are you all right
yeah yeah yeah okay so we're talking
about continuous increasing digits okay
for numbers like this one two
three you know single digit 12
34 you see so each number
okay each digit in the number is one
plus its previous one so like uh
678 that's good but not this one is not
right this one's not okay
can you do like
can you do like 910
very good question no
yeah yeah i know well let's that's a
very good question okay about
unfunctioning no we don't count that we
only count the digit okay but this is a
very nice point and also for the number
zero we don't consider it
continuous increasing region okay let's
just call let
let's just define it as a positive
number positive integer positive integer
x bigger than zero okay
where each digit of x is one plus each
digit okay each single digit is one plus
this previous one
okay
so
what's the
what's how many of nums uh how many of
these kind of numbers within the uh from
zero to from zero to a hundred okay but
we're saying we don't need to consider
zero so let's say from one to a hundred
last time
account is seventeen seventeen okay so
can you count it again
so one two three four five six seven
eight nine yeah single digit two digit
now 12
uh
and 34
67 78
okay yeah that's where
nine
ten eleven twelve thirteen fourteen
fifteen sixteen seventeen weather okay
okay so how can we do this uh if we want
to
find out the all the numbers within the
range within the range s
from s to e inclusive okay from s to e
inclusion
so what's your approach how can we solve
this kind of problem how many ways can
you solve it
any idea
it depends on how you prove us yeah the
most stupid way of proof of thing is try
every single number between s and e and
then checking each number if it's you
know if you satisfy this right but it
could take long time right yeah yeah why
is that because look if the s and e if
the difference between s and is quite
big then you have to
you have to check quite a lot of cases
right so that that's very bad right
okay so for the proof of thing and
stefan search
when we talk about the buffer session
proofworking we are talking about what
what what we are talking about what kind
of problem
[Music]
uh
here is the tree
or
graph yes graph so let's say if this
number is one so what's the next one
what's the next note
what's one what's next
two okay so it's 12. okay what's next
no no one okay look each digit this is
the first digit okay and then
first
yeah yeah yeah you see are not easy so
so
how many possibilities are first digits
how many possibilities
how how many if one would pick the digit
let's start from picking the first digit
how many choices do we have for the
picking nine nine choice yeah so we can
have these two and three three it says a
tier nine right actually nine there's no
no
uh no edges coming off online right
because it's nine
eight there's only one choice which is
89 okay
yeah and the vertex each vertex is the
number right so so we can for let's say
from breakfast search we can push
remember a few days ago we talked about
multi-source preferences we can push all
these initial the first digit into the
queue
into the cube so we have these one two
three four five tier nine right and now
we take one number look let's say take
one number
one i take it one i
first of all i take it out and i check
if it's within this range if it's with
this range then i point it to the result
and i append the kit yeah i turn the key
which is one two back to account okay so
look if this range is 10 up to 10 do we
have still have to push
uh actually no if this noise is
then let's say okay if i take the 1 12
out okay i want to push the next kid is
123 right
but look at this upper end if it is up
to 10 do i need to push this number
again
no
why is that
because
it's
12 is already bigger
so there's no point appending because
it's still bigger right
yeah okay
so make sense okay let's just quickly
implement a breakfast search
multi-source breakfast search
research
uh what kind of data structure are we
using
can we use to implement a breakfast
search
define
key
find
numbers yeah we're done and then python
what's the queue
okay let's say answer is a list
pl is a dq
dq offers the constant term in appending
and push uh popping in both sides
constant time if we're using a list the
up the pop left yeah prop zero is linear
it's not constant that's why we use the
dequeue by the way so at the beginning
we want to follow i in range one we want
to push the first digit so what should i
do here
fine wrench
well i don't don't look at my notes
before i learn to walk
there
[Music]
so one two the second parameter is one
ten ten yeah and then q dot append
i okay
and then y
q
we take a number c equals q dot problem
right
and now we want to find out if it's the
range right s smaller than e
smaller than c smaller than e
then we took answer dot dot one how do
we append it we just apparent yeah okay
okay okay so answer the opportunity you
can write it as this answer plus equal c
yeah we talked about that before okay or
alternatively you can write this answer
plus equal parenthesis look parentheses
c comma
this means that's the tuple okay it's
the same so you can put the table put
the content of the topper
into the list okay this is also okay
that looks weird weird okay so why what
is a comma okay it's very strange
because this this is like a number right
but this is a topper
a couple with only single element that's
like let's that's why we put the cup
comma yeah come on how do you call this
coma comma comma in
just
to say this is a tupper
not a number right
okay now look if
c
is p if c is smaller than e right if
it's still in the range then i can queue
uh okay so if this number is c what's
this the rightmost digit what's the
digit at once for example one two three
what's this number um
okay so let's say air equals c modulus
and then i want to append the next
number which is what
in a q
look this is one two three and what's
next is one two three four
yeah
so i need to how can i get this number
from this number i need to multiply this
by
[Music]
1 10 10 and plus these number
plus one right
so this is c times 10
plus l plus one right
okay
yeah
and then return
[Music]
answer okay there's one problem here
which is if if the last stitch is nine
do we have to append it
no yeah because if last is in nine let's
say stop
yeah so we have to say if you can say
[Music]
910 not equals right nine then we can
open yeah okay okay that's the pressure
search
okay and then let's try the definition
okay it should be very easy okay and so
we keep this under but instead of q we
use the recursion on the stack right we
ask the computer to to
maintain a stack for us that's why we
use the recursion
so define
default search and we let's say the
current number is
is c okay
if
c
is bigger than s smaller than e then we
append it yeah we append this number
okay uh append
open apparently okay okay
yeah
uh okay because this answer is is
is non-local to this function we have to
declare non-local answer
now look
if
if c is bigger than the upper bound
right if c is bigger than upper bar and
i i just don't need to continue return
right make sense yeah
yeah and then i need i need to the last
digit is what uh c modulus 10 right
and what's the next number i can say
that's what's that if if
if air not this is the same as not
equals 9 then i can definitely search
c
times 10
plus a plus one right let's say it's
next number right because this is one
two three one two three times ten
plus three plus one is one two three
four make sense
yeah i know what's next
what's next
so at the beginning what should we do
now so this is the first i know we
should staffordshire's what how many
possibilities for the first digit
so let's say for i
in range
one to ten
and therefore search eye
and then i have this answer because we
can answer
yeah returns all we can sort it answer
if you want to
have increasing from one two three is
increasing make sense
yeah
okay
okay so this is definite search
so do we do we actually know what kind
of i mean
so
do you have actually think about what
how many possibilities are there you
know because we always stop at
is there upper limit for
how many numbers how many kinds of these
numbers are there
so you have to tell me first is it
unlimited or is it there's just a total
number you know we can find it now
limited limited why is that limited
because um because um
i don't know how to explain
because because um i i think because
um because um
because they're not
really a lot of numbers
okay because every time you
no matter what kind of number you pick
you always end at which number
no matter which digit you pick you
always the last digit always the maximum
you can go is what which number nine
that's it yeah so let's limit it right
so let's say
if it's limited what does the mean the
previous the if their previous the
different search preferences what's the
tango minecraft if it's a limited scope
how how many yeah look
it's constant time right because they're
only limited right it's constant
make sense no matter the star and end
the the given inputs
there's only the limited number of these
numbers
i give you one example okay so can you
give me the number start with one
yeah one one two one two three one two
three four one two three okay and then
here one two three four five six seven
eight nine yeah one two three four five
six seven eight nine is the biggest yeah
how many numbers are there uh you did
you just did
how many
how many counts how many
do you have to actually count the last
number is one
nine yeah okay so start with two how
many
two three
two three four two three five
uh-huh okay so how many
okay
and then three you need to count
seven
five
four three two one one is what nine
right this is what eight
eight nine right
yeah
makes sense
so how many numbers all together
how many all numbers together
these numbers adding together all right
wow that was quick
yeah how do you know it's 45
because yeah 45 that's only the 45
numbers because what
because how do you get this number one
plus two plus plus nine how do you know
what's the sum what's the sum of the
first and natural number remember we
talk about this sum of the first n
numbers
yeah sum of the first n so let's say sum
n
yeah
i equals 1 to
n sum i okay so my
that equals one the last number plus the
first number times how many numbers are
there divided by two so if we plug in
the nine
so the number will be what nine plus one
times nine
divided by 2 that's 45
if we plug in 100 what's the number 1
plus 2 plus 200 100 350. yeah 100 plus 1
times 100 divided by 2 that is 50 50.
you see that's the equation yeah first n
integer start from one n plus one
times n divided by two okay
okay so let's so we have only 45 numbers
here
right so we have only one 45 numbers so
we can actually
we can actually do this
yeah because there
look we can actually do uh this s equals
one two let's ignore the zero right
and we can do this we can start with
each number and then we can try the blue
four thing to all the digits on the
right right
yeah and we can find if it's the range
so we can do this answer equal that's a
string and that's a string for
i
in
range
render length
so let's start with the index index is
what zero
zero to
uh to ten right to ten
yeah to ten so let's start with and then
what's the
let's start from the left i with the
left index and the right index will be
for j in
range
i
plus 1 right i plus 1 to 10
and this number is 1 is s
i to j right right to j
and we convert it to integer
if
s smaller equal e uh c is similar equal
e then we can just answer the open
append
c
okay
then we can just do this and then return
sorting answer
something
because look because uh if you know if
you we don't provide this sort it could
be out of out of order right out of
other
for i in range actually is nine okay
it's not ten because there are only nine
numbers here so that let's
that's nine
the index will be from zero to eight
this i is the left index so
if i is the index for the left for
example if i equals 0 1 2 3 here
right
and then j will be
the index from i plus 1 to the n right
so there will be 4 45
yeah this kind of thing and then c
will be converted from a string to the
integer and we check if it's in a range
then if it's no in the range then we
append it right what's the time
complexity for this one
what's the time frame let's do one for
this
[Music]
there are nine iterations here
and one a one and they are at most right
you can say it's almost nine iterations
so
they are
clear at most here
as we said look 45
45 so it's actually a 0 45 so which is
why because no matter it doesn't this
aggregate doesn't depend on sne right
look
these two
are determined
these two are fixed no matter the value
s or e change
it doesn't change right
yeah
as a minion e a trillion
these these two are not effective are
not very right
am right
okay so only the only thing
makes a difference is this by checking
the range right
right but but this is the loop the
number of times
this loop executed does not depend on
the value of s and e so the time
complexity is of 45 the space complexity
okay we're trying to get a space
complexity
[Music]
how many how many numbers can we store
in these answers
maximum 45 yeah so which is
a one a one yeah right now okay
okay so um to sum up
the previous professor stefan search is
also all one right yeah
yeah you can't find more than that right
because we always stop at number nine
and when we expand the next kit we
always have the plus one at the end
right
yeah the next digit so the search space
so the search space is not it's limited
it's not unbounded okay it's it's
limited it's limited by o45 so all the
time implementation we'll talk about
today is
is a one constant term and
constant space
any questions so far
okay bye bye bye bye bye okay