so today we will talk about how to count
the number of nodes in a binary stream
remember what's the binary tree
is a tree basically the left one
should be bigger than two no that one is
should be smaller than the white one
now let's finally search what i'm
talking about is talking about is the
binary tree
okay so just just anybody on the street
okay so
how many notes are there five five yeah
yeah so you as human we can see there
are five yeah yeah but
how about a lot and then it's not easy
to count
at the beginning and we want to let the
computer to count okay
so today we're going to solve this okay
okay so let's do this right right
so we have the winner so let's look at
this note here so let's say if i have
many many
notes okay it's too hard to count okay
like that okay so let's explain
i know i know you're not counting okay
so how much how do we count it
how do you count ten how do you count it
three three four you become
three three four okay and how do you
count it orion
three three four how do i
know that is three dollars one
two three so there are two ways of
cutting yes seven eight
so you can cut it this way okay so you
first of all you can count
you can i'm the ruler here yeah okay
so first of all i know there's one one
note yeah
so it is root one plus the left three
okay the note of the left tree
yeah and plus the note of the right tree
okay five yeah
all right so in this case the left tree
and again it's in one note plus the left
and the right don't get it
yeah it's gonna take away no but the
computer is very fast
computer is very fast yeah the other way
[Music]
so this is called the default search
yeah that first you remember we talked
about this both uh
the different traversal agreement we
remember preorder post order immediate
in order yeah
yeah the difference search so so it
means that when you cut it because
yeah we could call the left turn the
right and then we
we add one meter okay yeah and then
press for 30 as you said but first
search is level by level okay so
how many notes it means number one yeah
and then there are two
and then two and then three one
one okay so that's another way of
counting it okay so let's do this first
[Music]
thing okay
define count let's do it
okay
[Music]
then what do we return
yellow yes square down yes okay so if
it's nothing
if nothing obviously if it's nothing
then yeah
we have one note yeah yeah i know what
we do
count
[Music]
what we don't write yes
enough yeah let's call that first
recursion therefore
look if we are wait for me
if the load is numb then we return zero
otherwise
there's one node of current and then we
don't know how many nodes in the left
right
let's call it recursively so let's call
this function
to call it again then this will solve
the smaller problem the left three
and then like that right three and then
yeah if last three
three left uh the three notes in the
left three and four notes in the right
tree and then total would be eight
because there's one more yeah
three four and one yeah you see this is
very clear yeah
okay yeah
okay now let's move to the uh second one
which is called the breakfast search
break first okay okay you're
okay so first of all we also need this
yeah we also need these
yeah if it's nothing okay i'm not going
to copy it okay if you lose it's nothing
that will be 10
00 okay yes yes okay then now
remember the preferences will use the
cube i'm just
writing this oh again yeah no no
no no look this is simple and you tell
me you tell me which one is easy which
ones
which one is better okay what's the
complexity of this one
there are a number of notes in and and
no
yes why why is the one because you have
to check
every note yeah yeah because we have to
visit every note to count it yeah
yeah we cut one yeah very good so look
up account another load
then we use a queue yeah q first row has
a load
in the list okay this is our uh
yeah so now why the length of the q
is bigger than zero when there's some
element in the q
then i also have a answer answer equals
zero we called it okay
so now look uh we
we need to pop it so p equals
q dot pot zlo remember this is to remove
the element from here yeah yes
and then we have remove one now so we
have to count it
yeah increment counters of another one
answer
plus equal
equals one we have removed one number so
what is
we have removed the node from the queue
then
we know one more note yeah yeah so what
should we do
okay
[Music]
left yeah if p dot left is not num
right then we do this q dot
append append
p dot left okay and then similarly if p
dot right if if the key
if the note has the left right that
would push it to the q if it has one
right
right side will push it to the to the q
okay
kill the append
he's alright is there anything missing
here return
return
because
we check if the current node has if it
has the left triad
then we'll push it to the kill i never
push the right half to a kill
right so in this case this equilibrium
will visit the node
like this is one two three four the
sequence
of the node visiting removing will be
one
two and what's next
three three four five yes three four
five level by level remember never buy
levels
yeah what's the time complexity of this
one
what's the term complexity the red one
yeah
[Music]
is it the same do we have the visit on
each node
yes oh yeah yes we have to visit each
now
right no matter which way you pick it's
the same yeah
it's just different for this one you
meet the sequences
one two
four five three but for this is one two
three four
five you see even they are different but
they are the counter is all they
all get we all get five notes using both
okay using each of them okay do get it
okay so this is called the default
search recursion within people using
because
so which one do you like whatever it is
which one do you think is easier quicker
that's what
so that's the breakfast search okay
let's look at the first one but did he
say
it he likes this one because it's
shorter right shorter to to implement
okay
okay thank you very much okay say bye
bye
oh yeah bye oh yeah oh yeah