hello
hello mister here with me serrano all
right
yeah today we're going to talk about the
mode m-o-t-e what does it mean
what's mean mode
in mass mathematics in mass m is the
most
most yes the number that appears the
most okay
yeah
in the first early days we talked about
the average yeah average is the sum
divided by the the length the count
right
and we talk about the medium what's
medium the most immediate like one two
three what's the middle number
two that's the medium okay and how about
one two three four what's the medium two
is the required three two three two plus
three divided by two the average of the
most
the intermediate and the meter to right
3.5 2.5 way down okay so the mode is the
mode the number that appears the most in
a array list let's say
one two two three
three two what's this mode what's the
mode of it three two right two two yeah
two appears three times yeah okay so
today it's not very easy given a time
given an array we want to find the mode
easy
okay by the way if the number if the
most number appears twice then we return
the first one right for example if if
these
if this is four
no no if this is four what's the mug
oh sorry
what's the most two or three yeah we
just picked two right because they all
appear in the most times they are
two and three but we picked two the
first time okay
yeah yeah
how are we solving this
right we just open it by solving it how
how do we solving this what's your idea
what's your most intuitive uh what's the
most intuitive way of solving this kind
of problem like one thing set
how do we i mean
yeah we're using number but first of all
we need to find out which number appears
we need to find out the number of times
the most element appears right for
example we want to find out okay this
one element appears
most times which is two
now we can go through this array again
and if this
if this number
all appears
twice then we return it right
am i right for example this one
okay so we we need first of all we need
to go through this element uh arrays and
we find out that some element okay some
element appears
some element appears to us
appears three times and then we go
through the element again
yeah and we find out okay two appears
three times appears most times then we
determine it
doesn't make sense
okay so how how do we remember how do we
count the number number of frequency
counter yeah weather counter so look
this is a yeah if we counter it
what happened if counter a
from collection import counter if we
counter a so what does it give us if
this is
what does this give us
give us a dictionary right scenario
a
one appears one times two
appears three times three appear two
times okay so when we counter a
it would give us give us something like
this dictionary the keys are the unique
elements one two three yeah only one two
three appears in this one right and then
the the value this is called the value
is the number of times they appear right
yeah if we're not using this counter we
we can do this yeah d equals dictionary
yeah this is this center curly brace
yeah and this is calculated decent array
now we can say we can say well for i in
a for i in a if i in d yeah we need to
check because we if i in d then
d i plus equals 1 as if if it's
appearing
the first time then d i equals zero if
if we declaring additionally using this
kind of thing this is similar this is
the same as did yeah but if we're using
the default addition area this is a very
special way of declaring uh
map and we say we in
it means that if the key is not existing
in the dictionary then the byte for its
value is zero integer zero so we can say
for i in that a d i if this is d d i
plus equals one we don't need to check
if it appears before right but overall
this is the most simplest way counter a
and you give us this one two three so
now we just need to return the element
which element appears the most
which element by looking at this
dictionary two yeah okay
so how how do we do that because looking
at the value yeah yeah looking for value
so we can say look at look at this max
if this is t
max t if we give this max t it will give
us the most maximum of the key which is
three right
yeah but if we have max t top values
values
yeah if max dot d the value will give us
three right we want to give
we want to return
the key with most value right
yeah you
you find out the most value and then you
return the key
that's right and then we can do this
first of all we can do this yeah this is
n
and now we can go to four n for i
in a
if
if d i
d i equals n right if d i equals and
then return i right
make sense
yeah look look we can say this
for
i
in
num in a okay in a
if
if d i
equal or equal n and we can just return
i yeah easy yeah
okay yeah
oh okay i'm going to give you one
quicker way of doing this okay you can
just say
return
max
d
key
equals d dot get
and that's it
d
d is the counter right look this is the
counter and i want to return max t the
key
but key is d dot theta k is the value so
i want to return the item look
item which has the most
value
letter max t key comma key equals t
this is the syntax exactly doing this
okay max theta value
if we don't put the values is max t is
essentially the same as max t dot keys
it returns three which is not what we
want
and next the value is return d three
which is no we want to return two which
has the most key most value right so we
can say okay we can first the first way
is n equals that we get a three and now
we go through the numbers and check
which which value
which which value yeah which i which
element has the value
three right okay one is one no one two
okay appears three times and now we
return it all we can do here is this is
the center
alternative we can use this syntax okay
make sense
yeah what's the time complexity
[Music]
there are numbers in the area we also
we actually we need to go through twice
right
right counter
the counter
i went
and then we go through this again so
it's actually o to n
but we drop the constant yeah when we
talk about the time complexity we drop
the constant let's space complexity
count out
yeah
make sense
okay that's it for today bye-bye bye-bye
bye-bye okay that's it