hello hello mr ariel all right yep okay
so today we talked about the repeated
kaylan substring okay repeat it repeat
it
okay lens
substring substring has to be continued
right remember
first string okay for example given
these a b c d abc okay
and when k is three
s is this we how many sub strings
which are lengths of
three abc
and cd are repeated more than once
abc and abc yeah because it appears
twice any other sub lens which is
how many sub layers which it has the
three lens how many subways which has
three lens
then three which has three characters
how many how many substrings which has
the three characters
a lot can you count
not really
abc bcd cdx
dib
abc
so how many of these five
five how many characters one two three
four five six seven
seven seven characters
so
look if we want to iterate proof of
thing all these k lengths so okay
let you say it's five yeah one two three
four five so it's actually the length n
minus k plus one okay
yeah
the length seven characters
okay we are looking for three
and then the number of uh the total
number of the substring which is k
length is n minus k plus 1
doesn't make sense because we we can we
can do this we can hope this can we
iterate for i
in range
start from zero okay the oh we don't put
a zero star from zero to n minus k
right
how many iterations n minus k
how many iterations
they are
uh
yeah is it
no no n minus k plus one okay plus one
yeah
so there they are they are n minus k
plus one iteration okay
so we want to find the so now this is
the way of finding all the substrings
with the
k lens
and we want to find out how do we check
in with the repeated ones how how can we
do it i mean in set instead of hash chat
yeah we use the hashtag
okay so i know we can do it okay that
would be easier what's the time
complexity if you're using this kind of
thing
and now it's written on the white board
and minus k right because we italy yeah
we're iterating that much time okay
okay
and you tell me okay define
define that let's say k learn substring
sub string string
[Music]
and we need the s we need the k all
right
yeah yeah yeah
okay so now we have uh this data
beta equals default dictionary okay
let's say
before dictionary
and the type is integer okay because we
are we are counting the number of
substrings we're counting the substring
and then the number of times they appear
right
all right
yes
can you can you tell me what to do next
data
and now we have these columns let's say
we have sharing
okay so that's because here
here i'm going to
current is the
current i'm going to use it as the k
lens
k lens substring okay
canon substring
yeah so
so okay let's say if it's here empty and
then we need to go through this
this there for i in
range
uh
let's just go go through the array first
the string first
and then we can build it yeah we can
concatenate the string
right and then if the length of it
is bigger than k so we need to look if i
just if this substring a b c d a b c
okay now i'm putting this current as a
and then i believe the b and i put a c
okay and next time
next time i put a d but which is more
than three characters so what should we
do at this moment
what should we do at this moment look we
have current iterating put a b c and b
now it's more than three characters what
should we do
uh
[Music]
pop yeah
but look currently the string is
immutable right so we can't do it so
let's put it at least or better we can
have a dq yeah dq because when we have a
dq top left is constant time right so we
can just say current
dot append i right
yeah i is the character abc
and if the current bigger than k then
current needs to do a
current
left
for black
now the current
is a string which has
what which
then we need to remember that remember
the number of times you appear right
current
plus equal one okay
yeah make sense
and then what should we do after that
now we need to find out okay answer
equals zero and we need to go through
the dictionary theta
for i
in data
if
theta i bigger than one time right
bigger than one time and answer plus
equals one
return
answer
make sense
what's the space complexity if you can
remember
[Music]
uh
okay so look data this is the
dq so
we we can we can
the key needs to be hash of because it
can't be the least so let's put here i
need to put please join
the join
current okay
what does this mean
empty space don't join current what does
it mean
uh it means you join not a space between
every yeah yeah nothing if they don't
put all this look if this the list is a
b c then
dot john you'll become a b c a okay
what's the space commercial uh are we
using any space yeah yeah
uh what what what is it how what's the
space complexity
so oh what
um
oh is it oh and
[Music]
no okay right why is that because every
look if it's more than k i just pop out
so
at any time
there is no more than k
elements in the current right okay okay
this this bit is okay
but this bit
how many of the data
default how many data how many current
is actually how many how many
uh kaylan substring we we talked about
like n minus k plus one okay so actually
okay plus
o and minus k
okay so you add it together it's
actually o n okay we're done yeah yeah
do you know how why we got this oven
okay yeah
this is m minus k plus one we drop a
constant and okay plus o n minus k
yeah
k is cancel out so it's
okay
so this bit yeah this bit we can make it
prettier
we can make it prettier
we can make it prettier so we can say
return
actually we want to theater yeah theater
theater what let's say namda
namda
x
x minus 1
for
x plus
x bigger than 1
plus 4
and then we have least the second value
which is the data
data the
values
yeah values
okay and we convert it to the list
look the theater the first one takes the
function or lambda function we which we
want to comp we want to find out how
many are bigger than one and then these
formula from data values because the
value is bigger than one it appears
smaller ones okay and at least is the
uh the filter and we want to find out
the lens yeah so we we put a lens over
it
yeah this is one way okay
yeah
or we can use the list comprehension
list
for uh
what we want to find out the key okay so
then it says i
for
forward data item yeah data item
for i for i j in theta item
and then if j is bigger than one okay
and at least will give you give us the
list of the
list of of what of the substring k
length substring and then we just need
to return the length okay this is the
the same okay which is
pretty much the same thing this is the
most uh intuitive way answer equals zero
we go through the dictionary we find out
if the value is bigger than one because
if battery is bigger than one means this
is repeated
makes sense
yeah answer equals plus equal to answer
so list this bit okay this bit
uh
yeah
okay so the
this bit um
what else
we can actually iterate over the
substring kn substring by the index
right so we can just do this
for i in range
m minus k and n will be the length of s
right obviously n minus k plus one
and then look the substring will be one
s equals uh substring will be
c u r so we don't need this okay c u i
equals s the substring substring what
start from i to i plus
k
right we start from i to i plus okay and
then theta
current plus equal one okay look
here is simpler
so
the index starts from zero to n minus k
yeah a minus k and that the substring of
the exactly the length
k so it's look from i to i plus k
yeah
i plus k minus 1 okay actually it's
minus 1 yeah 2 from 2 exclusive and now
we can just do this data and plus equal
one
yeah
make sense does it make sense
really
okay can you repeat what daddy says
today
so we
uh
b c
um
so k this is the s
k equals three how many repeated
substring of
how many repeated calendar substring
appear
you know appear more than once
how many
[Music]
k usually so what do we do here we try
every
and then b b c
b c d
c d c
d c d
so which one is repeated
make sense
okay that's it for today good job
bye bye
bye