so
hello mr erin mr ryan how are you today
okay
so let's look at these sublist again
0 1 5 3
4.
and then i given a range like
from one to four
okay so
this is a sub list let's say the lines
and we want to find out the the number
of sub list with maximum between this
range so let's take an example so
the sub is the three and four right
this sum is three and four
what's the the maximum is four is
between this range so this is okay
and then
one
three
four
yeah these are all okay these are all
surface which is the maximum is between
this range right how about zero one
yeah it's okay so how many of them
yeah no not a lot just five right
so if the surface is the
five
five elements in a certain how many
zombies together
how many sub list for if this size is n
yeah fifteen how do we get it because we
also can be a sublet we've had two or
more okay so use the f
c one and plus
c one two one
onion okay and then
and then
okay okay look you're basically right
yeah so let me fill out an element so
you want to pick one out of m that means
that the service was only single one
single element like instead of five
three four or one if we pick two it
means that we start we pick two index
that's left and the right right so
you'll be the sub list which with more
than one element so this is m plus
n times n minus 1 divided by 2
so if i put a 2 n over 2 this is the
same thing so we will get
and m plus 1 divided by 2 okay so look
this is the formula of the sum for the
first few integers right so five will be
one plus two plus three look n equals
five you'll be one plus two plus three
plus four four minus five equals fifteen
right so if you put a plus 5 in
5 times
5 plus 1 divided by 2 that gives us
15 as well okay
so that's how we get it
so
um so one example is that how can we
solve this problem i mean obviously if
we can go for the proof of thing yeah if
we prove us all the subjects that's
going to take us o and square term but
to check
yeah yeah because it needs another on to
take to check to get the maximum of the
sub list and then to compare if it's
between this wave
let's do this profile thing first
let's do this first things first okay
at the meantime you need to think uh
what kind of accurate can we use to make
it faster
faster uh using your brain
yeah using my brand but how about your
brain
completely computer brain but we need to
test computer okay let's say
[Music]
let's say today is day yeah okay let's
say f okay the nums and then we have uh
uh lower in the upper lower and right
okay
so answer equals zero
all right we on the column and put it in
the lens i'm putting the answer and the
lens the let's say we n equal
length number right
and then we need to pull forward f4
i
in
range alright yeah
french and color
and then for j basically we are we are
forcing the left and right and then
the left and right could be the same so
we start with i
and then up to n right
okay another service what's the
summaries
s
equals nums
look nums
and then start with i up to j plus one
right inclusive because up to j plus one
means i j inclusive this is the service
right
but we want to get the maximum so if
if okay so air smaller equal than the
maximum of the sub is s smaller equal
maximum
what did i just say ryan what's the come
from okay look oh n
another loop
square
and at least one
this one takes another o and so o and
cubic okay
space complexity when you're using any
space so that's our one constant
uh
to be strict we are using constant term
of space okay we are using this answer
but it's constantly it's not it's not
when i say we are not using space that's
not quite right okay we're using
constant time of space so it's open
make sense yeah but how's that strict
can you not throw that thing into the
ball please
how's that
strictly speaking strictly speaking when
as what i said
oh we are not using any space that's not
accurate we are using constant term
constant space right because when the
numbers the number of elements in the
numbers grow
it doesn't does not depend on the input
we are still using constant
constant space okay
okay so let's that's the profession
let's prove one thing
keep quiet okay
so let's say
we want to find out this max a
is smaller than the right and smaller
than air right
so how about if i calculate the
calculated part which is smaller than r
first right so you increase
look if i put the numbers here right so
i want to put i want to count how many
in the range right yeah probably in a
range right i want to count how many in
a range here this part yeah
how about if i say okay i first of all i
calculate this part
this is a
and then you cut off and then i
calculate this part l minus one is here
i calculate this part
and then you cuddle this is b
so what's the answer here
so this bit this i want to calculate
this bit c okay c is between the numbers
between this bit
c is between
the air to r inclusive yeah
so now i calculate it okay so a is the
part
between the minus minus infinity to
to r inclusive and then b is the part
minus inclusive to l minus one
okay so what's the answer c
come on from the front of the graph
i want to take this bit
and now i know this strip and i know
this speed so what's this bit
that's it
yeah so c equals y
c equals
b
b is this speed a a minus b yeah a minus
b exactly c
a minus b
okay so the same here
we want to calculate the num we on the
count number of sub list right number of
sub is that the maximum
is between this range so let's say we we
count the number of sublease which is
smaller than r and the number of solid
which is smaller than the maximum sub uh
value of sub is smaller than l minus one
right and then a minus b now we can do
this twice right
we calculate
so basically we calculate f r i know we
calculate f l minus 1 i know we minus it
that will be the answer make sense
yeah
so now how do we calculate this this is
the
thing we need to
know okay
so let's say look i have a service if
it's
if it's satisfied okay um 100 here this
is the maximum i want to
the upper bound okay maximum okay one
how many of this
uh one
another number like hey how many surveys
three
ten how many sundays
six
okay so you keep adding that how about
lee how about now i add a thousand how
many service
do you edit
you don't like it right
no because you can't edit because this
is more than 100 so so we set it to zero
okay and now how many stop lists one
exactly how many zombies
yeah okay you get it
yeah i know we can count it yeah we're
done okay so that's the way right we
have a
current counter we accumulate
as long as the current number is smaller
than the upper bound
right
define
well let's say
f okay this is the num uh that's the
upper bound let's say the upper bound
upper bound
so current equal answer equals zero and
we go through this number for i in
numbers right
if i smaller equal than upper bound
and then i need to current equal plus
equal to one right else i need to reset
it to zero right
and then answer plus equals column right
yeah
yeah look if we smaller than an upper
bound we accumulate the one right and we
add the atom
as a length right so it's one plus two
plus three plus four right that's how
you get something number of times
i don't know the final return is written
returns f
r minus f
l minus one okay
what's the term complexity here
this is all n right because we're going
through the numbers
a for loop
exactly yeah the space a constant time
how many times we need to call this
function
yeah call this one call this one so
that's o n
plus o n
is
o to n
but we drop a constant so it's o n okay
yay
make sense
okay good job today bye