okay so this is the final three and the
green ones
are the biggest are the piggies
then
all its descendants right it could be
now it could be bigger or equal than the
maximum value of all these sub 3 right
for example 6 is maximum it's
what's the biggest in in this substrate
6 six is bigger or equal three the
leaves are okay right
leaves of course the leaf for the leaf
note with no children
obviously they are the biggest of their
descendants because they are just lesser
okay and then two
it's not right because the biggest is
six it's not
all right
so we also called how many notes
satisfy these how many notes okay so
each note four yeah yeah how many one
two three four so because
than the maximum of its descendants
right yeah
so
what's your what's your idea
yeah proof of thing might work okay
proof of thing so how do we prove
foreign for each node
for each node we
okay so for each node we can profile
each node for each node we just check we
just go through that subtree again
to find out the maximum value right but
let's going to take
what's the term complexity figure out n
square yeah well now because they're
equal a foreign right
and then you visit for each node you
need to visit
this subtree and that's going to take
roughly o
n right on every g o n two but the time
converse is o n times n divided by two
which is one square okay
let's do stuff
however if if
how about if i tell you that at some
point we know at this point we know the
maximum of left tree and then the right
maximum of right three right i know
obviously at this point at this point we
know
we know what we know the maximum
electricity level net tree and maximum
of right tree we can do this recursively
right and then we obviously we know the
value column variable and if the current
value is bigger than the left max and
the right next
then we increment the answer make sense
and then you return the answer
now for this one we do ten for each
recursion we do this we we return the
the maximum of the sub tree okay
what i mean
if look leave this three okay okay i
have a note what's the
what's the pre-order for for this
chinese spanish what's the pre-order
ryan
pre-order
yeah one one two
what's the post order
one post order oh two one i mean
one what's that in order ryan what's
another if you want to visit the one in
in the middle what's the in order
uh
uh one two three let me know let's play
other here
what's the another come on
[Music]
so now look if we visit the tree which
is the post order post order because the
repose order will be to the left tree
first with the right trees up first for
each sub for each recursion code we
return the maximum of that subtree right
all right at this point we know the
maximum of the left left tree and the
right maximum of right tree
and if this node the neutron is bigger
than the both then we increment the
answer right
makes sense
what is that you're busy joining
increment
what increment
what do you mean
we're going to implement this
are you finished or not
no
okay i wait if you finish
wow what you drawing
ryan i'm doing a doodle right okay
that's it no more no more come on can i
have it start with shooting stars okay
so now let's say defined let's say count
maximum okay
no okay comments now
and then we have la lute what's missing
color
okay and then now we want to
accumulate the answer here answer equals
zero and we have a first order yeah
that's my search press close order load
so what's this function return by the
way what's the this function written it
returns with that
what's the what what are we talking
about what's what
look
i just said for the post order
yeah post order i if i'm at this point
loot
so this is the left max the max of the
left tree the right so what's your
return for this definition
the one
left left and left
what's
what's your return
yeah and then what's at this point i
need to return what you need to return
if root is
greater
than left max and right for each
recursion we just want to return the
maximum value of that substrate right
and then it can be compared by
by the by three values what are the
three values we need to compare
right now yeah do the value left and we
can do this because
the bottom up right in the bottom so we
we passed pass
so we passed top yeah we passed along
the way okay
so look now if not loot if loot is empty
what should we return the maximum
the very small value what can you think
of
the smallest value you can think of
plus one
y plus one
mass dot infinity yeah
infinity
and one
no we don't need one okay why why you
need to put plus one yeah no return
math dot infinite infinity then one
one what what one is coming on infinity
and one because if infinity and one is
smaller then
okay so you mean no no no no next
infinity is the smallest number we can
think of okay look i can think of
something
the first order we just say the first
order of the one
first order this is the root
and then this is left
this is the right so what's the post
order
first of the is left
left right and right okay so left equal
dfs
left
and then right
minus infinity just kidding
blue dot right okay so
so now
why do you have a minus infinity there
okay
okay so i have
[Music]
and one left is here and right right so
because this one
okay now at this point i need to i need
to compare i need to increment and what
cases i need to increment this answer
okay i need to put it here there's a
number here to to allow us to to
increment this value here non-local
answer okay so i in what cases we need
to increment our answer
if if one
if root of value
is bigger than one equal than one
come on
left and right yeah left
and
rule the value is bigger or equal than y
right
because now at this point this node is
bigger
this node's value is bigger than the
left tree and the right tree all right
i'm right all right and answer plus
equals one okay
and then i just have the difference
route
and then one return
return
answer
easy what's the time the next thing
each node is visited exactly one what's
the space convexity
because we're using the recursion post
order the stack okay this day the stack
is implicitly used okay by recursion is
a mistake the compiler the computer
build the stack okay
yeah here's the step for us
can can you not draw that i'm gonna ask
you questions can you explain to me
what's this function return test search
answer i no no no
what's this function return it returns
return it returns return max read dot
value what's right yeah yeah then what
does it mean that you return the max
element of this and maximum this and so
no no no so what do you compare it with
this okay let's return uh what return
the maximum of the
value in the current subtree right
you need to express it well okay i know
you understand but you need to try to
express it you're trying to explain to
people okay
make sense ryan do you understand any
questions
no okay
bye
bye bye