okay so we're given a list of numbers
and we want to find out how many numbers
have this odd number of digits okay so
for example like 1 2 4
32 four
one how many numbers three
what are those one one two four and four
and one
one big brain quick match okay so these
are just quick rounds
so yes we need to go through these
numbers right and then we can check if
we need to come up with a function to
check if each number is uh
is odd number of digits okay let's just
write these
let's just assume these these function
function you know we're going to fill
the data up i given the number n right
and you need to tell me if it's true
two if it's uh number digi if false if
it's even number of digits okay
otherwise so let's just put the path
here pause means that okay we're going
to come back to that later okay pass
okay
and now we need our answer yeah answer
equals zero
this number for i
in nouns
and we can just say
if of
i
then we can increment it right yeah and
then answer yeah
okay this is easier this bit of time
contact stays what
oh very easy and then let's say
we are not sure what's the
time complexity to implement this odd
okay
um by the way this one we can do it in a
prettier in one line thing
return we can just return
okay or
i
for i
in
lambs
then this will give me a list of two and
four right a list of two and four
which uh if it's a odd number of digits
or four and we just need to count
as a term array.count count function
call how many of them count two okay
so these one two three four five is
equal to the same line return
at least a list of o i for i in numbers
country okay
yeah
okay now now let's focus on how to
implement this odd function okay okay
so how many ways can you think of the
most easy way to
to to count a a number to find out if a
number integer
in the type is uh has the odd number of
digits
we can do what you can mold the rest
we can
how
usually how do we get the length of a
string yeah we can just look at it yeah
but we can convert the integer to one
eye
okay we can convert the integer to one
to what type screen
digit and to the string and we can use
the which function to cut to get a
length
we can we can convert it to
a string and then
string strn and we want to use wall
function to get the length
which
and then we can just do this there we
can just do this
return length
strn and
we want to find out if it's even number
or all number right so modules two equal
equal one okay or you can just do this
one and one okay
ah
i have no idea
and the one n is the binary uh it's a
bit
so
great and one okay
equal equal one or you can omit that
yeah that's one way first yeah
the tangential for this one the number
of digits let's say d okay and then this
is o d i and then plot
uh and we consider the previous one
going through these numbers in the array
so the time connection is o and d right
okay this is the number digit for each
number okay
okay another method is we can use the
logs 10 function right
we we talk about the lock all the time
yeah lock
locked you can have different base 2
right log 2 a what's this number
2 to the power of y equals x a
3. yeah so look log
a
b
equals y so we can translate into a to
the power of y equals b okay so here the
same log ten
log ten
a thousand equals
three three you have your ten to the
power of 3 equals a thousand right yeah
so we can get these functions uh we can
use these functions to calculate now uh
we can use this math dot we can import
from the math master log 10 okay
master log 10
log 10
this number is n right
and i need to plus one
and convert to integer and we can return
this this thing if it's the even number
or number yeah
yeah
why this works okay so let's say a
thousand
a thousand and these things return to uh
return one
return three yeah three plus one four
digit right a thousand how many digits
one two three four four digit
uh a hundred how many digits three a
hundred log ten a hundred is two right
log ten
a hundred equals two two plus one you
got three okay how about 99 we don't
know yeah we don't know how many but is
that this low log 10
99 is smaller than 2 right smaller than
2 plus 1 is smaller than 3 right and now
we get an integer part smaller than 3.
we get an integer part so it's 2. so
it's two digits okay makes sense
but okay so let's before if we draw this
this function
remember this log term function yeah
when
when x okay so this is x here this is y
when x is one
log
ten one
ten to the power of one equals one
ten to the power of y equals one ten
10 to the power of 1 equals 10. if it's
1 that's 10 10 to the power of 1
come on think about it any anything to
the power of 0 equals 1 a not equals
zero okay
this is special okay
so 10 to the power y equals one come on
i'm writing that here 10 to the power of
y equals one eleven
zero zero okay 10 okay so look when when
x is one
y is zero okay so right here
when x is
ten
y
when x is ten
ten is here
y is what
log ten
ten
equals ten to the power of one equals
one one okay so one why is one here okay
okay you can come on here there's
nothing 1
log 10 to the power of y equals 100
100 is your x is 100 here so y is what
twice
log 10
x yeah so basically this function is y
equals log turn x so x equals 0
x equals 1
y is y is 0 right x equals
x equals 10 y is 1 x equals a hundred y
is two so this function is like there
it's very very
yeah this way
am right
so from two to three
why
from
this is one two three why look
from two to three x needs to go from a
hundred to a thousand make sense
yeah all right make sense this is
mathematics come on it's useful
when x goes from a hundred to a thousand
a hundred here to a thousand somewhere
here
yeah somewhere here
y value from two to three okay make
sense yeah
so look 10 to the power of minus 1
equals 1 okay so look 10 to the power of
something yeah so a to the power of
minus b equals a to the power of b yeah
1 over a to the power b okay look
so what 10 to the power of minus 1
equals 1 come on
equals 1 1 over 10 to the power 1 so
it's
0.1 right
so 1
when
x is
1y look when y is what
10 so look log 10
what
equals look look x equals uh
let's say
0.1 okay equals what
okay so that equals minus one
uh no no no no
10 to the power of
so one when x is
1 x is 0.1 here
so it should be minus minus 1 here
okay so this graph is like that right
this is why how do we interpret this one
so y equals log ten
x
equals minus one okay because y equals
minus one so 10 to the power minus 1
equals 1 over 10 is 0.1
0.1 so x is 0.1 here
okay so look this this function this
graph
never hit
okay this is one important takeaway the
lock
the lock function
the local angle y equal log x
log a x never hits never crosses with y
right
yeah
because you can't find anything you
can't find anything a to the power of
anything equals zero yeah you can't find
anything to the zero
right
yeah you can't find anything to the
power of zero does it make sense
a to the power of b equals zero you
can't find anything
there's no such thing so this line never
crosses the y
make sense
yeah makes sense okay so look the
original question the number needs to be
positive yeah positive
so if it's zero we have to especially
say if and if n is zero we return one
right because zero is one digit
right you can't you can plug in using
this one look because we put a zero here
what happened
ten to the power of y equals zero
there's no such thing
yeah there's no such thing so this will
break
so we have to check if n equals zero
return
one otherwise we can return
listing to check this thing if it's odd
number or even number you know how to
check the number if it's even number or
or number right we can
modulus 2 yeah all right modulus 2
equals 1 then that would be
odd number if it's 0 it's even number
yeah or you can n this is the same thing
n one equals one
odd number
yeah binary yeah
what's what's one one one in binary
what's this number
[Music]
15. you see the last digit the last is
zero one if it's zero it's even up if
it's one it's all number okay the same
thing i x
yeah now the third way we can divide it
by 10 remember we can divide it by 10
and
look how do we check this how many
digits are there how many digits
how do how do we ask computers do it
computers don't have eyes don't come
look at it
we humans have eyes
how can we see where your mouth is going
to
so how do we we can ask computer to lead
how to
calculate how to get the length right we
can ask him to remove the last digit
look 10. yeah that's the second message
i have october start the measure remove
four
becomes one two three i have one digit
remove three
another digit
remove two
another digit remove one another digit
okay so how do we make sure and how do
we
make from
one two three four to one to three
how do we
moderate give you the last digit
divided by ten right
divided by 10 is the
modulus 10 is the largest look
one two three four modulus and
how many remains you divide it by ten
and then remainder right three
okay
yeah okay in python there's a method
called divide mode okay that's exactly
the difference
timer one two three four ten so what
does it give us it will give us two
values of couple right the first thing
is the is the
how do you say this the integer part of
between how do you say this
one two three four divided by ten what's
the integer power
123. yeah 100 what do you call this
equation
and then 10
and multiply 10 10 is 4 right so you
return two values okay
yeah so look
we we want this the cone how do you
spell it
okay so we want to continue okay
thank you for teaching me other thank
you
and this is called remainder right
yeah this is called remember 10 is
called
no no four is called remainder okay
divided by 10
kunshin yeah
uh so look so we can do this wire
while again we need to check especially
check if n is zero yeah if n is zero
return one okay and a y and bigger than
zero
and we have a digit t equals zero and
what should we do and divide it by equal
ten yeah we get an n divided by ten the
integer bar and then d plus equals one
and we can
return this digit that digit needs to be
even number all number yeah
okay
make sense
which method do you like the best which
method do you think is the most
efficient one
there's no right or wrong answer which
means which measure do you like the best
intent
your loved time you know that's
mathematics method and
this is the iterative thing
the first lesson remember converting to
string it's most intuitive way yeah we
just convert an integer to the string
and then we can get the length using the
length function to get the length right
which message do you like
in australia
you like
land equally yeah okay that's fine okay
good job today bye-bye