go
hello mr are you all right
mr ryan are you right yeah okay so we
have talked about uh
we talked about the link list before how
about let's say we have a link list one
three
five
seven okay and that's it
and if the first note has the index like
an array
okay and then this is index one and
that's two index three
given
how about let's say we want to insert a
new node
nine
just right before the index two so index
two is this node number five we want to
insert the new node
between the number five between uh
before the number five okay so it will
become like this yeah so one three
nine this is the new note yeah this is a
new note
uh
five
seven okay
yeah
makes sense
so this this note okay can i have your
attention please this now is the
inserted neuron
and how about look i have a noun here
and i
can you draw a link list with the number
two insert and the zero index zero
before index zero yeah perfect okay so
because look at this because this is a
very special case why is that because we
are returning the note the inserted note
as a new head
make sense
this head is not changing but this this
has been changing yeah we are inserting
a new note which becomes the head of the
linkage right
he is he's the leader yeah yeah okay so
look if i want to have a put look this
isn't english uh this is a node yeah one
points to two if i want to put a new
node three
right between these ones two
what do you think
what's the steps
if there are three two nodes one point
two two and i want to be inside that no
three okay
so you pretend to present this guy is
great
yeah
and just you ain't
too bad okay that's one way that's one
way yeah but you don't know what
happened next right you have to yeah
that's one way but how about they're
fine i know how about it okay so you
so you just cut this yeah yeah cut it um
yeah but how how to cut it
oh yes
i'm just splitting it with no arrow yeah
yeah that's first step yeah and then you
put the three in the middle and then you
want it back okay you don't need to put
a three meter you just you you just do
this one and points to three and then
three points to two
make sense
yeah okay so that's one step so but
overall we need to do what
we need to do what overall
sorry
all right
i can twist my head
okay so
so because we are changing the head
right so we are not sure
yeah we are not sure if the new hat new
new value we inserted is going to be the
head come on listen to me
yeah what did you say he said they gave
me a new head yeah yeah okay so
okay so look
for the link please if we want to do it
we can have a dummy head dummy here what
does it mean so means
that which which is
we are not going to use it
yeah it's just a temporary note we are
creating everybody call it dummy okay
okay oh extra okay and then we pointed
to the neck to the head this is the head
yeah this is the head
okay
[Music]
but we also need to remember
remember the previous note which is this
one right this is the previous now right
so what should i do now i have a this
value value i i have this value
so how look this is the exactly the
situation once we insert the value
between these three the previous and
ahead
right
so
the first step is i previously had
previous.next equals the i need to save
this value first okay i need to save
this value
yeah
so previous previous value previous to
next equals value and the variable down
next
will be equals the head right yeah
makes sense
look so if so because look these
previous the next is this at this one
so i reassign to value so i basically
it's the same as cutting cutting these
and reassigning to value and values next
so in this way we are actually putting a
new value a note between these two now
make sense yeah make sense yes you sure
is here
okay so let's do it
let's do it
any questions
okay
defy
nope define uh
let's say insert
and we have a head
and we have a value
and a position no no no no yeah
so look
look if not if we are not we are not
giving anything empty we just return
this area return a new node no
no
no value right we don't care right we
don't care about the position because if
the if the original linked list is empty
we just return it right and then as i
said we have a dummy
equals note
and minus one minus one minus two it
doesn't matter yeah or zero
the second value will be the next yeah
so you actually you can say fatah me
equals note and feta me the next equals
head okay the second parameter is the
the next one okay so let's say we have
this note can english no
and then define
in it
itself
yeah yeah yeah can you can you listen to
me very oh and then
but do you understand
do you understand huh
yeah i'm going to close these okay i'm
not looking right you're not looking but
you're you're shouting
okay
so this is the
this is the definition of a linked list
now come on look at me long look at this
thing
yeah wow
any question for this one
okay so look the the first parameter is
the value the second parameter is the
pointer to the next number okay
so this one is the next node
and now
now we just need to find out the place
here so let's say previous equals
also equals damian by dummy
dummy
and now we can say 4
in range we want to find out where it is
yeah
so head
equals head
dot
next
high equal equal next and
and then we previous equals heavy and we
need to store the previous one
remember
yeah
and now we have to put we can we can
insert it here so we can say
previous
previous dot next equals
note now the value yeah we are inserting
this new node
right
yeah look this is previous
this is a head
there's a link and then we are inserting
as the value here
right
yeah so look three
previous the next equals no don't next
so that that will become here all right
so what's what's your idea
okay so i need to save this the previous
uh
same same this yeah so previous
previous dot next dot next
equal as head next one yeah
yeah previous so next is this one
and dot next is head
next okay and then we turn off return
what can you tell me
fat dummy
phenomenal retaining freedom or
photometer next
yeah
so
so totally okay so we are finding that
the places which is we are finding a
place which is this bit okay this bit
we repeat position time we actually we
walk position times and then with every
time before we walk to the next we
remember its previous equals hat right
so i when this ends when this loop ends
over here the previous is one note
before the head right
yeah so previously it was like that yeah
yeah look we want to insert
oh no
yeah the previous look so they're not
previous to next equals node value which
is this one
all right
and then previous the next the next
equals the head all right
all right so return certainly the next
right
constant time space or linear space are
we using any
what space are we using at this time
we're using a phantom let's see
a one a one yeah because that is
supposed to be oh fat dummy
okay
okay that's it for today good job let's
see bye bye