none of your business
hello mr eric are you all right
yeah
okay so we talked about sorting right
remember what's the time complexity of
sorting
[Music]
n is the number of elements yeah so
we talk about a quick sauce we have
quick sauce
and what's quick sauce and emergency
salt
yeah these two
are all both oh and okay on everything
but
in mind the quick thought
the worst case is d o n square right
another quick song right we have a
number we have a few numbers like three
two
five
four
seven one zero okay so we can pick
random we pick a random pivot right
remember if you in case you don't
remember pick one random view and you
pick a number
no no we pick the one pivot and then we
find out all the numbers we partition
the list by all the numbers smaller than
five
yeah smaller than five is what
three two one zero four right
this is uh one zero four let's smaller
than five a bigger than five is
seven so we construct it look we use the
p we we pick a random pick number as a
pivot and on the traditional list as two
parts one is the one the number smaller
than the pivot the other one is the y
number numbers they're bigger than the
pv and we keep recursively
sorting these quick sorting these right
yeah so let them become a problem why is
that if you because we're london in
picking this period if this preview is
not picked good enough then they'll
become a problem why is that look if the
number is already sorted like one two
three four five six seven eight look how
about if i pick quickly one but then
there's no such number that's smaller
than one right so i can
all i can do is that i have this pivot
and then everything bigger than that how
about then i recursively pick this pivot
right
and then again i only have
the numbers that bigger than the pivot
right
so we we're not making we are not making
the
best benefit of partitioning right so in
this case this is one square right
let's quickly stop how about multistock
much solid
the multi-store comes with the we know
how to merge to sort this yeah remember
do you still remember how to remodel
sorted it like one three five seven and
then this is the least another list is
two fours
two four six eight how do we merge these
two sorted
yeah so we compare the pointers yeah we
commit a value we have one is smaller
than two
so we pick the one here and then we move
the one to that right yeah two is
smaller than three pick a two
and move it yeah so we know we know this
o and time complexity to merge two
certificates so what we we can do for
this is that we we equally divide it
into two halves right
and then we divide it into half because
the result is too big and once then
becomes salted
i will merge it right
so this is on average if it's a worst
case
in the worst case much source is still
overnight right so in this case it's
better than quicksort but quick thought
if you if we generally we pick the
random period and that will give us a
very good uh you know
very good
burning time yeah on average in practice
okay so
this this is the most efficient log
salting algorithm okay most efficient
okay
and we are today we're going to talk
another thought which is not quite used
in practical but we can use it to
demonstrate how the sorting the simple
salting one of the simple salting
aggregates right
simple salting simple salting acrylic
what's simple
it's not complicated it's easy yeah yeah
yeah easy
so it's the time context okay i'll let
you figure out the time complexity okay
so how we do it we look
three we call it bubble sorting what's
bubble
uh
it's a round thing
so
where do you find the bubbles from
you find it
you just blow it
yeah but usually you know the diving
yeah driving yeah timing
timing yeah yeah look at this is that
this is the man yeah you jump yeah jump
here okay maybe
might be like that
okay
yeah and then once he's in in there
now he blows he starts blow and then the
bubbles where is the purpose going
going up
yeah exactly bubble okay so what does it
mean in salting right so we have numbers
right luckily look at this
three
we when we saw the numbers the by
default the
order is increasing yeah ascending order
right so it means the from the smallest
to the biggest so like three five two
one seven
six okay then that's zero okay let's see
we want to solve it yeah how how can we
start it so first of all
yeah
first of all the last
the last
few you know we started sorting and we
we arrange the sorting these numbers at
the end right so at the beginning
there's none salty right so about we do
it what else three and five
if three is bigger than five look if
current number is next is bigger than
the next number we swap it
yeah we're not swapping yeah
we do it sloping
[Music]
when this is bigger than the next one we
swap it do we swap it yeah yeah so we
sort it so let's become
two and become five
this one i always thought it started
stop it which is the next one uh yep
okay so
okay always open it
always open yes
are we stopping it yes
so do you see what i'm doing here
one cycle is so the last number would be
what
the largest yeah the last that is of the
unsalted list right
yeah so this is the largest when we do
the first month
we always swap it if the current number
is bigger than one it's like bubbling
yeah so what does it mean when it goes
to the end the largest number will be
the
the end at the end right yes uh
i don't really get
the largest number at the end so because
look if this is bigger look i have
another bigger number let's say
i have another bigger number 12 okay so
let's say 12 okay i know we're going to
slope it so at the end
12 must be go to the end why is that
look 3 bigger than 12 no right 12 bigger
than 1
so i swap it
bigger than five
yeah
that's a 5 12. you see
so the largest number will be always
move to the end
and six
you see so what does it mean
once goal goes to the left the largest
current largest number look we always
partitioning this the list into two
halves okay
we're going through the thing again
like this that's that's a very good
question i'm i'm now i'm talking about
this right look so this is the list yeah
finally there
look
when i partitioned it this is unsalted
and this is salted
at the beginning look
at the beginning this sauce is nothing
right but now when i do it i move this i
always move it start from here right i
move that and saute it to the to the
salted i go and i let these 12 become
the end right
so now 12 is the largest here right so
the next time i i don't come here again
so now next time the saltine will have
one element
and then i just have to
sort the an array with the one number
less
yeah
make sense
yeah okay so now next one look three
bigger than one or what we move it yeah
yes
one three three and five
nine five and six
six and zero yes
six and seven
night okay so now i don't i i don't swap
it i don't consider i stopped here right
because right now this 12 is already
sorted in the last one right
and number seven is the second largest
right it's the largest in these right so
and then i move here right so the
unsorted list will be here right one and
three
yes no i mean no three five
nine five zero okay
five six
no okay so six is the largest okay i'm
gonna move here all right so look do you
see this yeah
yeah this is serious how how this works
yeah so every time we bubbling with
purpling so the bubble the largest
number will be bubble to the end which
is the starting
ah
okay let me try the edge okay and then
you will understand
so this is the simple salting it's very
easy i mean just remember the bubbling
yeah we're always bubbling the largest
number to the end right
so define
proper
thought
with the numbers
first of all we need to get the element
of length of element yeah lens
numb
okay so for
i
in range
rejuva ng
for i imagine
but i am
so now i have to follow j
in
range
we only start from zero yeah
minus i
minus one okay i tell you what it is
so and then now i have to swap look if
noun
come on you can tell me
[Music]
j bigger than what's needs next
j j next
class
[Music]
a yeah so
j number three plus
here right
this is called the
topper top assignment yeah type of
assignment so we're swapping this
right and a little bit return on
linkedin number what's the consonant
[Music]
we want to go to the end round and round
and then look
these
and when i is zero right when i zero n
minus one we are not touching the n
minus one right this is going to j
j is here right j
so for each round
j will be start from zero right start
from zero two
to m minus i
okay remember we talked about
when we have one more round there will
be one more element which is included in
the sorted this is sort here right
so what i is including how many rounds
do we need to solve all the numbers and
one right
yeah we will we need the envelopes each
each one
each each one each each properly we
always find out the one largest number
in the unsorted and move it resolve it
makes sense
yeah
okay so we need n round okay so how
about look if the number is already
sorted one two three four five
can you swap any of these can you solve
any of these no
why why is that because they're already
salted
it's already salty it's already salted
look no matter how many rounds we need
so do we need to continue in this time
yeah if already if this list is already
sorted then we can
we can just break we can just exit here
so we can put it here swap
swap how do we know if it's already
sorted yeah look at swap equals false at
the beginning we set it to 4. but now we
once we stop it we study here swap
equals two right
whenever we find the element bigger than
the next one we swap equals two
right and then here and here we just say
if not swap
if not
okay
what does it mean so
here
yeah we're doing this one bubbling yeah
one buckling
but we are not swapping anything look
yeah we're not swapping anything
right we are not swapping anything right
because it's already stopping yeah you
can't find any animal bigger than the
next one right
right so we are not here we we haven't
executed here right because it comes
from any man bigger than the next one so
these loop will be doing for nothing
yeah so slobber will be equal so and if
not swap means that okay after this
round we find no elements can be swapped
then we just break yeah
huh make sense
yeah that's one optimization right
so okay
best cases
if the what's the time complexity if the
array is already sorted
what's the time complexity if the array
is already sorted
and square
already started come on
[Music]
nine
oh why is the low one come on look
here
how many rounds is it so it needs to do
this at least in time right yeah when i
is zero right
j needs to go to n times but then he
found out that swap is never
set to true
when you break so how many
come on why is that one in the worst
case it's always good in average cases
i'm saying
when the array is already sorted
one array is already sorted come on
okay follow me slow because false
okay so i need to repeat this end time
right yeah j three times yeah
but if we already sorted has this
variable being set to true
will it be set to two if it's if no
elements being swapped
okay so if not swap is true right
yeah
and then break so how many how many
iterations do i need to do
remember
i is equal to zero and i found all this
is not swap and then
i s
terminate the
loop
immediately what's the time frame let's
see if they already already sorted
one two three four five okay fourteen
and what's the tango minus three um oh
and exactly
okay okay and what's our one square your
own square is
on average right on average yeah
oh in the worst case if the array is
reverse sorted it means that five or
three to one
okay
yeah
okay so for example this is five two
five four three two one can you tell me
how the array will be sorted and that
will be that will be
five four three two one okay so what
happened next
okay
so
so i got this um
no no no i i just want you to to tell me
tell me what's the what's the next one
after five four three two one
okay so four swappings
yeah
okay you don't need to drop it you just
need to tell me where is it okay swap
here sophia and then swap here so you
put a fire here okay i know what's next
and then you just need to stop it yeah
yeah
i know where's the one one is here
okay and that was next
so
i need some more space all right
okay and now i'll stop
okay and then that's it and then one
more and a break okay good job we're
done
today bye bye bye