go
hello
hello mr mr ryan all right yeah
okay so yesterday we talked about the
bubble sorting which is a simple salt
right bubble saltine and we also talked
about
not non-simple sorting which is which
what kind of non-simple sorting we have
done in the past
the one with the oh and again yeah yeah
we're done
quick salt and another one
bubble sauce bubble sauce is a simple
saltine you know if there are numbers
and we have spread it and then
merge it together what do we call it
yeah i'm not salt
and with the bubble sauce
so let's say three two five
four
one okay so
when every time we start a round of
sorting we we swap the two numbers if
this number is bigger than the last one
right so look three and two three is
bigger than two so we swap it so we
actually when we perform this one longer
swapping we always move the largest
number to the to the end right so
basically we have a array we just divide
it into
two halves
the left sub array
that that sub array is the one which is
unsorted
yeah
and then the one on the right is sorted
so every time we do this bubble sorting
we move the one from the unsorted to the
salty one right make sense
okay so today we talked about another
sorting algorithm which is also simple
saudi arabia
which is called selection sort
selection sort
yeah what's selection selection
okay
selection sort
it means that okay so we have array like
three two five
four one seven right
okay so now
we if we divide this array into two sub
array the left one is the one which is
salted
and then the right
is the unsalted okay it's slightly
different
than the sim than the bubble soldering
bubble saltine is the opposite the left
is unsalted we bubble it out and move
the largest one to the end let's start
the inner third error
but the selection thought is the left
the left sub array is sorted the right
sub array this partition here is
inserted so look
so every time i pick from here which
number is the smallest
three to five for one second which one
which number is the smallest
one one then okay i said this one
right
and i swap it with these and here right
so what happens so this becomes three
this becomes one
all right
all right and now
in philosophy we have one element let's
move to here from two to seven which is
the smallest
which one is the smallest two okay then
two swap it with itself right
okay so then i need to move another one
to left five four
three seven which one is the smallest
uh three so what should we do with the
three put it
um
and
move it with a five yeah sloppy is five
so not five
three yeah and then now we i we have one
more element with the inner sorted so i
move it here so four five seven which is
the smallest four so what do we do with
the four
leave it
we stop with itself so it it doesn't
move okay and then five and seven okay
five is the smallest you get it
might make sense let's do another
example okay so you know i understand
this is very easy simple sorting
evidence is very very easy right looks
bubble solving right look right right
bubble sorting yeah you blow a purple
and the bigger bubble will be moving to
the end right
so
so we have a raise so the right hand
side then this part the right yeah is
the one already salted with the bubbles
of him
yeah you always pop it up
bubble up
bubble up largest element and bubble it
up yeah swap him but the ways the
selection thought is the opposite uh the
the area yeah this is this is sorted
and then here is unsorted yeah
so every time we perform a selection so
we have one more element
right select it from the unsorted area
so we have increased the sorted sub
array with one element and we have
decremented
let's unsorted sub array with one
element less
make sense
okay let's do one more example
five four
seven six two one
so what should we do
okay so now with five
[Music]
yeah
and uh
five swap with
six six yeah okay
six wow you got it pretty quickly yeah
let's the the that's it yeah that's the
egg one let's write it
and you need to think about
what's the kind complex pi
you need to think about the time
conversion
define let's call it selection sort
numbers
so now we want to call this n equal the
number of elements nums
right
so now i need to go through this for
i
in
range
n right
right and then i
for the and for now the mean index let's
say the mean index is i mean
index
is i and then i need to go through for j
in range
i plus 1 to n
if
numbers
j
yeah look this is index number j smaller
than nums
mean index yeah mean index
then i need to do what i need to
remember it
so now mean index
will be equal to z okay and then all
right
and then now at this one i just need to
swap the mean index with what with i
right because i want to put it in the i
right
so how do we swap two value a and b
how do we swap two values a and b
a b equals b a uh yes a b or we can use
another
variable t right t equals a a equals b b
equals t this is also okay
okay so now i need to swap the index at
mean index and i
okay
so what
number
j i want to sort the numbers i uh numbs
i
with nouns
i mean index right
and then i just swapped it
yeah
look it's so easy why
do you get it this one
yeah look
for i need to look for every round every
month i
i select i i choose the mean index right
so if look the mean index
will be i i want to swap the uh
i want to swap the minimum element right
smaller smaller list smallest element i
pick i choose the smallest element i
swap with i index
the the the index
ice element right the element i
so for j equals range so look that's
maybe it's easier then let's look at
these numbers it will be easier
uh one okay look at the beginning i is
here right look i is here
so j
i is here and then at the beginning the
mean index i set it to
to i right i'm not sure because because
i'm i'm looking i'm looking at from i to
this range picking the smallest so which
is
one right j in range i so j will be here
to the range i and pick the smallest
element which is one
right look and i swap this element with
the one and uh
and uh i right so because mean index
will be this one
my mini index will be pointing to the i
right so i swap it
if num j
smaller than nums mean index
at the beginning we are setting the mean
index to the i
and then we use the
the elements on the right compared to
itself okay if it's smaller then i
update the mean index
and if i go to the run what's the mean
index
what's the b index
yellow one two three four add me index
will be four and then
here i will just swap with four nums
slams i and nums mean index i'll just
swap these two variables okay
well
what's the time complexity look what's
the term number against
it all right what's the time complexity
n square where down square because we
have a for loop we have another for loop
okay
so
remember we stood backwards sorting we
can use the variable swap if if no two
elements right if the array is already
sorted then we don't swap we don't
continue right so in the best cases
when the array is already sorted the
bubble sorting if the time condenses oh
when right we know that
we talked about it yesterday but for
this one this is always o n square right
because there's no such thing to check
if it's already if array is already
sorted
it's still
the time complexity is still o and
square am right
yeah i'm going to check it again because
they they look if array is already
sorted you still need to perform this
right there's no such thing as checking
right if the array is sorted and no swap
but the good thing about this around uh
aggregate about the selection thought is
that
how many how many swabs does it perform
how many swabs
does it perform and whether that's a
good catch
no matter how complicated is the
array it always performs at most okay
and swap but for the purpose sorting
you know you never know right yo it's so
soft that would be n square yeah in the
worst cases look in the worst cases four
three two
uh yeah how many swap look
one swap two swap three slot four flop
and you put it at the end right and then
again one
two three four yeah
yeah
all right
so you perform a lot more swaps than
here but for this one we always have
this
answer but for the purpose of thing
the slope could be o n
square right it's actually n times m
minus one divided by two or whatever
yeah
but followers
let's let's do this
let's do this direction so
five four three two one okay so how many
soap do we have look
we always pick them
right we pick the smallest which is one
right
yeah
we swap it
one swap okay i hope everyone's one okay
which is the smallest
two two i swap it
three
okay
three i don't stop four i don't love
yeah friday i don't swap okay so look
at most two swaps okay
almost too slow
oh no no now we're doing too slow but
but look
this one you can say it's exactly o and
swap why is that because if i equals
mean index you swap an element with
excel does it count the slope
if you call this slope
it's a n swap if you don't count this up
like this right you always look i'm here
i'm picking the small air demand which
is three
i swap the switch with itself
does that color swap no
okay no
yeah but yeah maybe sometimes look
because
both are okay yeah if you count it as 12
that's okay because what look
this still gets executed if i equals
mean index right so it's work with
itself but if you count it as no slot
then we have to to release look at if
i not equals the mean index
right
then
we can
avoid
swapping excel okay so the time the
number of swaps at most is o n is n
slope right that's the advantage of the
selection thought
because they will be no more than n
swaps
but for the bubble sorting
these could be in the scale of o and
square right because the swapping would
be a lot more
every time you do the bubbling you
always always
14 minutes you always put
only move one element you don't change
the order of others so
so you will keep swapping swapping the
swapping will be more than the selection
saw
but what's the advantage of uh
what's the advantage of the bubble
sorting compared to selection salt
uh bubble sorting is technically the
opposite of
selecting saw is putting the minimum on
the front but
also
the
biggest number of
bags we're done and
when
in what cases
when the array is worth then the bubble
slotting is better it's quicker
when the away is already
yeah when the array is already sorted
the improved bubble sorting you know the
first one checks
there's no more swapping so yeah i think
the array is already sorted then i quit
so like that would be just o n
right
but the selection source still needs to
perform these you know two loops or one
square
but in what cases
look
if the swapping is very expensive
okay look if the sloping if you swap in
two elements is very expensive
then which which aggregate is better
selection saw or
bubble serving
good job bye
[Music]