hello mr all right yes
okay so uh
we talked about
quick thought yeah
quick start we talked about multi-source
before yeah
and we talked about the bubble sorting
and yesterday we talked about what
selection saw right
yeah
okay
so these two are simple sorting
algorithms simple simple means they are
easy to implement right but on average
their time complexities are an old and
square
graduated these two are the most
efficient sorting algorithm on average
the running times oven log n right yeah
so let's
let's what we have if we call the
array.function okay
bubble sorting selection saw okay so now
let's just do a quick review of probably
you know what kind of uh how does this
algorithm work okay so for example we
have quick sort yeah we let's say five
four
seven six one two quick so we randomly
pick a number as a pivot yeah as a pivot
and then we try to put
all the elements smaller than the pivot
yeah in the left and that's the pivot
yeah could be many right and then all
the elements they're bigger than pivot
on the right and then we recursively saw
that left and right right
but in the worst case if the array is
already sorted four three five four
three reverse thought here
and then every time you pick the first
one what happened so in this case you
you you don't partici uh partition into
two you always have all the elements on
the right hand side so in this case
uh what happened the time complexity
will be
downgraded to o n square okay period
multi thought yeah we know how to merge
two sorted lists so the idea is to
divide the list
divide the array
into two halves equally to half and i
will cursive we saw the left part and so
the right part and then we merge it yeah
the time come next on everything again
and worst case best case worst case
uh average case for
it is all in login okay
bubble sorting
every time we bubble out the biggest
number to the end right for example like
five four three two one so what's what
happened after one one of the problem
solving
four three two one five yeah so every
time you swap if it's bigger than the
next one right so that becomes four or
five
and then
and then five keep continuing to swap it
so piece of it so four three two one
right
so proper slotting the best case is we
can improve it if we can add a check if
the sorting if there's no swap then we
can terminate the loop right so that in
the best case is the time complexity o n
for the improved proper sorting in the
worst case
uh average case is o n square
right uh selection sort so five four
three two one how what's the selection
uh putting the smallest number at the
front
so it is
okay so every time we pick them
we swap the minimum value to the front
right so on the left hand side is sorted
on the right hand the right sub array is
unsorted every time we pick the smallest
element from the
unsalted and we swap
swap it to the front right to the front
of the unsorted right that's the
selection so
okay so today we're going to talk about
another sorting agreement which is
called what
uh
okay one more thing before i forgot is
selection thought the
the
the advantage of selection thought is
that we can
uh the number of swaps no
right is no more than n right if am
right because if if if the swapping is
quite expensive then we can choose the
selection so because butter sorting
could be
right it's always swapping soaking if
this operation is very expensive that
might not be
very good right all right
so that it has different advantage okay
and then we have we talked about today
we're going to talk about another simple
sorting algorithm okay
simple sorting simple means easy to
implement easy to understand right
it's called insertion thought
okay so
what does it mean look if
if we have five
four
three two one okay like that okay so how
do we select how do we sort it
so at the beginning we are here
and then we find
we want to we want to put this number
right
so
so at the beginning we have one one
element which is sorted
yeah
all right and we start with the second
element how do we put the four into the
into the front right we want to insert
this value to the front
to to the sorted right so it's four five
right
four five
now
i only put a three
i want to put a three in what cases
three at the very front yeah yeah okay
so how do we do do it look every time we
pick this number and we want to swap it
we want to insert it okay this is called
insert insert in the front of the lid
but how can we do it look three so when
these three is smaller than five right
when three is so smaller than five
so first of all we take the number t
equals three we remember it right
we remember it and then we move it we
shift it like look we shift it
so what happens is that i five i put it
here
four i put it here okay and then i have
a space for three so i put a three here
okay another one two
two two here so i key equals two right p
equals two
so now
two is here so i want to put it in the
front i want to insert it in the right
place of the fifth four five right it
could be in the middle but in this case
it's in front
so so what should i do look
so remember i already take the value to
here so
i move it all right look that's the
magic yeah
move the fire here
all right and i move the four here
i move the three here so and then i
change d here to two make sense
yeah
does it make sense
okay can i i want to give another more
example okay how about one here i put a
one now i want to put the one in
the list of these
whatever very front yeah yeah but but
all the other elements will be shifted
one position to the right right yeah
okay so how do we insert it how do we
enter we take we remember we want to we
know
we know
the current element is one we want to
put put a one in the front
so like look
one is smaller than five right
yeah one is smaller than five so what do
we do so this value this value this
value next value would be y one
will be copied over the value will be
five
and a copy over four yes so basically
you move it you move all these elements
one position to the right
okay now here
so this is the right place because it's
at the beginning right so i put one here
make sense
yeah
okay then let's try another example okay
just to make sure you totally understand
this
insertion so okay which is let's say
yellow
one
three five
four okay let's say
now
i'm here i want to put the four
four
people over five yeah
maybe put a two here i only put two okay
so it's in the middle right yeah but how
look
how i compared to this
this is smaller than that right
so i need to push these five to the
right right
yeah so it's pushing
five to the right i can just write this
value as five right and now here and
then i need to here two
all right two is smaller than three so i
push three on the right so yeah
yeah yeah
two is
is
is bigger than one right
so in this case what happened i don't
don't shift it
so i just need to
change this value to 2.
yeah
make sense
does it make sense
okay so let's go get to the code okay
and tell me
define
insertion
sort and now we have let's call it a
what do i miss
not even looking
so and equals length a
so let's say
let's say
we need to go through the array first
therefore i in red let's start with the
second value we have 1 to n
look
so
this is our way array a yeah a it was
away
to
5.
so i
start here yeah because at the beginning
we we have
we have already one
list
one sorted
one so the sorting this is less one
right we want to put the element in that
so now i need to remember what value is
it key equals the a
a
i right so key is this very uh
key
key is the
uh
actually the let me think about it it is
each key is a i right yeah key is a yeah
exactly
so now
j let's say j equals i
plus 1
y j equals y plus one j is here uh
j is here
so y j
uh actually j is
i minus one what j
y j bigger equals zero right
and
the key is smaller than
as long as the key
it keeps this value key is this value is
smaller than this value
yeah a j
now what do we do we need to set this
value
j plus one
a j plus one will be equals aj let's
let's we shifted it and then j minus
equals one
and at the end we need to set uh
a
j right we want to set this value aj
equals key am i
make sense
so
uh
there might be a problem if a actually
is a j plus one okay let me just double
check because this is this aggregate
it's not so easy to make it right at the
beginning we have to check the boundary
et cetera right
uh let's stop the chat
so if you're looking this this what's
the tongue complexity if you look at
these
i think it's
[Music]
is it right j uh smaller than aj aj plus
one equals aj j minus equal one
aj yeah the next value needs to be set
to the key
okay yeah i think i got a good idea
let's just
just run this okay let's just run this
and then
and we can correct the mistake if we
have
uh
one three five seven
uh let's say one three
seven
five
two okay yeah
n will be equals to what
one two three four five five why
yeah
i
will be from one to n right so i will be
in this event at the beginning will be
here right
j will be i minus one so j is here okay
j is here why
y j is bigger than zero
right j
is bigger than zero or bigger than zero
y j is bigger or equal than zero right
yeah and key key will be equals to ai q
will be three
key will be three at the beginning
so key
three is smaller than aj
is not right
no okay so look then this loop this
while loop is not
will not be executed and then the next
will be aj plus one
aj plus one will be this one equals key
so it basically set it to three
yeah
okay now move to the next one what's
what's n
here the number of the elements okay
maybe maybe this is not a very good
example here because this is already
know that so look
if it's in order this does nothing if
it's this in order if it's one two three
four five so what happened what's the
best cases this is already sorted so
look
if this is in order so can you tell me
do we go in here somehow if it's already
in order
yeah because j aj j is i minus one so we
always checking the previous value
yeah
if the previous value is bigger than the
key right it never it's never true right
array
yeah for assorted array
key is
always bigger key key is this very well
key is this value
and we are starting checking the
previous one key is always the
bigger than the previous value
right so these key keys smaller than
previous value never true is never true
so these y loop never gets x cubed
so what does it mean we all in the best
cases what is time complexity
oh and yeah it's like the bubble sorting
here bubble sorting we have
we have added a check if there are no
elements are being swapped in this round
it means that the array is already
sorted then we can terminate right
but here if it's already array is
already sorted then this while loop
never gets executed and then if the best
cases is o n right and in the worst
cases look five four three two one right
so look
so four
is right is smaller than five so i need
to so basically i need to squeeze the
previous element for the space to put in
the form do you get it
okay so
so look for example look here i'm right
here five right
all right
five
so look um this is already sorted right
here one three seconds sorry it says
nothing
so now for i want to squeeze
check the previous one squeeze if it's
smaller
so look five i miss this guy okay says
okay i'm smaller than you
you need to make space for me
so he will squeeze this seven to the
right
yeah
okay yeah
all right
okay two
smaller than seven yeah and then say
okay squeeze more space for me
two to the five
still smaller
so it's like you're waiting in the line
and then you're always checking okay
smaller than five okay please don't go
behind me because i'm smaller than you
yeah
so check the previous guy
it's still smaller right
okay make space for me
okay
yeah but but it's not doing one by one
it's doing all at once okay so let's do
so it's it's
it's not
look
two here so you check
okay
smaller
go to the right five
i am still smaller i'm still in the
front
three
yeah i'm i'm not in front of three two
no right it's okay i'm position i'm here
okay so for all other elements
so needs to be one position to the right
right so these three needs to
move one position to the right and then
you put a two here
like this that's what it does look aj
plus one equals aj
all right aj plus one equals aj what
does it mean so
look phi seven aj plus one equals aj
so what happened okay happen over here
if j is here so what happened up what
happened after this aj plus one equals
aj
what will be
happening
what will happen
it's okay c is here so five seven aj
plus one equals aj so what happened
after this
a j plus one is this one equals aj that
means that's what this is no no it's not
sloping i just this one a j plus one
equals aj what's happening
aj aj plus one equals aj
aj plus on equals aj so what happened
they're squeezing these two changes to
five five another two five and then
and then here aj plus one equals key so
the so because j will minus one i so j
will be here aj my plus one is here
equals key that would be whatever okay
right now okay so that's what in the
best cases is o n okay
okay i want to talk about another
another concept which is called stable
you're not stable
stable what does it mean
stable
what's the word in in english
what's not stable
not balanced
okay balance yeah yeah balance okay in
sorting aggregate stable means that look
if i have two value two two
two two and right so if these two okay
so this screen two if i i have these
so after sorting it like that will be
three two two four after sorting
yeah
after sorting if this green two is still
on the right of the black uh black tube
right
it's called stable
yeah because they are the same you
basically you can swap it and it's still
salty right
all right
yeah but for some egg run this would be
become two two
right
two two three four maybe yeah or another
kind of anger is what is two
two three four
so can you tell me which which which
sort of result is sort of stable which
one is not
which one is stable
which one is not
so the original array is three two two
four and then one sorted array is two
two three four the other one is two two
three four the only difference is these
two
left
why
okay yeah that's a good question no okay
so which one is salted which one is
stable
this one
this one yeah this one is solid stable
because the original uh order is the
green two comes after two
and this one the green two comes before
then actually you are
you are not maintaining the order of the
similar of the
equivalent elements am right make sense
yeah
okay so
the bubble sorting is stable right so
because every time you take a round to
buffer sorting the same angle as some
numbers so it's all uh is stable the ins
insertion salt is stable
the
what
the quick thought is not the much salt
is stable
the selection salt is not stable okay
i'll tell you why it's next install is
not stable okay
three
two
uh
um
three
four okay
yeah uh
okay maybe this is not a good example
let's say
so how does the selection so well you
always swap it right you always stop it
you always sloppy uh
so this is three this is three
so let's say this is two okay so and the
first one and the first one okay let's
let's make these three
and the first one you pick the smallest
index which is two
and then you swap it with three ah okay
so that's four okay two
yeah
okay all right look
selection so what happened
what selections are what element do you
pick which one is the smallest
okay so what happened what should i do
with two swap it with three right
yeah
so once you swap it what happens it'll
be two
four
three
three this is the problem this green
three is after
black three but now why do you need to
swap two with a green screen yo the
selection saw look
yesterday we talked about selections all
right what's the next song you pick the
minimum right
and you swap it right
so sorting with the
with the the beginning of the
unsalted list all right
yeah remember
let's let's hold the selection so what
yeah in terms of today is this freezing
yeah the bubble sorting is you know
every time swapping with the next one
right okay so let that's not stable okay
because look after one round of sorting
swapping the
the green three is now becomes in the
front of the black three that's not
stable right
right
make sense
okay so let's just release the taper for
these three sorting and a little bit
okay
what do we have
bubble sorting
and yesterday we talked about selection
soft
today we talked about insertions all
right
and
at the beginning last year we talked
about quick thought
yeah
and then merge sorry this is the five
sorting again we have learned so far
right yeah
all right
okay let's say the best case best case
time complexity
average time contact speed
worst case complexity
space complexity
and is it stable okay let's just
consider this okay
yeah
bubble sorting best case is o
n yeah average o n square
was one square
space o one
stable
yes selection sorry yesterday best case
is o n square yeah it doesn't average o
n square
was o n square space of one
is it stable
what no yeah remember that thing yeah
it's insane so today best cases
average average is also owens you know
this is simple sorting that everything
was is the same it's o n square okay
space or one
insertion saw is uh stable okay
quick sauce best case is
quick saw remember we picked brandon
choose the pivot and then we put the
elements before it smaller on the left
bigger on the right and we recursively
saw the both part
or what's the terminal recipe for the
salting you know it's me
why not
remember if it's the reverse yeah if
it's five four three two one and every
time you pick the pivot as the first
element and then
you are not making use of these fed they
partition into two halves or in square
space
uh worst case o and stable no
magistrate or when again
average or when logan yeah
worst case owen again
space oh and worst case is this stable
yes
okay so let's see
any questions what were you join do you
think it's better if
you you like the best
you have different advantages in this
advantage right
yeah
i like merge
because the it's quite safe it's stable
and it offers quite consistent
performance in the best every general
world right
yeah
and all these that have different right
look and this one is consistently o and
square which is very slow in 15 okay and
it's not stable so yeah i agree with you
much salt and it's very easy to
understand yeah much soft i have a
hundred and numbers to sort first of all
i cut into half
fifty fifty right
so i i don't care how you sort these 50
numbers each but once you have these 50
numbers we we know how to merge it right
much to sorting this do you still
remember
i don't put it together and for the 50
numbers we can keep dividing it
right into two halves we what how much
for each
for 50 numbers
we have 25 and 12 and keep dividing and
then we we top down and until we get one
element it's already sorted and now
we're starting to merge it back yeah one
element one limit we know how to merge
right
so we have two elements now and two
elements two and you know we know how to
merge
four elements four
got animals
you see this how beautiful is this
sorting angle right you know there are
quite a lot of knowledge about this
sorting agreement and then there are a
few more but
which which bits are simple sorting like
one two three these two are simple
sorting
why is that because the average is
always square
it's easy to implement right it's
usually two two four loop right
yeah
but for the quick solid multi so it's
it's usually complicated
right you have to write more a lot more
code using this
but you know the modern computer if you
use the a array that's all it's usually
based on quicksort
it's a mixed sorting agreement quicksort
and sometimes merge thought yeah these
three aggregates
yeah it's use use just useful to teach
you
how the algorithm works okay because
look if the number if there are million
numbers this is too slow a million times
a million it's crucial right
got it yeah okay that's it for today
good job bye bye bye bye bye