[Music]
hello teacher hello teacher hello
so tell me what what is binary two
two okay so in particular what
what's two a number
so what's decimal you know the decimal
yeah decimal
it only has a point uh yeah that's one
meaning the other meaning is the blunder
we're using like one two three four
five six eight nine ten right how many
digits are there
one two how many digits how many types
of digits
from zero to nine
nine ten yeah we got zero zero one two
yeah so zero one
this one the numbers were daily used
yeah we used daily uh
based on these right like uh 23
34 yeah yeah yeah is it
how many there are 10 digits yeah we
call it base 10
base 10 and also this is the one decimal
yes decimal
decimal yeah so we are using this
specimen this is uh
yeah yeah yeah this is also called
arabic yeah arabic
arabic numbers did you say eric
no arabic yeah
yeah yeah this is the number system that
everybody in the world in the global
globe
knows yeah if you go to china if you go
to united states
everybody knows this kind of number it's
international if you go to africa if you
go to
uh somewhere europe or you know maybe
europe
yeah so this is the number system every
people on the world knows
yeah it's international even africa
yeah yeah yeah so look africa
look let's talk about a little bit about
the number system we're using so
look at this one two three okay what
does it equal
no no no this is one hundred and twenty
three yeah
this is 100 yeah yeah this is tens
yeah and this is once all right so these
equals to one times a hundred
plus two times ten plus three times one
right
yes so look this is 100 is 10 to the
power of 2 right
yeah this is 10 to the power 1 right
this is 10 to the power of zero right
yeah got it yeah okay so now i take
10 to the power of 3. the next one is 10
to the power 3 4 here then it'll be
4 times 10 to the power of 3 yeah so 4
1 120
okay okay okay so now
it's the same the binary numbers how
many numbers are we how many digits are
we using
g two yes two because the decimal is ten
now we only two so what kind of digits
are we using
binary zero and one yeah we only have
two
possibilities zero and one yeah yeah so
why is why why this binaries
the computers are are very uh good at
binaries
because we made a computer in such a way
that binaries are fundamental
because look computers are made of chips
yeah
not wonderful
so the chips so if you power on yeah
power on the next one if you power off
that's zero yeah
if you have a low power that's zero if
you have a high power
voltage yeah what is this one so it's
very computer is very good at this kind
of thing yeah
so the binary let's call it now we have
only one
zero one so so for example
uh if we uh look this is decimal the
specimen of the the numbers we're using
december yeah that's the final yeah okay
so look let's
zero one two three four
five let's check that a binary what's
this
one no binary yellow and then okay
yeah and two because we don't have two
we only have zero one
we 9 and what's this 10 10 yeah
because we run out of digits so we we we
go back to the zero and but we we
carry over right
well yes exactly okay so now what's next
three
eleven no okay seven what's next
twelve thirty one twenty
two there's no two oh yeah so what
what's the look what's this
look 99 you carry over
you curl it over 100 yeah so what's this
here
100. you put one it's carrying over
100 you see you see this and then there
was
101 one one ten one one
one and then one thousand you see so
these are corresponding to each other
yeah
one zero one one zero one
one one one okay that's it no more you
see
so look it's it's similar look
this is one but that is to be equal to
one to
times two to the power of three okay
you got it this one one so one one is
one to the power of two
plus one to the power of one plus one to
the power of zero
so that's what four plus two plus one
so it's seven you see is it
so this is corresponding to each other
so how about this
four is one to the power of two you just
count how many digits
on the right right and one and one
okay so so now let's write a program to
convert these
into decimals if i tell you a number
like one one one one
tell me what's this what's this in
decimal one
thousand one hundred and eleven
so look this is this is what
one thousand two to the power of one two
three yeah
this is two to
[Applause]
sorry because it's binary it's like
if sesame is ten right yeah okay if it's
specimen you'll be one ten to the power
3 plus
10 to the power of 2 plus 10 to the
power 1 plus 10 to the power 0. so
that's what a thousand
a hundred ten one so it's a thousand
a hundred eleven yeah you see
yeah that's how we got intestinal but we
are now talking about binary so it's two
right base two eight plus
four four plus two and one
so that's what that is
15 15.
okay so let's write a number and write a
program so let's
let's do this define the five binary two
decimal
right b
[Music]
column okay so now we got the answer
yeah we're up with the ones
then we look in the video so for
i
why are we using b for binary
look we can move this value so look look
we don't is one zero one one zero okay
this is binary right
first of all we got this one right so we
need to come
times itself by two first and plus this
one value so we call it uh we
convert it to uh integer
okay and then that's it and then return
answer that's it
that quick yes
yeah yeah yeah bye-bye oh yeah yeah
so look listen
now we are here yeah so now the value is
one right five
and then if i move here the value will
be one
times two that would be two yeah two
plus zero
yeah because look at 110 is two right
and then if i move here is two times two
equals four
this one plus one is five right
plus one that's five and then if i move
again
now five times two equals ten you see so
that's two
that's eight times eight plus two that's
ten
yeah so every time look if it is the
decimal if it is rotation
one two three yeah if i put a zero at
the end
it's the least value times 10 right my
yeah so i i put this value shift the
value to one position to the left and i
put a zero here and
this entire value is times ten it's the
same here
this entire value is times two if i move
i put something on
only right over zero but it could be one
and i put a
then this is the thing is i move one
position to the left and plus the least
current digit
and this is the final value yeah got it
okay how about the other way from
decimal to the finale
so let's take a look at the decimal how
we get it okay
look one two three how can we get this
number one percent
[Music]
you're making me noise busy okay look at
one two three divided by
ten let's divide it by ten that's easy
remaining three okay and then 12 divided
by 10
one remaining two right yeah divided by
ten
zero remaining one yeah once it's zero
now look we have one two three we get a
very one
so we'll write it this way one two three
yeah yeah
the same as fifteen the the same as
fifteen
fifteen in binary one one one one okay
yeah
yeah so 111
two divided by two is seven
remaining one right yeah but divided by
two
three remaining one all right
dividing by two one remaining one right
dividing by two zero remaining one so
what's the answer
uh one more one yes you see ryan
got this okay look at it okay so can you
tell me what's the 14 in binary and
that's it
fourteen finally finally equals one
right here
[Music]
one two three four
how about okay so that's one one
one zero what's this impact in decimal
what equals what in decimal and then the
other way
is 14 in decimal equals
how many in binary okay so this can you
do it one is
can you pick one and do it
can you guess is that binary
no no just listen
14 in decimal is how many in binary is
only one and zero remember yeah
remember what did i just tell you that
uh
one ten ten in binary equals
so we need to divide fourteen yeah by
ten
yeah yeah that's one remaining
four no no not divided by
ten divided by two right remember we are
converting to the binary
seven remaining one
okay then seven divided by two
three remaining one and divided by two
uh one remaining one divided by two
do i remain
december uh december decimal it was one
one one zero
two base oh sorry one one zero
binary equals one fourteen yes see
these two numbers are equal you see and
how can we get at least
this 2 to the power 3 plus 2 to the
power of 2
plus 2 to the power of 1 okay plus 0.
so what's this 8 plus 4
i mean yeah 2 and one so that's what
uh
yeah yeah yeah let's see so do you get
it this finally okay
five five five five bye bye bye
[Music]
i'm a happy new year