hello me saying mr roy how are you good
okay
okay so how many saltine ingredients
have we talked about so far vegetable
insertion salt bubble sauce quick
selection salt
quick salt baba
quick
that's it yeah so which three has this
uh
average o and
square com complexity controller
um
this one this one is oh and logan
remember oh yeah wait
wait this bubble
yeah yeah yeah this three and this is
the oven again okay
and for the quick saw the worst case is
on square okay and in the best case it's
the bubble saltine with om yeah
and also the
insertion saw this is oven
and the average this is our n square
but for the selection yeah for the
selection song
the number of swaps is no more than n
right yeah
okay
so
um so today we are going to talk about
another sorting diagram which is not
like channel this is generous
means that we can sort anything right
it's just giving me the numbers the
elements the strings whatever because
these resorting agreements are based on
comparison right yeah what's comparison
you compare all right follow for example
bubble sorting we want to compare
the current
number to our element to the next one
and then we want to swap it if the
current number is bigger than the not
letter so that's comparison yeah we have
this comparison quick saw yeah you know
you need to find out the numbers which
is smaller than the pivot bigger than
the pivot that's that's kind of
comparison in search and sort yeah you
want to insert the current element
to a place where it belongs to so you
need to compare the numbers along the
way yeah backwards selection thought you
select the number
which is
slightly smallest number right in the
unsorted area and then you swap it to
the front right let's selections off
emergency thought
yeah we want to compare we want to
divide the
array into two and then we
sort both parts and then
we can merge it yeah we know how to
merge two sorted array right yeah
okay so
selection thought um
so any questions so far
any questions no
okay
okay so what's the difference between
insertion size sections these two are
sometimes quite
confusing to each other right it's not
easy to remember right
yeah
okay so i i try to explain one more time
okay insertions of let's say
five four three two one so we are here
we want to insert these to the front so
let's become four five three two one and
selection thought is that i want to find
the minimum
which is one and i swap it with the five
so it becomes one four three to five
right
yeah
okay
so
which which one has the best cases or
when i i think i mentioned it but i'm
not quite sure you get it which one has
the
[Music]
why is that because every time
if it's already sauteed one two three
four five every time
you are not swapping there's no sloping
laser in the white loop right it's
always in order remember we we have this
y
uh j bigger than equal and zero okay
let's for i in range
range one to n right and then a key
would be equals the numbers i
and y j j will be equals i minus one
right why j bigger than zero and the key
is smaller than
yeah it's a key smaller than the num
straight and j minus equals one uh
uh nums i love j equals num j plus one
right about number j plus one equals num
j
all right num num j
num j plus one equals num j yes okay so
if it's already in order these while
loop will never get executed okay so
that would be o and in the best cases
okay
okay let's a little bit review
now let's talk about scouting so which
is not general sorting counting so
what's counting what's car
counter counting song yeah yeah we're
going to use the counter today so what's
counting
how do you do how do we count
by just counting okay like it's three
five
two one ten
okay so if i tell you that i have an
array like nothing left has the this
range right look so let's say we have
another two here
one here okay so what's the order after
this
it is
1 2 2
five ten yeah yeah but how can we do
this look if we know
what's the minimum of this array one
right
the mean is one what's the maximum
ten
right
right all right okay so easy look this
is the magic
so we have a ten bucket
now we have ten buckets
at the bucket this is for one
this is for two
this is for three
this is for four
okay
five
okay and then i have another six
seven
eight
nine
ten okay
so i have ten buckets
one
we can use the counter actually right
like one how many ones do we have one
two one two so i put two here how many
twos do we have two
how many threes would they have one how
many fours zero number one five
one
six yellow seven zero eight zero nine
zero ten okay
now we know
we
look there's ten buckets and we know how
many times they appear right and then we
can construct the sorted array right
do you see how we're doing it look
we start from one because we know the
minimum is one the maximum is ten wait
look look
so how many ones do we have okay two
okay so how about i put two two here
two one yeah how many twos
two okay look at what i'm doing look
look what i'm doing
how many three
one
how many fours
how many five one
how many six
seven eight nine ten ten
you see salty do you see how how we
doing we count it and then we start from
a minimum to maximum how many and we
just open how many times they appear in
an array right yeah
yeah yeah this is quite interesting
right but the problem of these is that
white you need to start from a minimum
to the maximum and if this could be very
large what happened
this maximum is convenient
i don't know if it's left me man yeah
okay i mean yes
so look we have to start from one and
then count to a minion right you see
doesn't make sense it's a long time
that's taking a long time even
the bucket is empty
right because we starting from mean to
the maximum we count how many times they
appear when we don't know
yeah we don't know they
if they don't appear at all right so we
still have to check right so let's take
some
okay and then in order to count how many
elements how can we do this in python
specifically
the thing you know from collection
import was
phone collection in power
import in power
the one how what kind of data structure
can we use to count the number of
elements appear like in the array or
whatever
yeah notebook hash table and what
specifically for that thing we start
with the c what's that thing called
counter yeah counter
so let's say divide counting saw
counting song and then we're given a
numbers yeah
first of all we want to find out the
minimum so we can say minimum value
equals the mean we can just do this mean
and the maximum value equals max
num right
and then c equals counter look if we do
the counter we count how many elements
the number of times they appear right
okay now we have design so we want to
construct this away yeah this is the
sorted array come on
okay let's say sorted sorted array okay
sorted
array a r equals empty and now we go to
list for i in
range
style is the minimum value up to the
maximum value
do i need to do something here
[Music]
the inclusive minimum to maximum what so
what should i do with this one because
it's open it's closed open so i have to
do a
plus one yes
and what's the missing here
look i'm now chicken eye right look then
i need to do one look sorted array
saudi array dot append right not a pen
plus equal all open
and press one
point one
dot okay let's do a dot 10 okay 10
open what
uh actually we're not the opponent we
want to extend there's a function called
extend dot extend
what's the difference between append and
extend and here you okay it's then
all right
i times how many times do they appear
ci times right so look i this is the
number we only check how many times
right and how many times they appear or
we just append it right yeah yeah i
learned return
salted alright right that's it
look it's easy look
first of all first we get a minimum of
these numbers maximum numbers counter we
count how many of numbers
for each number sorted array this is the
sorted array we wanted to return and now
we try from the minimum value to the
maximum value increasing because we have
to pass one here
and extend yeah how many times they
appear ci for i element to appear
alright right look
a equals one two three this is a list
a dot append
append four that will become one two
three four right
a dot extend
extend another list like four five six
alright look
look right look
yeah a is one two three and a dot
extends four five six a will become what
22.6
yeah exactly so here it's ten because
this this thing
remember we have two
two twice right so this thing
will be two
times two right everyone look
original way we have 2 twice yeah
so this i is 2 2 times 2 2 2 so it's 2 2
i look
2 times 2 is 2 2 and now we want to
extend it so basically we want to it
please apply this to the sorted array
right make sense
what's the time complexity this is quite
tricky what's the same complex
[Music]
square
where's the square thing here
oh and cubic
oh there's all oh no
no no no no
there are any elements okay if there are
any elements look remember there are n
elements so this is o n yeah this is our
n
this is o n
right but this one mean to the max so we
have to define another range let's call
it r the range of the minimum to the
maximum
but think about it yeah think about it
and return something okay so one one
problem of this one is as i said if the
range is could be very big this r will
be very big yeah so this is very slow
yeah yeah am right even look if there
are two numbers
a million
so you still have to go through a
million times right
even though two numbers right because
look we are creating buckets a million
buckets yeah we need to count how many
of them right
with the counter counter so you just say
one zero zero zero zero
zero yeah one minute
yeah you get
999. so
that's right yeah so
in what cases can we use the this
counting soft what's the amount of in
what cases we
this disadvantage this this gives a
advantage
can you think of a scenario that we can
use this
uh
when
when there's only a short range of young
numbers well look like what
if you have a million
students in your class and then a
million students have an exam the exam
score from zero to a hundred so they are
100 bucks 101 buckets but they are
million students right
so
n
sorry
say 100 million okay okay maybe not not
quite strictly because this ends still
here we need needs to find out uh n
right so for example if they are
like
if the range is very small like the exam
papers go like from 0 to 100 right and
then there are
you know some students and then you can
count right you can count right you can
count how many scores for like how many
students get a score
one how many students get a score two
three right yeah
what
is this a stable or not remember the
stable thought
do you still remember a stable result
three yeah three parts if after sorting
the order is exchanged if you
after sorting you give me three three
dash three and this is not stable for
this one it's not easy to say right
because we are constructing the number
so
so it's not a stable slope right because
you don't know which which i is which
yeah because we are constructing the any
sorted array makes sense
okay
that's it for today good job bye bye bye