hello
i don't mean stay with mr ryan all right
okay so we have a sentence s equals
hello
eric
hi
ryan
hi okay so
we only have we have a
sentence with only the uppercase
lowercase letter let's space okay
we want to be able to truncate the first
the sentence by first few words for
for example k equals three then you need
to tell me
the the output will be
hello
eric
hi hi that's it because that's the first
three words and they're joined by a
space okay
so
look there's one tiny thing is that the
space man there may be extra space here
okay there may be extra space
another input maybe
maybe having these multiple spaces
between the words so we'll be able to
handle that we'll only be able to we
need to be able to return only single
space okay
there will be a single space so in order
to do this remember how do we
convert a string how do we convert the
string into an array of string by
what's the word what's the
join
split
which which one is it split yeah look if
you look at this is hollow array and
then high yeah
so if we split
look if we split the sentence by the
space then it will give me an array of
uh
string right
so look
if this string is a space
space b space c
if there's only one single string you
can say okay this is
s star spread
you can give a delimiter yes delimiter
what's this one mean delimiter
it means the limit
it means that the single thing between
these at the limiter so you can specify
a single space and you
you will return a
a list of a b c right but how about if
there are multiple states
then you if you split by single space
whatever you return something in this
page whatever you've written space
whatever you think
about the amount of times you've done it
sorry
so we have given lisa if
if we only if we have multiple spaces
and we
split by single space you will have
extra space empty space between this a
and b which is not what we want okay so
the key thing here is that we don't give
it a parameter so we just call extra
spirit and if i have extra space it will
ignore it even the space between before
and after
so you would still tell me abc
you still tell me a b
c okay even there are multiple space
between these two different words and if
there are extra space at the beginning
at the end okay by the way if there's a
string have a leading space
on
all the what do we call it the tailings
string we can use this strip
strip function s dot string function to
get rid of it and then we have a left
strip that airstrip which is take care
removes the leading space and we have a
r strip
yeah
holding koi strip of stripe strip yeah
strip to get rid of the
you know the tailings
what do you call the space at the end
this is the leading space what do you
call it alien
uh we call it tailing or
tail tail space okay whatever okay
so
yeah so
so we can split it and then what do we
need to do afterwards what do we need to
do afterwards
all right yes what do we need to do
afterwards we need to
do
so because if k
if k could be a minion we still need to
return the whole sentence right yeah if
the hello string hello every hello ryan
if k is 100 what happened we will return
hello every camera let's let's see yeah
yeah that's it so we we should be able
to handle that yeah
so
let's say define
truncate
sentence
the sentence s and a k okay
so first of all we don't want to split
it so you tell me a equals s dot spread
should i give you the parameter or not
yeah
no
if we don't give a parameter what
happens
yeah yeah okay and now we have look a is
an array of string right
so we want to how do we how to convert
it back from the array of string back to
the sentence to the s remember
so what
john what what what's john john by us in
the space yeah
john we want to join what
array all right up to k right so what
should i put here up to k this is column
up to k
but the k could be the smaller could be
bigger than the length of a right
yeah so what should i do here what's
your right here
what's what's here
what's here
this is k and we want we have a k and we
have a length of the a so which one
minus
km lens a which is the look k could be a
minion and lens there could be only four
words so so you have to return all of it
yeah i know i know we want to up to k so
which is what what do we there's a
function
that's a function to call which is
smaller so what do we call it i just
said it
[Music]
to get a smaller of these two values
right because the length a could be
four words k could be a minion so in
this case we need to return forward
right but if k is two words and the
length a could be
for us we want to return two words okay
so what what should i do here to get the
minimum so to get a smaller one so
what's the function
[Music]
the together picking functions makes to
get a smaller function
okay
make sense
yeah it makes sense to get a smaller one
okay so let a little bit yeah
yeah
yeah mike says
how about if the string is empty what
happened is this going to break yeah
no no
let's try s is empty empty string that's
pretty you'll be a ob empty
a is empty
single space.john empty up to
minimum k whatever length a is zero
right
so this value will be zero a empty
string up to zero so let's empty
return empty
you'll be returning
i think you'll be returning empty okay
yes so it's not gonna how about one
single word
hello
space that will be single words up to
length a would be one right so the
minimum will be
this
yeah
here okay so how about k equal is
negative basically at least it's going
to break okay
why is that because k if it's negative
it doesn't make sense
right if k is a minus ten
minus one doesn't make sense
actually my but
you might know my
look
this a equals one two three remember
a
one what's a one going to return
one
up to one yeah up to one so that'll be
one right
a minus one
zero so this is still make sense up to
minus one so you'll be
up to minus one should be
this one right
f2 up to so you p this one i think yeah
so it's better we check this k if k is
smaller than zero then it doesn't make
sense right
right if k is smaller than zero we just
return
nothing all we can you know soil an
exception raise exception raise
something raise an error okay
index slicing okay i'm going to say one
more thing index
lighting a
up to one is this right
a
one
two two
zero one
up to two so excluding three so it will
be two right make sense yeah okay so in
the index sizing suppose the negative
one right for example a minus one what's
it
what's this a minus one one two three a
minus one
a minus one is
the last one and remember we talked
about three yeah a minus two
two so exactly okay so we can also have
this a
minus two dash uh column then you'll be
starting one the second to the left here
and then to the end that'll be 2 3.
yeah so a
dash
to minus 2
0 to dash minus 2 so 0 to minus 2 so
i
this is minus 1 minus 2.
okay
yeah actually i have to check eight
times minus two give me a second to
check okay i'm not quite sure
wow
okay let's check let's check a equals
one two three
and if a dash minus 1
yeah 1 2 that's minus 2
1 ok ok yeah
so look
a is 1 two three
a
to touch minus one is one two a two dash
minus
my uh column minus two is one one okay
make sense
yeah yeah okay okay that's it for today
bye