oh
hello misery are you right
yes okay
so
you know the gene human gene g-e-n-e
genome human genome
yeah you must be heard of this before
genome and dna yeah these keywords
cumbersome
okay
yeah yeah yes
so
our human
you know you know how different people
look different they have different hair
colors different eyes right these
controls by gene right and then we human
have 23 pairs of chromosomes okay 23
pairs of tongue each chromosome
has hundreds of genes right
yeah hundreds of genes gene pairs okay
so 23 pairs and one online controls the
sex the gender right
for example the boys are ex-wife
the girls are xx okay
the girls okay
the
boy
so mommy and daddy
if mommy and daddy going to have one
more kid yeah one more one more baby
so what's the probability of these kids
being a boy and what's the probability
of that being a girl remember how do we
calculate this out we take
yeah how do we we take one of these and
we combine with one of these okay so
what's the probability of x x
look if we take x
yeah look at x i pick this x x x x x
there
pick this y
y x
y x right yeah yeah y x y okay so they
look any x y yeah y x x y is the same
okay
okay x y okay so look these two there
are two four two out of four boys two
out of four girls okay so
boy
boy girls
50 50 yeah 50 50.
yeah 23 chromosomes
one of them
is controllers
yeah the sex the gender
okay so each as i said each chromosome
has had a thousand you know many many
uh human genes yeah human genes and the
genes are
there there are four types of
you know you know the dna of dna that is
the two string two string
two stranded so you will have these two
pairs
jean pairs yeah same pairs
gym pairs
so it's like a two chain uh two you know
twenty eight pairs
yeah right i'm just drawing a few okay
it's only a few so
the these
they we have they only have four types
of gene which is a c g t okay you don't
need to worry about
how it pronounced it's just different
symbol to represent there only four
types of genes and a always pair with t
c always pair with z okay so here if it
is a i just
wanna see what it stands for
it's a very very very long you know the
biology terms you know which you
probably don't remember
yeah we can we can google it later okay
yeah yeah it may be more than 10
letters okay look if this is a what's
going is going to be
t
okay if this is g what's going on is b
c okay exactly so
what so look it comes with pairs that
means that the dna this dna can be
can can be easily repelling itself right
right if 109 is broken right this is
broken
right a human body knows because this is
g so he knows this is c
okay so that's why your human body is
repairing itself right he knows how to
debate dna right yeah and he cannot take
care not because easily right with least
so it's very uh you know secure way of
chain right it's match yeah
okay
okay so yeah i'm not an expert on this
biology okay just these these things is
just the basic okay so now
coming back to today's problem we have a
a gene uh a gene
group okay so look a if i have this one
well let's consider only one side of it
there yeah if it is a c c t okay
therefore right if let's consider four
players
okay that
okay
i write the acct so you know
automatically no no the pair f t g g a
right
yeah automatically so let's say at least
let's just use the left hand okay
dna comes two pairs you know you might
have other words which is called rna and
rna is only one single
singular okay
so let's say a c c t
and two genes if they belong to the same
group if they only differ
one
one gene for example a c c t and
a
let's say
a g
[Music]
c t
that belongs to the same group why is
that because they only differ one yeah
make sense yeah
okay so now if i give i give you a list
of the gene
yeah gene mutation group okay let's say
gene mutation because they only differ
by one and we say that belongs to the
same
gene mutation because look if you change
these to here there will be a mutation
and mutation that belongs to the same
mutation group because it says one step
one difference
makes sense
now okay so i have to give i give you a
look i give you this a c c t
a g c t
and i have given t t c c
how many groups how many
how many gene mutation groups are there
how
many two right two two yeah because
these two belong to the same these two
is different so there are two groups
make sense okay so today's task is this
given a list of genes with the same
length we want to find out how many
groups are there the mutation group
yeah
make sense
any idea how can we do it
i mean this is this problem may be a bit
you know think about it
think about it
so look if we can see the leaves as a
note
as no you know grass yes graph
graph
graph graph is the collection of vertex
and edges
right so if i can have this
acct
as a
node as a vertex
and
a g c t as a vertex
so
and here is another one so i can
consider each gene
is a vertex
right
so is there an edge between these two
yeah
yeah because they belong to the same
group right yeah so i i can add an edge
right
right and then there's no edge right so
the problem becomes what we want to find
the number of
number of components the goods for the
graph
make sense
yeah
so our task is to find given this graph
yeah we know how to we given this a list
of genes we know this graph we can
represent the genes in this kind of
graph
and the edges
the edges connected to different
different genes
who are belong to same
mutation group right for example i can
have another one which is what
c g gt right because
these and this only differs by the first
one right
what's this
yeah so
so we can look at the white ball and
then say okay we have two
two components right yeah
make sense
yeah
okay so now we are asking computers to
do it remember
what kind of deck algorithm can we use
to
translate a
graph
you know we want to find the number of
components
yeah buffer search and differences here
definite
you yeah we can do this episode easily
today okay or you can talk about
breakfast therapy and also we can use
the
union fan disjoint graph right there
this joint set remember
this joint set
yeah we could talk about that someday
disjointed union friend so look
for this journal said we have this
vertex we have this statics we find out
they belong to the severity scopes and
we merge these two
right
and then later we find out this and this
belongs to several schools
mutation group
we merge it
and then we find out and then later we
find out we can just say okay how many
groups how many
connected components are there and then
you can easily tell us that there too
okay so for the default search
for the default search
we try here
we start with any one any node if it's
not being connected right we start from
this one and then we try to visit
and mark
all the
vertex
yeah
right
and then we
we mark it and we implement the
answer which is one right look here i'm
here answer equals one right and the
mark of the connected
okay this is being marked
i skip this is bing mark i skip and here
this is not being marked
not being visited
right and there might be some other
group here which is what ptca okay okay
right and then now i increment the
concept which is two and i mark it you
see that's different yeah
make sense
all right you're right okay
okay so let's let's do this definite
search today and we talk about breakfast
search this june said some other day
okay because i think deficit is most
easy
to understand today
so define we want to find the number of
groups yeah let's say
five
number
of
groups
and we're given these genes
so in order look for the graph deficit
we need a kind of data structure
remember that nodes we have visited
right what what is it called
that is the the thing
what are the data structure what is the
data structure we use to keep tracking
of the nodes we have visited
so we can remember
yeah loop set okay
so we can say seeing equals
set
uh set will be nothing at the beginning
and then we let's say i have a let's
have a g which is the
uh the gene let's say we put it in in a
set so we can easily find uh
find if a gene
is in the
input
in
by using this hash set lookup which is
one constant right
and now we can do this this define
define step first search and then we
starting with a right
we are now here so and now
here i want to i wanted to say answer
equals link zero okay i know i can say
for
i
in gene
what
if i
not
in sin
and i i need to answer plus equals one
and then that first search
difference search i okay and then i
write an answer
okay so look
here i i
if i write it here then there will be a
standard template for performing the
definition on the graph right on the
graph look i'm going through this gene
yeah yeah i know i haven't finished yet
for gene genes you can consider it as a
vertex right it's the same thing here as
the vertex
right i'm doing through the vertex i
check if this vertex is not being
visited
then i increment one answer
and therefore search from these right
favorite search
okay so now after this determinants and
that will be the number of the connected
groups now that's research a and then
first first thing i want to add it to
the scene right scene
dot add okay i have visited this a right
and i need to okay so now i have this
gene c c
a a
what's its neighbor what does it what's
what's it connect to
remember we talk about the mutation
group right so the only difference by
one character right so it could be what
c
c will be could be one character would
be one
it could be this could be a this could
be g right this could be t
right
so
so then it's neighbor it's connecting
the vertex it could be a c a a
g c a a
t c a a okay or it could be different by
a here
it could be another one c a c
the second character yeah c-a-a-a
c-g-a-a yeah you see c-d-a-a-m-i yeah
because they say look this this one
connects to
which which one the only difference by
one character yeah so we can blue
forcing these because like we only have
four kinds of diff uh
four times of possibility for each
you know gene right so we can
bring forth all its possible neighbors
and then check if it's in the original
team
so let's say for i
in
range
length a
and then for
x in okay so therefore possibility a
t
c
g
so what's current c
that's the neighbor the name will be
what neighbor neighbor will be
a up to i right plus x plus a i plus 1
okay so this this is the neighbor look i
try
i enrange these i try each partition
instead of using the original character
i use the previous one i use the
next and then for this one i brought
forth all four possibilities
yeah
are you okay eric what happened to your
eyes okay yeah
and then look if and not even seen right
if this note is not being visited and
also we need to do this end also this
end in already
original
when we do this one left massage
and why
yeah this is the type of search
you see hey
i i i i say it again okay we go through
the genes equals to the vertex okay g
equals vertex g
is the vertex
we go through that vertex
if we haven't visited this vertex we
increment our answer right we have one
more component and we try to mark the
neighbors
we try to visit i definitely search from
i from terminal
so for the first thing we visit this
vertex we have to put it a civilization
in a notebook so so next time we know
right
so next time if it's not if it's
visited it doesn't go in again right
and then we go through like each each
character we try to replace it with all
four possibilities
right and n is the neighbor right and
neighbor is not in sin it's not being
visited and also it's already
in original
g
and in g right look you can say n in
genes but you if you want to look it
look up find
find the item in a list it takes one
time right so that's why i converted the
list into the
set so that will give me a one to
finding a number in a set time
complexity
a one finding a number in the list time
it's y above it sorry
um
yeah that's why we convert it to set
right to the test table so if you
provide us okay
yeah so let's let's just search
we can do this another way which is what
so instead of seeing we can go up we can
have a left right so we want to find out
the number of
we want to find out
so this thing is allow us to keep
tracking of the nodes we have visited
and how about let's say we have the
vertex and every time we visit the
vertex we just remove it right remove it
so let's say we can have this
left equals
left equal set gene okay jeans and then
we don't need this uh scene
and then different cells you know we
instead of scene.air we can do what we
can say
left dot remove a
remove a yeah at least it's the same
if then we can say if n not in left
instead of long e c we can combine these
two into one which is if
and not in
if n in left right
okay this is the opposite okay
so look
with the scene
it's is we checking even note
if it's visited if not
then we do the different search which
the left is that if the left
if the note is still in the left then we
do the default search and then here
again if i'm not in scene we change it
if i in left okay
i'm going to do the default search make
sense all right
any questions i mean i mean this is a
little bit too much for you to digest
right
all right
kind of but when you understand the
principle right how how do we do it
okay so how do we do it look
i have a c c t
i have uh
g c c t
i have
t c
a a i have another one c-c-a-a so how
many groups are there
[Music]
so this is the genes of vertex and then
i need to find out which which two are
belong to the same group by differing
one
threw at one edge yeah one and this two
yeah dc a8 yeah
right okay so how many groups are there
yeah easy so how do we do it
we start with any vertex if it's not
invisible we incremental answer equals
one
plus one answer and then what do we do
we mark it
visit it visit it
if it's written we skip and then we go
to here
we increment our counter and then we
do the default search
yeah
visit it visit it simple as that
this is the template for the default
search look yeah forget about the genes
whatever right the genes the vertex now
the difficulty here is that the graph it
doesn't give you the graph directly
right
all right the difficulty is that it
doesn't give you the
edge directly you need to figure out the
edge right and how do we figure out the
edges here
we try to go through each letter
and then try to replace it with four
possibilities
yeah
yeah if it's already if it's in a gene
now we added there's a edge
so what do we do with we equalize the
edge
what do we do if there is an edge
and then
therefore yeah so it's easy huh makes
sense
okay that's it for today good job bye
bye
bye bye