hello mr all right
yeah okay so yesterday we talked about
the uh condoms on the the aids you know
what's that human gene yeah
yeah so given a gene group we want to
find the number of uh mutation group for
the gene
so a pairs with what
uh
c pairs please
yeah i know you uh how we're using it
we're using the step first third right
remember deficits do you still remember
let's form yesterday
yeah we go
this is the genes answer equals zero so
that genes is the vertex each vertex and
we want to find
start of breakfast search as long as
it's not
visited right it's not visited when we
start developer search
with the
vertex we increment the answer right
all right can you stop that please
ac acct the neighbor its mutation only
by one difference is gcct
right so there's an edge between these
two vertices
yeah so there's an edge between these
two vertex so then i do it when i do
this data search
i go i find out i it brew for the
possibility of one letter difference
and then i check if it's in
if there's a vertex for it then i
definitely search
so in other words when we do this level
search we try to visit all the vertex
connected to current vertex right and
then when
we visited
these components and we'll try this one
yeah
at the same time we mark it as one and
we do the different search so what's
here
so this is the different search for the
graph right but for these one we can do
this breakfast surgery as well right so
for here i can do this right in for the
other vertex here yeah
yeah
we can do this step research to connect
all the pieces to mark all the pieces we
can also do the preferred search right
yeah
it'll be the same right
makes sense
okay
so do you still remember how we
implement the process
yeah how do you implement the preference
search
this is stefan search now i can change
this to breakfast search and change
these to processors
yeah
but obviously i can i still need to do a
little bit more work right
so how can we do this
for the test for the question search
yeah yeah exactly okay so this perfect
such i
i just need to
erase all of it but this this thing is
the same right so we haven't
finished this yet
so
these stairs work okay so for answer
equals you know this stores the number
of connected components right we want to
find out the number of
you know the number of what islands or
whatever yeah the trees yeah
the
yeah
maybe not a tree okay
uh
isolated
what do you call it isolated component
okay components so the task is to find
how many components are there right
so for we start with any vertex in the
component we do this preference search
of different search yesterday we talked
about differences now we're focusing on
the processors so in order to
implement preference search what kind of
data structure can we can we use to
implement the data search
definition recursion and how about
preference search
represent
put a note a here
we take it out
we put it connected neighbors yeah it
could be four right
yeah and then we take one now we again
push the kids on the right hand side
open one open
append right pop left
dq double and dq yeah yeah okay
okay so let's let's do this
first of all
uh
we convert these genes this is the list
of vertex this vertex we convert it to a
set so let's say g equals set
gene
why are we converting this to to set
what's the advantage if we convert the
list into a set it will be a one a one
yeah so we if you want to find out a
number like like this one two three
or whatever you want to find for example
three is in the list yeah this is the
list
that's on right i want time to look up
you know what's good because the last
one it finds it sequentially right it
checks if the first element is the one
you're looking for
if yes that's great right if not keep
going keep going so in worst case it
needs n iterations before it
finds it or not right but if we're
converting these to a set
then we can just say a element in a in
set a right in set a
then that's a one because of the hash
key hash table yeah we we talked about
the hash integration
yeah
so we convert it to a set
and now we can do this uh define
first search
a
first of all i put a q q equals dq
and i put the root which is a in it
right
at the beginning so this is the node a
right and then here b here will be c
i i don't know b and then here will be
another number this is the graph right
graph
yeah
and direction the graph
if it's not connected yeah it's not
connected
all right
so
okay
so product a as a wire
wireless
and element in the queue we take the qr
current equals q dot
pop left yeah pop left
and then we need to look we we have this
a c this a okay current equal could be
could be a string yeah a c c t or
whatever okay so what's what's what is
the neighbor how do we generate a
neighbor
we can try
to replace each letter with four
possibilities right that could be its
neighbor right
yeah so we can we need to try every
possibility for follow
each letter we try it's negative how
many neighbors does it have
uh
three
yeah that's a good one it's three it's
not actually yeah because the numbers of
genes are unique right so we don't
consider the duplicate of the duplicate
right so we don't need to consider
itself right
so it's three because if a letter c then
there will be other three choices but we
we can
you know
we can simplify the implementation right
i actually for i in i will be the index
in range
length current
okay and then now i want to try to
substitute this index i with other
choices yeah so for
x in
you said there are three choices but
let's leave all the four choices
a c
[Music]
g
t right
yeah because look at this player a
converts t c will be g right but we are
considering just this these this is the
genes number of genes yeah
for the inside chromosome a human
chromosome yeah
human has twenty three commas and one
i'm like is the gender right x axis is
the girls x y is the boys
and then each chronosome has hundreds of
these these pairs
right and a matches t and c matches g
so it's very robust right so why not one
of them is broken the human can repay
right
yeah so that's called dna
how can you repair it look this is
broken and just look it up this is a so
this must be
exactly yeah you see unless these two
are broken so
the chances of two
broken the sun at the same time is less
likely than one broken right all right
makes sense
yeah
so it's like two servers one server go
down
could happen right but to the
two servers
at the same time going down
is
a lot less likely yeah at the same time
at the same time yeah the challenges are
less likely right because for example
like maybe this this one percent of time
those stars right and this is another
one percent goes down so
what's the probability of these two go
down at the same time
you do what what operation for this
this is 0.01 and then this is 0.01 so
what's the probability of both going
down
0.
[Music]
yeah you multiplying together
yeah so what's the chance
0.0001 right
so what's this
chance it's zero point zero one percent
okay
you see
i even have three summers going down but
first you did three zeroes after the
decimal but then you did one
sorry what do you mean he did three
zeros here but now he did one
0.01
this is percent so you need to divide by
100 here so put another to zero
yeah so that's three zero that's fine
yeah okay
so another another computer going down
at the same time
you multiply right
yeah
make sense
yeah we talked about the probabilities
before right so one of them has the
one of them
that they are okay so there are two two
coins
yeah
two coins
so
this box can have a coin oh yeah 50 50.
and then here is 50 50. okay so both
both boxes not having a coin what's the
probability
fifty percent has coin fifty percent has
gone
and what's the probability of both
not having any coins in it
keep dividing yeah keep keep turns top
right okay
yeah yeah yeah
yeah
yeah yeah right okay so if x in this
then the next the
end the new one would be
uh
current yeah current up to i
so look here this is i current up to i i
wanted this part okay this is i i only
start
plus x this is the four possibilities
and plus this bit here
so which is current
i plus 1 to the n y
and this is neighbor i try each
possibility and then i just have to say
if n in g right we have this one
right if we have this one what should we
do first of all we should what should we
do with this if we have found the
neighbor what should we do
what should we do
and apparently what
kill the apparent and
without
yeah
i know b that's the breakfast okay so
what's the difference is this one yeah
we going through each vertex
if it's not being marked visited
instead of doing that research we're
doing the breakfast search
because the target our our target is the
same
our target is to follow
the edges
to visit all its neighbors yeah it could
be many neighbors huh yeah could be
connected look at it
it could be many
all right look it's always here
so with the tefl search you just visit
all right yeah with the breakfast search
it's still visible we'll mark it as
you know mark is
visited so how to remark is visited we
do know it from the g
this is g will be a set of the vertex
which has not been
visited so once we visit it we remove it
from the g
right so we just remove it and remove it
yeah
and once we
we mark it then we continue to visit
those vertex which has not been uh
visited right but once we when we
started we need to implement answer
equals one because that we start another
new
component new component right so these
targets to find how many
different components okay
that's it for today bye bye
bye bye