hello hello mr are you right yeah okay
so yeah we have been talking about this
uh jin human gym problem yeah we have
this a
so this is the dna thing a pair with t
c pair with g
right a p plus t c but g and then it
could be many many right
so we want to find out
the
[Music]
gene mutation group right gene mutation
what gene mutation group it differs only
by one gene right for example a c c t
and
c c c t
it belongs to the same mutation group
because the only one difference
and a g c
t t
a
g
t
d t belongs to the same group right
but a g t c t is not right because
differs on this one and this one is
right different but this one
and then this one
is it looks
yes but but okay that's the thing look
because this one connects to the second
one right so this one yeah
a g c t
a g t t t and the second connects to the
c
a g t c t right yeah
yeah
so these two belongs to the same
mutation group okay
they understand because they
there's a connection
right so
the first day the day before yesterday
we talked about different search
yesterday we talked about preferences
right so this is a graph problem graph
problem
graph
how do you
how do you spell graph gr aph
it's a graph is the collection of vertex
and an edges
right
and then now we have one vertex this
vertex is the genes right the gene group
the gene
and where are the edges where to the
energies
[Music]
yeah but the problem you see this
problem
statement does not give you the edges
directly right it does not tell you okay
we these two
gene belongs to this edge there is no
but how do we find it now
that's a rule right we check if these
two
belongs to some mutation group but only
one right so if like there's one thing
one letter difference then there's an
edge right yeah and our test is that
look we have a server
server
vertex seven gene connected by uh
by edges and we want to find out how
many number of the connected groups in
this case there's two right
do you still remember the different
search
research is
traveling by you're like
traveling from a note to note by
traveling along the edges yeah exactly
so
yeah
and then you go no more that's right i
know yeah
yeah
quite right yeah you're quite right
so
so i'm just writing that
last thing again okay
define okay let's say fine number
of mutation group
and i'm given a gene look at these genes
these genes are vertex right
okay
so look we have uh
we have a definition of preferences yeah
this is could be definitely perfect
branch i know
we just
yeah we just don't implement here right
now so look we have answer this is the
number of group then we can say 4i in
gene right those who leave each gene
group
right
and
if i
still in left remember the first one the
left left equals saying
gene
if still in the left
and then we do a test search
i right next to the search i and then
answer plus equal one
right look yeah
so what with this different search you
will remove all the vertex that
connected to i okay all right
we can answer yeah we talked about that
the day before yesterday look
this i will go through this i look this
is the gene yeah there might be some
group right some group like that right
right here goes only i
and then once i do this step for search
i
then i the first thing i need to do is i
don't remove a uh g don't left and
remove a
so what does it do
then you will remove it from the genes
right remove it from genes
so you remove all these things so next
time you go here look i found another
group right i found another group
so answering comparative one and look at
this definition
the order of marking the nodes doesn't
matter here right that's why we can use
the preferences
makes sense
because all my target is to what all my
target is to what
to remove all these
as a whole i don't care in all order i
remove them right
make sense
so i can do breakfast search i can do
different search therefore search
recursion stack preference search using
the queue level by level right look this
is this is one this is two three three
four therefore search
all right the first search one two four
three breakfast search
one two three four make sense
okay so
do you still remember a data structure
which is perfect for it for this kind of
purpose
right so we want to find out the number
of the groups and we at the beginning we
have n groups and then we can if there's
an edge
we mark it as a group even less than h
we mark it as a group and then we can
find out the number of
groups what do you call it remember
do you still remember
a data structure
yes exactly this joint set these tunes
are unified
this joint set this joint set okay and
usually we can do this union fight so
what does the union find so this station
is a status structure which supports at
least these two kind of
operations which is unit
which is where another one is fine so
union you have two groups you union and
together union united in union find
you can tell if a vertex
element belongs to which group
right okay
so
i'm just quickly writing this at this
june set thingy okay
i think we talked about a long time ago
and you may forget a little bit but
that's all right so we can revisit it
now
defy
union find okay let's let's unify
that's a class
or actually that's a class class
and then we have an
indeed
in it
uh
which is the constructor
and now we have what sizes we want to
put a size which is a dictionary and we
can
have uh
you you can implement this as a fixed
size you can pass a parameter which is n
and
a number of groups
right if you know
if you know the number of groups then
you can pass the n and then create a
static array
which end size
with an element but we now use the
dictionary which is the more flexible
okay it's left of parent
parent that's koi pak okay
okay and then two two things one is the
five
five union and fine let's say one five a
yeah if it's not in there then we return
what if we want to find it
so if it's not in there what should we
do
what should we do
[Music]
we first of all if a is not in
not in
serve the parent right if it's not there
if it's not there
what should we do
so look if an element is not in a in a
parent then we want to set it up right
we want to set it right
yeah so we can say select or parent
sorry second
yeah
a equals one
a okay it belongs to itself
right if it's not a
if it belongs to the cell the
landline sizes at the beginning size a
will be equal to one and then we can
just return
return what return we want to return the
number of uh the group group which is
this right a okay so look at this
actually
this is okay so this is a class so we
need to uh we need to put the first
parameter excel to say it's a class
method okay say self a
right
otherwise look if
if not
okay if cell
dot parent a not equal a right if this
is not group then we can say what
self.parent
a
equals self
save define
file and then we pass this in okay self
dot parent a
okay
and then we we do this return
send the paragraph i expanded it a bit
so this thing okay we want to find a
pair we want to find its parent and look
if it's apparently it's not there like
we put it we set it to the parent and
then we can also send the size and
reconnect
if this look
what does mean look if this is ah okay
if these edges look eric i want to find
this
yeah i want to find this
a
but now it points to b and it points to
c
so because a's parent is not a and then
i need to do what so let me save the
parent a equals i find this one
and which is
again points to b so eventually i want
to compress the path because look
eventually even
if a path is too long then this
operation says the path find it will be
take a linear time right so if i do this
the next time i know i want to point it
to what i want to point here to here i
want to point this thing to here okay i
want to
shorten the path to look it up
right so ideally i want i want this kind
of structure this is parent this is
group a and i have these two that
belongs to the same group okay yeah
you see
these
these look two three four five and one
belongs to the same group one points to
itself which is points parent a two
parent points to parent a right to
parent one one points to parent one
right so that's why it is we can say
this is better than this
this is better than that yeah
yeah if you keep a union file status
check it like that what kind of problem
would be like
it will increase the lookup time right
because look i want to take the i want
to check out the go what's the group for
the tournament what
he said okay
it's the group it's the same group as
four okay what's four central three two
one you need to
look it up here so it takes time right
to go this way up right
but now look i i get get this parent and
then i reset it i reset it
so look five eventually you tell me is
one right yeah
so instead of pointing to four i then
point to one
four
you'll tell me it's one right
right but now it points to three
so to the next time i don't want to go
through this again so i point to one
three
to one right it's the same group as one
power now it tells me it's the same
group as two so now what do i do i point
to two all right so in this case
a strawberry a star right so what so
next time look two
what's the parent of two it's the same
as one okay one is one and that's just
one one
why does the note five have two arrows
okay okay
yeah it's the same yeah you see
do you see this guy getting it
so this this is called the compress
compress the path when looking
compress path when look up
look up okay
so self defined okay this is centrifugal
and then with the self define
we have also another uh which is called
union right union
which just needs to
get the thing union
union what does union do
union will put
you will tell okay two notes belongs to
the same right
define
union
cell
a b okay so then i
what should i do with that
first of all we need to check if two
equals the same right so now look we can
say okay uh
a
let's say x equals seven five we know
their self to find
a right and then y equals sev
to find b
if like belongs to the same group what
should we do
what should we do
we've already that belongs to the center
what should we do we just relax
that's a very good answer relax yeah we
turn we can just return yeah because
it's already in the same curve right
yeah in the same group
just return
okay now now look again again let's
visually look
so i have these
uh i have uh
these
only only one two three four four notes
and then i have
i have like a 100 here
so do you think okay
so now i'm i'm telling you like okay i
want to this this
yeah this is a this is b
now i tell you i want to union a a and b
so do you think
which one is better putting a to b or
putting b to a
a to b why is that because
a has less less notes
if okay if we put in b to a what
happened
it take
well what happened i mean what happened
what do you think because eventually
look if you put the b to a then the next
one the lookup you will have more
notes to compress right you have more
notes to handle because these eventually
will be relocated the path right so it
will be more work
to relocate all these nodes to to as we
assigned to a right but now if you look
if there's just one or two nodes you can
just do it why not to know that will be
easier right yeah
so then we need to
tell the sizes if
if the size is
x right is x right
smaller or if it's smaller than seven
sizes b
all right why and then we just swap it
how do we swap it x y how do we solve it
how do we solve it
how do we solve it if we want to solve
something something equals something
okay so x y equals y x
and now i want to
now x is thicker so i want to
merge y to x y so i have to say
serve the parent
i want to put the y to x
x is bigger x is bigger
so i want to assign b the parent of b y
equal to x y equals x
right
and then now i want to update the sizes
so served
the
size is
x right because i put a y to x so the x
sizes will be
having addition of original set of sizes
why right
yeah
right makes sense
uh we can return the force here and then
we can return true here
right to make to to indicate whether we
succeed the
the the union right
make sense
yeah
if if the size is a uh x smaller than y
yes
okay
[Music]
a a is bigger than okay a is bigger
yes yes
all right yeah
um
okay and then another operation is to
get the count right to get account
define count
how self
this retains the number of connected
groups right
so it's uh it's a property property
value you can say property
property value here property value
so with this one we can just return
return
uh return the number of cards pretend if
the parent parent is a dictionary x uh
if it's a group right if it's a group
then x will be the same value with x
right so i can just return y
reason why
i need to sum
okay somewhat x equals or y
for
x y
in self
dot parent dot item right
all right
right
okay so this is the union file okay this
is the universe how can we use it as the
uh how can we use it how can we use it
in solving this kind of problem here
how can we use this installing time
[Music]
so we can look all right look
let's let's look at this okay
we haven't known right yeah
we have a that's a few notes
right so look if we know these neighbors
we can just union there yeah you need
union
yeah union these and then we can union
this and then later we just find out how
many connected groups all right make
sense oh yeah so it'll be easier it'll
be very straightforward intuitive right
intuitive
let's say define let's say fine
grooves fine grooves mutations
okay so now again again we want to find
out what we want to find out the g
equals g sets of g what what's the
advantage if we convert the list to the
it will be
okay now union phi equals union sign
that we we just defined this structure
and then
we go through that list therefore
i in g
f i ing
now we want to find out for
okay let's say for j
in range
length i right we want to stop we want
just find out the neighbors
all right
hey
why are you drawing my desk it looks
good a c c we want to find out the
neighbor how do we find out the neighbor
a equals
so for each letter i want to try try the
neighbors right and i want to find out
if it's in there right so look the
neighbor will be what uh
g
up to i i want up i want to pick the up
to i choice and replace with okay
i i need to go through that thing again
for x in
a
c
t
g right this is the four choices
and then then this column one is what
i
up to j
plus x plus i
j plus one to the n right
yeah okay so look
look at cameron you already look
currently this is j here right so what's
his neighbor i can pick the
letter up to it which is a and plus
plus their fourth choice yeah a c t g
and then plus one
plus the the next letter after it will
be ct right
do you get it
this is what it means here so when i am
at index j
i i have four choice and then i can pick
the choice pick the letters before it
and the letter after it concatenate it
right
i know what what's next
then i can say if
n
is in g right this is one lookup right
i know what's what do we do uf dot union
u n
i o n union i
with n
and now what do we do return
uf dot com
okay this is a property so we don't use
the
bracket to call it right yeah
all right
makes sense
mugs
yeah makes sense
accents
do you understand this one
look let me repeat again a little bit
let me repeat
union file we define this unified data
structure set we convert a list of
vertex g
to g so we can use the one constant
okay look when we go through each each
vertex
for each vertex
i generate its neighbor which is this
mutation right this is generally the
mutation mutation
okay what's this i'm testing what's this
that's if
the mutation
[Music]
vertex right yeah if we have robotics in
a group then what should we do now
we shall
um look for a
c
[Music]
and what's n
what's this
the neighbor
neighbor so there will be four neighbors
so look i'm i'm visiting
vertex i right
i want to division and i
connect all its neighbor okay so here
there's a mistake here i need to remove
it g don't remove it do i need to remove
it yes because i already visited i need
to remove here am i
do i need to remove it probably not
right do i need to
do i need to probably know
properly we don't need to remove it so
we need to remove it
we can union it
we probably don't need to remove it we
probably don't need to remove it in this
case so if it's already in energy if if
we have this vertex in in the graph then
we union i because i and n are neighbors
they belong to the same group right so
yeah
okay so let's see in the same group okay
so let's try
okay
yeah
let me write it and can you simulate
this process
okay can you simulate it okay i have
this
a c t let's just try easy
okay c c t
t
[Music]
and then wave
c c
a okay and then
t
t t p okay so there are four they have
one two three four five finals union
five
okay you can say over one two three four
five the least okay
yeah yeah that's fine so i'm here atg
okay i'm a ct
so now what should i do where is
neighbor which one is neighbor n
yeah yeah neighbor so which one would
you know is his neighbor
this one okay so i connected yeah
okay does it have another other neighbor
with this one
uh
no right not directly right okay
okay so now i try with this one probably
yeah we don't need to remove it if a new
movie that would be a mistake we don't
know
cct where's the yeah
you see okay and then
does it have any other no
okay
what's his neighbor
generally it's neighbor which one is a
his neighbor
[Music]
yeah okay
okay and then cca
cca
which is neighbor this one but we
already merge it that's fine we can do
it again yeah and tta okay so that's why
we don't remove it okay yeah if we move
it what happened if we don't move it
then for example here i i join this one
and then we move it
and i can't find this this one
do you get it
if we remove it and who who connects to
this nothing
right but we eventually we need these to
connect this so after this uf.com what's
the answer
we're done that's it
got it make sense yeah so which one do
you think that better i mean you can you
you understand the most
or you
you can implement it
how many ways of solving this problem
about
a lot
how many days we we talked about this
uh a few
what what is the field i mean how many
days we saw so many yesterday we talked
about what
we
we talked about the gene being released
yeah i know it's the same thing so what
kind of agreement i just talked at the
beginning
what kind of agreement
to solve the problem how to research
yeah okay professor steph associates
union fan so how many ways of doing it
three okay which one you think you can
understand the best
uh i'm not sure which one you think you
like the most i'm not sure
you're not talking about a big one which
one you like the best
which one you think it's the most easy
way to understand i mean
which one you think is the
most intuitive way of solving this
problem
i mean there's no right or wrong answer
i mean just a quick survey uh
i'm not sure
you're not sure yeah what do you mean
you're not sure i'll just choose this
one choose this one you think it's the
best yeah okay that's it for today bye
bye
bye bye
come on bye say bye bye bye bye