[Music]
hello mr harry are you all right
yeah okay okay
we want to talk about the first
recurring characters
so for example
what's the foreign it means repeating
again
air and then in this case we want to
return
the index of the second air right so
which is zero one two three three you
start with zero that's what we think
okay another one a b c d a what's the
first recurring character a
so we're gonna do four
four zero one two three four if there's
no recurring letters abc minus one one
is
okay so we can with this problem right
so what kind of data structure can we
use to remember the letters we have seen
so far you know we have talked about
this quite a lot of times
the data structure
to remember
the notebook notebook okay and in
particular in this case we want to
remember the notes we have seen so which
notebook is it
no you know
[Music]
contains the unique letters right but
hash table is the key value pairs right
yeah so we want to use the hash set
to remember the things the letters we
have seen so far and then if the second
time we seen this letter before then we
return its index so we kind of which
function returns that can we use to
to re to return a pair a topper of the
index and the value at the same time
remember which function
start with e what was the function e
liberate yeah
what's the calling means repeating yeah
so let's say sin
equals
right and then we can do this for
i
the value in
enumerate okay enumerate
s so if i do this
[Music]
if i do this
i which which one is the index which one
is the value i
is a value because you
i stands for index yeah
okay index index here okay and
value is v because
so that's why is
[Music]
yeah three of them that's fine we all we
always return the first one we always
return the first one thing
i look i know what we want number one
you return the index to the last one
that's a very good question look a b
a a a we return this in there why
this is the question
come on
so we rotate so look a
we put it in the set which is this is
okay and then b
i put it here b
and then a okay it appears before
then i return it okay so what you are
doing with this return the last one
return the first recurring letter okay
so what should i do with this
one
boring letter
v right
right yeah i said i said b
okay and then return if we don't have
minus one minor okay so what do we think
of this problem
it is simple
wow okay single e okay what's the
temperature
what's the temperature
what's the space complexity are we using
any spaces
why is that
because we're losing scene
we're using sin yeah i accidentally said
we're losing we're using well
okay so look if we're not using the set
we can we can also use this we can
usually okay
we can use the dictionary as well right
since equals dictionary right then we
can say if we in t
but instead of dictionary then we can
say this instead of cinder as v
[Music]
so what should we do with this we can
say c we can assign any value of it so
sin
v
okay we can say cv equal anything one
for example or c equals i okay let's
still also okay if we use conditioner
which is
highest paper okay
make sense yeah that's it for today bye
bye
meow