hello hello mr ryan are you all right
yeah okay so we have a list of numbers
right
three a minus a minus three zero one so
which number appears
which if there's a k yeah if okay which
number comes in pairs in the at least if
there's k and then three
three a right okay and which one we
which which one has the largest k eight
yeah i see a larger than three because
and both a and three is negative
appears right
so yeah today we want to find out the k
and k largest k
largest
k
which it has minus k
in the array
right and
zero yeah minus zero
right okay so right yeah yeah
it's here it's the same so tlo is the
very special case and if zero appears
only once then we also think it's
negative also appears right it doesn't
have to be two zero okay
yeah
so in order to solve this problem so
what should we do
we
first of all we can move first yeah so
do first is that we try each number
so we can try each number let's say we
have this answer
at the beginning we have
negative infinity right
negative infinity
so we try each number for i in numbers
then
for each eye i need to check if it's
if if
minus i in numbers
then we do this answer equals max
answer
i okay
this is this is linear or when because
we are looking up an element in an array
this takes all in time right right
and i answer you go back and look if if
this number is not
if it doesn't find if we don't find any
if we don't find anything that's
satisfied if we only have this number
three two
then you you need to tell me it's minus
one because
we can't find any k okay don't put them
yeah we can't find anything okay so now
we just say return
minus one
then we yeah answer if answer
not equal
max infinity
else
minus one okay so this is the same thing
as
if
you can put this
writing this if answer
not equals mass
infinity return
answer
as written yeah s return minus one okay
this is the same thing okay we just put
this interest
into one line it's the same thing
so look this is time complexities o n
square why is that because going through
these it will be o n and then for each
one you need o n
so the problem is this one is takes time
right so we want to
speed up these
so we can use one kind of data count
hash table
hash set
notebook
to speed up this to make it a one so one
if this is one
n times one is n so let overall time
complexity is over n okay so so we can
just do this right we can just
we can just say
sim
equals set numbers right
or we can say sing equals counter yeah
counter numbers
so the set contains only unique elements
right so you just tell me okay which if
they are set if this is two to
one and then if you convert it to set
you will only have these two and one
right look
right
yeah
this is the num yeah if we convert it
to a set
you only contain the
unique number which is one and two and
looking up an element in the
set is a one look up because it has set
and for this counter
if we count the nums
so you will tell me additionally yeah
decision which is look two appears two
times
one appear one time okay and still you
can do this if minus i in numbs
you're looking at the key if your keys
is in the dictionary right yeah
so
any any questions so far uh answer
equals next answer actually here is
we can put it minus i or i it doesn't
matter okay because
because we're going through this entire
thing
right yeah so
i or minus i all work right
because look if you go into a
you can compare a and or minus a
right they come in pairs right yeah
uh
any questions so far
okay what's the space complexity
where down because we are using
headset yeah counter this and in the
worst case that
each number is unique right so you need
for example there are 10 elements and
then you need a
set
of counter or hashmap dictionary to
store
10 elements right okay good job that's
it for today bye