hello
hello mr eric are you right yeah
yeah yeah yeah okay so remember what's
the subsequence
this is something
okay this one
subsequent what's the substance remember
subsequent
all right
subsequent what's the difference between
subsequent and sub-list or sub-array
a
subsequent can pick live and
you can pick for some sequence you can
pick like two and three but for sublets
you only can play in continuous yeah
yeah yeah okay so you're right yeah sub
these and some are basically the same
thing yeah they continue you have to
prove us that we need o n square time
right remember we talked about is to
compute the number of the sub list for
given
yeah given given array we if there is
there are an element yeah if there are
an element of this array
and then we pick c and one yeah the sub
is with only one element plus c and two
pick two index right so that will become
n times n plus one divided by two okay
and to blue force it it takes o n square
time right
but the subsequence is different is the
original ray where i did it one or
or nothing or we did zero or nothing
or more than
more elements right so i can remove two
and the sub sub sequence would be one
two three if i remove five the steps can
become two one three okay
yeah
so today we're going to find out the
largest subsequent sum
largest
with largest k subsequent sum largest
k subsequent sum okay
so look if this k equals three so i want
to to find out the largest three
subsequent sum
okay size subsequent so you pick three
elements right
which has the largest sum can you pick
which the three animal which has the
largest sum the subsequence
yeah but 5 3 2 is not subsequent what's
the subsequence
you're right 2 5 3 2 is the largest
three sum but what's the subsequence
two five three two is not the
subsequence
exactly okay
yeah so two five three okay so
you have to do it that way
that's a good question if i'm if the
question becomes
if a question is that okay pick the k
largest sum right then you can sort this
away and then pick 532
easy yeah so if this is array you can
just do array dot sort
and then you can just return i want to
return this yeah return
return what
then the sum yeah the sum of it so i can
just return
all i return what are r
because the rate of source from the
smallest to the largest right so i can
do this minus k to the n right yeah
and that will
give you what
that will give you what
two three five right
yeah because when we sorted this array
you become
one two three five
and minus k minus three is at this point
i only look you're with me and two three
five or you can arrange the saw and you
pass that in parameter called reverse
reverse equals true
and array dot so that will become 5 3 2
1 right and then you pick the first k
first k so you can return a r r
up to k so it will return 5 three two
right
but this is not that simple right you
need to tell me the original subsequence
is two five three i don't want five
three two i don't want two three five
okay
yeah because in this case it'll be easy
what's the time constant recording the
song
uh oh and logan yeah okay
okay so the problem is that the strategy
of picking the largest cave
is your right yeah sort it picking the
largest but we want to be able to locate
the original index so we want to come up
with a solution to solve that numbers
while maintaining its index right so we
want to be able to say okay i want to
pick these three numbers but i also know
this index is
is what zero two three i want to pick
the numbers from the
smallest index to the biggest index okay
so
remember what kind of work function
of what function person do we return the
index and the value at the same time
remember we talked about a few days ago
pretend that you know the index and then
value remember
at the same time that's the total in
four
in star with e
enumerate yeah new line
so yeah
so we have this emulator that's fine so
let's let's do this okay and then you
can follow my lead so you can do it so
this is let's say this is numbers
these numbers
okay so then a a-r-r you tell me what it
is a-r equals list because e-numerator
is the iterator yeah i want to convert
it to a list enumerate
and then i have these nums so can you
tell me what it is
enumerate array so array
will be a array of
of what
that of what
eliminate what's the universe function
remember
test it returns the index and the value
right
yeah
okay so the index of two is what what's
the index of two
uh
index of two come on the first one
that's the value what's the index
yeah okay look yellow two that's a tuple
right and then one one right
and then two five and then can you tell
me the last one
zero one two and the last one is
three three yeah okay so that's what it
basically does enumerate has the index
and the value which is the tuple i
converted the list so that's the left so
i want to solve this number but i also i
want to sort it by the value like the
second key right so i can do this
already because this is the magic arr
the sort
right i want to sort it but i want to
give you the key because it's a tuple i
need to get a key key equals
yeah lambda is the short function x and
then i want to do this x one
right x is here x one is the value i
want to look basically this is to sort
this arr array by the second value right
by the second value but of course this i
want to maintain the index this is the
index right
yeah
okay so now i have these okay this is
the command okay so i have i'm sorting i
i can also sort it in the reverse order
which i put the
what put the
key equal uh reverse equals true right
now i want to get the index right
so index
equals i
right look
index what's the index
so look if i sort it and then no become
i i sort it by t so the ai will be
the value the first three values will be
one the first three
uh
so that will be one two five three right
one two five three
i know what one two five three so you'll
be
one one
two five
three three
uh actually now one three
one
one two yeah one zero zero two
one two the second variable and then
three three
and then two five right i want to solve
the second sort by the second value and
then this is the sorted so i want to get
the
last and last least the index will be
zero three two right so index so be i
for i comma j in a i
a r from
minus k to the n minus k to the n
so that the first index will be 0 3 so
index will be 0 3 2 right so now i need
to sort the index again right index.
yeah index dot sort will be
will return 0 to 3 right and then i need
to just return what return
i have the index and i want to use the
index to retrieve the value in the
number so i will say num
i
for
in
index all right
make sense
everything makes sense
okay so let me repeat okay you just
follow my lead first of all i call this
i ai equal list and i have this thing
the first element of the tuple is the
index the second element is the value
and i saw the array solely thing
by the first key equals x1 by this so
you tell me that the the sorted array
will be one one zero two three three two
five because i thought it the last value
yeah my last value
and then minus k two so i get these
three parts which is
two three five but i wanna index tier
three for two right this index will be
zero three 2 and after sorting it will
be 0 to 3 and then i go go through the
index to get the index to get kind of
index from the original number which is
0 to 3 so which is 0 to 3 0
three two five three
make sense
sorted
uh salty oh n sort it oven
again again
so two o and log in okay so the time the
complexities to oh and again but of
course this k
i need to i need to observe yeah we need
to assert this k thing as that k is
bigger than zero and smaller than the
length of the
smaller than or equal to length of
lambda okay we don't want to deal with
negative place or the k bigger than that
if k is a minion right
that doesn't make sense right yeah
okay so
this is one way
the second approach is that we can do
this using a
window sliding window a window thingy
so again is this the
okay let's consider a bigger
example okay
the numbers
equals 3 5
7 6 and k
equals three okay what's the largest
what's the k what's the
largest
subsequent which has three elements the
sum sum
uh it is
five
seven six yeah yeah you started the
number and then they picked the largest
the smallest one look this question is
easy for human right it's easy for us to
do it right all right we just slowly
pick the largest three numbers
which is six seven six five and then the
subsequence would be five seven six
easier it's very easy for us to
to find this solution but maybe a bit
tricky for computers to do it okay so
look k equals three let's let's maintain
a window of three so the the first
window of three is three five two right
this is a window window
three five two
okay and then now i am starting at this
number what's the minimum of these
two okay it's one bigger than two
no no then i i don't
we just skip it right because we if this
this is smaller than a minimum it means
that we come we can't we don't kick this
one right because
this one is more even smaller than the
minimum of it right
there's no no point to replace any of
element with this a smaller one right
seven
is it smaller is it bigger than that
yeah okay so what what do i do i do boo
i don't know the minimum
and i replace it with seven i append it
to the end right which is seven
okay six what's the minimum sorry i
remove it and i put it at the end
okay
five seven six
yeah
original
got it
yeah okay this is sliding it works why
because every time we cut the minimum of
this win right
and if this number is bigger than a
minimum so we can replace it yeah
right for a better solution i'm right
yeah that's a pretty solution now okay
so let's do this a little bit
and you you need to tell me what's the
time complexity think about it okay
define let's say
uh
largest
k
subsequent
then we have numbers we have a k
and obviously we need to assert this k
thing is bigger than zero smaller than
length of num
okay the window thing we know
window will be at the beginning will be
norms up to k right
and then for
i
in range
range what
which index we need to stop eric which
instead we need to start
[Music]
we already have the first window okay
yeah and up to lens end right
okay
and then look this is current minimum
equals we can say mean of the window
window
and then look
if nouns if current element
is bigger than the current mean right
there might be multiple solutions we
just written a new one look look if
these two
three
uh
h actually
okay
two three four
if they are duplicate anymore what
happened
so four four okay there's no duplication
if they duplicate element we need to put
the equal sign
should we select for the equals and
there if at least the pick the last two
is four four right
it's four four it's four four yes so if
it's bigger okay if it's bigger
if it's bigger than the smallest one
right if it's equal we don't replace it
because we we are not
we can't find a better solution it's
it's a easy it's the same services we
don't we don't we don't uh we don't
replace it and if it's bigger than the
current minimum then we do what we we
can do this window
don't remove remove the current element
current minimum we remove it and then we
need to append it to the end right a pen
all right what's it doing
apparently our eye yeah and then
at the end we do turn
return
okay
okay let's try with the duplicate
because i'm not quite sure let's do this
uh three two two three two
one and k equals
k equals two okay what's the k equals
two in this case
k first to keep the largest uh three two
two three or three two it doesn't matter
right you can tell me one okay so let's
say this window two three
okay two is smaller and it's bigger than
the minimum
yeah if it's bigger then we replace it
with three two okay it doesn't matter if
we put an equal we if we put the equal
that'll be three two if we don't play
equal it will be two three okay why is
that if it's equal look when we find the
second two eric
if it's equal then
if it's equal to the minimum we don't
move it and replace it apparently it
will become three two if we don't
replace it you become you will still be
two three okay what's the time down next
complexity
here is n
but
look finding the minimum here
finding the minimum this window is k
right o n times k
and
remove it remove one anymore look okay
list
let me let me do this all right come on
a r r
one two three four and then a r r dot
remove this operation remove two for
example yeah
remove two then a out become one three
four yeah easy yeah but if i remove
now is this element here if i remove -2
then the computer will screen
because this minus 2 is not in the list
yeah
makes what do i just say
if you do like
negative number
it will scream
it's not because it's negative because
it's this is not in here right
okay okay okay so what's the time time
relaxed to remove this it's o n okay so
this is o n as well
uh
o n but this is k because look
this window is k size yeah this thick
side
okay it's a thick side
but every time i remove it i have plenty
of one so it's always k as fixed size so
this is still one as well so all
together is one all right
o n
okay so all together
[Music]
o and k
which which is p which is bigger oh and
log n and o and k
what do you think which one is bigger
it depends
that's a
good question that's a good point but if
you think about it
if you think about it
yeah because if you look at it
k and log n you're not sure which one is
bigger that's a very good first point
but in this case is k smaller or bigger
than n
smaller where if it's smaller okay let's
say if it's at most it's n okay so if
it's m n let's say
o n okay o n square
o n square no learn k which one is
bigger
and square and oh
yeah of course yeah because we know
k is smaller or equal than n right
yeah so let's say okay in worst case
it's n right
but in worst case it's ending if it's n
we don't actually we don't need to
continue here right because look if
given this side the largest case is it's
excel right
yeah
yeah okay so if it's worst case is one
and obviously this is better okay
this is better
right
if we can if we don't consider about
last thing we're just considering
these two things and k is smaller than n
and
o and k
o n
k is
is the o and log n is better than okay
right but actually if it's if k so look
k k is for for example is roughly n
divided by two
right if n divided by two
i don't know we we can put a let's say
we can put a hundred there right a
hundred a hundred
divide n is a hundred k will be fifty
o log 100 yeah still better than k
equals 60 okay
so yeah clearly this is the winner okay
yeah any questions so far
okay say bye to people
bye bye