hello mister we are all right mr ryan
are you right yeah
so what's dynamic programming we talked
about this a few times ago
talk uh dynamic programming
in one word in one word
[Music]
it's
for remembering yeah remember we want to
remember the computer and the
computed result yeah so we don't want to
we calculate it over and over again
and specifically we can put the cache
the casting
above the
function the message so you ask the
computer to remember it yeah
to remember it okay
yeah let's uh
we have two kinds of dynamic programming
top down and bottom up depends on just
just think about the people matching
number your fibonacci number
now f n equals f n minus 1 plus s minus
2 right if we keep if we compute from fn
and then we need to fn uh n minus 1 and
minus 2 for n minus 1 we need n minus 2
and minus 3 right it's a tree right it's
a tree look if we want to compute fn i
now know become msn minus one and f n
minus two
and look
we only compute f m minus one we need
the f n minus two and
f and minus three right so look if we
want to compute this value
so we need two values
which is smaller and then if i want to
compute the n minus one i need a minus
one minus three so if we go in this way
let's stop down but if we're going from
that way if we start from f0 and f1 f2
let's bottom up right f top down
you can just say okay define f you can
say define
f n
and if if and equal equal 0 or n
equals 1 return n right
and otherwise i return
f n minus one plus f and minus two
okay
this is the top down top down
yeah i have your attention please yes
but this is
expensive why is that look
f and minus 2 here f m minus 2
right this could be a lot right look
it'll be f minus 3
f and minus four again look f n minus
three x minus three
it's expensive here f n minus three
yeah
and then f n minus four look how many
times i need to
at least over and over again but if i
magically put this here magically
and i just need to remember n value so
look the first time i kick your f n
minus two
i save it so next time
i won't continue this way because i
already know it
i already know it right
dynamic programming okay
so we have an array of numbers 1 5 11 5.
can you separate this array into two uh
subsequent okay remember the subsequent
and then the sum would be the same
do you understand the problem
this is
okay
and this one
subsequent
okay okay okay can you go back okay this
is not a dungeon
so look yes subsequent subsequence uh
subsequence and someplace what's the
difference between subsequent and
subless can you tell me what's the same
continuous and one of them is
okay the subsequence is not continuous
subsequence is that the original array
and we can okay
okay look listen to me not continuous
that's what i said okay subsequent not
continuous it's like the original array
and then you can remove zero or more
characters uh numbers right on it for
example one five eleven if i did it five
and five and the remaining would be one
eleven is a subsequence the sub this
is continuous right you pick remember
the cn1 cn2 right cn1 plus cn2
cn1
i have n elements i pick one
that
this is the number of way of picking one
out of n i have three apples
ryan
you want to pick one to eat how many
ways how many apples can you pick how
many different ways three exactly okay
so c and what makes me think
yeah cn1 is the meaning that the
subplace with only one single element
and cn2 is like you pick two index two
index 11 right now you pick these you
pick this
there are n elements you pick two
okay and then one five eleven this is
the service you pick this you pick this
five eleven five is a service okay so if
you do this that would be n times n plus
1 divided by 2 this is the number of the
total sub is continuous and that's the
in the scale if you want to prove first
it let's oh n square right but for some
subsequent
subsequent we can think it this way for
each number we can pick or not pick
right that gives us two choice for the
second element we can pick or not pick
give us another two choice so divide
into plus then or multiply
one question
multiply multiply and for the third one
i can i still have i can pick or not
pick so and i can multiply two so if
there are n elements what's the tongue
and brexit
you'll be something like level
yeah 2 to the power 1 is 2
2 to the power 1 is 2 and you know it's
very very stupid the graph
okay so um so if we want to prove
firstly right we can try
every subsequent we can generate
each subsequence and then for each one
yeah
we can get the sum of it
get the sum of it so
i know we can check if it's equals to
to what
t 0
the total sum look the total sum of
these is what
22 even okay so for the subsequence we
want to check the subsequent sum equals
to what
even to the equal number
yeah yep yeah yeah if it's even number
we can find that maybe we can find the
solution but if it's all number it's not
right if it is 23 or 5 there's no way to
split it into half right yeah
okay but look okay guess 22 this is the
total sum for the array and i want to
change i want to find the subsequent sum
that equals to what
to what eleven eleven whatever half of
it yeah eleven halfway so that takes to
get the sum of the subsequent that takes
one time so all together that'll be o n
times 2 to the power of n
right
n times 2 to the power this is quite
slow okay
so
so we want to use the dynamic
programming to save it yeah because look
we can come up with a function okay
come up with a function
so basically
as we as we talked about
for the
solid x number for this number we can
have two choice pick or nothing right
and now we also have one dimension which
is the remaining sum so at the beginning
we give a half of it like 22 will give
11. and if we decide to pick the number
we substitute a number
from 11 right and if we are originally n
and then if any any time
we're reaching the end
so we can we can do what we need to try
it out but
if the sum is being reduced to zero okay
so let's first of all substitute some
subset sum
i know we have nums
and then let's say tota tells uh can can
i have your attention not too too loud
please
counter equal sum
nums okay that's o n right but that's
okay
this is some function we can we can use
the mathematic building function some
function okay oh we can do this and uh
total equals zero for i in lumps and
total plus equals i right this is the
same thing that's our ni that's owen
if
total divided by 2
equal equal one yeah what does it mean
and now we need to return first can can
somebody explain to me what does this
mean
you want to check
yeah if it's all then there's no way to
split it into half right
or
module two
yeah or we can do this n one it's the
same thing modulated
0.2
okay now the half half would be
total
divided by 2. this is the sum okay let's
come up with a function define
dp
and now we are considering the ice
number from the left to the right okay
and now we are considering the sum
s right
look if i equal equal length
nums yeah we are running out of numbers
then we need to find out if the sum has
reduced to zero right
yeah yes
make sense
what did i just say
we we're checking if
the number reduced to zero and what
cases we need to do find if it's even
i don't know if i
that we're considering the numbers here
numbers
from left to zero index right index i
index i i index i i equals zero the
first number i equals length n
we are now at this point we are running
out of numbers if we are running our
number we need to check if the s the sum
has been reduced to zero okay
otherwise we can just do what i look at
any point if the s is reduced to is
below zero what does it mean what should
we return here
we will if the sum has been reduced to
zero
become negative
so what's your return 12 hours here
come on think about it
why is it true
because it's even
no no no i mean then something
false yes
if it falls below zero it means right we
are using too much sun right so in this
case it's not
this is not
not a way to separate to split the array
into half okay
then now i just need to do what return
dp if i pick the choice if i pick a
number okay look
i plus one and then s minus what nums i
right if i pick this number
or if i don't pick it d p y can you tell
me if i don't pick it what happened
if you don't figure it
what's the first parameter if i don't
pick it
[Music]
here i'm here
if i this number i don't pick so what
happen i should move to the next
so i
i plus one and then what's the thumb if
i don't take it
what what's the sound
if you don't know pick us
if i pick it i need to subtract if i
don't pick it what happen
you need to
be the same be the same so s
what's missing here
if i don't pick cash
if i don't pay cash yeah
there will be multiple times this
intermediate value being calculated
again again but if i
put the cash what's the what's the time
complexity if i put the cash
look at s baby
i i is the what then some length of the
numbers right
name s s is half total so okay let's say
half the total sum right so some
some let's say sum is s s times n okay
the time complexes o
s times n divided by 2 and we drop the
constant right because this is the total
sum we are looking for a half half of it
s times n
right
so look this is the total number of the
maximum
values we can catch right we can catch
and that also means the time complexity
right so look
make sense yeah
for this number
for i'm standing at this point for i'm
still looking at the ice number for this
number i can pick it
i can pick it yeah uh or i don't pick it
here
in both ways we need to move to the next
number and when we reach the end
when we reach end we have to check if
the sum is zero if we reduce the zero
then that's a good
okay and any at any point right if the
sum already falls below zero so we don't
pick
right
make sense
yeah so okay by the way these numbers
are non-negative okay
yeah yeah no negatives not about decimal
things
no decimal
not decimal just just positive integers
okay
okay that's it for today tomorrow we're
talking talk about the photo app
solution for this one okay it's quite
similar okay bye bye bye