[Music]
i'm
so today we are talking about the
intervals
so can you tell me what's interval
interval
what's the interval why why don't be shy
you know you
you know you just say intervals
[Applause]
[Music]
is yellow yeah yeah we got the numbers
on it and
integers yellow be only one month
and and it can be half of it maybe
you know 1.5 yeah something like that
like these are called fraction of
all real numbers yes all these are
called real numbers okay and these are
integers
integers okay the intervals for example
like interval it could be
zero one so it could be zero one yeah so
it means this is the interval yeah
okay yeah yeah one
is one yeah yeah what how about i give
you a list of intervals
like uh zero uh
okay and then maybe minus one ten
okay okay so what does it mean yeah what
does the mean
zero one here is here yeah two three
yeah
they're not intercepting each other
right separate yeah
five six maybe here five six is here
yeah
yeah minus one yeah and then i need to
do this or minus one
okay so can you tell me that if there is
a if there is a
interval that is part of every interval
i mean
do you know what i'm talking about okay
for example like
if this is 0 1 zero one two
three four five zero five and then if
they are
uh they are this is two
two six okay two six so the interval
part will be two to five correct
yes in this section so look t
six here this is the part of interval
and then
here is the parting you know what's the
common part
it's this tip yeah this period this
speed is the common part the
intercession is yellow yeah
so for this one is there intersecting
each
no no because these three are separate
and then they're not common
right so how about if i tell you that
give you a list of intervals and i want
you to find out if they are
if they are common intervals and what
are they what way
do you know do you understand this
problem no
not really okay look look
[Music]
okay right if i zero one
two three four five six seven eight nine
look if this
is zero two like i give you an interval
here yeah zero two
yeah and i also give you an interval one
three so what's the common part
one two exactly okay so let's say
suppose
there are a list of the uh uh
i mean there are n intervals yes there
are intervals
and then can you tell me try to design
the
algorithm to find an algorithm
yeah it's a way to design a way a method
to find our
comment in the comment the common part
of
all intervals do you know how to do it
how about this style is two two
intervals like zero two
zero two and one three so how can you
find the intervals of this
[Music]
any idea how how can we find this
so at least if this is look
we just have to draw it no but the
computer don't know how to draw so
i give you a hint okay i see it
i give you a hint so 20
that's yeah something about the one two
yeah but how how how to get this one how
to get these two
so for the left boundary yeah for the
left starting power
we want to find out the maximum of all
the
intervals the left we want to find out
maximum of these uh the starting
of the all intervals right yes
and fallout's ending point finishing
point we want to find out the
minimum of the all the intervals
yes yeah does it make sense
yeah look look this interval
the first star we want to get the next
uh
bigger one yeah right and then for let's
finish we want to get a smaller one yeah
so then it will be the interval yeah can
i try yeah but that's part
drawing yeah but look if i don't i even
i
i don't draw and you tell me okay like
uh
five ten and then
uh three and seven so what's the
common part what's the common part
remember we want to find the maximum the
starting point the first number
five three plus seven sorry
these three seven yeah five seven yeah
we want to this one
yes the first number we want to find out
uh
the maximum of all this interval which
is five and then the second number we
want to find the minimum of all these
which is seven yeah five seven yeah is
it two
if we draw it let's find
10 and then three seven and of course
the interval is this bit yeah yeah and
if we have a lot this surface can be
applied to it yeah
so let's learn this please
define define interval
interval intersection in the section
column and let's go to
right equals the first one yeah so
so the first one will be uh
the first first element is zero zero
yeah so this is the intervals of given
these intervals are given like that yeah
3 and then three ten yeah
are you okay yes are you okay yeah okay
how about the interval is nothing so if
if it's nothing if
it doesn't contain any animal we need to
store uh return
uh return what's this yeah let's okay we
can return
we have four or anything so an
exceptional section
so look we can check if if
length yeah this interval
equals zero then we return
return long okay because there's none
intersection and we will return
long interval and obviously there's no
intersection so this interval zero
interval zero is this yeah
interval zero zero is this this okay so
the left
interval zero one is zero one so it's
seven
okay so that's right left is five right
is seven okay
and then now we're looping the interval
for i
in range in not in now
yeah in the full group
so now now now left
equals max we want to get the maximum of
all the starting point which is i
zero right right we want to get a
5 for the first coordinate interval
starting with
interval we want to get the maximum yeah
and then for the right we want to get a
minimum right so which is mean
yeah right what's this what's the what's
this i what put the number here interval
i what this is one one yeah that's one
because
yeah and now we have left and right but
up if there's no interval what do we do
look
if we if this is this is one two and
this is three three four and what
happened in this case
the left will be three yeah
finally the left will be three and right
will be two right
yeah so let's left will be bigger than
the right
right which doesn't make sense there's
no interval right
yes this is no interval right because
one two and three four
they don't in uh they don't intersect
right
yes so but in this case if we got a
maximum of left which is one and three
which is
three and the minimum of the right which
is two and four which is two
and now left is three right is two
what does mean no interval no
intersection yeah
so if left
left bigger and right
return noun yeah because there's no
intersection okay
yeah and otherwise return what determine
the intensity
left and right okay
got
does it make sense yeah what's the
complexity
[Applause]
and what's the space complexities of one
right because we
are only allocating the constant space
the left and right and it doesn't we
don't need to
i locate uh the space
it is likely if there are any intervals
we don't need to
the space we allocate that do not uh
increase as the size of the input okay
so
it's constant left and right okay so now
right
i'm relaxing okay so now can you tell me
can you tell me if if left and right is
equal
is this still interval like if it is 0 0
and 0 1 what's the interval
of this what's the intersection of this
[Music]
zero zero zero so so yes zero zero is
still valid intervals so so it doesn't
look
if if you put if in this case
left will be zero right will be zero so
we're still retaining zero zero okay
function so it actually will return the
maximum of these two values right
so if you if you want to write it as
evil you can write write this this way
if
i zero is bigger than left
column left equals i zero okay
and then mean is the same if if i1
is smaller than right then because we
find a
new smaller uh right then we
do this right equals i one all right
okay so any questions no no
interesting interesting yeah okay say
bye-bye merry christmas and happy new
[Applause]
year