hello miss very mister right now you're
right
okay so what we talked about yesterday
is that we given a list of numbers and
we want to find out if we can partition
the array into two halves right and both
have both halves have an equal subsystem
for example in this case this is one
five eleven five ryan
can we partition this array into two
halves
whichever five and eleven yeah whether
so look one five five
five five is ten and first one yeah and
eleven is separate eleven is a separate
subsequent okay so for in we can proof
off yeah because the pro to profit
to generate all the subsequence it takes
the o two to the power of n right
because for each number we can choose to
pick or skip
and then there are n numbers so each one
is so you multiply two n times that's
the two to the power of n
let's the time complexity if we go in
for the blue forcing that's too slow and
especially for each one it's
subsequently generated we have to check
that we have the calculated sum right
and it takes another end time so it
needs to times n right
that's way too slow so yesterday we
talked about top-down dynamic
programming which we declare uh dpis
so which
which means that can we pick the numbers
from i
to the end that's a sub array we can can
we pick
can we pick the subset from this range
which is subset s right so then it need
um
so
so it has this dynamic programming uh
equation
yeah that's the original version
so look
if i reached the end then we need to
check if the subsequent s equals zero
right and if at any point as fail falls
below zero that means that we're using
too much sum
we we are using too much numbers uh for
this
for this subsequence and then we
determine fourth yeah because all the
numbers in in the array is positive
numbers positive integers if the sum
falls below zero it will never come back
to zero right
and then the equation will be like if we
pick this number then we start from the
we have used this number and we start
from next number and the sum we reduce
the sum right
if we don't pick this number then the
sum remains right makes sense
okay so this is based on these but we
can also make it
make it slightly different that can we
pick the numbers from the can we pick
the subsequence from the
up to these the first i numbers for the
first i numbers so
with the subset of s so here will be
chance to if s false below to zero we
return we check if the sum is zero this
is still the same and instead of plus
one with minus one right with minus one
going backwards yes going backwards if
we want to calculate put i
so initially
so we want to get uh calculate this
final answer instead of putting the dp
dp 0 right and we now we need to change
to dp
n minus 1 where n is the number of
elements the index starts from zero so
the last index will be n minus one and
because in order to calculate n minus
one
and
n minus one and then you you'll be
recursively calling n minus uh n minus
two which and again minus three minus
four until i falls below zero that will
be considered left leg okay
so let's uh dynamic programming
put a top down yeah top down recursive
call calling the uh function recursion
right we we want to call that dpn
cpn and you'll call it dp dpp
n minus one right if we're going for the
first uh the original version we want to
give it a girl dp zero then you'll call
that dp
dp one and go db2 right it's the same
thing
so we can actually
we can actually store the numbers in an
array and then
in a two dimensional array right right
in order to do it
right n
what you're doing
well the time conductance for this one
is
is what this this sum as s and the
numbers will be n so the time come next
will be s n o s n
space complexity is also osm because of
putting the cache and each combination
of i and s
so there are possibilities here and
there are s possibilities here right so
we multiply that that that's the space
we're going to save we wanted to use
right we're catching the values
so we can actually using the bottom-up
approach
but i've approached so we in in order to
do this spot out we need to store the
numbers we need to store the numbers uh
in a two dimensional array okay in a two
minute dimensional array so i'm just
going to write it okay
so the beginning will be the same we
first of all we sum up the sums and we
check if the number is even or if it's
odd then return first immediately
because there's no way to to split the
partition in the array into two sub sum
okay
so i'm going to define
let's say
subset sound
ryan what are you still singing i'm not
singing okay
okay s equal uh
total modulus 2
half
equals total
divided by 2. let's just
let's just substitute some we are
looking for right we're looking for
remember for each number we pick or skip
right
so now we have we want to convert at
least the dp function into a two
dimensional array so we have a list
so at the beginning with each one we
sell the pulling at the beginning with
force
for underscore in
range
so
that would be
half half plus one
yeah because we're going to use the half
half index so we need to plus one here
and then for
in
range
okay so we are missing an n equals
length number
that's the index and then n plus one
so this is the two-dimensional way so we
can use this dpi
s so okay so
let's just go for one version because
the other one remember we for this i we
can interpret in two different ways
right so first first way is as we said
yesterday so we are looking for the
numbers
from i
to the end right
and the second second way of
interpreting psi will be nums
up to i plus one right up to i right for
the index up to i
so we're going to going for this
approach because this is quite similar
okay
so if we go
go for this approach we are looking for
to find
find the subsequence in this range with
the subset sum s at least return true or
false right so let's then we store these
intermediate values in here
so at the beginning we need to do what
for i in
range
range n right right n
d p
i
zero
equals
equals one
i look we
at any point can we find the subset sum
which equals zero and
this
is it two of us
can we find it
yes two of us
[Music]
substitutions here yes yes because look
0 means we don't pick right we're not
picking right so it's true
right then we can do this for
because look in order to calculate at
least dpi
then i need the value of dpi plus 1
right
i plus 1 right because remember at this
point we choose to pick or not pick and
i'm going to the next one
so let's say if i'm going for i i need
the dpi plus one so i need to
iterate and
iterate the
the index from backwards right right
okay this is quite tricky okay
if we want to calculate dpi
and that's based on dpi plus one right
so i need to iterate the index
from
n backwards right
yeah
[Music]
make sense
because look because if i iterate from
this one
i idp one but db2 is not calculated
right so i need to calculate iterate
this backwards i calculate pp2 and then
i get calculated dp1 right because 2 is
already calculated so that would be from
and n minus 1 minus 1 to the n
minus 1
and then for
j
in numbers
if j
is smaller than
is it smaller than
uh nums
i or actually it should be bigger right
and then dp
is what
if if it's first law if it's smaller if
if i is smaller than dp
dpi
j will be equals to dpi minus one i no
no no because look we are using dpi plus
one here
i plus one here and j
right
we're going backwards right
if look if j is smaller than if j is
smaller than nums i
uh
s
d p i
j
equals d p i
[Music]
past one
uh
okay so let's start in detail
okay no no no this is not number so this
is half okay we are we are we need to go
through the half okay this is the
from half
up to minus one to zero minus one okay
that's the mistake because the second
the first iteration would be going
through the index they are going to like
that the second iteration of going
through the subset sum okay such as sum
so j will be something if the subset sum
is smaller than the left then then we
can't pick any numbers right because
this one is smaller if it's bigger then
we can take to this
num is i
okay
and then we turn
remember at the beginning we're talking
about uh
yellow and then what sum are we looking
for
what time are we looking for
we start from zero what somehow
half yeah we're done half
okay let's double check because look
this is a
there are more details here right
especially the index right and it's it
might be easier to use the top-down
dynamic programming because we can let
the computer handle it in the location
right what you're doing ryan
okay
uh
let me double check okay let me just
double check if j is smaller than arms
if j smaller than okay
dpi
[Music]
sorry
nothing
okay so there's one missing
look this one is to
because we we haven't got enough
in this integer this number is bigger
than the sum right
now we can't pick it obviously then we
will start from the next one and this
one
while we we can't have the ticket so we
can pick on our pick right so we can
have this dpi plus one
not pick
or
we pick it right so this is pick or not
pick so there's one missing here
and then we we because at i we need to
retrieve the value for i plus one so we
need to here we need to put the i minus
n minus two okay the second to the last
value
okay
and now we start from the sec vp 0 is to
get to the first
db 0 at half is that
we're checking that can we make the
half from the first element onwards okay
okay
yeah i think i think that
that's correct
let's should be correct
okay no no no no yeah no yeah
okay
look
we we are calculating the dpij and then
based on dpi plus one look look this is
quite tricky okay it's based on dpi plus
one only right yeah
so we can save these
same
space right instead of two dimensional
we can only we can use the one
dimensional okay we can use one
dimension because in order to when we
calculate dpi we only need the dpi plus
one value
right
okay so how can we save it
so let's say save it let me just write
it here okay let me just write it here
so instead of two dimensional i need a
one dimensional and then
one dimension that will be
at the beginning will be fourth
for
in
what what's that
range
half half plus one okay
so instead of
instead of two dimensional way we we use
the one-dimensional way
and then we just do this for
i
in
range this is the same yeah for i in
regular
for under
so let's go through the numbers for j in
numbers we're going through the numbers
and then
for i in
range
we start from half
and then
as
yellow
minus one minus one right
yeah we started yeah
and then what
uh
if
if j the number is smaller is
is smaller than this half the sum right
smaller than sum now we do this
dp
i because we're calculating this dpi
equals dpi
or dp
i minus j right and then we just can do
this we tan
vp half okay vp half
yeah
is it one dimensional array
and we're going through this each number
look for j in numbers this is actually
corresponds to the first loop which we
are iterating over the index the numbers
the second loop the inner loop is always
going through the
subset sum okay and then if if the
number is smaller than the subset sum
uh small i will say smaller or equal
okay smaller than equal yeah
p and the first number dp0 let's say
dp0b needs to be true okay this is one
thing missing dvi will be dpi or dpi
minus j j is the numbers okay yeah
yeah and then dp half look this way we
are saving the term complexity is still
the same right because we have two loops
right we have two loops the first row as
i said going through the numbers if
there are n numbers the second loop
we're going to the subset sum which is
half okay s
the time capacity will be o and s but
the space convexity here
is os and the previous one
previous one is o n times s okay which
is better
[Music]
this one is better yeah yeah because
look we
instead of o and s space we are using
is os
the time convexity is the same okay if
two algorithm
they perform the same thing but which
one use the
one of them use the less memory
is that one a better one
not really sorry what do you mean not
really if there are two come on listen
to me these two backgrounds right yes
they have the time complexity both is on
s but this one use the ons space this
one use the os space which one is bigger
better
come on i just said which the one used
the less memory is better right right
yeah so this is the map does it make
sense look if two things run
run particularly them for some time
yeah all right
yeah
if both algorithms run at the same time
some complexity but one of them use less
memory obviously is better right yeah if
both
both aggregate use the same space but
one of them use the is faster which one
is better the one which is faster yeah
of course this is easy to compare but
how about however sometimes in reality
reality it's not always like that it's
like okay
you can okay it's like this it's like
okay you have uh
uh this is time this is uh space okay
one the first argument yeah
maybe o and time and then you need to o
n space all right but the second second
approach is o n square time but you need
a one space so do you think which one is
better
you see
the first agreement the time is based
complexities o n the second
argument the time compresses o n square
quadratic and the space is always
constant calculated we also call it the
time polynomial time okay polynomial
so do you think which one is better
this one but this one is more more space
than that it's faster than this but it's
use more space you see
do you see the problem is that i know
there's always a trade-off yeah
trade-off you trade the space for the
speed
right this one is slow but it use less
space okay so there's no right or wrong
answer here right there's no right or
wrong but if i say okay this is also all
in time oh and space so which one is
better
oh obviously
yeah yeah you see one of them yeah yeah
okay that's it for today bye bye bye bye