hello hello
allow me stay with mr right now all
right okay so let's visit the binary
trees okay butter cheese binary trees
okay we talk about vinyl trees a lot of
times spinach
so in one sentence what spinal choice
is a tree with numbers
and the last two kids
okay
the left and the left of
the tree the root must be smaller than
it and then let's find the research
trick okay you're talking a little bit
more about it
okay so i pick the keywords okay so
two right binary two right
yeah and the numbers it's actually the
notes does not necessarily be numbers it
could be strings you know any type of
data so binary is like a data structure
okay it's a tree and what are trees
trees are directed a cyclic graph okay
yeah
directly means that it it's actually
don't have a doesn't have a
direction but we we call it directly
ascetical because usually we were given
these trees pine trees you know whatever
now we can only visit the kids from my
parents so it's always one direction
yeah we cannot go in a reverse order
yeah
unless you store the you know the
parents that's totally the other story
exactly it doesn't have a cycle if it
has cycle we call it graph okay it
doesn't have cycles
graph okay the trees are graph and the
binary tree particularly let a kid a
parent can only have two kids a mouth
you can have one kid you can have two
kids but you cannot have more than that
if it doesn't have any kids we call it
leaves okay if the parent if if a kid if
a note doesn't have a parent like what
what do we call it
[Music]
foreign okay so for this binary tree if
we remove one edge what will happen
uh it will
separate and be a forest
well done it will separate into two two
trees two sub
two trees okay one tree will be the
subset subtree of the another one of the
entire tree okay
so we call it uh let's multiply the sum
of these two right for example if i
remove this edge
so that will become a four okay so
what's the sum of these remaining trees
uh it's uh
eleven eleven then that's times the sum
which is forty-four
okay and then how about if i remove this
edge
that'll be ten times five is fifty okay
so this this is the maximum okay if we
keep removing because look they have how
many choice can we do can we separate
how many edges
if we cut that yeah yeah one four three
four so if you cut one edges they'll
become two okay
so we want to find out to maximize the
splitted sum
yeah
okay we want to maximize the split
system
how are we doing we how can we do it i
mean we
can do that so look this time
maxim sound okay so if we remove it
right so first of all
if we remove it
if we remove it we'll get two trees
right let's focus about the subtree
right because look if i remove this edge
this is a sub tree right if we know the
sub tree and
if known as substrate let's say if the
total sum is t okay
right
all right the total sum is t we can do
this with definitions your preference
search one go you won't go right yeah
remember if it is t and then if i tell
you b the sum of these is
our sub 3 is left side t prime
okay
okay what's the subtree of the remaining
i just actually
written
written there sorry
if the whole infinite sum of all
everything is t and if the subtree if
these subject
t prime and then what's the remaining
sum come on it's very obvious
one
that
no
sorry the whole minus t prime t minus d
prime yeah i would just written there
and then wrap it down
and then yeah you see so
yeah yeah so look at that maximum sum we
want the maximum these we have t
minus t prime
times t prime
right t
t minus t prime is least this will be
yeah if we remove this bit t prime is
this bit
okay so it's actually
t minus t prime is listed times t okay
so we want to maximize maximize we want
to maximize this maximize
maximize t minus t prime times t okay
uh
times equal okay sorry times t one okay
yeah
so in order to get this t
sum we can do this different social
processors it's easy yeah let's let's
quickly write it it's easy we've written
this before us defy
loot
if not
that pen is bad
nothing
then the sum will be what
[Music]
it's not good
okay it's wet
returns yellow okay
land return return
lose the value plus the left bit what's
that speed come on it's easy recursion
it's easy um depends
root of value plus the left bit sum what
and then plus somewhat the question come
on
i also calculated the sum of the entire
tree and then if the node is empty i can
return
and
and lose the value plus the left b plus
the right come on this is the easy part
you can figure it out
huh
yeah easy this is easier look at that
with the question and the question
look at the the sum of the entire tree
equals what look the sum of entire tree
equals one
plus the left the three the sum of the
that tree and the sum of right three
which is we already know we already know
yeah this is the recursion yeah yeah
okay make sense this is easy so if we go
in if we perform this step as search
because then recursive definition once
that takes over in time if they are
unknown right then we get this t right
right yeah
so then we could do another test search
and then at the meantime yeah we at the
meantime we
can because this is the such sum of
every sub tree right basically is the
sum of every subject this is the same as
we remove one edge right so we try every
possibility of removing each edges
so once we become remove one edges
once we become removing the edges that
would be a sum
yeah that would be a partial sum of
another subtree right
so we can do this
no
so we can we can do another type of
study okay
and
i possibly need
okay
wait give me one second
so guys let's have a little chat okay
sit down please
please okay so
so we can do another different search
okay tf
search route
so at the meantime we have this answer
at the beginning let's say
max infinity the negative
the the most small is the number we can
think of is the uh
minus negative okay minus negative okay
so this part is quite the same yeah if
not root
return return of zero actually we we
just copy over right i know we can have
uh these so the left bit
so so what the
the current will be equals rule the
value
plus therefore search rule the left
plus therefore search blue dot right
okay so once we have these values okay
so this is the subset summary so we can
say okay answer
equals max
answer yeah we want to get the maximum
right but now we know the total sum
right so before we call this function we
have a total
so the let's say this is called t equals
sum
blue right so we we use this function
to get the sum first and then t times
t minus
current times carbon right yeah that's
what we said yeah
right now we are at this point we know
that's the sum of this subtree right
yeah
and then t t is the total sum minus
the current subtree is the remaining
tree that's the the sum of linear tree
and times itself okay and then we turn
this is the same return
current
okay
yeah so we do this once we do this twice
uh to another so look these two
functions is quite similar right except
that
this function by itself
by itself is returns the
these two functions is actually the same
returning the sum of the current
sub carbon tree the only difference is
that we have added this plug in here
plug in this value to obtain the max
split tree a split sum
but it needs these t first right we
don't have this value first right so
that's why i need to call this function
first so get this t right because the
sum of a total tree doesn't change right
am i
yeah we can manage financing you know
the sum but yeah already right it's
never changing right it's not changing
but we can't call this function directly
because t we haven't known right we need
to get it
yeah right
this is o n this is o
[Music]
sorry
if i perform this oh n and this is our n
what's added together
okay so another way another way would be
will be similar to this instead of doing
this we can store all the values all the
subsystem in the in a set right in a set
which is unique yeah in a set and then
we can go through the set of later right
so i'm just clicking
yeah
[Music]
so we can go so look we have this sum
okay let's say
uh sum okay some equal a set right
what's that
what's set
set is
like if you it's better than the um
because if if you look up so for
something you would say set is 01 but in
list is
oh and yeah
okay it's not there is no one better
than the other it's just for different
purposes the set stores the unique
numbers only yeah it's a unique it only
stores the unique
elements all right
so let's say we have empty set and then
we have this therefore search first yeah
so this is the simple yeah if not loot
if you're not root return yellow yeah
yeah
and then left beat equals definite
search but the sum of the left tree
the sum of variety
because therefore search
through the right
yeah because requested recording this
function to attempt the sum from the
left bit left tree and left right by
three okay now we can do this sum
dot at
we add the left tree right look i need
to yeah and it looks
so one two three four five six seven so
look if calling this loot here and i
will call the left which is the three of
these the sum would be two four five
two plus four plus one eleven and i
added that eleven to the set okay
i thought right three what's the sum of
the right three is three plus six plus
seven is sixteen and i put a 16 in the
set right
right right
and also the current would be what
so i also need to add one thumb dot add
left
plus right
plus neutral value right
and i need to return this value return
this lieutenant speaker so let's total
okay let's put it let's say uh we can
save this in a value total left plus
right
plus neutral value
okay
look yeah
so
once i've done this what should i do
next next once i've done this i watch i
do next
we
run it so look if i do this i some add
the set
as the possible left tree sum the right
tree sum and then all over all right so
i need to go through the set right
right
and i know this uh i know these that's
the total right so i can do this
uh total equals that's a search root
for i yeah and then that goes through
that i in this set yes some sum set okay
and then answer
also be the minimum again
infinity yeah infinity
answer equals max
answer
t minus i right times i right
yeah this is the same so we actually we
do this we first of all perform this
step search and then we're collecting
all the sums in the set
yeah so the set contains all the
possible subsets sum because we're
adding the left sum
the right sum and then the current
overall sum right and then we go through
the set again
t yeah we already know this t also okay
so this function return that does two
purposes
first of all is to collect the values
the possible sums in this in set the
second value
the the purpose second purpose is to
return the sum
of the overall tree of the currency
right what it just did you just say
it to some of the overall things of the
tree and then what's the second purpose
the second purpose
is to
uh
add the overall
what are these sorry
i don't know
the um
[Music]
huh
what's the two purpose of this function
come on if you read this function
okay the search
uh is not ready to return zero yeah i
know i can read the code whatever what i
mean is what's the purpose of this
function what does it do come on
what's this what what what does they do
they are two things here yeah first
thing
and here's two things okay so what what
is these two
i'm saying like what's the purpose of
this function come on
um
some add
left yeah i know what's what
and some of the
ad right is adding the right part yeah
into
the set
is and it returns the answer
the value of the the sum of the country
yeah
okay that's two purposes yes i know you
understand yeah okay
but you need to work out on your
presentation skill to make it clear to
to demonstrate that okay extremely well
okay and then by going through this
number the subset there's some possible
sums in this in a
in a set
now we can try we can calculate the
maximum of the space sum right
yeah look
t minus i times i what's this mean come
on
e minus minus i times i yeah what's tm
can you explain to me what's this t
minus i times i
it's a t
which minus i and times i yeah what does
it mean
so what's t
t
did she
what's the t here t equals definition
what's t t is the difference it is the
difference actually
the tree what is in detail what does it
mean
what does it you just say here then t
equals definition so what's this meaning
the whole tree what what of the whole
tree
what are we doing here what are the
whole tree so what's the value if i call
t equals dfs good loot is here points to
here what
what what's the value of it
what's the value what's this t
t is the
value
is the what values come on what's the
what do we tell is the value huh it's a
load here root is one so what i call t
equals f research root and what does t
equal
t equals one
two
one one over two
what are we doing here one two three
four five six seven yeah whatever what i
would do with the number three
one two
wait one
what's this function return left plus y
plus root of value rule of value is one
left is
root left one two four three five six
seven
yes i okay you're still not getting it t
equals stiffer such load if we know that
if this is the tree i know that it's
pointing to here this is the loop
and what does it return if you say okay
it's written that plus y plus root of
value so the left is dfs root on left
here
right html to the right value is one so
it equals one plus the left b plus the
right bit so that okay so the left bit
equals two plus the that bit plus the
rabbit so it's recursion so so once this
function returns what
does it return
11 right now
the left face
[Music]
the right street yeah i know the left 3
plus the right trick what plus how do
you press the left tree and the
parachute the numbers what do you what
do we do with the numbers
that's the one i want um i want add them
together that's the sum okay t is the
sum so it's one plus two plus three plus
four plus five plus six yeah so that's
how much 38 right is it 28
wait two plus four six single five is
eleven eleven plus uh yeah okay
twenty eight okay so t twenty eight the
possible sum okay the left left bit is
one two plus one so i what's in the sum
sum is four five six seven yeah i know
what two plus four has five
yeah what's that
two plus
and then all together is what
is what 28 right okay
so i need to go through this number and
then i try to do this t minus i times i
okay coming back to this question what's
t minus i times i
it's the sum
minus
this is the total sum and the minus
i is here i see here i is here in one of
the
t minus i times i what does it mean
it means the total sum
subtract
the
i there yeah what does i represent the
left and right tree it's the sum of the
left right
is the sum of any sub tree right yeah
so remember coming back to this question
we want to split remove one edges and
split into two if we remove this one
edge
then this sum would be two plus one plus
five which is eleven and twenty-eight i
know 28 right so what's the sum of this
bit
it must be
something where down yeah the total is
28 never change this is 11 right so the
other part is 28 minus 11 and then last
product is what
t minus i times i that's it
makes sense
yeah we're done okay that's it for today
good job
bye