hello mr mr ryan all right
okay so
we have a rod or rose or whatever a
stick yeah
yeah
basically the straight thing and we know
the length which is n this is the
integer positive integer
right
so we want to cut it
yeah we know
we want to cut it and sell it yeah we
want to cut it and say so
for example like if we have these
you know we have all these array prices
array okay
which is one three five
seven seven right let's see
okay so it means that if we kind of grow
it in colorado okay let's try a lot if
color rot with size one we can sell it
at one dollar
size two
three dollars five three five dollars
okay
okay so look this is i right so
basically price i
price i
means that we can sell the size with
size
i plus one right why is that parasol
because i is the index the first element
is zero okay
so if the n equals six right
if n equals six
how can we
cut the rod so that we sell the maximum
profit
so for example six i can cut it with one
plus five
right so in this case i will have i will
say what one plus
seven yeah
yeah okay that's
size one two three four five so one plus
seven
right
so that's eight
but if i cut it into three plus three
so one two three here so i could set it
with ten so this is bigger right or i
can cut it with two plus
four
so i could set it with
two plus five
uh
two plus four six and equal six so i
would say with three dollars for
for the size two three and four
for the six
so that would be two plus
so that could only be six
why is the complete on six could only be
do you get this problem
no no not really okay
sorry you get it kind of okay so look if
we said it was that if n equals six then
we can
split into two and four two for two
would be three dollars for four would be
seven dollars so
three plus seven is also ten right
any other options like
one five
three three two two four okay this is
only option right
okay
makes sense
so
how
what's your approach of doing this
what's your approach think about it
um
okay so you just see that price and
write
uh
everything up to the end that's right
yes and then like one two three four
five and
[Music]
again
five is seven well i know so we try
every possibility there we see look this
is the integer so we we we talked about
let's play how to split the integer
before right so if we have this as n
which is integer
we can spread this and right we can use
the default search preferences right
yeah
to do it so we can try with one okay so
one i split it to one i calculate this
so we have this function differential
with this current
uh what we with the remaining we know we
remember n right and then with this
current profit
right with the current profit
and what else do we need
and we can just look it up right so
let's just quickly write the suitable
for the different search and then
yeah
so look
uh actually definitely says n right so
we don't probably not normally uh don't
need the left profit thing define
okay
so
we want to find out
what the maximum right so we will have a
maximum
maximum perfect here right so let's say
maximum profit
at the beginning is zero right yeah
maximum perfect now we can look at this
we want to find out this n
we want to cut this n right cut this end
so we can try every possibility so at
the beginning for i
in range
right
for this end i can cut it or not tactic
right all right
yeah
so for this i i i range let's say
let's say what
so i want to try look for this n i can
try with up to n plus one right
up up to n plus one
yeah
and then i can cut it
uh hold on cut it
d f s i
right we can give us i
uh actually no dfs n minus i n minus i
plus
twice so now i can have this price i for
i right where is i but n minus i minus
one right because i start from zero
right
yeah
yeah make sense
now i have this answer will be at the
beginning of the match dot infinity
and then this answer will be the mean of
this answer
and then this week right and i just need
to write return answer all right
okay so now here i need to check if n is
smaller or equal than zero return zero
right
right yeah
so what's the problem with this one
why is it
actually
because and price price is uh
the okay so this index starts from zero
to 10 minus one
so but the the actual size it represent
is one to n right so it needs to plus
one so this is n
and that needs to m minus i minus the
price i right
right look
yeah so look look
i try every possibility for for i
currently the rod size is n right so the
log size is n how many possibilities of
cutting this i have this for example n
equals three how many possibilities of
cutting three and equals
zero one two three
how many possibilities six
the n equals three by n equals three
the size they are three how many how
many ways of cutting it
i can cut is one to two right or i can
cut it in two to one
or i can cut it with zero
sorry yeah is it sweet
so look i cut three ways cut it
if i don't cut it if i don't cut it
okay so look if n equals 3 here i is
from zero to two right i is from zero to
two so price will be from zero to two
oh okay yeah if i don't cut it actually
if we if i don't cut it the size will be
remaining the three right right okay
if i equals two
uh if i equals to two then n minus two
minus one okay so then i the remaining
would be n minus three x okay that makes
sense make sense
okay so look
what's this look i have a a rod with
size n
right
yeah yeah yeah this is basic so i try i
can try cutting with the
one cutting with two cutting with three
look if i cut it with i right
with cutting with the size i
okay look if i cutting with the size
um
size i actually is i i plus one the size
here is i plus one okay
okay so what's what's here what's
remaining here if this is i plus 1
what's here
the whole the whole thing is n
if this is i plus and what's here
n
minus i plus 1
plus
i
minus i
what
this is i plus one n minus i
minus one
minus one right so this speed is smaller
okay so if i cut if i want to keep a
size with i plus one so this bit i can
get a profit of what
price price i right yeah this is known
right
yeah okay
this speed is known yeah
and what's the what's the speed what's
this bit what's the price for getting
there
n minus i minus all right this is the
size
so but we we are not sure how many cuts
for this right so then we can call this
step from a different
dfs function to solve the problem with
the smaller size right
yeah so that's what this part is about
you see
yeah and then i i can do this with
answers and compare with get the minimum
okay what's what's the problem of this
approach definitely
okay if i tell you that
if i tell you that there's an easy way
to make a default search the proof of
thing deficit
into a dynamic programming
and
you have used this before so what will
it be
if i tell you an easy way there's an
easy way between this approach if i edit
something here that will be become a
top-down directory programming
what's the problem of this theory it
will be explaination because we
calculated yeah yeah we're going to put
a cache here right oh yeah oh yeah
[Music]
sorry nothing
uh
[Music]
what's the what's the why
what's this bit
we speak therefore search n minus i
minus one what's the can you expensive
okay so we know this is i
i mean i plus one and we can track it
and this is n minus i minus one but it
hasn't been
okay so you kind of yeah i understand
right now but yeah okay so
so we are trying every possibility for
this size and yeah we can try you know
keep a size with the keep a fixed size
right we only sell the size first part
of this yeah and then i get the profit
prices i right
and then when i cut a color size keep
the size i plus one and i have the
remaining size
so then i can call this function
recursive recovery function
deficit here
to find out to compute
the profit i can make
the profit i can make by
cutting you know at this point we are
not sure
the best of optimum way of cutting that
it would be no cut all there will be
many cuts but we don't know but we call
this function to recursively find it out
right
yeah
look this answer at the beginning is max
infinity and we're getting the minimum
we compare the minimum right and this is
this part is for i i already made the
decision i so this part i make the
decision so every time i make a little
decision right
look this this whole whole rod
i don't know how many cards i want right
that would be too complicated to
consider all these right but what should
i do now i can try okay let's make a
little
little decision what is that i can make
a decision okay i can cut the size with
one
yeah i can keep a size with one i can
keep the size with two i can keep a size
with three right
so i can keep size with this eye
and once i keep a size with i then i
know
the profit i made from from from cutting
this bit right right yeah
and then i i can keep doing this right
make sense
at least is explanation without the cash
right remember the difference that dfsn
is the maximum profit if we can
share
the rope with the size n right
and then i'm iterating all possibilities
of cutting the size n with the first cup
i
with the first cut i when i first
cut the size with the first i
i have remaining n minus i minus 1
right
and then i look this is a smaller size
with n at least it's smaller than n
right
you see
if this is smaller with n and i can
recursively calling me something to
solve a smaller problem
right
eventually i can look i need to produce
if n is smaller than zero if n
if n is zero the base cases
right too noisy if the n is zero means
that the size is zero what's that i can
sell empty i can sell air what
for nothing so what's the price of
selling nothing
right we're done zero
right okay
what do we call this dynamic programming
what kind of dynamic programming is this
top down
top down yeah is it total
yes
okay this is the top-down anime
programming so
uh so tomorrow we'll talk about butter
up okay
yeah and
what's the time from next year space
complexity
[Music]
let's look at their n
n right but for each one i have to do
this
one square yeah one square but the space
complexity
i want
i have a cache why is there one what's
the space from recipe
every ryan
anyone one final answer what's the specs
from let's see look at that n i put a
cache
how many states i need to store need to
catch
two
two or two
look at this n if n is a hundred how
many how many values of dfs and i need
to stop yeah one hundred and what's that
oh and yes we are done
yeah i know and look at that but the
space is the time is o n square why is
that for each end i need to iterate with
that
with n right got it
okay
okay that's it for today bye