hello mr mr ryan are you right yeah
okay so remember what uh what we talked
about yesterday
the lot yeah the rod we only cut the
rods
yeah and we want to sell the rods
right
so uh one three five seven seven
seven okay so that's the wrong if we can
sell the drop color rock and we can sell
the rock if size one is
for size one we got one dollar for size
two we get three dollars size five three
we get five dollars etc okay if we have
a lot we size six
and the maximum profit we can get is
cutting into two pieces of three then we
get ten dollars or you can cut it with
what with two and four and still get ten
dollars okay
yeah this is actually a unbounded nut
set problem what's next
that step
what's in that step anybody
net set
okay nasa it's a bed yeah it's his back
look
nuts okay look
okay
so i'm balding upside
what does it mean it means that
we have a few items yeah yeah this is
the item we have
we have items
items these is the
item value okay let's say the value of
items
[Music]
ready song item and then the size for it
for for each one is one two three four
five six this is the size for that this
is the value for that and we have a nut
set
which has compressed uh
capacity with n
and for each item you can choose as many
as you want
as long as the total
weight does not
exceed the total capacity capacity okay
and then we want to maximize the value
right we call it anabolic net set
and bounding
okay so look we want to maximize we want
to maximize what we want to maximize
the profit
which is what
so for these items yeah we can pick as
many items as we want right so let's say
for each one we pick uh
we pick one number the the
lowercase n and i okay so we want to
pick p equals n i
and i
times its values v i
yeah
we get the sum
as long as what as long as dc
uh as long as what
as long as its total capacity
does not uh is less or equal than n
right so the total capacity is what uh n
i
and i okay that's the weight okay let's
say the weight weight i okay
yeah
as long as the total capacity
n i times w i
right yeah w i is less or equal than
total capacity bigger n okay
and because w i equals i plus 1 right i
plus 1 if i start from 0 so we can
change this to
i plus one okay
yeah this is an upset i'm bounding
upside and yesterday we used the
what what kind of approach did we use
yesterday
[Music]
so eventually you make it work
top-down dynamic programming okay so
let's review this a little bit cache
yeah what's cache caching is asking
computer to memorize the values for us
okay yeah so this is the magic keyword
okay so we are asking computer to
memorize yeah because if you don't ask
computer to memorize you just forget
and next time you ask it to calculate it
will happen
he forgets you calculate again it takes
some right but if we add thing with cash
okay then if dividends three it
calculates for example it's like it
stays time uh it spends like 10 minutes
to calculate it right
yeah
and i remember it he remember in his
memory yeah he his memory yeah and the
next time like five minutes later i
asked computer what's different three
does he need to do calculator again now
you just you need to be fetching from
from the cashier for the cash what's
cash
what is the meaning of the cash
remembering
okay remember it's associated with
remembering so what's cash thing
it's like memorizing you know the
cashier money
not that cash this not this cash cash
c-a-c-h-e cash
what's this in english
testing cashing is that
another language
yeah caching is like computer cache
memory you can you can treat it as a
memory right
it's exactly the purpose of this i catch
it
i i catch it for later uses okay
so and when i try for look
if the size is n
if the left side is and then i can cut
it in n ways right so each way i cut it
if cassie i keep the size with i right
keep the size with i plus one actually
and then profit i'm keeping that is
price i
and the remaining size is n minus i
minus one and i could recursively
calling the differences function and now
we want to calculate
la
what
uh we don't calculate the maximizer so
it's the maximum profit
okay so why i write the minimum here
this is the maximum right this is the
maximum yeah we want to get the maximum
they're not a minimum okay that was a
mistake okay
yep
uh
so now so what's butter out right so top
down let the computer to cache it for us
the bottom up we need to remember the
things ourselves and using the static
error array so we remember the values in
the array okay edp yeah dp array okay so
let's
write it
so we want to ap able to caches the
uh to be able to store n
and values for dpn right so let's say
so look for previously this defaults and
make a noise again
we have n values so now we just have a
dp array which is at the beginning at
zero times n plus one okay
so leave we are starting the values in
this dp array right
then i can go through the values i want
to check i want to
i want to calculate which is n plus one
and then i need to go through the values
up to range i
yeah
and then dp
i
equals the minimum of
dpi and then
l-y-m
so look i'm i want to calculate the
i-d-p-i value this is because from the
previously dfsn right okay i want to
calculate the dpi value
i want to get a maximum so how many i
can cut it in j ways yeah in general so
i can cut it as pp
so now the remaining of this was i minus
j minus one right
yeah this is the remaining size
plus price
price this is the value the value yeah
the value we can get by keeping the size
what
keeping the size what
j right size j plus one right because
they start with zero three by one
right and then return we just return the
dp
n right or we can return dt minus one
right easy you see
that makes sense
i need
so
i got a question yeah that's a good
question
on the fourth line you said it would be
the maximum but you read the
yeah yeah i always like the mistake okay
so it's maximum
what did they say i said maximum minimum
he said maximum five row the minimum
yeah
it proves you're actually listen that's
good right
you're actually listening yeah you pay
attention right okay
yeah because sometimes i read the code i
write a mistake but when i say something
i wrote it i i may
not write by correctly okay okay what's
the time complexity if you're looking at
this what's the time capacity
what's the time to make it different oh
n
last one
that's another root n square
yeah n squared look this i goes to n n
iteration but for each eye it needs to
goes to j right so actually it's look
n plus n minus 1 plus n minus 2 plus
okay so these if you add it together
you'll be something like m plus 1
you know yeah if you add it to 1 then
you n plus 1
divided by 2 okay
n plus n minus 1 plus n minus plus t1
do you recognize this
1 plus 2 plus 3 plus 4 plus 5 the
equation is this this is nothing but
look 1 plus 1 plus 2 plus 3 plus 4 5
yeah plus 200 what's the sum
yeah
100 times 100 plus one divided by two
550 times 101.
what's this
[Music]
yeah exactly so that's the equation here
to sum up the first n
integers
from one okay so look this one if we
wrote it out it would be n square plus n
divided by two first of all we drop the
constant
second of all look this is n square i
have n here but look which is bigger n
square and n
which is bigger
if n bigger than one and
square and square yeah so yeah square
this is bigger so
in
what we said complexity we always keep
the most dominant one right because this
is much more complicated than this one
so we also dropped it okay
it makes sense yeah we talked about this
before so that time comes let's say oh n
square that's why we get the o n square
okay
yeah because look the second iteration
does not go to the end right it goes to
the i only right if this goes to n
for each i
for each n
another n so that's n square that's
easier right we can easily get one
square but for this one i goes to n for
each j goes to i
so that's what we get
so let's let's the complexity is
actually all n squared plus n divided by
two first of all we drop the constant
second of one we drop the smaller parts
so we keep these most dominant part
which is on square that's why we did it
yeah space from xt
what's here look at me how do you play i
won
oh n yeah because we are allocating n
right and one last one
okay o n plus one is actually one okay
we drop the constant we don't talk about
the constant
in the time or space complexity okay
yeah make sense
look at this one what's this what's this
we want to calculate dti first iteration
we want to call calculus dpi right cpi
and then for each each size of i
i can cut it into remember the previous
one the top down dynamic programming we
we go through there and uh
and uh ways of cutting the rod right so
if now i
keep going
no no if i keep the size with j plus one
and the remaining size is i minus three
minus one remember i asked you this
question yeah remaining so this is the
remaining one we use previously we're
using the recursion with the cache
ask computer to do it to look it up the
values we calculated before now we're
looking up in a stationary
in in an array right because we are
memorizing
memory
you know we remember those things those
values using a array by ourselves right
proactively remembering the value
and this is the profit
price j can anybody explain to me what's
this bit price j
yeah
um
that's the size yeah yeah they use the
size thing and the price is like the
price for each size yeah the value and
the value we can get yeah so look that's
a low yeah if i cut it with leaves this
is the bit i can sell for the for my
money yeah and then remaining i don't
know how much how many how many clocks
right i look it up here okay this is i
look it up this bit i cut it with j
and the value i can get is here i don't
want to get the messy one okay
make sense
yeah that's it for today good job bye