hello mr eric are you right
okay
so
remember we talked about professor
stephan right okay so that's one easy
graph one a b
c
the
e
okay so this is the quad
and directive yeah undirected there is
no direction undirected
graph okay and then
what's the perfect search order if we
start from a this is the sauce
a b c d e
and we use the q right yeah we push the
look at the beginning we push the q q
equals a right no right
so we take a no a we visit it yeah
yeah of course because it's a graph
and we don't want to revisit the note b
again once we visit it right so we take
the a out we check if we have a scene
and we have a signal we have seen we
have we have not seen a before so we put
this is output yeah we visited and we
put a here
what's the a's children b c d they'll
push the kids
into it
we take the b b out
right
yeah
we take b out
if it's not seen right we put it out
and then we put it we put this in here
what's the peace children
what's these children
these children
and
because it's un-directional look i
understand i think
a is already seen right
yeah so we don't we don't put it but
okay so b we put a we don't we don't put
it there's a way uh
we can check the theme check even note
we need to check if the note has been
visited before we push it to the queue
so it's been visited so we don't push it
to the queue so we only push the e out
right and we take the c out
we take the cr
we put a scene here what's the c's
children
hey right but we have visited here so we
don't push it right so continue we take
a dr
and now what's the these children
what's this chosen
a visited so we don't put it yeah and a
uh
uh yeah hey we uh we visited so we don't
put it yeah so let's let's put a d here
and then we take it er okay
so let's let's give us the order and
then we take e
a b c d e okay
what's the definite search
order if we start from a
a b e
c
d c
okay
a b e d c so to sum up the breakfast
search travel level by level so it
always increase the distance right so
when we find the c
we know
it's the shortest distance right if it's
an undirected graph we we know it's the
circ
or a to e right
for the data search we explore the nodes
until we can't right look we go to b and
now i'm just trying to follow the load
b
to e
this is quite similar to traveling the
binary tree and we talked about binaural
trees quite a lot right a b c d
f g i
a to b and i can travel to d
and i go back to e
c
f g and the process is a b c
d e f g okay for like breakfast for a
different search we use the stack but
usually we implement with the recursion
and then the computer
to maintain the stack for us because we
call a recursion then computer has the
stack right so the computer needs to
push the core into a stack yeah
so define
therefore search we are covering a
current right
so obviously there is a scene somewhere
we can put in the parameter or here
right
so if current in sin
we just don't continue with this return
otherwise for the note in
g
g is a graph at current
and then we can definitely search and
all right
yeah
and obviously we have to put it if we
check the current diffusion scene then
if not then we seen.add
a column
and that's the difference let's
in a calling exam right
g graph g g is the verb
a set of the vertex and edge right so we
can use the g
g
the vertex here that will give us the
list of the nodes
which for example g a
a will be a list of nodes connected to a
which is
b c d
this is called this is the way
to store the graph which is called
adjacent right
a g a d j a c an adjacent list
because we can
get the list of nodes it connects it
look
a connects to bcd okay how about g b so
what what does g b give us
g b
what's the g b give us
what's the nelson
e yeah and e okay you get it again this
is this adjacent metric is different
adjacent metric is the metric
right so if you have a metric one zero
one
zero
zero one zero one zero zero
one zero
zero zero one one okay this is adjacent
what does it mean
look at this diagonal is always one
because the standard you can say this is
a b c d and then this is a b c d
if a and b is connected you put a one
here right
if a and b is not connected uh look c
and a is not connected equal to zero
right so you basically look it up
right so if there are n vertex here so
these space complexities oh n square
right
yeah look you just look it up for
example d to
d to speed c is one okay can you explain
to me why this this diagonal is one
it's always one
because um there's
this
there's a um
diagonal it's like a a like bb yes
so it's excel right it doesn't matter
actually you can put zero it doesn't
matter because it just means that the
note is is you know it's a node itself
it does not it does not represent
a edge between two vertex right it's a
it's basically a vertex
b to d right you look it up b to b so
look if this metric is mirroring by the
time what does it mean if it's mirroring
the mirroring you know mirroring what if
it's mirror if this is zero and then
diagonal here it's all this is also zero
if this is one this is also one what
does it mean
think about it what does it mean
[Music]
yeah it's undirected right if it's
directed if you look a to c but c
there's no point to a so a to c could be
a to c here is one c to a here
and zero right okay we're done no that's
a good job let's adjacent match adjacent
list
okay so so okay so now we want to visit
the
the preference search okay professor
define whether search
source
which is q
q equals dq here remember we use the dq
pull the source in and then we have uh
scene equals set by the way what's the
advantage of using dq instead of list
because
if you're gonna look up in the list
and
in the list it takes a long time to look
up
and but for this cue we don't need to
look it up we need to do what um
a pen it's a one pop pop from the left
is o n right but for the dq is always
201 in both direction
so y and q
and then we can say say current equals q
dot pop left
and then we can just say for now in g
current
is not if n not
in and then we just queue the append
q dot append and right yeah
and then obviously we need to put it yes
n right this is the
this is the breakfast search right
there
q dq
sim y t or y cube and we'll put the
source in the queue we take
take the q we pop it from the left as
long as the queue is not empty and we
track we push this kit
if it's not being seen to the queue
right yeah look how simple is that right
okay so one question
if i change this queue to stack
step
good question that's a very good point
but i changed this to pop just pop
another stick first in that right yeah
so what will happen does it become a dfs
not really
no really okay yeah your answer is right
but let's let's look it so the default
search is one
a b e okay the difference search is
a b e d c right right yeah
but if we pop it if we're using the
stack so if i push it to the right so
let's
the ladies is the step yeah i put it a i
take it out
a and i put a b c b here d
c b right
the sequence is a okay i'm going to take
a br right
yeah
and then i need to put it what
put the e at e
i take the e
take an e you're just putting it and
then
getting it back
yeah yeah yeah look because i already
visited it's not be seen right this
scene equals a
i take it i i already visited it
equals a right
and
i pushed the kids bcd and bcp let's put
it in the reverse order i take it back
take it out
i take it off
i'm gonna push it to kit which is e
a already visited so i don't push it
okay i take an er
yeah and i push the kids which is d
already push it so
i already push it i don't take it right
so now i take a what's next
c right yeah
so c
uh
ap
okay so a p e c d
e c t block e c t
which is
which is different than a b e d c you
see the difference the temperature is a
b e d c but for if i change this b q
to a stack
yeah i emulate this for you the sequence
is a b e
c d it's different right it's not
so
so preference so first let's search if
we change the queue to step it's not
actually the same as definition
yeah
okay okay so this is just a sign note
okay um
one question the the depth of search
is guaranteed uh shortest path
you know the shortest if i want to visit
the shortest path between a
c
b this is the triangle i want to visit
the shortest path but i want to
calculate the shortest path from a to c
what's the shortest path and directly
okay let's talk about
what's the shortest path
atc yeah
yeah okay but for the tesla search it
might come this first a b c right once
you found the note it's not guaranteed
the optimum right
yeah it's not guaranteed it's like a
tree
a
b
[Music]
c
d
uh it's not optimal okay so
if i
i can do this e
f okay
g
okay and then i have at least another
edge okay l by i have another g
analogy here okay
so look if you do the test search
define the g i want to find the shutter
speed which is the entity you do the
definition you quickly find this but
it's not a shortage it's not a guarantee
right
okay
because there's a path here which is
shorter
make sense
so the test search does not guarantee
the shutter speed unless
unless you will visit all the paths from
a to every element yeah
blue forces because look if i exhorted
all the search to all other
nodes and i can come back get a minimum
right make sense but for the preference
search it's always guaranteed
again i'm talking about under rescue
graph okay the shortest path look a b e
c d f a h g okay i found it this t here
not here right makes sense
but there is a way
to change
okay this is the part of today there's a
way to change these
dfs to
breakfast search to to guarantee a
shortest path that's away
we are adding a
maximum depth
mass depth depth yeah limit oh we call
it that's named
that's name
what what does it mean look
okay let's travel with the maximum
distance one
the short the different search so what
does it give us
a a
okay this is like what's and okay let's
increase the deep depth to two what does
it give us
b and
e okay
okay we still haven't found the target
let's increase one more time the target
to three
yeah
yeah yes kind of like breakfast search
not really breakfast thirty is like
traveled knows by notes but now i'm
saying that i want to do the different
search with the maximum
distance up to three so i can do this a
b c
d e f it doesn't go any further once we
hit the next the distance we stop right
and then we can increase to that small
right that's right okay so in this way
we can find i find it is it faster or
slow
it's like the same as breakfast
not really we okay that's the difference
perfect search for each node here b is
visited once
but look
if i increase the test for differences
look one is the distance two i visit the
b when is instance three i visit the b
again a b c when i increase one more
test abcd you see i repeatedly go over
the test search again and again okay
make sense
so look at
so
the only difference we added for the
test search is to what def test
with no current but we have a maximum p
we added this so
so what is it what so what first of all
if
c u r in sin we still return yeah we
have visited it nobody can
and then we visited g uh sin
carbon uh cinder a current in the air
carbon
okay and then now i added this is one
more okay
if d
uh okay so this d is the maximum uh
maximum d and we also need the current
the current d
currently
this d
is the maximum you can go this is the
current depth so look
if
d
bigger than d
that would be 10 yeah we can just return
because we have a current we are
limiting our search distance to maximum
three steps but now we are traveling too
fast so we stop and then this is the
other thing is the same for n in
g
c u r
right i know what should we do now we
travel t f s
and
this is t never change and i look at t
i need to do what
what what should i do with d
what should i do with the d like that if
i visit one more number what should i do
plus one plus one like that yeah first
one look this is only different
this is the only difference with the
normal theme
and then for the
follower
for the one
then we can say wire not found yeah
not file
the file at the beginning equals number
not file yeah now we can say look
definite search found include default
search
this t
uh
we can start with the source the d
d and then at the beginning is zero
right or one it doesn't matter and then
look
and what should we do we increment the d
plus equals one right
this is to increase
our deepening we call it in iterative
deepening
iterative
iterative deepening
differently means that
we perform the data search with the
depth depth d
and if we found it we we allowed it to
have one more
maximum distance right so we increase
the maximum d
one more right until we found it
so look as as we said the nodes
okay so the nodes with the depth a
and then the certain distance if it's d
it needs to be visited uh how many times
look
this is a okay this is b this is c this
is d
okay now if i want to travel from a to b
a to b is the shortest distance right so
this b how many times it needs to be
traveled how how many summit needs to
visit okay
a not visiting it b
a b
visited one time
a b c which is another times a b c d
music and another so look the the notes
needs to be visited some notes will be
visited one more time right so look at
this distance is one two three right
right and then this distance is
one so
so the the notes needs to be visited
three minus one plus one okay so look
this is d
this is a if this the distance is a and
uh how many times it needs to be
meditative is d minus a plus one okay
make sense yeah
so
it looks like okay we
we have repeatedly
visited no it might be slower right yeah
all right it might work but but there's
advantage of using this
uh iterated differently
look if a tree remember this binary tree
if it's a perfect
either yeah it's the perfect binary or
not perfect we call it what full binary
for banana tree
four by the tree every note every layer
every every note except the this note
this is the leaf number which all have
two notes two children right
yeah
look
if this d equals
the depth equals one two three
what's how many in these notes are there
how many how many
how many notes in depth equals three one
two three four five one two three four
yeah hey
so it's eight actually two to the power
of n right yeah
okay so for the transfer search
we need to
the space complexity look we're talking
about space mode basically needs to
store all these
right
yeah
all right so the space complexity is
exponential for preferences because we
are expanding all the nodes
all the notes right could be exponential
i'm talking about the four binary
yeah follow deepening
for the deepening it's already different
i don't need to store all these notes
right i just need to store the depth
yeah yeah
so let's say
so
it's the space complexity is less than
this
like look i just spread i just need to
use the stack to store
once the path right yeah i don't need to
store any other thing right
yeah
makes sense
yeah any questions so far
really
okay so
okay answer me what's the advantage of
iterating differently and breakfast such
which one but because for the breakfast
search
um
you can okay
so if okay so go like oh yes oh yeah i'm
here
exponential right yeah
okay you'll become bigger bigger bigger
always double
yeah yeah
every time i try one more step okay
let's see if i can visit i can find this
note with the
maximum distance one that's like that i
can't then i increase the step too
i can't
step three so i don't for the test
research i don't actually need to store
all the nodes for the same level right i
don't need to keep a user q
the only the space i need to use for the
depth search is stack
which stores what the path is this piece
right
yeah oh n right
yeah
o n this is o n and this is o to n right
so the space it's already depending is
faster than than
normal speed i'm talking about the space
space safety a space is used
space used by the devil search is less
than a professor in terms of you know in
some class right and for you you know
for some uh complex algorithm like uh
uh meme max 3 or you know play chess
yeah you know the chess
i play one i want to get a chest usually
two players
yeah you know it's like i i you play a
chess i i take one i move one step you
move one step so look i want to
maximize the score like a hundred and
then you want to minimize the score
right so that's
yeah you take one step and then
i i take the mac
folders
up
layer i want to maximize for the even
layer you want to minimize
huh yeah because each one take a turn
right
and then for this in this kind of
chess playing algorithm usually we use
iterated deepening
to allow us caching some
you know some
states
so it's actually
not
it's actually faster than breakfast
search okay in some cases okay
it might be a bit too complicated but
okay what's your most important takeaway
today
i talked about a few things about
the different
research and what's the new concept we
are talking about
what is the d what's this
is
so okay so what's this bit the last
question what should this be
if d is b
if like like um like if we um okay we
are
and like this part is saying this and if
um
if not we visit the next one using the
kosher definite search but why why is
this the plus one here what's the person
d plus one is uh
um what's d
d is the
kind of
deepening thing what's the
tis
turns distance
it's a distance i visit one more node
the distance will be plus one and then i
check if the distance it sees the
structure max vector if it sees when i
stop don't go further right
okay so for this one is it already
depending uh let's say
i want to visit a to use
hey look the different search right abc
ac is normal uh optimum but if i say
okay let's visit a with the step one
a b
a c okay i busiest because from here b i
don't continue because it sees the
sensor right
so look the pure devil search does not
guarantee a shortest path because ac is
the shortest flight if you do the pure
depth research you will go from abc
this is not the optimum but if i edit
the
depth
and then at the beginning let's start
with one note
a b ac i found it right because a b i
can't continue why is that
because it sees one right this is the
distant one if i go here that will be
distance two
right
and i will be returned here it doesn't
go continue look make sense
okay that's it for today good job bye
bye
bye bye