hello
hello mr mr ryan all right
yes
okay so wait oh look this is cool yeah
so look there's her head there if i saw
it
okay i saw it what's the
probability of the
facing up 50 percent and another 50
percent
they both
have electric signs on them
okay but this is tail this is the head
okay let's say okay 50 percent facing up
50 facing down right yeah if i have two
coins
50 facing up each if i throw the coin
each coin
once what's the probability of i have
two coins or both facing up
[Music]
yeah so let's
come on yeah
that will give us
okay
half is 50 the same thing yeah one over
two
huh
okay i got 25
yeah this is 25 exactly yeah one over
one over four look one over four
is equals to uh
if you times 25 25 over 100 it's the
same thing yeah it's the same thing same
portion right
oh alternatively we can list all the
possibilities if we saying that facing
up is one facing down is zero right so
what's the how many
different outcomes if i throw these
coins each coin once so two coins
so look it will be one one both facing
up one two one zero first position up
second facing down cl one
first facing down
second facing up and then the other both
facing down okay so then we can pick
those values yeah look both facing up is
one out of four right both okay what's
the probability of pose facing down
[Music]
what's the probability of the one up one
down
one up one time
two right two out of four yeah you pick
two okay exactly
okay so
yeah let's say that's the normal coin
how about if we have a coin that uh it's
not normal it's it's very strange like
for example the first coin 50 is regular
but second
coin coin 20 facing up if you saw that
10 times only two times we're facing up
we will face up then what's the
probability of if i throw each coin once
at both coins
uh facing up
fifty percent for the first coin twenty
percent for the second goal
ten percent yeah you times it together
right yeah that exactly
okay so today is tough fifty times
twenty is a thousand right but you have
a percent your percent yeah so you
divide by zero divide fifty percent is
equal to fifty divided by a hundred yeah
a percent look listening
yeah listen what does it mean
oh yeah
but but this thing is look
percentage you divided by 100. look at
two zeros two zeros you move these here
okay
we have a point we have a coin the
probabilities of facing up let's say
probability probabilities are freezing
out like a a list of values of
probability of each coin facing up like
what do we say 0.502
right this is the probability of
throwing this coin facing up yeah and we
are we are about to throw the coins flip
the coins exactly once per coin right so
we want to find out what's the
probability of having the k coins facing
up
k equals two and then you need to tell
me
if
one uh is ten percent yeah it's ten
percent ten percent is zero point one
okay
yeah remember a few days ago we talked
about the subsets on partitioning so
partitioning subsystem remember so what
was practitioner yeah we have a list of
arrays 1 5
5 11. do you still remember this we want
to we want to partition these into half
and both have equal sum right first of
all we check the sum if it's odd if the
sum is odd it will happen
if this sum of the array
is odd you can't um yeah yeah because
yeah you can't separate it because all
the numbers are positive 1.5
yeah yeah yeah look and then look at 11
we we get the total sum is 22 and then
the target sum we're looking for is 11
and now we continue we pick these
numbers
yeah for each for each number we can
pick or not pick right so if we pick we
subtract
the sum
this number from these
right and then continue moving to the
next one remember the dp once you're
right yeah top-notch
enemy programming yeah
and we can skip if we skip this number
for this one we have still have 11 to
pick right
yeah so remember dfs
we are picking the icon underneath this
sum
we keep we pick it so we pick it with
minus nums i yeah
or we don't pick it oh we don't pick it
uh actually it's i plus one we go to the
next coin and then we don't pick it and
then some will be
remaining will be s right
so for this th this problem uh the coins
for each one
we can let it facing up right or we can
let it facing down right it's it's
almost the same right yeah
the only difference is that we have a
probability right but
but for
for the coin uh
for each coin we can have it facing up
with that probability and what's the
probability of
for example this one's 20 facing out
what's the probability of facing down
everything down come on this is easy 20
facing up and what's the other half
um
eighty percent facing down yeah so so
basically one minus is one minus this
number is the problem probability of
things because one
bless you one
is one blessing one one is the one
hundred percent one hundred percent is
is everything yeah it's told is that
every outcome right and then i have
twenty percent facing up and the rest
will be facing down right because all
these two events adding up to one 100
okay
yeah
so
so let's see
so let's see okay
let's see these
so this problem might seems a bit tricky
at the beginning but as i said for each
con we have two choice we cannot be
facing up with the probability p
p i and if we let it facing down it'll
be one minus p i right so let's say i
have a function like dfs
and we want to pick from
the icon yeah so if we look at the coins
here p equals
0.5 0.2 blah blah blah okay so i we
start from zero or we can start we can
start from
remaining it's the same let's say we
start from the beginning we pick the
first point right with some probability
facing out
and then we go in from the right so this
is i and then this is the coin uh
the number of coins facing up already
right
yeah so let's see if i is reaching the
end
and length probability
then we first we need to
do what
we tend to return what
we want to return the number of
the probability here will be a
probability of zero and one
if k is zero it means the probability
uh is one right return one
if k is zero
otherwise
zero okay what does it mean you mean
that okay so this is the case remember
remember the partitioning sum is the
remaining sum yeah if sum is zero right
we want to reduce it so let's say at the
beginning we want to call it zero and
then okay okay so when it's k
ideally our target is to find the number
of coins face the number of coins which
is k
we want to find out the k coins facing
up right and then if we running out of
coins and then if it's coin
if there's no remaining coins to be
facing up now we do ten one then it
means that we find the
solution right otherwise if we still
have k is positive then it means that
least we still
it means what
it means what it means it means we
haven't enough
we haven't got enough coins facing up am
i yeah
all right
that makes sense so now if i pick it if
i listen facing up if i choose this
phrase now i say choose
choose equals bfs
i
i choose this one and then i will have
this i plus one right if i choose it
then it will be k
k minus one right
and then this would be probability of
facing up so this is p
i right
right
if i don't choose it if i skip it
right the opposite of choose is skipping
is dfs
if i skip if i skip this coin i still
have to go to next point
but i
i have this balance which is k because
it's not
subtracted yeah skip it and then the
probability will be y minus p i am i
yeah and then the return would be what
we kind of be these two right yeah
choose first skip okay
yeah
makes sense
does it make sense look
that to
for this coin i can let it facing up and
i cannot keep facing down but if i let
this facing up
is this probability if i let things
facing down okay so maybe i i remain is
that facing up okay freezing up facing
down and here i will be returning facing
up not sleeping down okay this probably
yeah
the probability of this coin face this
is coin facing up is this
p i right
right
and then i need to time choose the next
coin yeah p i plus one k minus one look
because this is facing up so i
substitute one
this is facing down
i keep it as
keep it as it is i'm right
yeah
and doesn't make sense larry
kind of doesn't make sense
so look this is starting from i and i
can do it as uh as the other way which
is front yeah which is from the n so
instead of from zero i can say d of x
from the
length p
length p minus 1
k all right because at the beginning we
want to find out if the possibility of
having the k coins facing up right and
then here
i equal equal length p this will be
changed to if i smaller than zero right
and this is the same at least i need to
change what i plus one i need to change
it to what
if i come from the right to the left
i plus one
change to uh i minus y minus one yeah
exactly yeah but look
let's say
i th this one is like start from the
first coin right i start from the first
one i'm looking at i'm about to throw
the first coin
right
and i want to have the probability of
k coins facing up right
so now
if it's facing up the probability of
facing up is p i right
yeah here the probability of the first
coin facing down is 1 minus pi
when it's facing out then the next point
i want to consider is i plus 1
but if it's already facing out so
because i want to look for the k coins
you if it's already
facing out so what what should we do
with the k
we should
if it's huh
this is this is quite similar to the
partition sound remember
yeah remember what's instead of k minus
one in the partition sum we substitute
the number right
yeah we we pick we know p right this is
corresponding to that pick a notepad
this is facing up y is minus 9
anybody
that's because that's
what's our target cake
okay
we don't have k coins facing out yeah
and now this coin facing up so what
should we do we should look for k minus
one coin freezing out right yeah because
this coin is already facing up so we
have k minus one to face up but why this
is still 10.
because it's still the amount of
yeah because it's facing down right so i
still have k coins to face out right
what's the probability of facing this
coin facing down
one minus p i right yeah and then the
result would be these two yeah why this
is plus no multiply
that's because
um
yes um
these two events are independent right
independent you're identical
but if these two coins these if these
two events are associated you multiply
like the first coin 0.5 the second one
0.5 and both coins
having
[Music]
the both coins having the
uh facing up and it's time right yeah
if 50 of the coins
if these two events are separate right
yeah
there's 50
of the coin
facing up but and then also there's
another 50 this coin single coin facing
down what's the probability of
of these two events you pass it together
you know multiply because these two
events are independent right yeah so
so for the probability usually you have
two kinds of operations you multiply
yeah or you add it
you add it if these two events are
independent you multiply if these two
events are associated uh um
what do we it is
it's like this corner inside the content
you want to have both coins
yeah it's like uh
price uh
remember the the
what naive bayes right nine base
p
b
a yeah
the probability of b even a occurs okay
given a occurs
yeah
the probability b given a test the
probability this is a this is b the
probability of b given a occurs right
you time these together right yeah
okay
what's the time complexity for this one
remember
yeah this is quite similar to
partitioning some thing
it's almost less what's missing here
cash we're done cash yeah because if
you're not putting the cash
exponential yeah because this
intermediate values will be
be
you you can treat you can
we can look at this list function
because you have i
i belongs to
what belongs to 0 to n right yeah
belongs to 0 to k k
k is the
integer right so that time if these how
many states are there so that's
okay n yeah okay and
if we put a cash
if we create a cash
there are how many possibilities for for
this
for this function of course
i mean
d i k
k n k times n right this is number
because look i
have n choice
okay so this is another probability that
i i will be n choice k will be k choice
how many different outcomes
how many different outcomes were for
this dfs function
this first number is i choice look it's
a table it's it's a table right i
uh you you have this table yeah
you have this table
this is i this is k k will be start from
zero one two to k
i will be start from zero one to n right
so how many values are there
n square
no no this is n this is k how many
values are there
n times k exactly right if we put a
cache
yeah
can i
please don't touch it yeah
it's shaking
okay
so yeah it will put a cash right if you
don't put a cash what happened look for
example i want to calculate this value
and i need to spend like two hours
calculating calculating this value right
okay and then i dump i don't catch it i
install some value here and then later
here
you call this function again and what
happened if there's no case whatever
he would keep he would spend another two
hours of working all this value before
it's working all the value that that's
the magic of cash we ask computer to
remember for us so only if we put a
cache what happened each value in the
table
is only calculated once all right
yeah alright doesn't make sense
yeah because because sometimes look if i
calculate this value i might use other
values in the table again but
i might just use these two values three
values right
and again i calculate this value i need
to work out this value
look evenly those values
need to be
taking a lot of time to calculate it if
we spend like hours taking length in
this value then exponential right that's
the magic of putting cash make sure that
each value is calculated exactly once
once we have the value we remember here
let's say one that's two
okay no so i might spend ten hours on
these two
to get the value too but next time i use
it i don't
i don't spend another 10 hours doing the
same work again because i already
calculated i put it in the notebook
right
yeah
doesn't make sense
it's like okay
what's the sum of one plus two class
three plus tier 100
okay
what's the sum of one plus two plus
three plus
a hundred and one
um
yeah hello
okay
how do you get this number because i
just said 101 to 250 percent exactly
let's dynamic programming let's exactly
dynamic programming right because
you already know this is answer so
this bit is
5050. you just need to add one more do
you need to start from the beginning no
that's dynamic programming okay same
thing
same thing
but this is this is this top down open
up
top down we put a cache we ask computer
to remember this for us correctly
if if we we want to store this value in
this table
let's call what
what does it call
if we store the values in a table what
do we call it
what's the opposite of drop down
but
we proactively store the values in this
table and we call it dynamic programming
but for this one it's top-down enemy it
okay yeah make sense yeah look okay one
last thing is that this is quite similar
to to picking the values they are
picking the values look
picking a value instead
instead of picking the value you
remember the partition subset sum yeah
instead of this probability you have you
have what you have this sum k minus nums
i right you just replace it with k
numbers like yeah all right
yeah and all others are similar yeah
similar
okay instead of because this is not
uh
we just we just return
k equals zero right it's not probability
one zero we just return true if if k
equals zero otherwise
four i remember the subset sum right
yeah
makes sense for the subsystem remember
yeah for each number we can pick or not
pick if we pick we know minus one
instead we minus one
instead of one num yeah yeah this is the
sum remember the eleventh thing you have
one five five eleven
this is twenty two sum
we want to look for the sum half which
is 11 k equals 11 right
and then if we pick it we substitute
this number if we don't pick it we still
have the k sum right
yeah and then we don't have this
probability now only difference is this
we have a probability here
and we have a minus one here and we tend
one if k equals zero i don't know i zero
okay
make sense
yeah any questions so far tomorrow we're
gonna talk about potable
you see the first day we talk about top
down the second day we talk about
yeah
makes sense
okay that's it for today good job
bye bye okay one last thing the time
come next
time
[Music]
what's the space complexity
look at this table what's the time from
recipe
[Music]
tv
okay so let's face time come back to
space once it is supposed to encounter
okay that's it for today bye