okay so what happened yesterday what did
we talk about yesterday remember
multiple conflicts yeah
so like we have two coins yeah the first
one has 50 percent facing up and then
the second
second coin has the like 20 facing up
so
if we want to have two coins facing out
what's the probability
the first one have 50 50
you know the second coin has 20 facing
up how what's the probability of two
coins both facing up
um
everywhere
[Music]
the first coin has twenty percent point
three
the first coin has fifty percent facing
out the first second coin is twenty
percent
ten percent yeah yeah okay
okay so
we use the dynamic programming look at
this is right dfsi k here we can let it
represent that we are
we are now
freaking with ice coin and then we have
k coins remaining
take heads remaining okay the balance
okay
all right
obviously when i
when we're running out of coins we just
need to check if the balance is zero if
his balance is zero then
that's probability one otherwise
probability is zero okay
but facing up we can let the current
coin facing up then we have k minus
coins yeah
left
if we let the
common cone facing down we have
still got the
balance 10 right this hasn't changed
but in both cases we have to move to the
next card
right
moving to the
moving to the next cone when the coin
common coin has their probability facing
up is p i right this is given and the
probability of it facing down is 1 minus
p i right yeah because both events added
up to 1.
okay so this is dfs we use the
top down dynamic programming with the
cash with the cash
if we don't put the cash what's the time
complexity
[Music]
if we don't put a cash remember
sorry
if i put a cache is oh i times o n times
k now if i don't put the cache what's
the time zone velocity
what's the time complexity i don't
remember the values remember
okay
oh two and right now what what
two to the power one why why is that
because for each coin
we have two choice yeah each coin we
have two choice so it's basically the
same as picking the
you know finding the subsequence and
finding the subsequence of what
yeah
in
the number of subsequent right remember
i was subsequent
a b c how many subsequents are there
a b c okay
if empty is also subsequent but how many
subsequent for abc
seven yeah including the subsequence
empty you'll be a so look
a b
a c right so for this look for this a
you have two choice for this b you have
two choices for let me see you have two
choices two times two times two a okay
so each one we have uh two choice so if
there are n
right if we look if we want to have at
least k
so it's actually two to the power of k
okay because
yeah we want to find the subsequent
subsequent with k hat facing up right so
2 to the power of k but we use the top
down diameter with the cash
so with the cash i remember the values
so i don't call i don't calculate it
over and over again right because i
remember i asked the computer to
remember you use the cash right the
computer will will remember once it
knows this value d p d f s i k okay make
sense
the bottom of dynamic programming yeah
in other way we we remember the values
in in a
two-dimensional way right in our way and
then we store the values once we have it
right and we calculate the base cases
from
dfs
what dfs zero the base cases and then we
use the values to
calculate the the i and k yeah
dfs int with the larger value right make
sense it's like fibonacci number yeah
fibonacci number n
so quarter
s0 is 1
f1 is 1 f2 ra is what
f1 plus f0 yeah
f3 is f2 plus f1 so so we store these
values in an array right now iteratively
right because to calculate fn we need a
fn minus 1 plus fn minus 2 right yeah so
we store this values in the array
and then we use this array to
iteratively
update
yeah
so in this case this would be if i to n
right
how about if we yeah let's just
transpose this matrix okay so this is i
to n
what i this i one to n and this is k
right so we calculate the first row yeah
we calculate the first row and then we
will calculate the second row
we use the value for the the previous
number when we calculate the third row
we use the value from the second row
right you see so we remember like
variance okay okay so let's uh convert
this to the
and first of all if they
okay so if the look if we have k if we
have n coins and if k is bigger than n
is it possible
now we should return what
uh
zero the probability is zero okay
so the
define let's say coins okay
and we have this probability p and k
right so first of all n equals length p
there are number of coins if
it's what k is bigger than n
we can
okay
yeah yeah i have two coins i want the
three heads no poster right make sense
yeah and now i have a tp4 very oh let's
call it f okay loosen up previously s
s i k right yeah
f i k we have k
balance right so now let's call it f
this is the two dimensional array so
let's initialize with zero
for underscore in range
so the k so that would be the k it'll be
k plus 1
up to k
and then for
the look at this table yeah this table
this table
this is i
and the coin i yeah up to end yeah we
are we are trying to fill in the table
okay flavor here
this is
paper paper
okay
and this is the one this is the
i and this is the top this is the k k is
the
from zero yeah the number of coins
facing up right
up to up to up to k okay
right
we are trying to fill in the value
here and the result will be
at
f
p k
uh okay s n k sorry f n minus k right f
n minus one so f one minus one
okay so the result
okay
so this is the return value we want to
calculate this already here right
okay
we're trying to fill in the value so
here we're going down one we calculate
the row one row by row and we have this
value this is the result this is the
result f
f n minus one
k okay
this is the value what are okay top down
remember the cache
the cache we asked computer to take this
value and that computer okay it needs to
find out this value for example yeah
okay this value needs to find out this
value for example and it's you know this
is top down
top down right yeah and then now butter
up i calculated no by now this is but up
makes sense
yeah just different ways of doing it
right so when the computer work out this
value you can't we put the cash it
remembers it now we remember here we
remember here yeah
so for i in
range
look the first one this is the column
this is the row okay this is the row and
how many rows are there are there
from
from zero to minus one minus one
and n drops okay and rows okay
okay so look f
we need to initialize the value yeah so
for this one the first coin
the first point
if it is zero
and then these two values what should we
initialize it
what what should we initial isaac
look the first coin
of facing down
the first coin or facing down is what
the first point of facing up is p right
p 0 right yeah the first point of facing
down is what
the p0 is the first point probability
the probability of facing up is p0
what's the probability of facing down
[Music]
one minus t zero here
yeah okay
twenty percent facing out what's the
probability you're facing down
eighty percent easy that's easy math
yeah one number one hundred percent is
one okay that's two representation okay
and then now we just try to put to four
i in
range
we start from the first row
especially we don't need to pick we we
don't need to calculate this value yeah
why is that
because the first point if i'm i'm
throwing the first coin
the k
these are all zero okay these are zero
what can you explain to me why this is
zero
because zero
times
whatever is no no no no why is this dude
i'm throwing the first coin and why i
can't get that f zero two f zero three f
g of y come on that's easy this is the
number this is the coin how many coins i
saw
you can't get anything for zero you just
get nothing
quite close zero is the first one i saw
the first coin what's the how many
outcomes do we
we have one how many outcomes
yeah
i saw the coin zero how many outcomes
two what's what are those
heads and tails heads here tails here
this is too hot i throw the coin that's
not impossible for to get two heads only
have one hat okay i throw two coins
okay so this is i saw two coins
zero heads one head two head got it so
this is always like that yeah
this bit
this bit is always zero when
i throw the coin and coins and i get k
k needs to be smaller than equal than n
right yeah if it's bigger than n returns
zero here
yeah
that's what i say here
this bit the outer triangle
this bit
i have a turn point
but i want to get a hundred heads
what's the probability
zero percent yeah three yeah
make sense yeah
now one end
and then i need to do four
j
in
range
f friendship i can
i can get it to i
look icon i can get into i or i can get
is i i think i can get it to i
i plus one
time to i plus one yeah r plus one yeah
uh
then i can say
um
if if you wish right because i have sold
end coins i have several end coins and
then this is the number of targets we
want to
yeah we
we also have a number of cat this is the
number of heads
half okay and then i can say f i j
yeah f i j
f i j look there are two possibilities
one one is the
the previous one is facing up so
previous one is p
i
what p i
times
f
i minus 1
times
j minus 1 yeah so this we want this coin
to face up so we have this probability
and then
yeah and then the previous one would be
j minus one right because we already
have one right plus
one minus p i this is the carbon cone
facing down and then i can say f
times f i minus 1
j right because the balance hasn't
changed right the balance hasn't changed
and then look we can look return this
here yeah
we can hear return
within the speed f
n minus one
okay
i
f minus one k
yeah
so look if j is more than i what will
happen if j is more than i
um
if j if j
is more than i so it's in the upper
corner then will become zero okay
and if i set it to target one uh let
will be target is k
k plus one here
does this still work
does this still work if j is more than i
is
j mullen i okay so it still works right
let's put it this way maybe more magma
clear okay but you have to remember that
the first upper corner is still always
there because there's no way
right if we have thrown the ice corn
we have thrown an ice coin
and we want to get a j hat yeah this is
what i mean
if i also i have solar icons and i have
concentrated jpegs it's the probability
of current i score and facing up this is
a probability breaking down probability
if i facing out it means i choose this
head choose this coin and facing up so i
have j minus one heads remaining
right
yeah
look i minus one what's i minus look i'm
here
i'm here what's it i'm what's i minus
one here
[Music]
i'm calculating this row what's i what's
the what's the previous note i minus one
note here right yeah
i look because you know this value
is based on previous row right so i
start from the first row and i use look
i start from filling the first row and
then i use the first row to calculate
the second row i use the second row to
take it in the third row i kill 0
yeah yeah look f i
is based on f i minus 1 right
right all right the horizontal this is
the number what what's k here what k
here
[Music]
okay can you explain to me last question
what's f i j
f i j is
like
like this is i
what's ij what does it mean here
this is i said you got i
coined yeah
[Music]
okay one english question english right
there when you say something about
what's the difference the number
and the amount
the number of coins and the amount of
coins which one is correct
you don't know i saw the number is that
you can count but the amount is
something you don't count like water you
don't count the amount of water the
number of coins
yeah
yeah but we're not talking about water
yeah no i'm just saying that you say
amount of coins is that the right way of
saying it i don't know yeah
okay
okay what's the time complexity if you
look at this question this is easy
because look at this n and if this is up
to k it is o and k right but if this i
change this to k k is smaller than equal
than n so it's o n squared
the upper bound okay the outer part
makes sense if k is bigger than n
we return zero here
what's the space complexity
one
why you always say oh one what's the
space comedy i'm pointing to these
o minus
okay
o minus k plus one
um
bye bye