hello
hello mr mr wine i alright
yeah
okay so today uh we're going to find the
minimum difference absolute difference
in our way okay so let's say
mean difference mean abs was abs
difference
of of two numbers
two numbers in a relay
so let's say three
four
a hundred
20 30.
what's if we pick we are about to pick
two numbers what's the minimum
difference
yeah yeah the minimum difference minimum
has a little difference yeah one okay
okay so now if i have another one here
which is the 19 okay so you need to tell
me that the minimum
difference is
three four and then it's a pair
increasing and another one 1920
1920.
so you need to tell me okay this answer
is that okay so 30 100
yeah we so find the minimum yeah find a
minimum pair
of
of numbers that have the
absolute difference which is the
smallest and then we output the
pair in ascending order okay
yeah
and then and one number can only be used
uh
it can can be used twice i think right
look if i have one another 21 here
right
if i have another one side here you can
you need to tell me okay
another one 21.
so look even the 20 appears only once
right even appear up here once we still
need to output it yeah
make sense
okay so this task right what what's your
approach what's your idea i mean
sorting
something forward
okay good idea so but to do this
to do this we need to separate into two
steps right first of all
first of all what first of all find the
minimum difference which is one yeah
first of all you need to tell me okay
it's one the difference is the minimum
difference is one yeah well what if
if there's like two two um does this
count like there's two notes we're
saying and
then
that's that's a good question yes yes
obviously if that duplicate numbers like
the difference is you know you find a
duplicate number right yeah okay
so first of all we find the minimum
difference and then we go through the
array
again and we output the pair okay so for
the first for this one how do you you
said blue first you said uh
salty okay for the proof of thing
layer
and elements in a way what's proof
what's the term complexity
yes look
what's going for thing for i
okay for i in range and for j
yeah so for i
in
range and right
for j
in
range yeah range up to i right and then
we have a player j i right
then we just have to say okay
uh if that we first of all find the
minimum difference okay the difference
let's say at the beginning the biggest
number we can think of is infinity and
massive infinity then we can say i can
think of
a bigger number infinity and one
infinity is a it's not
it's not a concrete
concept it's a concept yeah yeah that's
what i said it's this this thing this
thing
infinity yeah
infinity so there is
actually not beyond the infinity because
infinity is it's not a concrete number
it's it's like you know so big you
cannot even locate it right okay for i
in range and for j and i and then this
difference yeah mean difference
mean difference
equals mean
difference
okay so the absolute difference we use
the abs yeah abs numbers i minus num j
right what's abs from here i talk about
this all the time
yeah and then now i got a mean
difference
look this is n and that's one square
right
okay what's abs
[Music]
is absolute value okay when it's when x
is bigger than zero is x when x is
smaller than zero what does it return
value this is
[Music]
it's just the distance to the x to the
zero okay
yeah absolutely
so this is o n square
and we sort it if we sort it how do we
do it look if we started look we saw
this number
so the mean difference would be
in what if i saw this number what's
after sorting yeah i i please say
up if i do this ar out. what's the time
complexity
what's the time convex before this one
very light what's the time breaking for
this one
20 21 22.
100. okay so now if i sort it how can i
get the minimum difference where are
they
the meaning is different
look if i sort it so what why is the
resulting mean the arrays because
because because you because when they're
close to each other they're the most
near to each other and the other numbers
are yes we're done why we sort it
because sorting then we can just
calculate this difference that would be
that closes right there's no point to
calculate the difference like right
let's look that's different 16. it's
certainly smaller than a bigger than d2
right so i just have to calculate these
different right in all intent right
yeah
so i can just do this this
equal okay again minimum
infinity yeah and i'm gonna do this for
i
invent
one to n right and it's the length of
the
array and then look f
equals mean
this
nouns
i
what numbs i here i start from here i do
what eric can you can you complete this
noun is i and what what
yeah minus i minus one
okay
look sorting o and again this one o n so
overall the time complexity is what come
on
come on
first of all i saw this one second of
all i go through this linear time yeah
so if i put it together it's always
logan plus n
but o n of n is bigger than o l right
yeah so we keep the most dominating
power which is o and okay so we drop
this point okay so once we got this
difference now we need to go through
this array again right
yeah those are these array again and
then if the difference is equals the
mean difference i added right look after
this the difference would be equals to
one right equals one and that goes
through this okay alright
the difference is one okay so i put that
array three four
this one no
this one
okay
so 19 20.
this one
yes or no
okay no okay
okay so actually it's o n log n plus n
plus n
yeah
oh log n plus 2n we drop this
yeah make sense
yeah
which one is better
o and
log n the second approaches first of all
o n square
yeah the first one again because we get
the difference i want o n square and we
need to go through that
the same
process again and then to check if the
difference yeah if the difference
between any pair
is the smallest difference then we apply
it to the result right make sense
yeah so this one is currently better
yeah
yeah there's a huge difference yeah if
the angle is very large yeah o n square
could be like that yeah
and then our o and again could be like
that yeah you see
yeah
uh
actually no this is o log n
o n organs is is this is o n
o n log n is somewhere here
yeah because it's up is bigger than o n
right
it's bigger than one but smaller than
one square right
l is n squared this is o and log n
this is n right o n is leasing
make sense o n when when n is a hundred
this is 100 it's it's a triangle yeah
it's a what's what do you call this
triangular this side equals this side
this is the right angle
triangle
right angle triangle i don't know
you know what i mean this is the right
angle 90 degree and then this side is
equal to this side
yeah so if this side equals this side
what's the degree here
okay one question you probably don't
know right
okay so if this side equal this side
this side 90 degrees what's the degree
of here
this is
mathematics geometric
what's the what's these two three angles
like a plus b plus c what's this
how much anger is this the end of the
triangle internal angle
sorry
no no this is 90 degree yeah how much
the triangle any triangle what's the
triangle
what what's the
180 yeah we're done okay
we're done 45 you know how do you get
the 45 this is not eight nine this is 90
degree
so a plus b equals 90 degree right
yeah but because ac equals bc what does
it mean it means these two angles are
equal right yeah so these two languages
you can say 2a equals 90 so a equals 45
of course b equals 45. that's how we get
it yeah yeah okay make sense
yeah
okay that's it for today good job bye