oh hello hello hello hello
all right yeah
what's graph we talk about graph all the
time what's graph
a graph is a graph
a graph is a graph yes but it's a
collection of
okay so if there are two trees what do
we call it
forest yeah it's also yes
a tree is a connected come on come on a
tree
it's a connected a single component
connected no cycles yeah no cycles
circles
another concept simple what's single
graph
simple graph is that okay so you can you
can't have these
these
you can have two edges between two
right yes
yeah that yeah this is not a simple car
okay
okay it looks like a car
yeah i i don't i okay now it looks like
this is this is my simple car this is
this is okay
this is a single class okay it looks
like a rainforest
it looks like an unicycle
okay so but you know the trees come on
you know the trees are directed t-a-g
eng
this is a few concepts we need to lag
what's the energy
dng is direct cyclic graph okay so it
has direction yes direction and a cyclic
means there's no cycles
okay so let's say
hey
okay so this is a graph okay this is
a means you need to play piano okay
is like you can play games yay
okay
and then t is like you need to go to
sleep okay oh
oh just read my part of it okay
so
how many tasks do we do you need to have
to do first
before you go to visit all the notes in
the graph you have to do piano
work and and and
combo first oh yeah so so at the
beginning
yeah okay so look in order to visit all
the notes in the graph we have to visit
a and see these two can be done in
parallel yeah playing piano i'm doing
homework okay
okay so in we call this kind of
tremendous
graph we call it topology you know
what's topology topology is topology
topology
this has this can be visualized as
dependency in order to do the b you have
to do the a and c first yeah a and c are
independent you cannot do it in parallel
right okay so today's task very simple
given this graph
given the graph with directions
find out the number of the nodes we have
to weaken
uh minimum number of nodes we have to
visit in order to visit all the nodes in
the in in the graph
make sense for example the a and c this
is the minimum number of nodes we can
start doing
in order to finish or
visiting all the other nodes right
yeah
am i clear
am i clear yeah so for example another
one
another one you tell me okay
okay this is a bit tricky
this is a bit tricky okay uh
is it or is
it okay so look he has a cycle yeah or
maybe here here's a cycle okay
wow
well this is a bit trickier
well d obviously we need to store it
first but how about this a b c look in
order to a you need to finish c right
but in order to finish it you need to
finish b so there's a cycle right you
can't do anything yeah yeah that's a
good question okay so let's just do
piano you can play games
play again you could do
how you work and then you have to
oh okay
what
top logic
okay look at this there's a cycle yeah
it's cycle look this is a cycle a
triangle a triangle
a b c
in order to do b you need to finish a in
order to do c you need to finish b okay
in order to yeah this is a cycle so you
can't finish it right okay so let's
assume there's no cycle
let's not assume let's see
[Music]
okay how about this
yeah
okay so we can we can start with steve
that's the minimum number of the notes
you can start at first okay
[Music]
go to sleep play piano play games no no
this is different different ones
at the end yeah yeah
what's your idea looking at the graph
what's our approach to to find a note
that we we can start at first
the thing is um
it's it's
[Music]
it's um we need to check one
we need to check if it's
if you if
if um if like if something
points to it yeah exactly something
points to it you bring a very good
concept what's what do we call it
something points to it uh
in
degree
okay we have two characters in
okay in yeah this is in
this is out okay make sense yeah
going out of the edge is go up
degree means the number yeah how many
look we can count
how many look at this b how many edges
coming to it going into it i think so
the in degree is two how many edges
coming out of b one right so our big q
is one right yeah so we just have to
collect all the nodes which has the in
degree equals to what
if it has in degree zero that's the way
that let's say if we in degree is zero
then let's know we can start right make
sense
look integral is zero in degrees
in degree two
in degree
what
d the in degree in degree d is one
what's the articulator b
one what's our degree of d
zero what's out including a and z
uh
good job okay that's it for today easy
let's try the kill and then i'll be
saying
that's it for the day let's just write
okay and that'll be it
in degree
okay that's very very important concept
of topology
topology um
[Music]
note okay
now we have given uh
what let's get edges okay let's given
the edges i know
address a to b okay let's put all the
notes in the set right let's say notes
equals a set
all right and we just need to go
from a to b edges from a to b in edges
then now stop
at
we're adding this node a and then we
also need to do as well
we add a we also need to add a b
[Music]
okay and then look so okay so we have uh
we need to have a data structure to
store the number of to to count how many
edges pointing in yeah yeah okay so
let's say g equals before this generally
all right
what's before dictionary
okay
the type of default is e zero in okay so
then g
now we go through the all the nodes here
and in
nodes this is all or not and what should
we do with that we how do we check if if
g
and then we can answer yeah
what's the times complexity
the number of edges let's say n okay
n is the number of edges
go through the edges oh n yeah what's
the space from let's see
huh
what's the space complexity yeah g and
no
yeah make sense
okay okay let's say for today good job
it's quite easy today yeah isn't it
this topology uh
topology yeah
is that we given the graph with
dependency with the
directions it mainly refers to the dag
directive yeah a pointed to b means that
in order to finish b to complete b you
have to do a first yeah
but yeah for example the task
finish homework
and playing games right
and then we today we talk about the in
degree or degree in degrees the number
of edges pointing to that vertex all
degrees number of edges going out of the
degree okay i know what we're doing what
we're doing here like we do first of all
we calculate this in degree and then we
just append the notes with integra
equals zero means that there's no task
depending on that vertex right yeah
simpler right that's it for today bye