[Music]
hello
so today we'll talk about remember
yesterday we talked about the binary
numbers
two days ago we talked about binary
numbers yes final numbers you know
zero and one right yeah yeah so if you
want to
write a 15 you have to do this one one
one one right this is 15
in binary right so you can imagine if
it's a big number
you should take lots of the one and zero
right
yes because only we have only two digits
to represent the numbers so
so for example like two 255 255
in decimal three digit but or if we are
using the binary that would be
there will be eight ones yeah
how do how do i know because two to the
power of
2 to the power of 8 what's that
2 times 2 times 2 times 2 equals
60 16 x 16 256
right yeah 256
so 2 to the power of 8 so that will be 2
to the power a
means 1 in binary that will be that will
be a 0
yeah yeah if i substitute 1
minus one minus one that will become
255.
if if i minus one from from this binary
that will be one one one one one one one
oh okay
all that is missing one one so that will
be eight ones
so that's 255 do you get it yes
okay so now uh remember uh i think last
time we're missing a
missing uh implementation of to um
to convert this decimal into binary for
example if i want to
convert list 15 into binary that would
be one one one
one right so how do we do that we can
just write it define remember we divided
by two
yeah equals seven remember one
yeah three remember remaining one
one remaining one and divided by two
continue until
the divisor is zero yeah
and then we write it down this way right
yes
yes yes okay so now define let's call it
uh decimal to find binary
so that's n okay so so now we
put it in answer as the
as a empty string yeah and this string
now what should we do
y n is bigger than zero
right now we can answer equals
we need to make it as a star right star
and divide and remaining two
yeah remaining two plus answer i don't
need to be
stopped make it convert this star
function good question start function
make an integer
into a string yeah into a string yeah
so this is t r is star s clear string
so for star it makes an integer into a
string a quote
yeah a string this is number this is
string
different types yeah so now look this is
getting the remainder remember one one
one
one getting the remainder into a string
and plus itself so we connect it
in the reverse order and then now n
is n divided by two right
right and then return answer this is the
way to
to basically to convert a decimal into
binary remember this yeah
this is very useful now now today we are
going to talk about
passive decimal hexadecimal
x thick decimal i
probably not how do you write it but
hexadecimal
what does it mean hex hexagon
hexagon what's that hexagon six sides
yeah
okay good question this is six
yeah this is 10 so how
how how many all together 16 16
yeah we're done so hex hexadecimal is
16.
so we're using 16 kind of
different character to represent the
number so can you guess
what are the tens so we have zero to
nine layer ten right
and then what's next what's next
zero can you guess what's after what's
after
zero to nine what's after zero to nine
ten uh no no there's no ten ten ten
is one zero so we're using
a yeah
[Music]
this is 10 this is 6 we use this 16 kind
of character to represent the numbers
so it's shorter yeah
do you understand yeah so can can you
tell me what's
what's okay
wait wait can you tell me what's a in
decimal
weight
index what's nine
nine is nine what's after nine ten
yeah this is ten okay how about
f what's f
no no close very close
9 10 10 is b what's this
11. twelve by fourteen
fourteen see what's f fifth
okay what's sixteen what's after f
what's this e d
g no there's no g because we already
have this
remember after 9 is 10 yeah hey
hey no no let's not edge i
can't yes we're done yes we're down 10
this this this in hexadecimal is 16 look
it equals 1 times 16 times 1 yeah
yeah plus zero okay yes so you see it's
similar yeah
okay so it's amina so let's say okay i
give you another one okay
oh 100 in hexadecimal is how many in
this decimal 10
in decimal this is the hexadecimal is in
what remember 1
times 16 1 2 plus
0 plus 0. so what's this
256 yes
yeah you see yeah how about this in
binary
how about this infinitely what's that
100 and finally what's that
[Music]
yes
okay come on
so so basically you you just need to
this this stitch times the base
yeah there are two two positions after
that that would be two yeah
okay don't sing please
okay so how about okay now so
so let's write it let's write this hex
to
maximum okay p5 thanks to decimal it's a
similar to binary to the decimal right
yeah yeah okay let's do the edge okay so
now we got the answer yeah answer equals
zero
okay
answer equals answer times what times
what
16 16 because we are moving remember
if it's a maximum move one position to
the left is times ten
if it's binary if it's binary is it
times two if the decimal is times what
10 16 plus we need to
look look we need to map this i to the
value so we use the mapping
mapping let's let's do in my map first
okay then we turn i right return return
answer yeah
but it's and good question this n is a
dictionary
so let's let's just do it this way look
we can just write here
and okay this is bad
in hexadecimal it could be zero to nine
and a two a to eight
of f now
is zero we making into zero right and
then
one map into one and it's actually nine
mapping to nine and then a mapping to a
to ten right b matching to
eleven you you could have me yeah that
looks like
14 yeah yeah so another thing is this
could be
you could be lowercase as well so
instead of doing this
location uppercase we just do this i dot
upper
yeah i thought upper means to change
leads to uppercase
so a will become a
right and a is still
a right and if it's one number it
doesn't
have any impact right so we have this
mapping zero to zero one to one
a to ten b c d e f f fifteen right
and then we'll look it up yeah it's
quite similar in binary what
what's in binary finally remember
finally to decimal
we just change this to two right yes and
then
and one and plus i i i could be zero and
one so
finally that would be
[Music]
i look at you okay you are here
okay so now now what's the next part we
convert
backwards from that hex specimen to
binary
or to maximum so let's let's
uh no no no no from taxi to hexadecimal
so
we want to influence two uh if it is 255
okay
let's divide it by 16 okay let's divide
it
[Music]
255 255
this is this is maximum maximum the
number we talked about we want to
convert it to
hexadecimal okay all right 16
play 16 we call it backside
so first of all we need to divide it by
[Music]
really i'm not sure how do you know
sixteen one sixteen that's nine five
five ninety five fifteen remaining
five right no no no no no no no oh
fifteen fifteen yeah yeah oh
fifteen fifteen remaining 15 and divided
by 16 what's that
zero remaining 15. okay so we write it
this way yeah
yeah so 15 in hexadecimal is what
5 1 no no no in hexadecimal
f f remember f is 15
right a is 10 oh yeah and then
this this 255 is equals f
in c 16 correct let's try another number
x
number okay it says table yeah
let's try this let's try this let's try
this
uh 100 108
in 16 in in base 16 3
6 10 ryan right
divided by 16 equals one eight
six six uh
remaining 12 right is it
108. wait wait wait
it's remaining four no no 696 there will
be two 12
so remaining 12 right and divided by 16
that's zero remaining six
right so six four sum of
four sixteen like remaining twelve
oh twelve what's 12 in in hexadecimal
a b c which number
12 what do you see 3 10 11
c okay so so this is this is 16
okay so let's let's let's try it the
other way
once this system equals what what in
texas hex in decimals
60 16 equals what
equals that's what
6 times 16 plus c
c is 12. so let's look you see
let's the other way around right yeah
yeah okay
okay so now we we want to write the
problem
define decimal
to hexi taxi okay so let's end
come on come on remember what we have we
have to talk about
answer equals this yeah well look
why and it's bigger than zero talk about
mapping yes i will talk about the
mapping before
later okay answer equals answer plus
no no problem mapping first
yeah making n plus answer yeah
and another return answer that's it oh
no and
n divided equals 16 right
yeah upper this needs to end modular
modulus16
okay return written answer
so this is basically the same as the
binary but but look
uh look at this m is a mapping
mapping this how many possibilities of n
modulus 16 how many possibilities
16 yeah how many possibilities are m
modulus 2
yeah exactly so we need a sixteen
sixteen so mapping
equals what zero that would be zero
right
one one two three four five nine but now
ten remain ten will be
a right listen listen listen
okay eleven what's this
eleven what's next
b yes
uh so 15 is what
yeah so okay we got mapping what's the
time complexity
because each number is n every time we
divide it by 16 right
yeah yeah every time we divide by 16.
so how many 16 you could be log log
blocks not 16 base n right yeah
so it's like binary is log n if if i if
i tell you a number
and i want to convert it to binary then
it takes log n
right yeah base two log n
logarithm we talk about log ten is base
two
okay it's base two yes but at least it's
16 every time we divide it by 16 so it's
not
16 base and okay where's the base
base this is space look remember this
log x
y equals a
do you understand this is actually you
can write it as
x x to the power of a equals y right
yeah remember log 2
to the power of a log 2 a equals 1
remember this equals three because two
to the power of three equals a that's
why we write
log two to the power to the log base two
a is three okay yes
uh no questions
so what have we talked about today
hexadecimal okay the one last question
one last question
one last question one last question one
last question
[Music]
okay so that
what's this what's this one one times
ten no i'm talking about sixteen sixteen
to the power one yeah plus eight
so what's this number okay 16 plus
what's this 10 26
36 okay yes okay okay good job today
[Music]
sorry