go
hello mr mr ryan are you right yeah
today is christmas eve okay
so yesterday we talked about directly a
cyclic and the topology sorting topology
sorting
with regarding to dig directives a
cyclic graph is that for example this
given is directly a cyclic graph a
points to b b points to c that's the
dependency look in order to finish to
complete to visit the node b we have to
visit a first in order to finish c
yeah c we have to visit b and that order
will be abc that's the only way to visit
all the nodes right
and
yesterday what are we talking what did
we talk about yesterday
topology so yeah yesterday we talked
about we haven't actually talked about
sorting yet but we talked about where to
start the visiting notes for example
here
how do we
how do we do it because if it does have
in in grade or something like that in
degree yeah
we check like in degree if it's in
degree in degree is the number of energy
points to
the vertex yeah focus on b in degrees
one article is going out of the vertex
this one so we
compute we also we up uh iterate the
edges integrate over the edges and we
updated the
in degree and then again we go through
the vertices again and we find out a
collection of the vertex which has the
in degree equals zero means that there's
no dependency there's no edges pointing
to it it means there's no dependency we
can start it right away right this
yesterday we're talking about to find
the minimum notes
starting visiting the graph okay
and we use the in degree and then g gb
means that to update the in degree b
because the edge a points to b and then
b in degree needs to be incremented by
one and then we go through the edges
nodes again and if the indegree is zero
we can put it in the starting node list
okay the time convexity is not o n
actually it's all n plus m yeah
to be more precise
n is the number of nodes
here and
okay so look
we are visiting the edges this is added
here so this is all m if there is number
m number of edges and then the next loop
will be visiting the nodes there will be
n nodes okay so n o n plus m
right
or you can say o max
and m okay sometimes you can write it
this way right so look
the first step iterating over the edges
the second step iterating over the notes
the time space complexity using the
nodes let's o n
what's this these yeah always so let's
face complexity is our n okay
okay yeah
given there are n vertices for example
given they are inverted what's the
maximum number of the edges for this n
vertex if they are simple if this is a
simple graph remember it's like we
talked about single quad yeah this is
the simple graph single graph but this
is not yeah
yeah because
two notes there are one edges three
notes
three edges four notes how many can you
get
how about these two
six and finals
how many edges can you get look this is
a complete vlog
but but again i have added one more
edges i did one more vertex so what
happened i can have one more edges to
the previous and notes right
yeah
make sense
do you get it it looks like this
so how do we get it
how do we get it what we have one one
vertex what's the number of edges yeah
two two vertex
one i have points to the previous one
yeah plus plus one right so let's plus
one so i have two
i have
another
vertex here so how many vertex how many
edges i added
plus one
plus two
and i have look this is
this is three vertices i added one more
vertex how many edges i can have
plus one
three yeah exactly so look i have n
vertex i don't know how many how many
you got yeah
but i added one more edges one more
vertex i can have n
and yeah and more vertical edges right
so the answer will be one
the answer will be one
this is number of vertices number of
vertex yeah
look zero zero that's one
that's three yeah one three
i know what's next
one plus two three plus three six yeah
look so it's n n minus one
n times n minus one yeah
divided by two am i right let's put it
zero is zero one
uh
one is still zero that's not right
okay what one yeah one is zero yeah
that's right two
two two times one
yeah three
three times
two divided by two is three that's right
four four vertex four times three
divided by two six edges it's right yeah
do you how do you see how we're getting
this yeah
yeah
makes sense look plus one plus two plus
three plus four plus five right it's
it's
yeah it's it's like the number of words
yeah it's quite similar to to the number
of the subjects for
for n size this mri
okay so look
the topology starting is the order yeah
how can we get this yeah how can you get
this
look
this part is
is putting all the notes putting all the
notes here the answer answer is the if
answer is the number of notes we can
start okay how about if i change this to
dq right
and if i said pq what what's in your
mind
what kind of ignorance is the associated
yeah so how about i put it in the dq
right and then i do this breakfast
search right
yeah and what happened so i need to
update it i need to update it uh when i
do the
traversal right okay
[Music]
so this will be the same okay answer
yeah this means i will be the same so i
don't i don't write it okay and then now
let's say let's say you put in q
p q
q dot attend and yeah
and then now i can do this
wire
wire cube right
wire cube
four
okay okay come on do you want to finish
this quicker come on
while here
so
what's the first step to do the pressure
search
so i have this current q dot top left
yeah
now
okay so there's one thing missing yeah
because look i need to
i have this dependency but i need to
i need to remember which nodes
yeah which knows coming coming out of it
right
so we have to
integrate but we also have to remember
the notes that are coming out of it
make sense
why is that because because look yeah
look a to
b
this is c yeah in order to finish c
yeah
in order to finish it i have to finish a
and b first right yeah if i finish a and
finish b
and then i possibly can start with c i'm
right
yeah so look let's see information look
i have this in
i need to remember a note article i'll
degree so i need to look g b equals a
and then i need to have a node
nodes okay node will be
also default dictionary which is a list
of uh
which is the list of integer right
so the node
a points to b so i need to a node a
plus append b right yeah
yeah so look a
a will point
so i can i can
i can use this information to
[Music]
to see how many edges coming from a
right and how many edges coming to b so
i can just use the n right so look
i currently get a node c
and then i need to fall a in no c right
so this is a is the note coming from the
c okay
yeah
okay i will ask a question later you
need to
listen carefully okay
no c
what's nothing
next is the
thing that comes in from
in
yeah gb look this is a to b right b is
the
in degree a points to b yeah
okay yeah
a b and that is a point to b b
in degree plus equal one a
knows a plus equal b well what's this
mean what what does this mean
what's here what's this mean you think
that um now is the defaultionally least
type in this in okay it's the same it's
the same type okay node a it means the a
a has one more edges coming out of a
to b right
yeah
so i go through this it means that i
iterate
i iterate all the edges all the edges
from coming out of c and if i coming out
of c what happened look this is c
uh
i'm currently i see right
and then this a this points to a right
okay look
c go to a right and then now
c is the number is current one and then
c needs to put if i finish c
then i need to do what i need to do what
for this one i need to do what a so look
i remove one dependency from c from a
from yeah from a
c
c is the dependency of a points to a and
now i visit c so it means that this
dependency this integral should be
what
increment of my decrement
in degree increment
i i have this already i have calculated
this plus one equal already and now i've
reached c already so what's the what
should i do with sorry
decrement exactly because i already
visited c so look there's one less thing
to to do
you know
there might be another one called d
yeah look to finish a you need to put
the c and d first right and smiley face
yeah
minus equals one right this is integrity
minus one right because we already
visited one c so there's one less thing
to worry about
yeah and look if this in degree becomes
zero what happened what should we do
um
if it is already if i minus one here and
then minus one so what happened what
happened to this a you only have a small
difference
come on listen carefully yeah
if i look at a if i usually c and b c d
so what happened to a the integral will
become one zero so what happened in this
case if we in degrees zero what should
we do now we can visit it right so what
should we do with the q
what should we do
put it in the kill yeah look if g
a
then we can put it in the queue right
because look a is free now right we
already finished c and d minus one minus
one and then we can just say q dot
append
apparent
yeah look the order is coming out for
problem this is the topology starting
yeah
makes sense
so what's the topology starting what
what's the argument we're talking about
here
okay
so
what's the topology starting yeah
[Music]
so i have another graph here so you tell
me can you tell me one of the technology
stories you know the topology starting
might be different there might be a
difference just give me one of them all
right
yeah
points for c
and then d here points to b
point to
okay
okay so what's the topology sorting of
the this class come on
i need
[Music]
which one is also okay a
i mean can you look i give you a hint
what's this d can we swap with t and a
i mean can we start with p as well yeah
yeah because it's defective independent
yeah
and then you do one a you finish a then
you can finish b and c right
b
[Music]
c and then e okay so this is also okay
there are two topologies sorting okay
yeah
makes sense yeah
[Music]
and look we use the q first of all so
for the topology sorting what are the
initial notes
what what what should we put to the
queue first
we're done you're listening yes
and then
once we visit we take it this is the
kind of like breakfast look q equals uh
c equals q to the power black so we take
one from the kill
and then what should we do here what's
this what should we do here
we go
[Music]
so we'll take take one out look we take
one out and then if uh
if
um in degree is zero then you just put
it into the key
okay so for example i take the cr yeah
look c can be started i take it out so
what what should i do with next
what's this lc
d
what's lc
what's n c means
what's nc here
without degree
the number of the edges that the vertex
that points
from
c yeah so look nc will be
a
yeah yeah
yeah and c will be a
right because that there's a vertex
coming out of c and c
and then like goes through the out
out notes right out notes and then look
because i'm visiting with c already so
it means that a has
one less dependency right
one has less dependency and then i need
to decrement the integ in degree minus
one and when this a is
[Music]
how do you pronounce that one
the thing that depends on a
yeah
all the things that depends on a like c
d or whatever there's another e here
all the in degree all the edges come
going to a
cde these dependencies have been visited
so it means that i can visit a now
so when i want to visit it i can put it
back to the cube
right
so the number of edges look at the
number of edges whenever we we
we find out the
whenever we decrement the edges yeah now
we can have this in
r plus equals when i equals zero right
and then at the end we just check if
this r equals the number of edges in
this square if it's number e equals to
the number of edges in about what does
it mean
right every look i have three for
example i have three edges here right
and every time i sequence one edge one
dependency i i plus equals one and i
check this r
if it's
equal to the total number of edges if
it's equal to the total number of edges
it means that i can fit in all the notes
in this graph right
right make sense if if i cut if this r
is not incremented to
the total edges means that i cannot
i cannot right let's let's take an
example like
a
just simple example yeah b
c
okay this this look this graph yeah we
can't right
okay
so look we okay so maybe maybe we put
another one d yeah so the starting note
will be only d right in the queue right
yeah
right so the only edge is one two three
four four edges four edges
yeah four edges the starting point would
be
d
so i take dr right i take the dr what is
our degree a right
so i increment i i a g
g a minus 1 look how many what's the in
degree of a here t
what's the integral of a g
then what's the number of in degree one
how is the one
two right look two so i only increment
one so it's one already right
and then the next time
next time the queue is empty and then i
just clicked so r will be only one we
only able to remove one edges right and
let's say how many edges we have got
four edges what does it mean
if r is not equal to
number of edges right oh we can say i is
the number of edges and r minus equals
right if i is not zero
mean
okay and then i look every time i remove
our dependency i remove one ah minus
equals one i would be three now so what
happened
zero
you can do
i completed all the notes right if i
it's not zero it means i can obviously i
don't know all right
yeah this is topology something based on
breakfast it's similar to breakfast yeah
the only difference okay so today is
take away the only difference is what we
suppose facility you know you know the
level by level right level by level we
use the q dq yeah push to the right a
pen
pop left yeah take one out or take
everything all right the difference is
what we push
we push the note with in degree equal
zero to the q
and
we
decrement the out
the edges coming out of it look this is
current note and then there are many
many notes pointing out yeah and then i
need to increase that
i need to decrement uh
the in degree for this right for the
nodes that coming out of it and once
this in degree is zero then we push it
back to the cube
exactly and then order of taking all the
nodes from the queue
is called topology sorting
this this is useful
for example like i give you a list of
tasks that has dependency and then you
need to tell me the sequence right abcs
play piano do homework and then do what
you want and playing game right you need
to plan make a plan this is property
sorting helps you to do the term okay
yeah and then you also find can tell us
that if we can
if we can visit all the nodes in a
directive a cyclic uh no directive graph
okay exactly means that it's not
impossible right make sense
yeah you see this is really useful right
this is useful
yeah
okay that's it for today that's it for
today good job bye
bye