up
hello mr harry mr ryan all right
yeah okay so this number
christmas one two three four five is
this divisible by three
uh
yeah why is that because although
how do you know this this one 1 plus 2
plus 3 plus 4 plus 5 equals 0. last time
okay so today yeah so any numbers yeah
any numbers i don't know just make up
some numbers
the integer yeah it can be only you
could be divided by three only and if
only
all the digits
sum up the sum would also be divided by
three yeah like 21
2 plus one three let's divide by three
okay yeah
the the integer
so how that top number that's being
circled is in the eight times so look
look at this one two plus three plus
four plus seven plus eight equals 28 28
is it by three no
is it uh
i mean 24 24 yeah divided by two yes so
this number can be divided by three okay
make sense three of these can be okay
okay so today we're going to prove this
it'll be easy okay so let's say how can
we prove this
like a number yeah a number like like
one two three four five okay
one two three four five this number i
really like look
one is
in what in one
ten thousand right so it's one times ten
thousand
okay how many zero yeah
two is two
two times
what one
thousand right
yeah
three
is three times a hundred
five and four is four times ten five is
five times
one right this is ten to the power of
zero
okay
yeah this number
twelve
thousand and three hundred forty five is
this added together am i right
yeah yeah okay so this
one times ten thousand
yeah how about
is it equal
it equals to one
times
ten thousand
minus one
yeah i need to plus one right
this equals two times
a thousand minus one and i need to five
[Music]
look there are a hundred thousand twos
now i times
one less so i need to plus one two yeah
exactly these equals three times
uh a hundred minus one plus three okay
and these are four times a hundred minus
ten minus one plus four and then is
four five times
one
one minus one for us
13 notice this
what's this
999 what's this
99 what's this
9 what's this 0
yeah
it's not
9999 is it divided by 3 obviously yeah
yeah so the multiple always divided by c
so this divided by three this divided by
three please divided by this divided by
okay
so i have a number yeah
all right i have number
n
this is equals a plus b right
a is less this left side
is least divided by three
yes why because these are
multiple three right yeah
okay so this divided by three so
this in order to be divided by three so
this p needs to be divided by three
right what's b
b needs to be
what's b
plus one and the plus two and the plus
three and four and the plus five so
let's what's this what's this beef it's
a bitch
times the
thing no no no no no look these this one
this one two three four five equals
this whole thing right
yeah
this left bit we proved it's divided by
three the p is one plus two plus three
plus one five is the sum of the digit
right
yeah
[Music]
so this question becomes that if we can
prove that the sum of digits divides by
three then this whole number is divided
by three am i right yeah that's what you
said at the beginning
yeah that's how we approve it
makes sense
yeah
ryan do you get it
yeah okay so let's see we have a number
yeah let's look in python you can say
defined divided by three divided by
three okay and n and it's a
string okay str yeah we can convert it
to in
into f n and then we can say divided by
sigma x
but
to uh to demonstrate these process let's
edit up the digit okay everywhere let's
end it update it
so we can do what the digit sum would be
s equals zero then we can say f o for i
in n yeah
s plus equals converted each bit to
to integer and then we just can return
if s divided by so you have
e equals zero okay
yeah go through each digit divided by
three okay yeah
is another easy way will be some
retain sum of what
we want to convert each one to it in to
i
for i
in list
n all right if this divided by three
equals zero
what does it mean look this n if
this if n is one two three because
the
the string list n will become
one
two
three okay
and then i go through this i and then
convert it to each each digit to integer
and then i sum it up and divided by
three equals zero yeah makes sense
yeah so what have you learned today so
far about how to divide by three
and how do we prove it
okay so it's one times uh a hundred and
i mean ten thousand like if it's one two
three four five
yeah
it's the same as one times
ten thousand
no one times of
minus one which is nine nine nine nine
plus one and nine nine nine nine is the
can divided by three
so we are actually looking these yeah so
any digit oh one two three yeah it
actually can be represented as a
multiple of
of these 999 you know in the in the form
of nines
right in the form of nice plus excel
right three three in the hundreds three
hundred is equals three times 99 plus 3
4 40 equals
4 times 9
plus 4 yeah
yeah 2 2 000 equals 2 times 99 plus 2
okay so all the left bits are divided by
three so that quick the
let's the value is actually equals the b
this bit yeah uh
the sum of the digits yeah
n equals a plus b a can be divided by
three so we are we just need to prove
that b can also be uh
divided by three all right make sense
yeah
and somehow by digit yeah we convert
each digit the string to integer yeah or
we can use the one one line sum in i for
i in this end
list n make it array
in i for i in this array convert each
digit
to a value and then we sum it using this
sum actually this sum is a lot faster if
we can sum it because this is
implemented in
c plus plus okay it's it's better expect
is quicker than this
for loop yeah if we call in this sum
function that will be a lot faster okay
okay that's it for today bye-bye