let's say we talk about some next
problem yeah knapsack knapsack
that's actually like a bag okay okay
okay a bag
so bad
so we have a few items yeah items
a few
items like uh and each one has weight
right the weight
wait let's say we have three items one
kilo two kilo three kilo
okay and then for each item we have
values right for example the first one
has one pound
one dollar us dollar okay five us dollar
two us dollar
and this next set yeah can hold all at
most
and most what capacity five kilo okay
five kilo
so for each item obviously we only have
one you can pick it or not pick it so
what's the total
what's the maximum what's the maximum
value we can pack these item
into
the knife set the bag
okay
right so which which
these three items which one you want to
pick let's so to maximize the value the
value in the back
the last one
this one
and
look we have capacity five so we if we
pick this we have two more
remaining two so which which one we
should pick
the middle one yeah so look two plus
three
is smaller or equal five and the value
we get is
five plus three equals eight so this is
the maximum value we can get okay so
let's call the zero one next step
problem
generally so let's formulize these a
little bit okay so look
each one we can pick or not pick right
which one we can pick or nothing let's
let's put it as uh
pick p okay p
equals uh zero value yeah zero zero zero
or one value okay so if we pick it we
use the one if we don't pick it
it's yellow okay
all right so so we want to pick the item
we want to maximize we want to maximize
maximize
maximize maximize what
p
p i
times
p i i okay i index yeah p i times the v
i we want to we want to maximize this
yeah so
that's the sum of it so maximize this is
the sum okay okay when this is sum i
from 0 to n minus 1 n is the number of
elements in number of items yeah number
of items
okay
sum can you read this sum
i from zero to n minus one p i times v i
when it's zero
what does it mean we don't pick it one
is one we pick it right but this is the
maximum this is our target we want to
maximize this but we want to suggest to
what it suggests to what we don't want
the total weight to except the capacity
right so the total weight is what i
equal 0
n minus 1
wait yeah wait
wait it will be wi
times pi
is less or equal than c okay
you see
less than equals c w i is the weight
times ti look
if it's zero it doesn't use up the space
if it's one
you use such space right yeah okay so
and then also we need to say p i
is belongs to
the yellow and one okay
yeah
this this makes it like zero one knocks
up okay
can we can we choose the most valuable
one if we go for this strategy can we
choose the most valuable one
can we choose look what's your strategy
here what
you pick the
why you pick the last one at the
beginning not the middle one
it's because
because these are three yeah you just
run them and pick one right okay so you
might know what the right why is that
because look if this is the most
variable how about it's very very happy
heavy yeah
you can't pick it you can always
you can obviously put this 100 into the
c equals five right so this doesn't work
that's heavy yeah that's heavy items one
how about how about there's another
strategy if we consider v divided by w
the ratio yeah but you need the the most
valuable items in the uni in a single
unit weight for example that would be
2.5 that would be one that would be one
and how about let's put it 1.1 here
right so let's please yeah we pick this
2.5 but the next one we pick 1.1 which
is not clearly not the optimum right
yeah because this
misleads us to pick these but obviously
we need to pick this one
right
yeah
make sense
okay so
so for each item we can pick or not pick
so how many items are an item for each
one i can pick or not pick so how many
choices do we have
the first one we have and two choice the
second one we haven't two choice the
third one we have one another to try so
what's the time complexity if we prove
something yes
that would be equivalent of finding the
subsequence right remember the
subsequence
that's dependent
not continue yeah for each one we can
pick or not pick each one the first one
has two choice the second one has two
choice the third one has two choice the
the we have n items so they are in
choice right and choice here and choice
the tangent next is two to the power of
n right
this is the equivalent of finding the
subsequent the number of subsequent yeah
yeah
so yeah so the time convention will be
this one pick in the number and
obviously we need to times n to find out
the um
to sum up yeah to sum the values up
right so this is not very feasible very
not not it's practically very slow okay
but as we said for each one we can pick
or not pick and if we can
write it right
if we can use the computer to remember
it remember yeah if we give it a set
okay we ask computers to remember what
kind of accurate come to your mind
[Music]
yeah that'll be programming okay and
i'll use the top down today and tomorrow
we'll talk about the butter up okay
okay so for each one
yeah so look define let's define cut
defined let's say
first search i know for two parameters
the first parameter i the second
pendulum is c y
and c okay good question that's a good
question what does it mean it means that
we are remember that the numbers we're
picking yeah yeah we're picking the
numbers remember yeah it's quite similar
to that problem
we are picking the ice num ice item okay
we are picking the ice item okay
the
the the first item is zero yeah
we are kicking with ice item and then we
have capacity c
in the next
okay look if i equal equal length the
the weight or i value yeah doesn't
matter
if we have
we are running out of items
so we return the value which will be
what
[Music]
yeah it's the same you can put a value
yeah it's the same it's the length right
the length of the values and uh
weights are the same yeah different the
same thing yeah
represent the number of items right now
now for
now i i can get the answer at the
beginning of this year okay now like if
if this capacity we have capacity equal
bigger than equal the weight
current item is weight high
right so look we have capacity c and the
current item has weight this weight all
right
if
we have enough capacity to pick this
item
right so we can pick it we can try to
pick it
right you can just take it answer equals
max answer
and if we pick it
pick it dfs we need to pick the next
item
and what happened to the capacity if we
pick it what's the capacity left
minus weighs i yeah we just need to
minus here
i yeah this one
and then we we have picked this so we
have we we gain the value right plus
values what i
make sense
right and obviously we cannot we we can
choose not to pick this item right so i
can say
answer equals max answer
we're not picking it dfs but we try to
move to the next item yeah and then we
still have capacity c if we don't pick
it right
yeah
return answer make sense
what's missing here
if we're not putting any sketch
right
exponential it's like i said o two to
the power of n right yeah to the power
to the power because each one we can
pick or not pick each one will pick
nothing
i and c right so it's actually
what i and c so
i will be the item okay if we list the
values here okay this is i
i will be the number of items yeah so
you'll be 0 1
here
and minus 1 right this is item and then
c is the capacity
yeah yeah we we saw this
table before yeah if we want to pick
these
and minus one item and then capacity c
somehow here yeah c somehow here i want
to compute this value
but the computer needs to go through
these okay then you look for the
for what for the values here somewhere
and then these would be again we need to
calculate in order to calculate this
value i need to calculate a few more
values right
yeah but each time
each time
i calculate this value i make it i may
have to calculate some
same pixel same number again and again
right yeah but if i put a cache what's
the what's the maximum number of values
i need to compute in this table
and uh times n where down c times n yeah
yeah if i'm gonna catch it right because
everything i only calculate once if i
calculate it and what what what do we do
we store the numbers in the cash
right so the next time you just look it
up the value and you don't need to
to do it again and again right okay
yeah look look at this one
now
if if the current capacity is bigger
than the weight the weight now we can
pick it we can try to pick it when we
try to pick it
the weight needs to substrate these but
the values need to pass it right yeah
right
and
look eyes
0 to n and we can obviously we can start
from i backwards yeah from n minus 1 to
0 this is the same thing
this implementation is from 0 to n minus
1 because look this is plus 1 right if
we start from n minus one to zero this
this will be minus one minus one and
then these will be
smaller than zero right okay
yeah
yeah smaller than zero okay let's write
this book if this is smaller than zero
right smaller than zero and this needs
to minus one yeah
and then we in order to get this value
we just return dfs
uh n minus one which is length of weight
or length of values n minus 1 and at the
beginning we have capacity c
all right
so you'll be start at this value yeah in
order to calculate this value what
happened
we might have to calculate
this value uh here if we don't pick
anything or if we pick that item could
be somewhere here right somewhere here
right somewhere here
right and again in order to calculate
this value we need to take a release
value
or somewhere here right okay
and so these this looking up this is
top-down top-down dynamic programming if
we put a cache
yeah make sense
anybody any questions
no questions okay are you sure okay can
you explain to me what's this
what's this
what's this this is the most important
thing to take away from the cash
can can somebody explain to me about
this why are we
is um greater than the weight which is
good because
[Music]
if this is current remaining capacity of
the back right the left side it's bigger
than this item well wait we can try to
book it yeah yeah you can burn level one
you can put it and then once we put it
what will happen
we need to substrate away from the
capacity yeah do the dms but again we
get a value right and then you can get
another one yeah and for and we can get
around
this is just two choice yeah this is
this choice is that
if we can put a put a value
and try we try putting it
right
because in
basically for each item we only have two
choice we pick it or not pick it right
[Music]
right
we pick it
this one is we don't kick it if we don't
pick it we try the the next item
with why this is c if we don't pick it
this is very obvious what does it say
because the
capacity the capacity capacity why is
this see if we don't pick it why is it
seriously because because you don't did
nothing change
where does nothing change yeah if we
don't pick it nothing change we try next
item right yeah if we pick it we can
pick it we try next item but the weight
needs to be subtracted and the value
needs to be yeah that's the maximum
weather i know we get the maximum yeah
yeah okay the time can taxi l times c
times n yeah
as we said right if we put a cash it's
all c times n okay
and if we don't take it it's o to the
power of n
you have l to the power of n actually
because each one will pick up and times
times the
n right times n okay
the number of items yeah we need to put
two the number of items and this one we
can pick on the pick so actually this is
the same as
iterating the
array and try each subsequent right for
each subsequence we need to
compute its
its weight right its values right yeah
it's where it is
yeah okay that's it for today good job
bye-bye