yesterday we'll talk about this the zero
one knapsack yeah zero one meaning that
each item
that you can pick at most once right so
there's one item for there's one number
the quantity the quantity for each item
is one you can pick it or you you can
skip it
but if you pick it you can only pick one
right so we use the dynamic programming
top-down dynamic programming yeah dfs ic
when we are picking the ice items and we
have a remaining capacity c
right then you have two choice if the
remaining capacity is bigger or larger
larger or equal than the weight of the
current item and you can choose to pick
it right if it's smaller than the
current weight weapon
if the remaining capacity is less than
the weight of the current item do you
can you pick it no no because it's too
heavy right yeah because for example
your capacity is 10 and then the item is
20 you can't put the 20 into your bag 10
right but when it's bigger than the
weight then you can keep you can try
we can try to pick it yeah we don't pick
it we subtract the weight the weight of
the camera item
from the remaining capacity and in the
meantime we added the
the values we get okay and then
obviously for each item we can skip it
but we can skip it then we have still
remaining capacity
yeah and then the key point here is we
use the cache to remember the values
of the
how many values we need to remember
the n times c
n times c so the time complexities o and
c
space complexities o and c as well right
so we are actually storing the values
i times c okay so let's stop down we use
the dynamic programming top down the
question with the minimization right all
right
so in the process
in the bottom up yeah
[Music]
so we need to store these i time c
values
in an array right and then we take
can compute the values we fill the
tables basically look in the bottom we
feel the values first row of values and
then we start feeding the second row
yeah this is bottom up yeah in the top
down we want to calculate this value and
in order to calculate this value with
the question with the recursion with
minimization it needs to retrieve the
value of the previous node and again it
will recursion the location will bring
us down to the value with the smaller i
right i is the row okay
yeah
and how how the computer remember the
values cash
but in flipped r
we we use the i
array
which has two-dimensional array i can
see right to remove the values and then
we start feeling the values from the
first row right after we fill the first
row we fill the second row compute the
second row and compute the third until
we reach this yeah dp
n minus one capacity yeah until we reach
this value okay so let's do this bottom
up okay
just remember the directions yeah bottom
top
down the time complexity for each for
both is is the same the time and space
but usually usually the recursion
is slower than the butter up yeah
usually you know practically speaking
the
butter up approach is faster why is that
because there's no recursion call
there's no function call
for computer for us to call a recursion
right
we need to
spend time overhead in calling the
function recursion yeah okay which is
faster usually come on
and recursion is known
because there's a fun function called
right that's the function called that
you have to we have to push the function
call let's stack we have to push the
call into the stack right that's usually
slower than
us
actively proactively
what you're doing
we're actively installing the values in
in the array okay
okay so
let's just review the problem again
right okay so we have a few items
values uh the weight
is a uh w is the
is the
a list of the weights yeah weights like
one two three okay
and the values i is the values we can
get like one five three okay
right and then pi remember this pi is
the value of zero one selection meaning
that zero we don't pick it one we pick
it right
zero one knob set
and zero one message
so we have also the capacity like
something like five the next step so
what are we trying to maximize here we
are trying to maximize the goal
is to what the maximize let's try to
maximize what
we want to sum up this is the sum right
i equals zero to n minus one and n
equals the number of the item yeah which
is three and three items the size of
these are the same okay items
anyway what did i just say what's n
n is what
is the items
okay so we try look at the sub we try to
maximize i equals zero to m um
minus n minus one so the p i times v i
that's the value we are trying to get
yeah v p i times v i okay
p i times v i okay
and then we also want to
to make sure the total weight does not
exceed exceed the total capacity
so we are trying to do this i equals 1
to angle 0 to
n minus 1 p i
times w i this is the weight okay
and also you know p i
belongs to
zero one one there's only two possible
values you don't click it or we pick it
there make sense do you understand do
you can you read this mathematics
equation to describe the problem
do you know
do you understand all right ryan any
questions come on this is the good good
chance for you to understand that's
mathematics
what are we trying to do here
we're trying to maximize the p i times w
i v i the value look this is the value
yeah we times it something together yeah
now this is the value total value we can
get
subject to make sure that p i times w i
added together does not exist the total
weight
suggests to these uh equals to the way
okay
yeah and each value why this why this pi
has only two values zero one
[Music]
right look what is zero zero times
anything doesn't matter right look one
is a zero zero times wi
is yellow right anything so it means
this item does not take up
any capacity from the original one but
it's one
it's one now we need to edit the value
yeah for example this one
the value two plus three yeah look
what's what's the what's these uh p i
times w i sum together zero times one
plus one times two plus one times three
equals five is less than equal to one
and what's the value
five times one
look at it one times zero plus five
times one plus three times one which is
eight so the maximum is eight right the
weight is five okay
yeah make sense
all right right okay
okay then let's do this the bottom up
okay
let's do this button up
so we suppose we need to store the
values in array right so it's a two
dimensional way remember
yesterday we call this cache
top down and dynamic programming we have
this dms function i and c right so it
has two dimensions i and c so we need to
be able to store the uh these values the
combination of these values yeah
internal array okay
let's say define knapsack
let's take
0 1 and then
we have our values
we have the
weight
and we have the capacity okay capacity
okay
capacity so let's say
dt equal we have we need to allocate the
two-dimensional rate so at the beginning
which is zero
for the second dimensional is capacity
so for underscore in range
c plus one right because we need to be
able to
be able to store the value up to c
including c okay
and then
the first dimension is up to
for underscore in
range
up to n okay
what's n n will be the length of the
values right the length of values the
number of items
is also equal to the num the number of
weights okay
so now the first row remember the first
row yeah this is the first one
and they can't tell me what's the first
row okay so i
this is the first item okay first item
the second item third either here
n minus one the capacity or capacity
cll capacity we want to take fact
nothing when the back
has zero capacity when the back has one
capacity two capacity etcetera and here
c
okay
so the first row we need to be we we you
know for the recursion top down dynamic
problem with the recursion we can use
the if remember if c
is smaller if i smaller than zero will
become zero right we can just do an if
chair
so that's easier
that's that's easier for us to implement
but for the top uh butter up we need to
be a we need to
tell the computer what values are those
this initial value
so dp
can you tell me what
pp0 the first law
tp0c
what should we give to the value when we
are considering first row
and then we have the capacity so we are
only considering the first item okay
this is the first item
yeah and then we have a back with the
capacity c
okay so
so what's the maximum value we can get
come on we have only one item and we
have a bag with the
capacity c
so what values you are what where what
maximum value can we get one
one no no no
you need y is one
why is one y is zero think about it okay
so this item has the value
has the very v zero okay has the weight
w0
i'm telling you
that the item has the value zero this
value this weight and what is it with
this capacity c
so what's the value we can get
what's the value we can get what should
i put this in here come on should we we
need to
first of all check which one is bigger
right yeah
this value this this way
when this weight is smaller than c what
happened
when when the item i'm trying to put in
the back is is smaller so i can get this
value right
yeah but when this is bigger
when this is heavier bigger than c what
happened
then so what's the value there
we can't poke it what's the value we can
get
if we don't put it put it oh there's
only one item
there's one bag with c
and this item when this weight is
smaller than c okay we can put it put it
we get this value but if we can't put it
when this value is bigger than c we
can't put it what happened what's the
value
zero exactly that's
it but
that's true situation remember yeah
that's two different cases you need to
tell me
right
i'm right does it make sense yeah
yeah
make sense look this value needs to be
if it's heavier than a plug you can't
put it that's zero but it's if we can
put it that's the value we can get right
yeah
so we need to initialize this value we
have the first row okay so we need to
initialize the first one
for
i
in
range
capacity plus one right
look
dp the first row the first item
and
the capacity i equal even zero
if
is what is the weight yeah the weight
let's put the easy one w
if the first item
the weight is bigger than than i
right now we can put it right
and if we can put it then that's zero
right can you actually understand this
one
what what are we doing here
what are we doing here the whole thing
here
what are we doing anybody everyone
we are
doing
the first round we want to put a
computer first row right and first law
is that this is we are considered in the
first item right and then if we can put
it
then we put a if we can put it we put a
vi for example yeah vi here yeah
if yeah if we can put it for v v0 here
all right if component
if the way uh
look at the c
w zero is bigger than i if w zero is
bigger than i then
that's bigger than i i i is increasing
if i is increasing then then
uh
i i is increasing the capacity
increasing then there will be zero
obviously
in the right right it could be zero
look if c
is bigger
if the capacity c is smaller look if
it's more if it's bigger than that that
will be here would be the value
like most likely okay most likely
but if the capacity is smaller than the
value like this would be zero right
yeah i'm just giving you some example
and after this we're filling the first
row and then now what should we do after
we fill in the first row what should we
do now
second row until which row
three
until n minus one row because we have an
items right so that the first row will
be for i in we start from the second row
which is one second row right up to n
the interval and the second iteration
will be for j in range
let's start to c plus one right and then
now i i can i can feel each
each pixel yeah so each each uh each
number in each law in the ira dpij
equals max
max of what dpi's actually do we need
the pij
we
we probably don't need it okay let me
let me write it first
dpij and look if we can if we don't take
it obviously would be j
dpi minus one right the previous item
with sphere 3 complexity
if we can pick it
if we can pick it i minus 1
j minus the weight weight will be which
item
i
right
and at the meantime we have the value
value let's call let's
let's change this to value yeah the
value i right
what's the sound
okay
and but look
the j needs to be bigger than w i right
so i have to say if j bigger or equal
than w i
s otherwise l otherwise they'll be just
zero okay yeah and then and then at the
end we just return
dp
n minus one capacity c
right
i
j look when we compute the dpi jig we
are only
relying on i minus one the previous row
j and y so we probably don't need to put
a max here right we can just say dpij
equals least
uh max obviously max max of these two
approaches okay either we don't pick it
we don't pick it we still remaining j
capacity or we pick it j minus w i w i
is the current weight of the current
either j minus
i
but if we pick it we get the
value that v i okay
yeah
yeah if j bigger than w i right if j is
smaller than w i what does it mean it
means that the current weight the item
current weight too much
yeah
has has exceeded the capacity of j like
in this case we can pick it and let's
zero right remember this is quite
similar to here right yeah i rely on
anybody
all right
yeah
what's the time complexity come on it's
a easy one
and then
oh and c because we're just feeding them
we're just feeding the uh table yeah
rows by rows column by columns yeah
we're starting feeding yeah one by one
and the first row here and then second
row
and then so
yeah we are trying to fill in the table
yeah yeah we're trying to find whatever
when we fill in this table we need to
compute we need to rely on the previous
one this one
for example we are calculating here we
are calculating
this this
cell here yeah so we need to compare
this value which we have
we have computed yeah and then we need
to go through the
the range j minus w i could be somewhere
somewhere some somewhere here yeah for
example if with this one then which one
is bigger and then i put it here i stole
the value here right
yeah and when i store this value here
the next row
yeah the next when i take it right here
i also need to
to
reference this one right and then the
previous one right make sense
yeah
okay so to sum up what have you learned
so far today
[Music]
so what what
what approach is this we are we are
calculating from bottom to up so what
are we calling bottom of dynamic
programming okay what's dynamic
programming come on uh just remembering
stuff remember stuff we're done
remembering the values yeah we're
remembering that very well positively
solving the values in the array right
that's the difference to the
top-down dynamic programming which we
use just the magic keyword cache right
we ask computer to catch it
yeah the top down the top down we want
to calculate this value yeah okay this
is the keyboard come on
top down dynamic programming we want to
calculate this value we ask computer
okay let's compare that just to this top
down yeah you could uh for each value
you might we
you will have a cash to remember yeah
you can have this it knows how to
remember once can you calculate it let's
stop now but for the butter up we we are
constructing the table by ourselves
proactively right we're starting the
values in the dp right we can build the
first row we store the value in a table
and we use the first row to compute the
second row we use the second row to
compute the third row etc until we reach
the n minus one row okay
to answer okay the last row okay
yeah
uh practically speaking the top-down
dynamic programming is easier to
implement because the for the you know
for the boundary yeah for the boundary
if if the weight is smaller than
if the current capacity is smaller than
the weight of the current item then it
returns zero but
so we have to say okay it's zero right
yeah yeah yeah okay
so ideally
so to sum up the total dynamic
programming is
is what it's easier to
implement yeah because we're just making
use of the cache it match to match
keyword cache to ask computer to
remember the very fast right it's easier
to implement
the top part of dynamic programming
in a reverse way yeah a calculated value
in the reverse order
is
you know it's it's it's not
so easy to implement right we have to
construct the values array two two
dimensional arrays with stored values in
it right
and then it's it's i mean there's
details that
you might go wrong that things might go
wrong right but it's quicker
yeah
in terms of time and space complexity
both are the same right because both are
all computing the values filling the
values in the table and each one is only
calculated once right either using cash
or using the array make sense
yeah
okay that's it for today bye