anybody so what's the problem about the
problem hey there are
you know you have a bag i have a bag a
knapsack yeah that's good with the
capacity see yeah maximum commercial
weight
item a few items a few a few data items
yeah this is each one
in your bag
wait and then we have a value and you
fit it in your bag i know what's the
objective
what's
you up
you have a maximum maximum weight
yeah yeah okay so yeah to sum up we have
a few items and we want to put it in an
app cell with the capacity c and we want
to maximize the values they have values
each one has the value point number like
the value one
five three and the weights could be
something like one two three okay
and then the capacity to be
of the next step is five so what's the
optimum
solution if we want to
pick put the two put items in the back
right
three five and three three
so which two items you
would you like to take
one
yeah okay two plus three that's not
equal than five that's all you're gonna
find and then the values we attempt is
five plus three okay so let's be
objective that's the problem and if we
if we we can describe we can describe
the problem using the mathematics
remember yeah
so let me just repeat again okay just uh
so we have the v which stands for values
it's an array vi yeah vi is the values
and then we have uh
wi is the weight and we have a c which
is the capacity maximum capacity of the
knob set and we have the pi which is
stands for
wow stencil for the if we want to pick
it yeah decide to pick it so it belongs
to
it only has two values zero and one
right zero and one zero means that we
don't pick it the item is item we don't
pick it and one means that we pick it
so we want to maximize maximize yeah
maximize let's say maximize what
p i
okay sum of these sum of p i times v i
right
we also maximize the total value we put
on the next step but
we also we want to make sure that the
sum of the p i times w line
the weight
is less order equal than c right
okay and then look p i is zero and one
okay so that's the mathematic problem
that's we call it zero point two one
knapsack zero one what's the other one
zl1 is comes from here look it only has
two values p only has two values zero
and one okay
yeah and we talked about what
they we talked about what kind of
solution uh have we talked about
well what have we talked about talk
about the solutions
um dynamic programming
humanization
[Music]
top down
and the bu is that we stole the values
in the dp array of nfdp array
okay we're done
okay so let's review let's just quickly
implement it okay
shout out if if you remember yeah let's
let's implement the top down first okay
dfs
we are putting the we are currently
putting the ice item with the capacity c
right
if
i is smaller than zero means that we
we return
return one
if we're running out of items the
previous item would return zero right
yeah so for each item we how many choice
do we have
how many choices how many i how many
choice do we
have two what are those
obviously there's one condition is that
if the current if the capacity yeah
is how about if look if the item is too
heavy then we can't pick it right yeah
okay so that we have this answer at the
beginning this is the maximum value we
can put
when we're considering the item okay so
if c is bigger than bigger or equal than
the values the weight
weight of the item common item now we
can pick it right everyone come on
we can pick it which is
answer equals max
answer okay actually we don't need to
put the max here because it's zero so
answer equals one
b f s
i minus one the previous item but we
pick it
we pick it and we not pick it pick it
what happened to c if we pick it plus
rock tom see what what happened
what happens
c the capacity what is it plus capacity
because you need to add it
this is the remaining capacity if we
pick the current weight what happened to
c
is minus 1
minus this way yeah wait
okay but if we pick it we can
attend the value yeah values i right
yeah
okay and then this will be the case of
not picking it right not picking it
no picking what happened what happened
with the
what's the second parameters
if we don't pick it what happened with
the c do we need to change
this yeah
and every time
this is the top down okay
what what's missing here come on
what happens if we don't put the cat it
actually moves what what happens if we
don't put a test train explanation
why because you have to keep on doing
the same thing again
you can't remember it with your smooth
dumb brain
okay okay so yeah we put the cash to
last computer to remember the values for
us yeah remember if we cut
look just imagine if we put if we call
these like 100 like a hundred two
hundred i have a c equals four hundred
and then you would call the previous
value dftfs i minus one uh
yeah 200 and then these could be
something smaller with a smaller value
right but sometimes this value dfs ic
could be used multiple times and that's
why we need to remember it once we have
the value so the next time
we want this value we just just use it
yeah just like looking at the values in
the dictionary in the notebook
okay
so with the bottom up we store the
values yeah
we have this table look basically we
have a this table with an i and a c
capacity yeah this is a two dimensional
table
i equals zero first item two yeah
etcetera and m minus one yeah we we have
m items
index zero for n minus one the capacity
zero one two three assessor tlc
so we are feeling we we want to feel the
taper right we wanna feel the table and
the top down the enemy program yeah we
just ask computer to give us the right
the bottom right value right and then
what computer does is that okay you will
work out the the previous one the i
minus one variance here somewhere
somewhere you probably need this very
decent value this value and again in
order to calculate this value it needs
to
reference the previous value right here
here here here right great this is top
down okay here is top okay this just
imagination this is top this is the
bottom okay this is the opposite okay
top down okay top down all right butter
up right bottom
top now because top top look
cut that at least we are given this eye
like a hundred two hundred right right
we want to assess this value so look if
if this is the tree right 100 200 here
and then you need to be able to
calculate the value based on 99
something yeah
a few values yeah look a few values if
you explain the trick let's talk down
right down i bought it out in calculus
from the bottom of that so from the
first row right now
so so we talked about the top bottom up
we have stored the values in the two
dimensional array right vp
so basically look this is a two
dimensional i and c so we store this
value in dpi and c right
yeah
okay so for the first number let me just
implement this okay so for the first row
yeah we store the values and then we use
the first row to compute the second row
you use the second row to compute the
zero row and etcetera until we get the
last row right well ideally you just
want the value out here dp n minus one i
will be n minus one and then c will be
capacity like capacity
can i have your attention please okay
guys
okay
so what's the problem here what's the
problem here
what's the problem here come on look
let me just explain again i i calculate
we can kill the first row and then we
use the first row to compute the second
row we use the second row to compute the
third row what's the what's the problem
here
[Music]
so
first question do i need to keep all the
values in two-dimensional
why is that good
because that's the good direction why do
we why we don't need to keep all the
table because we will remember
look because look here
when i calculate dpi c
i just need the value of dpi minus 1
right nothing else yeah
so look in the bottom up right in the
bottom
in the bottom i calculate i feel the
first row right i feel the first row and
then i hear the second row so so how can
i
how how do we calculate the values right
fill in the table
minus one yeah yeah look we we start
filling the rows row by row yeah first
row second row zero and then for each
row we fill in the values from left to
the right so basically it's butter up
left to the right okay
okay so now uh so we we only need
required value for the previous load so
we can compress the space right all
right so instead of
instead of declare the dpic the
two-dimensional array we just need
which dimension do we need to keep dpi
or dbc which dimension
which
which dimension come on
i just need a previous though so i need
to declare which which dimension tpc or
dpi come on
why is dpi
ppc yeah look because this is raw i just
need these yeah yeah
okay so i just need the ppc right
right because every time i compute that
one row i just need a previous row so
why not just keep a record of the
previous row right and we just can say
we can improve the time space complexity
from dp
from what from oc times n right that's
the times and space complexity into one
the previous one the bottom up is what
[Music]
is the same because we still need to go
through the procedure yeah we need to
iterate there are an item there's no way
that we can make a decision we can
compute the maximum value without going
through the night am i right yeah okay
okay so uh
so let me just write uh
write a photo out dynamic programming
with uh
uh
[Music]
with what
we said
let me just try that out let me put me
okay
define
that's the knapsack
zero one and we have the values let's
just call v we have the weight and we
have a c okay
v value w for weight and c for capacity
okay so now
we we have to do what we have to dp
that's uh
we have
we need to find out the the length of
the the number of items which is n and
this length of the v or an ends of w it
doesn't matter okay so now t p
equals the first dimension okay the
first dimension is what
for
underscore in range this is the second
dimension which is c plus one right uh
and then four underscore in
range
which is n right so look so the
c
column c
and then n rows right okay and then we
need to fill our first row right
remember for i in
range
okay let's start from the c
up to
weights
weighs zero minus one and i explained
what what was here okay and then
d p the first row zero
yeah try to understand okay i'll explain
all right i
the first dimension is what is the item
the second dimension is
is the remaining so which is the value i
okay so what what does this mean here
remember this table yeah into memory
stable i
uh c
okay we are trying to
i equals yeah we're trying to fill the
first row okay initially initially this
is all zero and all the values zero but
we are trying to
feel the rows from c up to up to weight
zero weight weight zero
is the weight of the first item
minus one is up to remember this is up
to not including right so c
from we we change i we iterate from i to
from c to weight i because why is that
the capacity is bigger than weight then
we can get a value right yeah
previously in the previous lesson i what
did we talk about we just say okay from
i equals we can iterate from this row
right these values but we have to check
if the remaining if the i is bigger than
the weight if it's smaller than a way
what happened
if it look if we can
yeah yeah exactly if the weight is too
heavy to put if the first item is too
heavy to put in the knapsack we can't
pick it then the value will be zero
right initially will be zero but if
if the next step is big bigger than the
weight right look c up to weight
now we can took it and what value can we
get
v0 okay v0 the first first item right i
know with this then we can go through
the value yeah for i in
range
we can start filling the first row up to
n minus lower and y
one to n right and then we just go for
this it doesn't matter if you're going
from the left to the right or right to
the left okay for j in
range why is that because look
one
we already have the previous note so it
doesn't matter we go from the left or
that right to the left right because all
the values we want
is there right so
it doesn't matter if i i calculate value
from left to the right or right to the
left
right because the previous row is
already ready right
yeah so range let's say we can start
from the
zero to two capacity yeah c plus one and
then we can do this dp
i j like this is the function and equal
as what it was the max
uh maximum we put it on we don't put it
we don't put it we don't think it would
be i minus one j with the same capacity
yeah if we put it it'll be i minus one
j minus minus what the the weight weight
the i right
but when we put it we get the value we
have v i right but obviously j needs to
be bigger than w i so if j
bigger or equal than w i
dlr right yeah and we put these to check
yeah
all right let's start let me go with and
then return
within one dp
n minus one capacity
okay yeah yeah this is not new yeah yeah
this is not new we have talking about
that
right yeah
okay okay so now
we we just say we want to compress yeah
into least n times c we want to look
this is this is enzyme c table yeah we
just imagine we want to
compress into one row
yeah
why can we compress
because
[Music]
why can we compress what what why why
can't we do it
why can't we do it
it's because
when we access change when we calculate
the value here we want we want to put
the value here so what values do we need
the higher rise yeah the previous low
just the one do we need
two rows of above no right we so we we
at any time we we are feeling look we
are starting freezing some low barrel
yeah the first external loop is grow so
we we starting to feeding the low rose
from the bottom up yeah both up left to
the right okay
yeah yeah this here is purple right yes
but
it's quite
yeah
this is top this is the bottom
do you understand yeah okay
right dpi only needs the dpi minus one
and dpi minus one right
okay
okay so now we want to be able to
squeeze it squeeze it so here we don't
need we don't need this
we just say dp 0
times
tb 0 for underscore in range
c plus one okay or you can say zero
times c plus one okay this is the same
okay two there are two ways of writing
it okay yeah which way you think you
it's easier to remember
uh i think
these are the same which one the bottom
one looks kind of complicated
okay but some people find this this one
is quite easy to understand okay so i
have an array of zero of zero and i want
to times this z plus one times
okay so let's that's a little bit okay
okay
okay yeah that's fine so
again here
we don't need our first dimension right
right because we only have
have one dimension so we'll be able to
get get rid of the first dimension
yeah this will be okay and now this will
be okay and now here
okay
here this is a bit tricky so in order to
compress the final uh space you have to
we have to
inversely enumerate from j from capacity
up to
so we have to
go from the right to the left instead of
left to the right
why is that because if we going from
left to right the smaller that dp
smaller dp0 up to
j
yeah should be overwritten okay to be
overwritten
yeah so we have to go through from the
right to that to make sure it's not over
without okay what was it that you just
say
um
so which way should we use
these
i know what i mean what you just said
you missed what what did i say i was
just saying that
for j in range
previously it doesn't matter it doesn't
matter left to right or right to the
left but now we only have one one
dimensional so we need to
we we need to emulate enumerate the j
from the capacity from right to the left
okay this is only what uh direction that
it works okay
why is that because if you iterate from
left to right the tp with the smaller j
that will be overwritten okay that's
what i said so here i i just need to go
from j
well from the capacity up to
the uh minus y minus one okay and then i
need to go
uh remove the first direction yeah tpj
equals
max
j
and then and
erase the first dimension db j minus wi
plus vi right if j look okay so look if
j bigger than w i l is zero so i can i
can also get rid of this but and then i
change this c up to double
i
minus one right right so if i put it
then i don't need this if check right
make sense
yeah
alright yeah
so previously look j from ranging from c
up to zero right up to zero
but you have to check if j is bigger or
equal than w i if it's bigger or equal
than it
the cpj minus wi makes sense right plus
w and this means that we are picking the
i
because this current remaining capacity
is bigger than the way of current item
then i can pick it i can pick it and
then again
i can get the value right
only if j is bigger than w if j is
smaller than w it means that this item
is too big to put in in the back with j
capacity then i should get a zero right
yeah you get this part
okay so now look because this j j is
decrementing from c to zero at some
point it will fall
have 4 below wj so in this case i can
just say okay let's stop at w
i minus 1 which is up to
yeah it will be stopping at w i and then
i don't need this s zero okay
the time complexity look o n times c is
the same the space complexity
oc right because we are compressing the
space we instead of using two
dimensional array we are only using one
dimensional layer which has the c plus
one elements right so the time compare
the space complexity so c so
about all these three um
approaches
dynamic programming which one do you
think is the most efficient one in terms
of time and space complexity
the last question come on
which one
is this one
uh-huh why is that
alright
why is that
which one is the most efficient the
first one top-down dynamic programming
with the cash yeah cash
it's easy to implement right but as i
said before the location with some
implementation might be a bit slow
compared to the bottom up right the
second approach button up we create this
table and we try to fill the values go
by row column by column right from the
bottom
first row second row zero and column one
column zero from left to right okay and
the third approach we are optimizing the
space into one dimension so the space
complexity is c the time complexity is
always sometimes there so which one is
the most efficient one
which one
normally which one you know this is the
last series of the zero one next area
because i spent three days including
today to talk about this problem and
there are three approaches so normally
which approach comes the is the best the
last one yeah usually i talk about
optimization at least it's the most
optimal one we're done with that okay
access because because the time
complexity for all three
is the same oc times m although the
first one top down dynamic programming
is the cache
might be practically speaking a little
bit slow compared to butter up and the
second approach and the third approach
the same complexity yeah we just change
so what what did i think just change
look i just changed here right i changed
this to optimize to one space and then i
didn't change anything here right i i
changed the second loop from left to
right i changed it to right to the left
and all this i just remove the first
dimension right
yeah no much change here right so the
second approach the third approach
is is use less space right with less
space and
and generally speaking is the the second
and the third approach is equal
equivalently
performance yeah faster okay then the
first one okay
okay that's it for today yeah thank you
bye bye
bye bye are you are you still here are
you still with me bye
bye bye bye