[Music]
so we give it a string like a a b a b
okay
if we want to split you know split split
the string into two non empty parts
straight into two a
b a non empty how many ways can we do it
if we can
split the string into two parts but both
needs to be non-empty how many ways are
there
if the string has like these five
characters how many ways how many
how many ways can we split the string
into two non-empty parts two
two yeah two three or two two
one two
okay can you release the the a and abba
abba abba uh
how many characters one two three four
five let's end how many ways can we
split it
so it's n minus one yeah because we want
the long empty antibody okay okay
okay so above these four therefore yeah
how many
which two you know if we split into two
and each part has the same number of
distinct characters same distinct what
does that mean
this thing this thing what's this thing
unique yeah
characters we need
so look here we only have a here we have
a b right so look here has a this is a b
it's not the same
here a a
here a b here a here a b not the same
yeah a b a b look here has two a one b
this is one a one b but both have one
both have letters a and b so here
we count it and here
no right
yeah this is a and b here is b doesn't
have a
okay so we we want to check
and add is correct okay so look what's
what's the purpose here is we want to
count how many how many ways we can
split into the there's only one into two
distinct characters
right some distinct characters
any idea how we can do it any idea how
[Music]
how many ways can we can split into look
we can we said n minus one well we can
proof of it right we can just pull from
each
and then
and then and and then and then um how do
we check if both have intersect
in a set and what particularly in
yeah settle for the idea and another way
with
what kind of data structure are we using
to count
counter yeah we can use the counter and
we check the keys
right
we check the length of the keys if it's
equal right yeah okay so let's quickly
write this okay and then you know what
by implementing this we know the problem
better okay okay
please
define okay let's say just uh split
uh
split
into two three two okay
uh s
so first of all if the string is empty
we just return zero yeah because there's
no way
to
spread into two okay now let's let's
implement it let's let's do this for i
in range
length
s
okay
and then i look here s is here now i
just need to iterate this is i is zero
so i need to counter
i need to look here this part is s
i plus one okay and then
the right most bit the we split into the
string into two parts yeah the left
fifth is this yeah up to i including i
right the right bit is start from i
plus one to the end right
okay so let's say c1 equals counter yeah
we want to count
s up to i plus one
and c two is we want to call the the the
string on the right right so it's
counter
s i plus 1 to the n right
so how do we check if both parts have
the same number of characters uh you
know
distinct characters
we check the
what what do we check what counter what
does the counter have it's the
accountant
so what's the key of the counter
it's like it it's like how many times
each one appears let's try it yeah so
the keys are the distinct characters the
values are the number they appear right
so we want to check the keys or the
values of the c1 and c2 so how do we
compare it with c1 or c2
if
is what
c1 what's this what's how many
characters in c1
what how do we use it it's the same as
the
yeah yeah so it's length the key
length c1 this is the number of keys
which is the number of characters equals
the length of c2
all right and then we implement answer e
plus equal one and we need to initialize
the answer equals zero and return
another one yeah okay yeah
make sense look we go through the eye
and then each eye we split into two
halves and we use the counter right the
counter we do we count the stop the the
the string on the left and the string on
the right the partition you have to
partition
and then if the keys this is the key the
same number of the distinct characters
yeah we don't compare with the values
because values could be different right
yeah aab and aba
yeah that
aab which is
a2 b1 right and abb which will be
a1 b2 right look
but then c1 and c2 both
return two so these two equal right
answer equal one plus equal one right
make sense yeah we don't compare with
the values we only compare with the key
the length c1 and c2
so that does that mean you only contain
a's and b's
because because he said
we returned too
okay yeah that's very good point okay so
let me rephrase this bit a little bit if
the string only contains two a and b
okay and how about if we don't contain
it if not then we have we can change
this to one if we want to compare the a
and b are also equal right yeah
yeah so then we can say what if set
c1
the keys okay so if c1 the keys yeah c1
the keys is the
yeah a b right and equal
set c two dot b yeah
yeah
okay and then answer plus one okay make
sense yeah yeah okay okay that's a very
good point because if we use the length
what could happen if a and b at least
could be c and d they're different right
but then they're also two
makes sense
okay let's look at a very good one okay
what's the time from juxtaposition
[Music]
this is quite tricky look here and
where that one squared because counter
we have to do this and there's n here
and then let's here and the o n square
stays complexity
what's the space format
oh n
we can do it uh we can do it faster yeah
we can do it faster why is that look
every time by just right
with your big brain
okay so now look
i'm saying look look here this this is
c1 and this is c2
if i move the partition one character to
the right what happened
if i move this i position one position
to the right what happened if this
character is s i
do it how do we update c1 and c2
yeah
currently i'm seeing i hear the left is
c1 the right is c2 yeah
okay so what happens if i move the i one
position one character to the right
so what do i need to do with the ci plus
one
ci needs to include this letter yeah
but c2 needs to
delete it well done right so in
this one is slow why is that
because every time i need to count it
again again again yeah i need to
dynamically counting the two parts this
takes a long time but look i know i
every time move one character i can
update it a one time i can update c2 a
one time okay right
yeah so that'll be a faster right at
least will be fast okay
so let's do this
you're not gonna write the whole thing
just half of it
that's
about um
okay so in now i need to declare the c1
and c2 outside c1 is on the left counter
so you'll be empty so what happened to
the c2 c2 will be counter bar instead of
instead of looks at the beginning c1 is
nothing here yeah nothing c2 is the
whole string so what parameters do i
give it to string s s yes s yeah yeah
this is c
c two here okay and then i just need to
go for i in range by the way we no don't
need to
in the previous one we don't need to go
through the end we need to go through
tier n minus one right because they are
non-empty so in range here
length
s right we need to we can minus one
right because there's no
there's no point of checking
yeah there's no point of checking
here the entire path because if both
is non-empty okay so we can minus one
here all right yeah
now look c1 and c2 okay
now c1 needs to include a letter f here
so c one
s i
y and p something okay plus equal one
okay now c two needs to be moving yeah
yeah
c2
s i
minus equal one okay yeah
but when we minus equal one it might it
might reduce to zl all right when it
reduces zero what we need to get rid of
it right look if if even counter is a
equals one right if after this if c2 is
this one a
a c2 a minus one will be equal to zero
right yeah
so we need to remove this beta again so
we just say c2
as i
equal equal 0 then
we did it okay did it fts stand for did
it did it c2
s
i yeah
and then we check if c1
equal or equal to c2
yeah uh actually is we need to compare
the
the keys
this is the same yeah we need to compare
the keys only yeah c1 dot keys
yeah we won't compare to the keys the
value doesn't matter equals
i will put it in a set yeah set
set doesn't compare with the order if
the set c one and equals set c2 keys
if it's equal then we do the answer plus
equal one right and then we can answer
make sense yeah answer equals zero
okay
yeah
[Music]
and
here look
i i is the partition of
index
and that partition the index moving from
left to right and every time i need to
include
s i character to c1 counter
but i have to remove it from c2 right
yeah yeah
and actually remove the c2 completely
look if it is two that's right i remove
one but when this reaches zero i need to
get rid of this
right because if not
set c one dot keys a will be still
included here right we don't want to
include a key with the appearance yellow
because when it reaches zero it means
that there is no
such character in the set uh in a in a
in the current window okay so there are
two windows left and right c1 c2
and if the set if it's equal then we and
the plus equal one
equals one okay what's the time complex
this is n
yeah square
these
almost yeah because we're converting the
set okay
converting to a set so this is
in the worst case in the worst case c
one the keys
could be n
and converting to the set
and then c to the keys okay so maybe we
can just ch check the values first we
can check if dance you want the keys
equals then stop c to the keys
right
yeah if they're the number
if the set if
the characters number is not equal then
there's no point to check the content of
it right yeah okay so this is
a lot faster than the previous one right
because look
these two operations
are one right
counter is basically like a hash table
when we're updating the values yeah and
all deleted values from the hash table
is
one constant it's constant time
all right
previous one we are we are creating we
need to count it right let's take our
own time so this is faster here make
sense
okay any questions so far
okay and no questions okay so what have
you learned today what's this approach
about stream shots uh can you tell me
every night what
is when
like you uh
split her
so how come how do we i mean what's the
approach here what's the approach here
today
can you explain to people yeah
[Music]
the number the number of distinct
characters in each string is the same
okay so it's here it's looking for the
number of distinct characters so it
doesn't compare the content okay okay so
the question okay so here
we are now comparing each one has to be
appear in the same so we can actually
change it to length we just compare with
the length okay that will be easier okay
okay
yeah the number of distinct characters
so it could be in each window here would
be a b here or b c d it doesn't matter
okay yeah
i see okay
okay so so look at here then if we
change here to length then this is
obviously o n right because checking the
length
is constant time okay
checking the lengths of constant okay so
what have you learned so far what's
what's the speed
we have to have same amount of number um
yeah and how are we doing this how can
we how do we use this we just like move
we slide in window yeah we move this
partition up and up day one
update each c1 and c2 okay yeah
we move one character to the right and
what should we do with the c1 what do we
do with the situation uh one increase it
gets one thing and one still
we're done okay that's it for today good
job bye