go hey
hello mr you need to line are you right
yeah
okay that's good loud and clear okay hi
keys i'm gonna erase this bitch so let's
see we we've given a streak one smiley
face we are giving a string with only a
and b we can find out if
a or a is that before
or b
or a b for b so okay we are given a
string only containing the string at a
and b okay let's given a few examples a
b b
true a b a fourth
a b b a first empty string true b b
two
a a two only containing the a's or b is
true okay
and then also a
b a b b false okay yeah okay
yeah
so any idea how we're doing this
uh have any idea how we're doing this do
you understand what's the problem now
yeah
so let's
what's this
okay so let's take a look at these three
cases the inverted cases okay
what's the common thing about those they
have b the first ones are gn wow we're
done okay pas so we can just check if
the string has the pa right yeah and if
beer with return sauce otherwise that
would be all very cases right
okay let's do it come on come on can you
go back see please
okay that's very good observation okay
that's a very good observation
observation
and what's the if it's not valid then
there must be a va right that's very
obvious we think reversely yes we think
in in the opposite way okay so if if
this this function is okay
i need to get a new pen
where's the new pen
can i have this please
[Music]
in s right okay
simple easy what's the time complexity
n strings yeah all right yeah yeah
um
[Music]
in this case it's on but but normally um
normally there are different ways of
implementing checking a substring string
content substring look if we are looking
for a string with n characters and
characters
and the pattern pattern yeah the pattern
the the string the substring we're going
to check is a pattern
is n characters yeah the naive way
the naive way first way is we're
checking each partition right look this
is a string like uh hello hello
eric okay
yeah this is a string right if these
this is n characters right
and we are looking for eric
ryan
what did just teddy say come on if
you're looking for eric so what would
how would you do it if this string s
contains eric how would you do it
yeah i'm just checking i'm just i'm just
thinking yeah if this string is parallel
we want to find out if this string
contains
like oh yeah starting with so we first
of all we're checking with hello h is
this the same with eric no
then let's go from next one yeah then e
okay it's the same if
k is insensitive and what's next r
doesn't match so i do rewind it and then
i try next one next one
and so okay
the same ah the same i the same c that's
it okay we match because we found it
this is the proof of sway
the time context if this n character
this is m character the time connection
will be o and
o n times m right
this is very slow or n times seven so in
this case if it's going from proof of
two because they're two here two
character and n string now b o n o times
n times two okay we drop a constant
there's a better our algorithm called
the kmp
which bears the table in o and time
and then time spent the time spending on
searching the
substring is om but it takes om time to
build the table yeah because every time
we look h is not equal to e there is no
point
when you scan stand there there's no
point to go to the e he knows that he
knows what he knows because the second
parameter the second character e is not
equal to r it already knows that you
know
it's not equal so then we can skip we
can advance to the next one
[Music]
yeah yeah that's a good point and i was
just saying that casing okay so if in
this case ta okay chicken a string has a
substring is all and time we
linear time
good point good one okay so
um
so let's go back to that problem with a
and b for me okay so if we
we can go through another way of
checking w which is what look if a b
a a b
if we group the same letters right so
like that a a b b b
or b b a a b b a a b b b okay so we
group the same letters come on
we group the same letters so remember we
have a function called ether
give to us dot group by
if we use this function remember
to go back
you don't need to stop unless you finish
if we use it to a screw ply
so that will tell me a
uh this general with the keys is the
same for each okay so look let's use
this group so what does it return it
returns a dictionary saying a
is to a this is the iterator okay to a a
list of iterator a
and b to b
and a to a a okay so group by and you
tell me this and b to
b okay and for this one you tell me
b to
b b b okay three b's group and a two
a a a
and for this one you tell me
a to
a a a i
and b two b b okay so
based on this based on the result a term
from two pi how can we check if it's all
a's before b
um um
if
you see
if a b is at higher up higher than the a
then
okay and how about the number of groups
if there are more than two what should
we do
if there are two groups uh if there are
one group
is it valid yeah
if it's one group that could be just a
or b right if it's two groups how many
possibilities
it could be a b or b a we're done and if
there are three groups do we need to
check
right because it can't if that's three
groups that must be b must be before a
right yeah okay that's a very good
observation so we can do it
that's still too good because in that
case that would be
a b right
it groups the continuum yeah
yeah yeah it doesn't make sense now
okay so that you tell me okay
so we can just do this
define check
string and then we we can okay if
they're empty let's say if it's empty
then we just return true right this is
the special case
and then
the group let's say air equals this uh
ether
ether2 okay let's say
we want to
we we just want to
get the group okay so let's let's do
this list
i right
this i um do it we need to literally
decide no no no
because we can just do this i for
i
j in
degree by s
by s
sorry i would be the the key
look if then
if length air equal equals
one
okay then we return what
if there is only one group we can
okay if length two are
then the group equal if bigger than
three bigger equal and three
two bigger than two then return
if they have more than two groups what
happened
then it's a false first yeah we talked
about that because it could it could be
a b
a
something like that or b a b yeah
in both cases let's be a here right
otherwise now we have only two groups so
if it is two groups what do we need to
check if it's too good we can
we need to check what l zero equals one
we just need to check lg or equal as
well
[Music]
because we only have two characters a
and b so lcr equals a and
f a one equals b yeah but we don't need
to
do that we don't need we just can we
just
can
uh
check one condition right because there
are only two characters if you check one
and the second one will be different
right so
you would say that's the group okay
that's the beauty of group by because it
automatically
make groups the consecutive consecutive
same letters into same one group the sec
the keys
will be less the the letter the group
yeah and then the values will be
how many
yeah will be the actual
group content
so what if we use this goodbye what does
it return
the key will be the group
the values will be iterated to
a
a a
b
b make sense
yeah
make sense
that's the group i okay
yeah and the trunk of this is still on
right because we need to go through the
eater to us
go in the hour and linear time right and
we're checking and this is the
traditional way
what's the quickest way
what's the first approach
[Music]
which one which method you prefer
obviously
it's faster well maybe not yeah it's
shorter okay i'm practically faster okay
okay for today
yeah that's it bye bye
[Music]