go
hello mr mr ryan you're right yeah
what's binary string a boundary the
binary tweet i added
okay
it's kind of graph right the tree fluffy
okay so i'm going to draw the binary
tree here and then can you tell me what
is the longest part okay so can you tell
me
that
what's the longest path
which ones which one is the look which
one is the loop
which one is the rule this is the final
three it's three
three which one is the root zero
yeah that's the loop
these are these with no kids yeah leaves
yeah so if you look it upside down right
upside down this is the good yeah girl
the tree is going downwards okay
at least i have parents these are
parents there and also the children of
the
final trip because each each note has at
most two kids right
let's go to the tree okay
a binary tree is a graph right it's a
graph
and specifically is directed at cyclic
graph why is it directed because
usually usually you can only visit the
children from the parents so
basically there's an error here right
yeah it's an area here
it's one it's one connective connected
okay it's connected so it means a single
component is connected yeah it's
connected it's not like this this is not
a tree
what's this forest a forest and it's a
graph because look it's separate it's
not connected it's three trees a cyclist
okay it doesn't have any cycle if i put
another
link here it's not a trick right it has
a former cycle okay
yeah so okay so today's task easy we
also find out the longest okay first of
all the longest
even
pass
longest even pass so
0 to
right or 0 to 4 is the longest if i
change this to like four and change this
to eight and the longest will be
zero to eight
so it could be coming from here or here
right okay let's say i come i put
another zero here
yeah so that would be six notes right so
so
yeah make sense so we have to step on
the even numbers yeah
doing this
any idea
any idea how we're doing it um
think about it it's uh we're doing it
[Applause]
in this case zero two four zero zero
four eight three eight zero
okay yeah that's good level by level
what's that first search
order i mean if it's uh let's say if
it's a
if it's were if it's in order in order
you know that you know that left
node right
okay in order so that what what's the
sequence for the inorder
yet
in order
okay so in order actually uh
it's it's the other ways is four
two okay so now let's let's let's maybe
do it pre-order let note left and right
okay pre-order
let's be right
[Music]
two
four eight
zero four three eight wait don't forget
no look we visited the northwest so we
go to the left tree and then we go to
the right tree look yeah yeah and for
the left tree also we go to the null
first and then left three by three so
it's a recursion yeah we can easily use
the recursion to do a
different search okay depending on which
order we want okay
okay so look
we we originally we want to find out the
longest even part right okay okay so how
about if i telling you that dfs this
function dude
yeah
this loop tells me the longest
the longest even pass containing the
root node
right okay so vfs is zero you tell me
the the longest load will be four
because zero to a zero right
okay dfs rules
if we represent the longest even past
containing
this node onwards
yeah
so how does that help us
how does that help us
how does that happen
you you can use that
yes
unless if it's all even
okay so so yeah
quite close okay quite close look so
what how does this help us is that
we can use we can write the diff
definite search function and then we can
compute the path
like longest path containing a node
of this node and it's even yeah if it's
even we return we accumulate a path
otherwise if the odd number will return
zero right and by dealing with the
recursion we can recall
the
okay we can record the left and right
right
yeah
okay so look
this bit yeah
all right this bit
at this bit
this bit the longest the longest even
number containing this node
yeah the even longer longest even past
number continuously is dfs
blue dot left right yeah
at least it
is
dfs
blue
right okay
okay
this is the number we just call it
okay so if this is even number right
let's say this is l equals that and this
is r equals
so
if this is the even number right
listen to me carefully if this is an
even number
right
what's the longest
what's the what's the even longest even
longest part even past containing this
node
is that
and
l and r that's right a plus r plus one
right
it will be the longest right what is
that so look
the past that there can be only two
situation right why is that passing this
note or it doesn't pass this note
right
make sense
[Music]
yeah look at the longest part of a tree
longest part of the tree
right it could be passing the note or it
could be not passing the root note okay
so if i want to pass this one so
it could be something like that or it
could be something like this or
something like that right yeah
okay so i'm saying if this note is even
right
so the
longest path
the rule okay
should be
passing the root note
can contain this one right so it could
be somewhere here connecting here or
here right am i right if this is odd
number right
i'm right
so i should not include this in the
longest path
right i should not include it in the
longest if it was one
yeah so because it's even it's all all
numbers so the longest part should not
pass this move right so the longest path
could be
these or least all right
the longest is that one
yes
okay so so
make sense so we we the dfs function
returning the okay so dfs function
returning the
longest
even pass the note longest event pass
containing this no the neutral okay yeah
okay
so let's quickly write this okay
and then that's it for today
and you need to tell me they think about
how we're getting this answer okay think
about
let's say longest
long is even okay we are looking for
even
longest
and then loot okay
okay so if not lose obviously return
zero
yeah special case and now we want to
find the longest let's say longest uh
let's say answer okay this is the
elephant is zero
and then we need to define the test
research function right the loot
is not loose again
look if not root return zero right
because the
look this function with uh okay so you
would return the longest
longest even
passing rules okay remember this is
passing load
yeah
now i need to do the air are you i need
to definitely search the router left
okay
so this air is the
longest pass
long is even past on the left tree right
root or left and then r equals one can
you tell me
uh
right yeah easy okay now i have the left
and right okay look air and white look
here
eric i'm not i'm writing a tree here
okay
so this is the loot okay this is the
root
this is the root okay
okay
air loot left is this bit right this bit
this bit
is air
yeah
this bin
is r
yeah
okay so now if this root look
if
do the value
n one equals zero what does this mean
remember the binary yeah zero one one
zero what's next one one what's next
and what's next
[Music]
okay you got it yeah look if it's one
it's odd number if it's zero it's even
number binary yeah yeah
okay now if it's if it said if this note
is even number
if this note is the even number so look
the answer
will be equals the maximum of answer
this is the answer what what
what
what what's the look if this is even
number what's the longest part
one right
yeah
[Music]
if if root of value is with even number
and then that and we should return what
we should return what
we should return
okay so this function return returns the
longest even past passing the loop right
okay
okay so now i want to return now if this
is even number i want to return now so
what should i return which part is
bigger
yeah i need to compare which is this
part is bigger right
and then i need to plus one right
all right
yeah so return one plus maximum
of air and right okay
yeah if it's all number y should written
one
if this odd number
what's the longest path looking is even
yeah
okay so then look we can do this
definite search rules and then what
should we return what should we return
answer okay look there are two things
two things in this recursion function
can you tell me what are the two things
this function does the recursion
function
what are the two things
what's
what's what's first thing the second
thing what's the first you know what's
this function doing here
it is
uh
what is it
what's this function returning that's
the first thing and what's what what are
we setting this answer here that's the
second thing okay can you explain these
two things
the function returns what value what's
the value
i know what's returning what's this
function
what does it mean can you explain in
your own words okay
what does it mean
it means
it's the longest okay so if this here is
two
okay then you tell me okay
[Music]
okay so i'm cfs blue here so what what
does it return what's this function
return
it returns
which number the power
why is it five there are only four steps
why is where the longest pass
which five
2 4 8 10. okay so how many knots four
four four notes okay that's four okay so
this is the longest part containing the
even number okay because look here here
if i put another one ten it's this this
is even old number so it will stop here
right
okay so that's the first thing yeah if
it's
okay how about this one is one what's
this one's literally
i'm sorry
if this is
no that's the second thing i'm saying
that this function returning
longest events are passing
you see this passing here
you say you're passing okay so if i task
load here what's the what's it return
0 because this is all lambda okay here
if you come here right
okay make sense yeah
what's the second thing it does here
what's the second thing
what's the second thing about answer
what's the answer
the second thing if this is one the
second
the the longest path is
is the one you just said which is which
is what eric
the answer let me say answer zero
what's that
what's the longest path containing the
root
well no no
everything here
3 here yeah 4 8 10. it's here yeah it's
a little bit confusing yeah
so that's two things this function does
first thing
is this function return directly the
number of longest
number of longest even nodes
passing the loop okay but we're using
this function
to set the
longest even
path
all without passing the load so far why
is that we said it here this is the
answer you know
every time
we find an even number we set it
right
yeah
makes sense what's the time complexity
if you
think about it what's the time of next
day for the different search
what's the time the next thing is
endnote here what's the thumbnail
what's the space
yeah it's classical textbook right
okay that's it for today bye-bye