hello mr mr ryan are you right yeah okay
so yesterday we talked about the longest
even pass we want to find out the
longest path
that contains all the even notes right
the path is
between any two nodes right so for
example here the longest even path is
if this is four then it could be if this
is a the the longest path is six four
eight ten yeah
yeah because it's longer than this one
this is we know this is four notes and
yeah so we use the tesla search right
remember we use the default search this
default search function will return
the longest note uh even notes starting
with loot okay starting with for example
if therefore search load
here four you should tell me what's okay
that's a tricky one if a device search
load
for what
what's your in return
four
sorry now starting from here the longest
longest listen to me carefully longest
even pass starting with four
four
why is it four
because four
three yes four eight ten okay
yes okay so look this function returns
the longest part starting with even plus
button with four okay
so it's not loose let's review a little
bit return zero all right
the left is therefore search root
top left
the right is the first search
blue
dot right okay this is this bit is
simple right and then if the root of
value
and one if this is
it's all numbers
okay i'm just trying to to reveal if
this is an even number know what happens
then
if this is even number i need to recall
the maximum normal maximum which is the
longest path right right look if this is
the even number right if this is even
more let's say if this is even number
the longest path
yeah
must be
the left plus y plus one right it could
be passing through the loop right so
that the answer will be equals maximum
of answer
left plus r plus one right
and
i need to return
maximum
lag plus left and right plus one okay
this is a slightly different why is that
because i said this function returns the
longest load passing the current
right so it could be left or right it
can't be both right so i need to pick
the maximum if left is longer then i
pick the left if the right is longer i
pick it right okay
otherwise i should return what happened
here
if we say oh if if this is odd number
what happened i should return what is it
right well done okay then i can do this
definite search root
and then return
answer okay because we are
updating the answer yeah when the note
is even number and then we try to
try to do what left plus r plus one okay
so this must be the longest path right
the time time taxi is one for this one
because
sorry oh n
sorry i said
okay oh and because each note is visited
exactly once okay from surface search
right look next step is search right
we reach the left we reach the right
right so this kind of thing definition
we can use this to traverse the tree
right and each node is only visited once
so let's open
okay so today we talked about another
approach okay another approach
so first of all the binary tree
there's one problem with binary trees
that if we
when we go through the kits to the kids
we usually can't go back right because
the kids the parent has the two points
pointing to the left to the right but
the kids
doesn't have a pointer to point back to
the parent right
so if we travel you know we can convert
it to a graph right the tree is our
graph if we convert it to a
bi-directional graph right
so what graph is unique direction you
know the unit direction
or by direction two directions so it
means that i can travel i can visit
like from the parents the kids or i can
visit from kids to parents it's both two
direction okay two direction if first of
all i converted the graph listen
and then i can start with each
with every even note right and then for
each even now i can do a preference
search
yeah i can do a breakfast search or i
can do a different search there it
doesn't matter
so
i start doing the first research of this
note and that will tell me
the longest distance by following by
starting at that node
by only following the even nodes okay so
for example if i start a node
start do the preferences here it should
tell me
what what's the distance
what's the longest distance i can
traverse by starting here by following
the even nodes
three three yeah okay and how about here
you sure
i start from here the longest distance
what's that four yeah okay so for each
every even note i can do this and then
i can compare the value and store the
maximum okay i know so
we talked about how to converting the
binary tree into a graph we use the
adjacent list remember so let's do this
first of all converting your graph okay
so that's g equals default dictionary
default dictionary
list is the list yeah it's the list of
integer right it's a list of integer
or it's a list of node okay let's just
do a list okay and we find out what we
need
and now we can say okay so we need to do
a definite search
but we need to pass the loot and the
parent okay the parent
is not loot
yeah we're reaching the terminal notes
the empty we just return
okay now if their parent if the parent
is not numb then we can say what she
loot
stop a pen
parent right
a pen okay okay we are appending the
note so this is the number okay
a parent apparent and then g parent
a pen rule right
what does it mean yeah
so look
i'm here i'm at road right and this is
parent i coming from parent
all right i'm coming from parents so i
in the graph i added two uh two ways why
one is parent or visible
look and the load over this is the
parent okay so g c is the dictionary
keys are the at the vertex yeah in the
quad we talked about the vertex not the
not the node okay the vertex yeah vertex
and edge remember that g equals v
e collection of vertex and h
so i have a vertex parent i have a
vertex root this is the final trigger
and then i need to add edge from parents
to the root and also need to add edge
from root to parent that's what it does
i don't know i can do this definitely
okay
i need to travel to the lab what's the
parent of doodle left
okay
what's the parent of neutral right
what's the parent of little right
right what's this yeah that's a tricky
one yeah
okay now at this point then we can have
this g dictionary okay
and then i need to travel all it knows
your vertex then i can say this okay
answer this is the answer we have we
need to return the longest
longest even path and then i can say
for
vertex
in g
if vertex okay if we take some value
and one equal equals zero if it's an
even number and then i need to do this
answer equals
maximum
answer
questions let's start with the v okay
that's what we're doing here
yeah we have to implement this yes and
we can answer okay this is this
this is it
so we start with every vertex even nodes
and we do a preference search starting
with the vertex yeah
okay so now the word pfs we need to do
this period pms okay
so with the pss
up
so let's quickly divide it up pfs okay
so
what's the time complexity if you look
at this if this is bfs surely it's one
right what's this what's the time
complexity if we
if we go through
this is o n and we're going to yeah
we're going through
because in the worst case every node in
the binary tree is even number and then
there are n nodes i need to iterate this
and time and for each and for each time
i need to do this question search
right this could could take another end
time right
yeah consider these
extreme cases all nodes
are even numbered
then i need to go through this even
n times sometimes
yeah for each one i do the preferences
needs to do this end time yeah oh and
times n okay roughly
one square okay
a little bit slower than yesterday right
yeah so but this is a totally different
idea yeah
how is it different
we need to convert it to
graph and we treat it as a graph problem
okay
yeah
so let's do this breakfast search
do you still remember the processor how
do we do this breakfast search
note okay let's do this note what kind
of data structure can we use to to
implement a perfect search
okay
okay if not note
let's let's call it root
root
let's return zero right
special case and q equals dq
for each one i have a loop node current
node and the number of
the number of
distance yeah the number of distances at
the beginning is one okay and obviously
look if if not note
or
all the due top value
and one is is uh is an odd number than
return zero yeah obviously we can't
start if we start breakfast search on uh
odd number then we do ten zero right
yeah makes sense
yeah
now we start this and one or
in the worst case
it doesn't have any
even numbers to even notes to work right
it would be you'll be surrounded by odd
number then it will return one right
okay then i have answer equals zero then
y
q
and i need to do this what i i need to
do okay current
current and the distance equals q the
problem right
remember we use the
uh dq dq
what's dq mean
double queue yeah we we append from the
right hand side we talk from the left
hand side let's assume first thing first
off right
look and then i need to go through the
kids yeah
for the kids next end in
g g here we are using the graph here
look we're using the graph g
g current
right and then we need to
if it's a graph right if it's a graph
two and four i need to append the four
but when i up when i pop from the four i
need do i need to append two again
no right because it's i already visited
so i need a quest table a notebook to
remember the notes we have visited right
so i have i need to put here a sim
equal set right set is a hash table
and
yeah the key g n is the k is the next
note right this is current here and then
n will be its kit here
it's key yeah
the vertex connected to it and
i need to do what if
if n not in sin
right
also
also n
end of value and one is zero it's an
even number right because if it's what
number we don't care right if it's all
number we don't care we don't progress
then we do what now we can
sing
dot add
at n right and then q dot append
and
d plus one right we have one more note
the distance yeah
yeah
d one of the person okay so c here needs
to add the c scene.add root
yeah because we have seen the root right
and then return
okay now i have i i need to put this
answer here answer equals max
answer dui we want to get the maximum
this d we want to get the maximum of d d
is the number of nodes in the
longest path right return answer
okay
yeah
any questions so far i mean this is a
little bit little bit
i mean breakfast surgery is
usually
what it is it's usually a little bit
more complicated than deficiency right
because therefore search we can use the
recursion to do it right and it's more
intuitive yeah you visit the left tree
you reach the right tree you don't need
to worry about how to
maintain the stack right the computer
maintenance definitely but for the first
massage
the
and a pen right and we need to also
remember to tell it
we don't want to revisit it again but
for the default surgery we don't have
this problem why is that
we visit the kit
why do okay one question why don't we
need to have a
hash table seen
to
check if the note has visited come on
that's a good question right
look here we use the hash table
sorry
what
like if you
if you um move to another note you might
go back to say this is for the club but
for the tree to do we have this problem
that's right because three the parent
you go to the left kid you go to the
right kid you don't go back right
there's no way to go back it's one
direction but for the one that's two
direction that's why we need to use a
hash table notebook
we have a visited that no
we do we put it in the notebook
next time we next time we need to check
okay
if not has been visited then we don't
visit it okay
yeah
okay so last question what do you learn
so far
what have you learned so far
so can you tell me what's the problem
and how do we solve it
for today even
and how do we solve this yesterday we
solved it using the recursion data
search right today we started using the
breakfast search yeah okay
q our breakfast as you implement you use
the cube but how do we
how do we i mean what's what are the
three steps four what are the three
steps turn it into a graph okay first
thing planning the question so this is a
part problem and then make a set and see
so and then i started to do breakfast on
which notes
it's a graphic problem that's a graph
and then on which notes i need to do
this breakfast search even even notes
and the prospect search returns the
longest
path yeah longest distance of the even
nodes right
and then i can compare here answer
equals maximum answer preferences okay
so here
pressure search this this could be
replaced with staff search right yeah
yeah look at me
this could be replaced with
staffordshire but breakfast sets
is
it's easier right it's easier
it's more i mean
it's straightforward it's more
straightforward okay
okay that's it for today good job
bye
bye bye
ryan are you all right
hello hello ryan are you there
okay say bye to people bye
bye