yeah listen to me yeah so keep in the
pineapple yeah one
it doesn't matter what values we are
putting in all right that system
we don't need to put the values here the
binary is three
what's the longest part remember we
talked about the longest even process
long
longest
even
five okay so let's get rid of this even
today so we want to find out the longest
path six six six six six
okay let's say nothing two one two
four
four five that's the way
okay
so okay
i like it
yeah so what's up two one three four
five six two one three four five yeah
that's the longest yes okay so yes we
talk about the longest even pass yeah
last time yeah
and then we can we use the same
algorithm to solve this problem yeah
obviously if if we don't check the even
if it's even then you still work right
so we can use that research right yeah
so you still remember what what
difference search i mean
do we use i mean what kind of data
search i mean how can we implement the
different search
okay so let's review this
yeah let's level by level and another
way of doing this step for search is one
two six
three four five nine okay
and then we cushion we use the stacks
okay four five nine okay
okay so let's let's say
if we define these three differences
dfs search rules so what is what's your
in return can you tell me what you in
return remember
yeah
can you find that pen
i'm running out of time
what's that what's that what's this
okay so what's the return what's the
definition returning i mean
okay okay ryan mary
what's the deficit lose what would you
attend
what if i said this different search
will return the longest path okay
longest path
starting from this one one three four
five so how many notes are there four
okay yeah that's good
and okay so it returns that bit
right
so how about if i tell you that if i
tell you that okay so this bit this bit
here if this bit here is stefan search
blue
dot left
and let's say put it as air and this bit
is
that first search
bluetooth white
and let's put it as r
okay
yeah
this is l l b l will be two right bit
will be three right so l will be two
here
i'll be three okay
so what's the longest path
what's the longest pass
so what's what's the longest path that
passing through the
root one here
longest part passing passing to the root
one
what's the number start
six yeah what how do we get a six
how do we get a six oh we just how do we
get sick this bit is two
plus one
plus this bit three okay make sense yeah
yeah okay so then we can write this yeah
look that percentage root is the longest
that starting with this note okay right
starting with now so here you'll be
four right and attack this this bit is
stefan search new done right this is big
it's definitely search to the left right
so the common part like the longest the
path that's passing through the root
will be one yeah we have one note
and the last bit
the right bit right
yeah so this function remember this
function does two things
first thing it replaces the longest path
starting with this load right so you
and the second thing is that it needs to
compute the longest part yeah you
compare them you stole the maximum
number of notes that passing through
that root okay
so that's two things
uh i know we can just write it okay uh
let me just write it here
therefore search
therefore search that loot okay
if not
return what
and what's next
right equals one
y
and then in order to access the answer i
need to put it as a language
answer i mean okay because this is
inside a function i want to
i want to say okay this function this
answer here is the answer here so i put
a long local form
and then i need to do this answer equals
maximum of answer
can you complete this
so what's the what's here look
what's the
path what's the number what's the number
of notes that passing through the root
here
and one okay left right and one okay but
now this function needs to return what
we turn the longest so look here
here like this is left bit here this is
vibrate at least
this function should return the number
that makes the longest path that's
starting with this now so it could be
picking the maximum above both yeah so
what's your return
one plus one
the biggest one so the maximum of one
left and right right and that's all
right okay yeah
so for this one the time complexity is
our what if and not
don't don't do that
if that knows what's the term complexity
the number of nodes that visited because
we visited each node exactly once okay
yeah so look
quite similar yeah
last time last time what we did
last time what did we do before we last
last time we need to check
if here we need to check if the load is
even then we need to do this otherwise
if it's all number then return
zero because it's all number right but
now we just get rid of if
here right so everything will be
still be the same the death research you
see yeah the longest path okay so let's
not be it today so today actually this
is not new we actually this is something
that we have we know how to solve before
right so we just get rid of that
condition even pass right and then this
way we can check
we can compute the longest path between
any two nodes
yeah okay that's a bit that's it today
bye