[Music]
yeah yeah what do you do
okay so what's class you still remember
object template yeah yeah like a person
and we remember we talked about the
person and then
eric equals person yeah
what's prefix can you tell me what's
prefix what does it mean
what does it mean in
inspiring yeah so can you give me an
example what's pre-prefixed
prefix yeah yeah yeah exactly suffix
yeah what about suffix so prefix is that
before yeah before yeah like a tree
please in english what pre
means pre-calculate pre
[Music]
we do something i don't know yeah just
before yeah
it means that before right right okay so
prefix sum
is a very use common use technique to
speed up the
[Music]
speed of the calculation of in some of
the intervals for example if i give you
a list of the
numbers like one three five
uh this is a given numb so yeah
numbs please yeah so if i give you a
throne and two
like if i give you a quid a list of
quidditch like three
two four inclusive okay this means
inclusive uh four to five
so i want you to find out the
and all kinds of these clearly i want
you to find out that the
the sum the sum of the
this is the index 3 4 would be like 0 1
2 3 3 4 will be 3 will be pointing to
this 4 will probably need to leave
so 3 3 4 will be 7 plus a equals 15
right
4 5 is 17 right so you could be like
zero five zero one two three four five
so it would be
nine nine ten no 1 2 4 9
what 16 24 33
so you get it yeah i is zero
five zero means to start from the
0 is here 5 is here so what's the
how the sum of these will be 1 plus 3
plus 5
so how do you do do that i mean without
the prefix sum you just
you you just can do the indicator number
remember
[Music]
so then we can do this for i
in range let's say you see
from 2
plus 1 ok from 2 then we do what
sum equals plus lumps
i right yeah yes
yes yes do you understand now we are
calculating the sum i put it in the
variable as from the range from
index to two plus one because this is
two right
and this is the second parameter minus
one okay so
we accumulate the value sum in
in this variable s so what's the time
complexity
oh n
[Music]
i won i won no you all right oh when why
you say oh and you keep saying this is
over
because look you need to when you one
one tip
one tip is that when you see a four it's
usually oh
and right because you when you see these
four yeah
it's usually over because you need to
iterate
those numbers so right
time you say four ninety percent
ninety-nine percent maybe
i won't need the number four look
when you see this it's it's o n why
because we need to iterate the numbers
from
at this range right yeah so this range
are changed so it means that it's o
n o n
range yeah and this is variable this is
the input
if i tell you if it is 4 i
in range 100
i in branch 100 s plus equals i what's
the time capacity
a thousand maybe what's the time
confidence complexity of this one
[Music]
you guess uh wait
then that word
for so this is always what's this
a one a one exactly why is that because
this
is constant it never changed
it means if i have one you can say well
one thousand but we drop the constant
remember we talked about this in in the
equivalent complexity yeah
this is o and because n is actually
equals
two minus from right these two are
changing
this is the input so we can drop it why
the only one
oh one because this is constant it means
that no matter how big is the input
we're still doing this
one thousand so if we go one thousand
is a one yeah it's a constant it's a one
if it's a minion it's also a one in
series you know
it's only just one it's over
with n and n is changing so let's open
got it
yes okay so now look this is all n right
this is o n right because we every time
we need to iterate the numbers
yes but how about if we are n queries
if we are n what's the total complexity
what does it mean
so if they are like an entire m queries
query and number terms like every time i
give you a throne and
like two index i give you a letter and
in terms of it
so the complexities o what
all together m times
n right because n is the time
we are going to iterate we you we are
going to calculate one query right
am right and they are in terms of it so
let's um
omm right yes and time
then yes does that make sense yeah
because there are m queries and each
it really takes n time right right
yes so can we do better because if this
number is not changing if this number is
still changing we can
get it right
stop it how do we change it
how do we implement it if i give you an
example if i
i know i i calculate this if i say
prefix prefix i
physics and suffix
can you listen to me i'm going to ask
you all the questions okay
prefix
means that i want to store the prefix
sum of these the prefix
zero equals one prefix one equals four
can you tell me what he did
with two equals uh nine
prefix three equals sixteen can you tell
me
what's this oh it's twenty-four
and then thirty-five square
root number no no
this is four why is this gonna have a
toilet
because oh yeah three five seven nine
i need a toilet yeah three five seven
nine 3
7 9. did you get it because look
the first number is the sum of the first
number yeah
the second number is the sum of the
first two number the third number is
summaries three first three numbers the
first
four will be the sum of the fourth
numbers uh
i didn't know you were talking about
that yeah yeah yeah okay
yeah so i if i calculate this this
how if i want to calculate this array
what's the time capacity
back thank you season
yeah what was the time complexity if i
want to
calculate a prefix sum array of the
computer prefix sum of this array
[Music]
november we have a four i in
one yes because we need to eat once
so why is this happening if the prefix i
equals the sum of the first i numbers
so if i i want you to know if i want to
do
calculate okay this is the interesting
part look
if if i tell you i know
if i want to know the sum of from five
to
eight okay which is five
to eight is what is 20 right yeah 20.
so this co so if i have this prefix
sound so what does it equal
prefix if i say prefix one two three
four
five if it's five okay let's do it five
okay equals one
one plus four three four
nine 16 24 24
okay and then prefix of the first two
numbers
prefix two is what
one plus three four
so do you see the how we can get 24
ladies
[Music]
how can we get 20 from 24.
yeah why can't we strike subtract prefix
five
i know the sum of these five numbers is
24 yeah
and i know the sum of the first two
numbers is four
yeah all right yeah why is from
there look i want to calculate the sum
of these three numbers
i know the first sum of these five
numbers and i also know the sum of these
two numbers
so what does it mean
yeah exactly so look i can just do this
minus yeah so what's the term complexity
of this
what's better than why are we doing this
um i can just substrate what's the
complexity
what's the complexity oh
and again why is there no getting one
just guessing
one or one yeah of course look i i just
calculated to the math
right because i know this number i know
this number i just do this
so do you see why we are doing this we
here we have we we
we we we use o n
to calculate this prefix sum right yeah
and then we have o
n to calculate it so it would have m
query
and the concave next c would be
just o m right right yeah
because the constant time to look up
these two values
right all right does it make sense so
we're improving this algorithm yeah
so you see somebody coding no not yet
so look uh
so look we have given the numbers yeah
so we don't need to actually write
many things okay one two
three four five let's say i know we need
to have a prefix sound prefix
prefix let's let's let's push it at zero
at the beginning okay
yeah i'll tell you why i need the g n at
the beginning
[Music]
yeah s equals zero and for i
in lump yeah look
look s common sum is s plus equals i
right uh equals i right yeah
so now we are calculating the sum along
the way so okay
this s will be 1 3 6
10 15 right and every time we go to s we
just push it to the
prefix uh just to push it to to the
prefix
so now after this what what's the
content of prefix
can you guess we've got a yellow and
then
one eye numbers i one
and then two no no one plus two
three three and then six
ten fifteen okay yeah
that's the point yeah don't go one
that's a three fifth yeah
[Music]
inclusive index okay and then i want to
calculate that what's
t 2 oh i wanted to calculate the lumps
from the
lambs from f to lambs
t okay so what's this equal then i can
just say return
yeah return what return
return prefix prefix
speed
[Music]
prefix let's try prefix f
y it doesn't make sense doesn't make
sense
okay look t t plus one okay
why is that look let's see uh
what was the number one two three four
five right
this is the original number yeah all
right
if i want to calculate from the index
one this is index one to
index two three index three
okay i want to calculate the index from
two plus three
from index two to into four what's the
answer
24 yeah 24
6 2 plus 3 plus 4 what
i said two and four two two x three two
nine nine yeah from ah
this interval is nine right yeah yeah so
how can we get this here
from t t zero one two
three t t is three yeah so i want to get
the first
value zero one two three four so it's
ten
when we are done wait wait wait ten
and then zero two strong will be
one right one so here
you see so we got the 10 minus 1 is 9.
you see
we get it look at it remember prefix
why why we got the f because we added
zero at the beginning so we don't need
we can just do it plus one minus f right
look
yeah we don't need to uh if this is the
same
prefix that's a one
look if if it's the one to one to
one if from uh from front and two is
also one index
so t t one plus one is two
right right so t is one
t uh no no t uh this is
at zero zero plus one is one here
minus zero so look it's one minus zero
is one
so you get it yes so why are we using
this can you tell me in
in one sentence why are we using a
prefix sound
and then we can end this class why
why yes
why are we doing this
to speed up the calculation right yeah
because
if we don't have this prefix sum we want
to calculate the range we need to
iterate these
numbers yes we need to integrate
for example we need to iterate two plus
three plus one that
that's time consuming if we have a
million times or maybe a thousand
million than
to do right yes i know but now
if i prefix some you just give me me a
two
two positions yeah because i can just
look it up in the prefix array
and i can just do a simple mess am i
right i know be a lot faster
right but this is only uh useful if you
you
if this original array is not changing
right it's not just because the numbers
are staying the same
all the time okay okay okay so good job
today
say bye-bye
bye bye
why nothing bye okay