go
hello
hello michelle mr rhino all right
so today we're given a square metric
square metric yeah you know the square
metric
and
square matrix
for example this is the square matrix
three times three
and we want to find out if each row each
column contains all the numbers from one
not quite quite similar yes you do but
but no no no 1 to n for example this 3
this is n equals 3 3 times 3 so this 1 2
1 2
2 3 1 then that's okay why is that
because there's one degree there's three
one two there's two three one there's
one pretty the t won't create yeah
exactly so each row contains all the
numbers from one to and one to three
each columns contains all the numbers
from one to six okay this is one however
if i give another example
one two three
one three two two
two one one is it nine because
the first one yeah this one yeah and
then this one
okay
yeah easy yesterday's task easy
what's what's the idea um
you have to find
one
like
no no no no not necessarily the dire
ones just the rows and columns
but that's a very good point yeah rows
and columns
rows columns
content
content one to n
okay
[Music]
so
any idea we should solve this quick
so i mean this this problem is easy we
just go through each row
to check
if each row contains all the numbers one
to n we go through each columns to check
if each column contains one to n right
yeah
so
look
we are checking the numbers so we we are
not checking the sequence right we're
not checking the order sequence doesn't
matter but what matter is what the
numbers so
if we want to compare two
two i mean two lists have a sum
like one three two
or one two three
yeah these are the variants of the
permutation yeah but they are using the
same numbers so what kind of data
structure can you use
you know
to compare
these are all equal because what because
they only they all contain the same
numbers from one to three right yeah so
what kind of data structure can we use
to compare
if we turning into d3
into something
you know something that that is false
it's first
yeah
i'm saying this a is a list b
is this i want to find out if all those
three
this contains the same number of i items
same numbers
right so they they should be equal
because they all contain one two three
but different order so we want to
convert it how do we check this
we want to we can convert it to some
kind of you know three letters here
and then we can compare if these is the
same
any idea
what kind of data social have you
no no what kind of
data structure i mean the first one is s
the second letter
exclusive
so s what
set yeah set i just did that yeah so
we're converting these to set
yeah
then we can compare if the numbers are
equal right yeah the set is a very
useful
data structure the set contains unique
unique okay because we know these are
one to end only right so they they
contain the unique
numbers then we can compare if they
contain the unique numbers
right yeah okay so the the other thing i
want to look it's easy to go through the
nose right we just say for r in magic
and then you give us
if this is m okay then we say for row
in m
so this row will contain one two three
three one two
two three one yeah that's easy to
compare the row how about the columns
columns is not easy right
but in python we have this
we can use this chip
what's chip remember
what's chip
tip what's tip is
a zip yeah you put two things together
remember look this is one two three
a equals that b equals one four five six
and what's chip a b
one three four five six
what's the ib come on one two three four
five six
look
this is a this is b one two three four
five six
look at this look this is
one four two five six yeah yeah yeah but
so look this is the shipping yeah you
just imagine there's a
that's your clothes chipping so one vote
so you want we have you will have a
couple one four
two five
three six yeah okay yeah we take one
element from each
yeah we check it yeah look dip it tip it
tip it
okay
okay so now this is another way
of doing that is that we can use the zip
function but a little bit special here
so instead of chip we put a star here
chip m
okay here
so
so look
here
1 2 3 3 5 one two two three four so when
i check please
and i convert it to a list because this
thing returns an iterator if i
convert it to a list then it will give
me what
it will give me and then you can tell me
what what it is okay you'll tell me what
it is you'll tell me is one
three two
three
uh
two one three
three two one
okay
yeah
so what what it is what it is
from here to here water
come on
this is magic and if we can start list
what do we get here
we have learned this before right look
one two three what happened from what
happened from this m to the transition
to this it's just
yeah i was like single we call it
we have done this before remember we
call it trend
expansion transpose and we don't need
transfers
this one transpose metric
okay so
so it's like so
to be more precisely what why why needs
to give the transfer so for example is a
equals like that okay so that's one two
okay
three four
and then five six
okay so let's let what was this what's
the
so it's a metric of one two three four
five six okay so this is the three times
two
matrix
so if we transpose it
if we do this this
tip
star
a so what is it what do we have
so you will have what it will take one
from each one one three five
so you'll be one three five
and then two four six okay
two four six
so look these these elements each
element is a tupper but it's an array of
tupper so basically this is kind of like
one three five
two four six
okay so look one two three four five six
if we transpose this look one two three
four five six is transpose this will
become one three five two four six how
do we get it look one two three four
five six we take
one element from each okay so look one i
take one for the first one
yeah
three for the second one five from the
third one so it's one three five yeah
second two four six okay let's call it
transfer
so if we do this what happened now we
can transport it and then look if we go
through the rows again and these will be
the columns of the original
metric right so we can check if this is
that one to end all right
yeah
makes sense
okay so then we can do this look
okay let's let's write it okay okay
[Music]
define let's say check
and i for this is a metric and first of
all i want to get the length the number
of rows
and i can say and then i can i i need to
construct a set of one to end okay so
let's let's
two and let's say v equals i want to
convert it to a set
and then i will have a range start from
one
to n right
okay so this is the
set set of the one two three right and
then i just need to compare four r in
m
if okay if r not equal
okay so look i is a release i need to
convert it to
a set ah
not equal v then we determine false
alright we are checking the rows right
we can
and then i need to do this for r in
chip
chip star and transpose it when you
transpose it the rows will become these
rows will become original
will be the original
the columns right so and i can say if
set
r not equal b
return
4 right
yeah
this is checking the rows this is
checking the columns
and if we all finish the check if at
this point will return what
what's the time complexity
what's the sample recipe
this is
there are n squared numbers here we need
to compare
yeah so what's that
let's say comparing the set oh n squared
yeah let's say we're comparing the set
is is constant time okay
is it constant time yeah uh
no it's not constant time but it's all n
time look this is n this is n
yeah and this is and this is n so okay
so transpose it we do it one time
three one times thing so it's actually
o n square right transpose will be
another one squared plus n squared so
it's it's out n square times two
is always squared okay
okay so this is one way of doing another
way okay which you might
might not um
find it simple to implement but uh let
me just
just say explain what um
what kind of
aggregate can we use to
to compare the equality right
so
what's this x and y remember
still remember exclusive or
yeah
n or exclusive or remember
remember the tables
n uh let
let's uh write this table okay
one zero one zero
if this is all
one on one
is one one or zero is one zero or one is
one zero zero is zero yeah one of them
is two is true
if this is n
two
one and one is two all others are false
right
yeah so this will become
yeah all right
eric and ryan
needs to do work
so that's two things one one error to it
ryan didn't do it then that's false okay
yeah and now if how about you say eric
to eric all right so one of them
is true that is true right how about
exclusive or remember
one one is zero
zero zero is zero one zero is one zero
one is one okay so can you tell me what
what's exclusive
um if this is if they're both they both
are the same and then it's false and if
otherwise it's true yeah okay let's see
exclusive oh yeah exactly so it has to
be both has to be different to be the
same attribute to be one okay
okay so look
we we are checking we need we want to
check if
each row is one contains the number one
to n right
and how about if i i know you know
because one to n i can exclusive one
exclusive two exclusive three here
exclusive n right yeah if i say this is
x
right
and then if i exclusive all the numbers
again if i miss x
okay so can you tell me if i use this x
to exclusive one two three what happened
if i look i is s exclusive 1 exclusive 2
exclusive 3.
it chooses here n so what's this value
what's this value
come on x is one exclusive or exclusive
three exclusive to n and then i used to
add these x values to exclusive one
again
exclusive two exclusive three exclusive
four until exclusive n
so what's this value
what's the value from
so what does it mean x equals this then
it means that x1 exclusive one two and
then exclusive one again
yeah
so one exclusive one equals one
one
two exclusive two
if the same what
excuse me three
okay so x exclusive this whole thing
what's the value right zero yeah you see
because x is one exclusive or two to n
and then i exclusive one again to two to
n again so basically i exclusive the
same number twice right so that's the
important property if a number is
exclusive excel
it will be zero it's like an eraser yeah
eraser the same number
it chooses e7 and it makes it gone okay
yeah so i can calculate this value x
obviously and then i use this value
to do what to exclusive
yeah exclusive all the numbers in a row
and line must be 0 and i need to
exclusive all the numbers in the columns
and that must be zero right
yeah
any questions so far
i mean do you understand this approach
every friend
so what why this will work
right
look
one is good x exclusive one exclusive
two x goes to three
that should be zero exactly if we if
this is not zero it does not this row
does not contain the numbers from one to
three okay
yeah
okay so let me write it okay it could be
quicker
okay let's say define check
metric
and then i can say x equals zero and i
can say for
i
in range
i start from one to
uh okay so let's say
here will be
n equals length and okay
m plus one
x exclusive okay so this this uh this
symbol yeah you see
uh up error
it's on the number six okay number six
key
okay you press the shift six it'll give
you a list that's exclusive
equals i okay now we have x
and then i i just need to do what for r
in range
range
n
this is the row index
for c in
range and this is the column index right
uh but for each one i have to do this uh
let's say r equals x
cc equals x and then i just need to
exclusive these okay so then i are
exclusive equals
metric
ah c
and then cc exclusive metric cr okay
this is the
okay so look i inclusive metric rc and
then metric ci is this one right it's
the it's
it's mapped it's a map around the
diagonal okay here this is metric rc
this one matrix er
this is metric okay so let's look
how can we access this number three
metric
zero two and what's this
what's this
where's this place
no no no this is zero too and what's
this
come on
why is this three two two here so look
rc
if this is magic rc
right
come on come on
listen to me
let's say rc is here if it's map or this
is diagonal and this this place is
metric cr okay
that's rc i know i know it makes sense
because look
where's these two locations
mrcm mcr
yeah symmetry along the time okay that's
what i'm saying yeah ah
i want to exclusive all the numbers in
the rows by rc i want to exclusive all
the numbers in the column by cr
okay and then here i i say if
ah r or c c
if one column is
not zero then we return fourth right
and then otherwise he'll return true
r or c c means that r bigger than one or
c bigger than one oh we can do this
max
r c c
if the maximum of these two numbers is
bigger than zero what does it mean it
means the one on them is bigger than
zero right if one of them is bigger than
zero it means what it means that either
row
one row does not contain all the numbers
from one to n
or the column does not contain all the
numbers from one right yeah if it
contains from all the numbers from one
to one
the the exclusive result if it should be
zero why is that because we are
exclusive the same number twice
right
okay i'm going to give another
mathematic question okay 2 exclusive 3
equals 4 exclusive 3 exclusive 2
exclusive 4. what's the answer
yeah because look two twice four twice
three twice yeah if you're exclusive
something twice
yellow
like razor yeah three i'm this eraser is
three
i'm exclusive this place
come
yeah
okay make sense here is eric everybody
is here
eric
excuse me eric
okay what's the time to investigate here
what's the time recipe come on look at
this we are going to the metric
yeah
so what's the time from let's say
sorry
and it's here so what's the time rustic
why is cubic where is the cubicle
because you
put it away three times
no only two squares i went square look
why is that one cubic look this is this
is
n right obviously r n yeah
o n
o n and that's it
so that's o n square o n squared plus o
n what's the outcome which one is bigger
one square plus or n we drop the smaller
path so we keep the
most time-consuming part okay oh it's
great it's the same thing as here just
different approach okay so tell me to
sum up what have you learned so far
today about the matrix yeah what are we
doing with the magic
we are doing the sudoku thingy
trying to see if they have the numbers
in
from or each row and each column you
have all the numbers from one to n right
okay so how how can we do this what have
you learned today every line
how can we do it
which approach you think is better you
can remember
i can't remember any of them sorry
they're all very very very long i can't
remember
that's fine but do you know
the principle i mean i mean so
for this approach we are completing 22
minutes yeah yeah we are comparing that
we're comparing the
set yeah
all right
at least one we're exclusively
because we already know that
each one one this can be
computed from exclusive one to to n
and then
yeah we have a
we have an eraser containing the result
of one exclusive two exclusive three
exclusive tier m and then i use this
eraser
to rub it
yeah that's how i know what yeah and
then
if nothing left
is yellow right let me say
it's the one to end right yeah
makes sense
eric right come on anybody
yeah
okay so what have i what what have you
learned today so matrix yeah what magic
transformed
with only one two and yeah one two and
yeah
chip star m to
turn it 90 degrees
okay transpose is it 90 degree
look at this one
it will be
when i transpose this it will become
what one three five
one three five two four six
is it turns is it turning
clockwise 90 degree
no no not really because if you turn it
not clockwise it will be five three one
so it's not quite a 90 degree so how do
you turn this to here
you
mirror it you yeah mirror it and turn it
degrees
yeah
will be two one four three six five and
then turning 90 degrees
that way
anticlockwise
yeah okay
next of all transfer so basically it's
easy you just take one element from each
one three five and then take second
element two four six yeah
okay i'll be today bye