hello
hello hello hello mr mr right now all
right
hello hi
so we have to talk about the longest
trees remember a few days ago yeah
longest path in a tree in a binary tree
what's fine energy
what's financing
is a binary tree right
in the tree
it's you know this this is the loot here
growing downward these are the leaves
yeah
okay
so we want to find out the longest path
longest path is the path between any two
nodes so what's the how many what's the
longest path here
how many notes are in the longest part
anybody
what's the longest part here
let's say i put another number here
what's the longest pass
four or five yeah right two
one three three
seven right okay
yeah i will
we talk about the definition different
search the function remember the
function returns two things bfs root
the first of all this function returns
the number of the nodes the longest path
starting with the node right
and the function also computes stores
the maximum the longest path
between any two nodes because we're
passing that loop right
right let's quickly review this yeah if
not load
returns yellow yeah return zero because
if it's empty the longest path is zero
okay so left equals dfs rule down left
right equals dfs through the right okay
and then okay so we have our answer here
at the beginning is zero answer equals
maximum
answer
take no
okay so look here we are
at this point we are doing node here
right
dfs loader left is this bit
it's listed the longest path is the
speed yeah passing the route to the left
tfs root of right is the longest task
passing the do the right which is three
okay so here is air here is r
okay
so now the longest path passing the root
here 1 is equals to what
is equal to 1
l
plus
1 plus r
so here
right but now this function this
function will return the longest path
starting from the loop right
so
it means that
either the left or the right we want to
pick the maximum right all right
so return
maximum when we talk about this yeah air
r plus one right okay
look
these
and this a little bit different right
this is the two things this function
does
because it double search okay
okay now look this
three
what are three primary three dag what's
the az by the way any anybody do you
remember what's the iconic
errors are from the parents to the kids
in the boundary
yeah
because the final trick the trees are
usually you've needed the
children from my parents right let's
call it directly a cycling what does it
mean a cyclic
does it
what what's this what's happening
anybody
[Music]
but hey
a cyclic
means the opposite means doesn't have a
sign
a cyclic okay
the graph graph is basically a
collection of the vertical vertex and uh
okay vertex and edges yeah that's logic
okay oh vertex okay
can i show your face please
my face is a pikachu
okay so now
uh um
we also talk about we also talk about
converting the trees into the graph
right we also talk about what's the
advantage of converting the trees into
the graph anybody
you know why why do we need to convert
the trees into a graph because it's much
easier
much easier in sense of what
in terms of work much easier in sense of
what
look
as a tree we can only visit the para
tree like children from the parents
right but if we're converting the trees
into the graph then we can visit the
parents from the kids right so because
we when we convert the trees into a
graph
we're converting into a unique direction
but bi-directional graph right so it
means two-dimensional bi-directional
graph okay
bi-directional graph
right
like we we can use the definition of
preferences usually we use the
difference
and then we can
we can store the graph
in an adjacent list from the from the
parents to the kids and from kids to
parents right okay so today look
listen now this is the key point today
okay all right all right
what's the first what's the longest the
first the note i can travel from the
loop here from the lower one
what's the longest
uh the right
which number is it
what's the longest path i can travel
from here
if i walk here if i use the quest for
search
yeah what's the longest path i can
travel to
which note what's the longest point from
uh if i start from eight okay
okay then i go here
okay now what's the longest point if i
start here i can go
you know
visualizing this as a graph what's the
longest point if i can travel from here
uh one
what one
this is a graph
yeah
this is a quad what if one why can i go
further
because
don't worry this is the graph if i'm
here i'm doing a placement search
i'm here
and what's the longest place i can be
what's the longest pass i can be
seven
so
why is it three
yeah longest path don't worry about the
errors because it's it's a
two directional now it's a graph now
i'm here what's the longest place i can
be four
four okay
yeah
okay so i'm here here
so this is the longest path in the graph
you make sense
okay so how about idea
uh
okay this was um
so what did i just do i start with any
note right i do a definition of
breakfast search to be to go to the
service point item b
right
and then i do another different perfect
search and find another note
and these two
are the longest
the paths between these two notes are
the longest okay so let's let's give
another example okay
let's give another example
okay
okay so here i
let's say
let's say we start from the this place
yeah what's the longest path you can be
uh
the really
these are yeah okay
okay i'm i'm here what's the longest
house i can be
the really top left okay so the longest
path will be the root between these two
okay
yeah
make sense
[Music]
make sense yeah
why this these approaches were working
why
look why this is working
can you find any other example that this
of course doesn't work
so the point of doing that is that doing
two different searches that we can we
allow we can allow these
you know going out of a
global a local local i mean
local optimum right
yeah
so let's find another maybe another
example okay maybe another example so
so i'm here i'm here um
i'm here so this is the local minimum
here
and now
i have something going wrong and wrong
and wrong
okay
yeah maybe uh let's say
but it should be a graph right
it should be no cycle because if it says
it's a cycle there's no longest part you
can if there's a cycle what's the
longest path
what's the longest part of laser
infinity infinity where down look if
it's because i can just go through wrong
and round and round right it's if it's a
circle right yeah
can i can i have your attention no no
too much noise please
okay so i'm trying actually i'm trying
to find out the example that uh you tell
us why this approach was if we pick any
note
and we do the longest the definition uh
longest path then it will work
so um
um maybe this is too obvious yeah
because they
any notes will pick this longest one
right so maybe this is not a very good
idea
so
uh
looks like a guy he has long hair yeah
yeah okay so look if we start from here
look
yeah look if we pick a no which is not
the terminal now right because usually
the terminal
right
if we put a note in the middle
[Music]
that is not the longest part
right if they look because we pick here
now what's the longest part you come to
this point here
yeah and now we can go through here
again the longest path will be
okay so here right
right
yeah so look
what what what's
why this is working okay um maybe i will
do this okay yeah one more note yeah so
look i start from here the longest path
the top one okay you will pick this one
okay i'm trying to pick another one here
look which is here okay
okay look the longest path
i start here you pick this one right why
because from here you go here they are
odd
so one two three four one two three four
okay i have another one
okay
okay so i said why we're done i'm here
right thank you very much all right and
then from here you go to here right yes
yeah look so so you see so the first
first test research first search
you allow the node to jump out out right
to find this uh find the furthest from
from here and then from these you can
see more area right we go from here to
and you will pick the path
okay
okay so can you tell me what's the
approach here why how can we find the
longest path it's because we always
um
that says grape not grass yeah graph
can you tell me
what did i just say here i don't know
yeah
um
the longest path is
when you pick a random note you always
like to choose
one
the that
it is yeah it's it's not easy to prove
right but but
by intuitive is
is that you pick a start you pick a
random note you do it you do whatever
search preferences to the longest part
yeah
yeah and then you start here you do
another one right okay so then you have
you have us to find the longest right
your helpers
you see you get the meaning yeah do you
understand yeah okay maybe i'll try
another one and then you tell me okay
i i just draw anyone and then you tell
me
what's the longest part i don't know
okay
i'm just guessing
okay what's the longest path here
can you try and continue
okay so six two three four five six
seven i guess seven okay so let's say if
i start from here right what's the
longest pass you can go
uh the top right one yeah okay here
and then here
i can go from
here right yeah so one two one two three
four five six seven well done okay
yeah so you found it yeah
okay so this is a simple strategy yeah
so look we can do this breakfast search
we can prefer search on only speed right
we can prefer searching with speed
[Music]
okay let's let's try this okay let's try
this
uh let me remove this bit okay because
we already seen this code before
and here
so first of all we want to convert the
graph into
convert the binary into the graph right
okay so let's say
g equals
t equals before dictionary okay we use
this uh
before dictionary this this is a note
right and now we can do this bfs
by passing the root and the parent
why do we need to pass the parent here
if not root return can you tell me i'm
trying to convert the tree into the
graph and i'm passing the parent
okay
return
okay and then we can say pls blue
dot left what's the parent of root of
that
root
and then i'm trying to dfs neutral right
[Music]
is parent right look the parent of loot
is para park okay so now we have part
then we want to construct an edge
between the parent and the root right so
if a parent could say
and then you call it perron
g parent he thought a pen
apparently right
and what's the next thing i want to add
another edge the reverse way so what's
that
[Music]
this one converting the trees to the
graph okay we use the g before
dictionary the key is the note the the
value is the list of the vertex notes
yeah it connects to make sense
okay
the tangent let's see for this one
what's the time complexity we'll try to
convert the trees to into graph what's
the time to react
[Music]
because there are any nodes and nodes
that will be mapped to
map to end vertex okay
what did you say he you said
um
we can use the
trade in the parity
okay
the the term conduction space convex is
om because we are visiting the endnotes
in the tree and we are converting the
nodes into a vertex in a biology we call
it a node in a graph we call it vertex
okay
vertex
edges we are having two edges
apparent to lose room to pattern okay
both way two direction
[Music]
oh now okay so now
we once we have this graph ready then we
need to do this breakfast search when we
have this preferred search all we can do
is search it doesn't matter and we start
with the loot right
right and we want these functions to
return the furthest point from dude
and the distance yeah it makes sense
look remember
remember this yeah we start with any log
this could be no
right
and then you tell me the furthest point
is here
yeah you return a top up the first value
is the first one the second value is the
distance to it so that would be one two
three four five six
make sense so this function will tell me
that
right
and how does that useful look if this
function return that and what should i
do look all right all right
come on this is this okay don't worry
about the implementation about this one
is loot right
this is good
and then this function will return uh to
a tupper
so i can do this look
the first response
the first response first is f u r t h
it first and the distance
equals p f s root right
and then you tell me it's this bit
okay the first third is the number will
go to this bit yeah
this is the forest you'll turn me first
and the distance will be one two three
four five six six
okay and then what's the next thing
what's the next thing i should do
what's the next thing i call this value
what's the next thing
[Music]
do another one
and then i need to do this one look bfs
furries
okay
look i do the flowers and then return to
value which is another one i don't care
understood and okay and then i'll be the
distance
and i just need to return the distance
okay
because after this you will tell me the
first one is here this is another one
let's say a okay here is a and
here is a okay the distance will be
one two three four five six seven eight
okay distance will be eight
do you get it
i'm calling it suppressor search twice
yeah
make sense
okay
what
okay now the breakfast search okay so uh
let's implement professor how can we
implement the personal search there's
one data structure we need to use which
is what q q i know yeah q equals pq
and then let's
at the beginning we need to put the root
and then the number of nodes is one here
that's a temper
and we want to find we because in the
graph we need to we need another data
structure to find out if we have visited
the nodes before and what can they what
kind of data structure is would that be
that the the thing that that asks to
check if we have visited a node before
what would that be
notebook a hash set okay equals headset
a set
and then let's say answer equals the
okay so then the file is let's say the
first first let's just go in for this
equals root and distance
equals one okay one node it's actually
not the distance is the number of nodes
okay and then now we can say y
q
and current
t equals q dot pop left
okay and then
we want to find out look if d bigger
than the distance
the number of notes then distance equals
d
and series we store the first point at
this point and which is current and then
let's say we want to find out the next
the the the nodes it connects to so for
n in g
g current
if and not in sin okay not easy
sing the ad
and and now we want to push these
appendix to the queue so q dot append
a pen one append the next note is n and
the distance the number of notes
increasing will be d plus one right
okay and then
later would we turn
attacker first
and then this time
okay you see
first massage
yeah
a perfect search
okay so what have you learned so far
today
about the longest path
longest search
we can use the
actually we can use the different search
here as well right
even we can use the depth research to a
breakfast search look at the beginning
we use the test research to convert the
trees into the graph we can use the
pressure search at the point as well
right
yeah
we are using preferences to travel to to
do this traversal to the longest path to
the longest point from the loop from the
current node right we can also use
staffordsearch to do it the key points
today is that how do you find the
longest path
yeah
we start with any node
we can go to the furthest point
from here and now we start at that point
to do another
you know traversal yeah we can do the
different social preferences from that
point
yeah remember this graph right the time
complexity is o n
but for search we do it twice
it's out to n we drop the constant which
is o n
right the space complexity obviously
always right we have we need
a hash say headset number to store the
number of nodes we have theme
yeah we're converting we we are
converting the trees into the graph we
also need the data structure to store
the graph right graph vertex and edges
okay so look the number of vertex is n
the number of edges is what the number
of edges
if a tree has three notes what's the
number of the edges the maximum edges
okay the one last question
if a tree
if a final tree
has n node how many edges are there
the the maximum
they are one two three four five six
seven
so it's it's a is a
magnitude of n right
something like that look because it
doesn't have cycle one two three four
five six one two three four five six
one two three four five six seven yeah
okay you're right okay look and if i 9
on the one
one two three four five six seven eight
eight edges how many notes are there
nine okay
yeah you know why is that
why is that i'm
a
tree a tree with n nose has n minus one
edges am i right
yes
why is that look consider this one three
notes
n minus one edges
all right look
why is it n minus one if i add in one
more what happened
look n note i'm adding if they are
unknown here
n minus one edges
if i add one edges what happened
you'll be having that will be sagar okay
so v e
is also n right we're storing the
nodes and the graph okay
okay
everyone
okay so can you tell me what have you
learned so far today the last question
please may not be
[Music]
what's the problem we're trying to solve
here
longest
past longest pass and how are we doing
it
longer
and then
okay we're done good job that's it for
today good job bye bye bye
bye
bye bye
come on come on
[Music]
that's it for today bye bye
bye