hello
hello mr mister right now you're right
yeah
so we're given an array so we want to
find out the increasing subsequence
increasing
increasing subsequence
what's the subsequence
triplet what's triplet
three numbers together three numbers
triple three numbers what's subsequent
is when you can any way you like
okay so let's say
one two three four five what's this how
many subsequent i mean let's say for the
triplet subsequently fifteen
how many of these
the subsequence of the what subsequence
by the way
you can pick from anyone
yeah subsequence is original this is the
original way
and we are allowed to remove
remove zero or more
elements from it and the remaining is
the subsequent for example if i remove
two and four the remaining is the one
three five
if i remove one two three the four five
is the substituent okay so as we can see
we remove the sum elements for the
original value
the remaining is a subsequence the order
right the relative order between
two elements do not change
the surplus on the other hand
is continuous right remember the sum
sundays
sublist
or some away sometimes
something is a separate right one single
any single animal is a service summary
and then otherwise we can pick two
index the left and right for example if
we pick the first index as
you know the first index here and the
second index here and then one to four
is a subsequent sub list
yeah two and five into service two and
four
okay so listen to me
is is service
uh also a subsequence
so can i say sundays
belongs to one of the subsequent is it
true
[Music]
it's at least true surplus is belongs to
subsequent
[Music]
yeah
yeah yeah of course this is true right
because subways you know
is also subsequent right okay
okay
what you doing
nothing stops okay so now please we want
to find out the three numbers
triplets right three numbers three
numbers and then they need to be
increasing okay so for example if this
is this true like we can find a triplet
which is increasing in this array
uh one two three yeah obviously or two
three five or one four five oh you know
and every sub uh every triplet
subsequent subsequent triplet
is increasing so that's true okay and
how about i write another one on the
other hand which is
five four three two one
can you find us increasing subsequent
trip in this array
uh
um no
no okay that's good because that none
you can't find anything that's already
stand for
okay
no
okay so what's your approach to solving
this problem
what's the approach of solving this
problem it's like he
what can we do about it
through
rufus and yes we can prove
what's the time complexity if we want to
prove for the triplets
come on keyboard okay
[Music]
if we want the blue force
uh
what's what's the what's the name of
four numbers together
called jupiter yeah what's the temporary
thing oh
four to the power yeah you got it so how
can we prove us this one look we can do
this for i
in range m n is the number of the
the number of numbers yeah and then for
j can i not hear the noise please okay
in range we start from i
i cross one to n
and then for k
in ranges okay and then j plus 1 to n
right
so in this case look i is smaller than j
j is smaller than k and we just have to
check if
nums
i smaller than num j
smaller than numbers k okay
and then we return to why
easy right yes otherwise
yeah
is it
you understand do you understand why
this is i plus one start from i plus one
y k start from j j plus one so why are
we look i from zero to n minus one but
why j is from i plus one y k is from j
plus one
it's because um
we want to make sure what we
want to make sure that it's a triplet
and three and like in order
we only make sure i index i the numbers
are one at each other right i j k and
then these is the increasing okay
obviously this is very slow right yeah
yeah
so look what's the
so can we improve i mean can we improve
yeah obviously yeah otherwise there is
no point of doing this lesson right so
we want to improve this
so
what's the if if we can find the first
two numbers
right if let's say i can find two
numbers first two numbers okay two
two numbers
the smallest two numbers we found so far
which are increasing
so look i have i've look if i know one
three
is the
you know it's the first two number and
then i can just check if four is bigger
than both of them then it's true right
all right yeah so look if i know let's
say an another
less obvious example like
one zero
four
two
uh maybe let's say one zero
one two
uh zero
four
zero five okay can you find the
increasing subsequence uh stripless here
uh
is
are you sure it's very obvious
it's very obvious
can you find some number which are
increasing
um
[Music]
come on keep keep looking it's there
thirty four
zero two four yes all two four five okay
or one four five okay yeah
okay so now minus one
minus one zero
four yeah yeah many so look so let's say
i have to look at one one
and then this number is smaller than
that so now becomes zero so i have
smaller zero
zero minus one no okay so minus one yeah
minus one two okay
right so now 0 bigger than both no
because 0 is bigger than 1
uh bigger than 2 so i replace 2 with 0
so it's minus 1 0 okay then 4
4 is bigger than both minus 1 and 0 so i
return true right yeah so the key point
is i i keep tracking of the first two
numbers in order so i keep tracking look
look
okay let's say
let's say a equals infinity at the
beginning b equals infinity okay so how
do we get it look
one is smaller than infinity so i change
this to one
yeah zero is this smaller than one
yeah yeah so i change this to zero
minus one is it smaller than zero yeah
okay i change this to minus one
two is smaller than minus one
nine is it two smaller than infinity
yeah i change this to two okay so i have
one minus one two here all right
zero is this smaller than
minus one nine is it smaller than two
yes yes so i replace these two with the
other so now the the subsequence first
two is minus one zero yeah
four is it smaller than minus one
nine smaller than zero
what does it mean if it's not smaller
than a it's not smaller than b what does
it mean
yeah we can put it on that it's bigger
than a and b
a b here right so if it's not smaller
than a it's not smaller than b so it's
somewhere here so we find that
increasing substance
yeah
so this is one zero four minus one zero
minus one zero four yeah you see get get
it get it look
is it smaller than a
no is it smaller than b
no so where is it it's here
so a is smaller than b all right a is
smaller than b and it's somewhere here
so we find the c here
we can chew so what's the time what's
the time complexity
exactly what's the space for west b
are we using under additional in your
space no
what's that
it's better than this one right
obviously
okay so let's quickly write this and
then we'll be
okay can you tell me okay define
increasing
triplet
subsequent you know sometimes we use the
triplet you know you know like the twins
yeah yeah the two look the same right
yeah the triplets three
three kids look the same that's also
called triplet yeah
got it
so n okay let's say numbers here
not n equals the length of the numbers
yeah
and at the beginning a equals b equals
the biggest number you can think of
which is what infinite
mass dot infinity
and now we can go through the number
actually we don't need to
like this we just can go through the
numbers for i in numbers
if
i is smaller or equal a
come on are you okay
if i
if i is smaller or equal than a what
should we do
um
a a
yeah and ask
a if
i is smaller than equal to b what do we
do
[Music]
yeah
and otherwise if we follow this then we
can find it and return
[Music]
wow
you're on fire today
yeah is it is it right
uh
is it right
any questions so far today
so what have you learned today
[Music]
zero minus one five can you find the
increasing sub
summaries here
three four five
two four five yeah zero minus one five
um
can you find those increasing sub
surveys
here come on there's one
um
three four five which it just said okay
three four five yes another one
um two four five two four five okay got
it yeah one four five one four five
okay that's it for today bye-bye
[Music]
okay bye i can touch