go hello hello mr mr right now you're
right
yeah okay so we're given a sentence yeah
and sentence s equals
e let's say i write the ascendant e r
i see
thank you very much ryan you see i'm
trying to mix up the captains
ridiculous ryan's
lions
good friend a good friend okay good
friend
good friends good friend
all good friends
ryan eric is ryan's good friend what's
wrong with that
okay
so we want to capitalize this words in a
sentence in such a way first of all
what's philosophy
last thing okay so don't worry about the
possibility okay
so lee is our letter there are only
letters what space in the sentences and
we want to capitalize the sentences in
in such way if the letter if a word is
less or
less than one two letters okay if it's
two letters or less then we make it all
up a lowercase which is is
otherwise for others we want to
capitalize
make the first letter uppercase and all
the rest lowercase so this will be e i i
c f
r y a n
g o o d
f r i e n d okay
clear
yeah look this is very special only the
very special okay if we if that word has
two letters or less then we make it all
lowercase uh
okay okay
okay so what's your all your thoughts
how can we do it
how can we do this
[Music]
okay so we want to find out the first
letter of the word to make it
[Music]
so the first um is the string how can we
get the words extra words from the
string
remember we get it
how do we get it
we
how do we get it how do we copy
so
the computer sees it what do you mean
computer scissors computer computer sees
it how how can computer seizing
find the noise but it's
okay come on come on seriously how can
we do it how can the computer do it
[Music]
what are the separators between the
words
split and join spirit and john that's
the word okay so this is as if we split
it
by the spaces okay five spaces what we
have got is one
is a list of a string list of strings
these are a list of string lists of
words like that
yeah
i s
i y a and s
okay
i'm going to write it
i'm not going to write it okay now
i split it look from here to here is
what
s dot split
yeah
and we have this then we go through each
word
and we check if the letter if the word
has the length
lower smaller
and equal than two then we make it all
lowercase yeah remember how do we make
it lowercase
if this is worth something we make it
lower okay stop lower
and how about how about this if you want
to make this
first letter uppercase the rest
lowercase so what's this if this is one
okay for w
in
okay so we can say if
length w
smaller or equal than
two then w to lower right
yeah
otherwise what otherwise what how can we
how can we make the first letter
uppercase then the rest will be
lowercase
so what was the first letter
w you'll be w0 right the first letter i
only need to the uppercase
after
and the rest will be lowercase i need to
plus
w 1 to the n dot location
right
yeah
does it make sense this one
the first letter is zero
are only in uppercase plus
from
the second character to the end and only
lowercase right yeah
okay so by python we have another
function okay look at me you don't need
to write this this bit of
crap okay yeah not
crap okay so you can write it look w
can you guess the word
t
i
p
t y there are two letters here
tighter tighter will do the exactly the
same so you make the first letter
uppercase and the red noise
yeah
but if we want to implement it ourselves
the first letter uppercase plus
okay can you explain to me what this is
number two
no if it's uh
that's the index start from the second
letter to the end right
yeah so so let the first letter w zero e
the uppercase then you become e
and then w one to the end will be
this bit
make it all lowercase so you'll be
ah ic and you press it together it will
be etheric
yeah
okay so let me write it okay let me go
ahead
instead having a hiccup
drink more water
defy
okay let's say capitalized
okay i don't know how to spell this word
s
s is a sentence and then let's split it
by the
by uh to a list of words okay so let's
say
array
let's say was okay what
equal s dot split
okay you can given a space but without
giving a space you can treat you can
treat much of a space at the time okay
so let's say split and then we can say
what
for
for i
w in
enumerate yeah we will
get the index enumerate what
right we're going to the index i will be
the index 0 1 2 3
and w will be the word there like e
e r i c
uh
is
etcetera okay etc
so now
look
if
length of the word is smaller than equal
than two then i want it to
be all lowercase so i will have this
what
i
equals w dot lower right
ass
was i
remember all we have to talk about left
we want to make the first capital
uh uppercase this the rest lowercase so
we use that function which is what
title p-i-t-a and that's it and then now
the word is the modified
it's the modified
list of words how can we make it a
string again
split
no no no how can we make a list of
string by
what's the opposite of i mean
we
yeah yeah join join come we return
empty space.join
join what okay
yeah can you have a look at this come on
can you have look at this
yeah
uh what's immunity come on what's in my
neck
[Music]
what does the immune give us the
what's
talk about this
what's enumerate come on
look at me come on what's fighting so
busy
what's your number here
one or zero yeah
so what does it give us if we without
the enumerate you give up it's like the
index um yeah indexing give me the index
right zero one two three and then the
value of w will be the value okay
yeah okay so
how about if we we can do it another way
look this is the easy way because we use
this title function
yeah this is already
there we can just use it we don't need
to reinvent the wheel right
all right
but if we we are not allowed to use
these
if we are not allowed to use this
function and we are not allowed to use
the split function okay how can we do it
right
very very tricky okay let's say look e
e-r-i-c is
a
good
toy all right
like that
so
orion yeah i have a ryan here okay yeah
so look
so
i can have two pointers i points to the
beginning of the first each word and
then j
j will be moving to the end
that j will be moving moving moving when
you move when it meets a
space
then i check the last word if it's more
than two
if it's more than two
then
no one
if it's more than two will happen
if it's more than two then i set the
first character to uppercase all the
rest will be lowercase and i move on and
i i move the i
to the to the beginning of next word and
i keep moving keep moving if it's
smaller than two
then i set everything to
lowercase right
and i move to two to three n until i
reaches the end makes sense
okay can you explain to me what did they
just say
what's i what's j what's iron want to
say i point to the beginning of each one
yeah and what's j j is character by the
girl movie
yeah we we use this in beard functions
doing functions to spread to break a
sentence into a list of words okay well
this is kind of like a quick easy way
but we were also talking about
how can we do it without the help of
these kind of functions yeah
[Music]
and let's quickly do it come on everyone
can we can we pay attention please
define
capitalize
s
okay so at the beginning we have two
pointers here i equals j equals zero
right
and then the end will be
the length of a
string yeah
so now
why
why let's say if j points to the
beginning let's say okay
i smaller
or equal than n okay
and then i need to do what then i need
to check if s i
equal equal n if it reaches the end or s
i
is empty space
then this is then look what happened
here what's what's this condition what's
this condition
what does it mean here
if if it look
uh actually no if i equals the n okay
sorry if i reaches the n or s i equals
empty space what does it mean
okay this is a space array
is a good boy okay now
i is here now what happened
oh i is here what happened what should
we do now
keep
so we have this word already right so j
you'll be here right j is here
so i need to make i need to check the
length of this one right so what's the
length of this what
if this is i this is what's the length
what's the length of the word
yeah that's it
now we need to check if if i minus j if
it's bigger
right n to noise increase if if it's
bigger than two bigger or even two what
should we do
it's bigger than two right because
if it's bigger than two then i need to
set
i mean
s j
equals f j
dot upper right
yeah
all right
s j equals f j dot upper and then
and then what then j equals i'm then j j
needs to be what j needs to be where
this needs to set to be upper so now
it's after now what's j j is going to be
one
j is going to jump to where which
position
i
is here is
better okay so what's eye letter this is
i this is either so what's either this
one we're done okay so now j needs to
jump to i plus one right okay now look
uh
okay so now
oh okay so now
s here as this bit
okay so if it hasn't reached the letters
yes so we need to set everything into
lowercase right so i will set everything
into lowercase
okay
so big why is that because everything
look i can just
convert everything to lowercase
and
i look listen to me i can turn
everything into lowercase first and then
only make the first letter capitalized
if the word has more than
two letters right
all right does it is it the same
so look
if it hasn't reached the what what
boundary
if we haven't reached the word boundary
i set everything to lower case right and
if it reaches the boundary
i need to check the word then if it's
what more than one or two words we we
set the first beginning of the word
characterized right
okay so first of all this s is to be a
it's a string which we can modify
because the string in python is
immutable what's your multiple you can't
change it you can do that there's one
way of thinking which is what let's say
okay let's let's make this uh
let's say a sentence okay sentence
and then this sentence is a string and i
want to make a s
equals this
this sentence
all right
this function it's like it's kind of
break but it's not look look a b c yeah
i want to break it into
a
b
c look at me
yeah abc this is a string i want to make
it a list and i i just need to read
list and you make me a list so look
sentence is a string immutable
i make it a list
s is a rate of words
a rate of characters right so a rate of
characters and then i can change it and
then after changing i just need to
return
uh i i just need to return what
i want to make it a sentence again i
have
now i have a list of characters now i
want to make it a string so how can we
do it how can convert convert it back
return
[Music]
a
b okay look
c how can we make it a abc how can we
make here abc to abc
how to make here from here
from here
join with empty string look
empty string dot join join one
join us
which one
what are we doing here john which one
which one is the
[Music]
what are we doing with all these kind of
things yeah john s yeah because we are
modifying
yeah right
yeah so do you think
do you see this so which one is better
if uh there's one more thing missing is
that what look when i i needs to be plus
equals one here yeah because you know
when it reaches i need to move to the
next character i need to move to the
next character okay
yeah
okay let's
e
left hand beginning of what
right hand right finger
every time movie is what i okay this is
i
ah look at me
e
r i c m z space okay check the length
more than four
more than two characters i change this
to uppercase and then i jump to the next
beginning
yeah i know i will just think okay now
here not j no no left right hand
check check
empty space means okay
we check the length of the word two
characters
then we don't change anything now
jump to the next one
next one blah blah blah next one
you see
how you left
yeah any questions so far
what have you learned today
about the
title yes what's titled doing okay let's
say a b b c d
if
good job bye-bye
bye-bye ryan are you alright
[Music]