hello mr erin mister right now you're
right
okay so we have talked about try before
yeah a long long time ago try
this is the prefix tree anybody remember
we have talked about
all right
so let's try previous three okay i
understand you might not remember let's
review this again
previous trick so if that
if we want to we have a few words right
we have a viewer like like eric
ryan
chelsea he
cairo
okay okay
so we have a few words right we have
capitals that's okay
we have these words right and i'm going
to insert it into
and we want to find out look if we want
to find out if a given a word like he
won't do search yeah you want to search
search this a word and then we want to
be able to return if this word is in the
in a word
we could use
we could we could just say what
in was right
but that's going to take over in time
right because we need to do this minimum
search
to check one by one right that's slow
alternatively we can
we can do what we can convert this word
and put it in a hash table notebook
right if we put it in a set
so if we put word equal if we put it in
a set set words right
so all this word in is put in the hash
set and then if we set
if what in
okay so let's say this is a in a what's
the time complexity we do that
if we convert these words into a set and
we set we check if the word in a what's
the time complexity
i'm sorry
it's not okay
i'm saying convert it to a hash set
we are without the converting we need to
check one by one that's our n if we put
it in a hash set hash table what's the
lookup time for the
what's the lookup term for
one o one yeah constant that's the
advantage of using the high headset yeah
we talked about that yeah
okay so how about if i wanted to find if
a search
a word has a prefix right so if i if i
if i say this is a
prefix it's not exactly the word right
it could be a prefix
then the hash set may is not working in
this case right because that if i search
er you need to tell me okay it's true
because er is the prefix of eric right
if i determine if the prefix is chess
and search prefix will return true
because chess
is a prefix of chesley
yeah ryan makes sense
eric makes sense
yeah
okay yeah makes sense so but in this
case how can we do it we will of course
we can do these menus yeah we can do
this
you know and
checking it you know
and by the way this this is not exactly
though right we are
uh we are assuming to compare two words
towards
these oh one concept but uh ideally you
know practically
to compare if the two strings are equal
that's going to take oven time so it's
actually one square okay
or n squared
now prefix is the same right it's the
same i have to do this uh
check one one
one and check if this is the prefix of
that right yeah and we're checking with
the prefix of that so that's going to
plug on square time as well
so how can we do this uh better using
the prefix tree so look everything this
is magic yeah this is the review how
come we do this
so we built a prefix tree so
so we go through this yeah we go through
this let's say okay this is the rule
there this is a tree previously
root empty here this is empty here and
then
okay
e i got e
yeah i got the r look
i got i
and i got the c
okay so
yeah just just by attending the letters
on the tree and r y a n
r y
a
and okay so at the end when it's
terminal notes when one list what
right when this node look because eric
this is a word boundary ending here so i
set this additional field to true
to true otherwise all other nodes are
false right and chessy again chesty
so c
yeah
h
e
s
s l y
l y
i'm pyro
okay p
[Music]
y
oh okay let's do another one maybe let's
put it like uh
like what every car okay
e-r-i-c-a every car
so look e
r i see and i put another a and then
this is also a what that means is true
and y n let's say
writing okay let's put another one
okay so r y a n and i put another white
here why you need okay so what look this
is the previous tree how does that have
okay let's say if i want to look up for
a word like uh
maybe
chest if a chest is a prefix from adding
words here so i can just do this
okay so look it has to try c i go here
h
e
s s okay fine look
it's here so
i can fall on the path so okay chess is
a is a prefix right
easy how about chair overlaps abc
it doesn't have a okay so i know
it's not prefix yeah
another example like uh chassis
okay so look c is there
h is there
e is there ss
okay but now this one doesn't have white
so we know the chassis is not part of
the original dictionary
yeah how cool is that right
yeah
makes sense so so how we process look we
possess these words in a in a list of
words we put it in the tree construct
the prefix tree which is called how do
you pronounce this by the way
try try
try okay
try
okay prefix tree okay so the time
complexity looked up to check if
to check if uh
okay okay to check if a word is in that
we is o n right n is the number of uh
the character in these right compared to
o n square right remember previously o n
squared because look linear search
n times for each one
in the worst case you need to compare
n times right
but now this is oven so it's the many we
are improving from ln to
om square to on and the space complexity
the previous one we haven't used any
space is a one right if we do a blue
force search but now we are using
addition a tree
right we're building this so what's the
term capacity of building this
is o n square right well if the each
word is n
and dense and they are inwards so that's
o n squared okay that's the space
complexity
all right i like to insert a word in
that it's easy as well look how do we
use a look let's say i want to insert
another one like uh
arrayed like okay without space how can
we insert this okay e is here so i don't
create it ah i see okay and then what
air it doesn't have air
so i put another air
okay
a
i remember when he finished here i need
to set this field t to true
right so next time i can just follow it
look this is you can call this like a
dictionary tree right so we we are
basically putting the words
yeah we're putting the words constructed
towards here
including the tree right so and this to
search
a prefix and search it it takes a long
time
okay so this is the
try yeah we talked about a long long
time ago yeah long long time ago
probably
i don't know in the first 100 days yeah
last year yeah
how does that help look if we
so now
okay so now i want to do this i want to
search something so i want to search if
i have a question mark here means that
it can replace any words so okay so can
you tell me if this is exist
e
question mark i see
if it is exists in in a word in in this
dictionary
now remember this is the thing any
single word
e something i see is it in the
dictionary yeah yeah because e i c okay
exactly how about how about
c
question mark question mark e question
mark question mark is it in the in here
c
c question mark yeah question mark
no
okay so it's not how about
c
question mark uh question mark question
mark
see
yeah question mark
okay so how can we do this what's your
song
obviously we still need to feel like
pillar
we still need to build it right
yeah we still need to build this
dictionary tree but how can we do this
when we meet a question mark
okay so let's say we want to meet a
question mark we don't care
that's good we don't care how do we not
care
it could be any good good point so let's
say look if a tree i'm here right and if
i made this letter and the next letter
this is the dictionary right this is the
dictionary
yeah this is a tree oh look it's a tree
right
so here
the next letter is question mark right
look this is for example this is
a for example and the next letter is
question mark
so all i want to do is that there are
four possibilities right so i can prove
first i can try each possibilities
yeah so that this is a word like uh
let's taken this e i c for example right
e something i c right so now
unfortunately
yeah
yeah question mark means any letter so
look if i try this
e okay it matches but the next one
is any number right and any characters
right so let's put another one maybe e x
a b
e q
c d okay i don't know e x a b
x
a b here there's so many
things attached to my name yeah yeah
look at e
e q c d okay
okay and then look so now i'm here the
next next character could be anything so
there are three choices which is qri
right it doesn't matter because the this
one matches any so it could be this one
so i how about if i try q
q then the next letter i need to start
with i see now i need to match
match if these are ic right or i choose
here i need to max the match this is
should be ic or match here should be i
see right
yeah so i just pull for all the children
and i can do this therefore search
yeah
i can just do this definition okay so
let's quickly rewrite it okay it makes
sense
yeah
okay so let's repeat again this is the
letter we are currently at and the next
letter is a question mark and all i have
to do is take the kids of this in a try
in the track and then blue forcing it
blue funky and how can you improve first
thing
definite search we do the different
search
yeah
and then look e r e something i see then
look e if i take if i try this part
this is this can be
this can match to a single uh
single question mark
and all i have to do is follow the path
to see if the next few characters
matches i see right
again here i take this rule the next few
characters should match ic
and x the next character should be
should match i see here right
yeah
okay so now
quickly let's quickly light the try okay
how can we write a try easy very easy
okay let's review a little bit
class normally we define a try in a
class we have to try
this is object
and then define constructor init
init init init cell
right so usually you can say self.
let's say words
is a dictionary right dictionary with
empty dictionary
and self don't leave is leave is what
let's say it's e or equals okay
okay
right
now
now i have to do this insert okay let's
do this in the inside and then the rest
will be distinctive inside i want to
insert a word in this in a try right you
know instead of what so
so first of all i get the root blue the
equals set
right so i'm going to say for
w in word i go through the characters by
character in this world i want to insert
look i want to insert this eric in in uh
i want to insert this eric in the try
right so now currently this is empty i
want to use the array so now i have to
check what
if w e is not in
blue dot word right but what
then i have to create a note in it so
loo
dot words
all right so the words w
equals try right
and then i i need to walk through so now
i create a word which is e here
here and then i need to walk through
that blue
right
and then
i keep doing this until
until the end when we reach reach the
end eic i need to set this to true so lu
da is leave
is leave is what is what it was true
right
yeah so this is the magic right this is
the magic if
if not in if this character if this
character we haven't got a character for
this then we create it and we put it we
put it in the try right and what we
work with okay so
so what does this do here
i go through e okay e is not here so i
create the e i work through it
okay r is not here so i created r one
three i i created i was three c i work
through it and then i send this to true
okay so for example if i have another
one e r and b okay
okay e is there so i just watch it i
don't i don't create it
r is there i don't create it a is not
there
i create it i'm not jump to it
b is not there
b and that's a little true make sense
yeah
insert let's to insert insert a word
into the chart okay time complexity this
is n
if there are n characters in the world
and o n
right the space complexity we're not
talking about space here because the tri
uses you know
is already thinking space there right so
there's no additional space in this
method okay
okay now the next word will be search if
we search it yeah if we search
search easy
if not in left then i need to return
false right easy if not in that i return
false otherwise return true
right
and then look if we search entire word i
can do this i can say okay return
return blue dot is leave right because
it has to be
it is what it has to be exactly match
but if i search a prefix look if i
search it with the prefix
prefix then i just need to return true
make sense
yeah
so each word is isn't
awake ryan what you doing
it's what what is warming
it means it's not this note if there's a
word ending here like eic right for
example i
the field is is word
is false because there's no word there's
no such word ending here right but yeah
i see there's actually a word
ending here so we send it to true this
field so such prefix will return true
but search what we need to return
that rule the note
is what equals true okay
ryan what did you say
right
okay now okay now let's do this step for
search bit okay easy
that's a search it's quite similar so we
we just have to
to
define we have to
search okay this search
please uh also have these words but this
word
can have a
question mark meaning it could match any
character okay so now most part is
similar rule dot self
and i go through this for w in
word okay i go through this is what okay
now look if w equal
question mark okay
yeah if this is a question mark so what
do we do okay so let's let's skip this
for a moment
as
if we know question mark if if what if
if w not in
root of one right
this is the same yeah now we return
false right yeah
if it's not a question mark and if it's
not in
in the in the next note right then
we return false because it's not
matching any
any prefix right
now i have to do this load equals i go
to next
kit yeah i go to the kit
do the word
w okay
and then we can
return true or if we want to match
exactly then we do potentially if we
don't want to match exactly we return
low dot is leave
that is what
we imagine matching the prefix right so
now look
if word equals question mark then i have
to do what i have to
i have to go through for the kids for n
in
in what in do
words okay now i have to go through the
keys now the kids what
if
search okay this is a search
search work
search anything such these uh
these things will be look
okay e
question mark i see right
so now i'm a question mark i have to try
each n each end search each n and then
go through
the uh
go to what i have to go through
the next one look there will be e
there will be a few right a few and then
this is a question mark right this is
question mark so i would go to try each
one to see if matches this this part
okay
yeah
so how can we write it so
i have to actually use the i index i
need to go through the index so that
would be enumerate enumerate give us the
index and
the value
index level right if w equals that and
then i have to do this i have to do the
word
from
from i
plus one
right to the end i want to search this
one
right
so i have to search this one yes
okay so i have to i have to
give uh
give a place give a loot here
right
so look do this to say where to start
okay if not loot
then load equal self okay so i tell you
what's happening here so search this
word and i have to go through that start
from the next one so you'll be
uh
you'll be what
do dog words
n
uh rule the words n that's it's kit
right
and then if you like that then we can
true
if one of it
is there if one of the paths matches
return to otherwise we can form
okay this is the logic here
okay
yeah
so okay so let's review this a little
bit okay
the no we we are passing extra parameter
to say where where is the
try which node to start looking for
right
before we start with the loot with
everything with everything in the top
now because we we have this question
mark so we have the matches but we have
matches if this is matches
if because this match any character then
look what happened look this matches any
character i see so i i want to match ic
in
in what here
here here right
so i want to match ic where here
in this level right
right
so this level which one is this level
it's the next level so i have to pass
here
right i see this this level matches
question marks
if this match is the question market and
that goes through all these kits
everything matches
with every yeah question mark
matches one single characters okay with
everything yeah with the one character
let's just double check a little bit
just to make sure
it's all right okay
yeah so look if for
for if if this is the question mark and
then we go to
uh we go through the loop dot
words okay rule of words and then we
need to go to the next character look at
this is i i i plus 1 to the n will be
this one
yeah and then we search if the root of
theta alluded was a right and if it is
a is a is this one and do dot
dot word a would be its kit so you'll be
this one right
yeah
and then you've learned you become true
okay uh
[Music]
okay so yeah
okay so if we
i think this is it
any questions any questions i mean this
is a little bit tricky yeah
is it we are using the tesla set
yeah
okay so what's what's special about this
one is here
yeah this bit okay let me do it again
look
previously if if we don't have this
question mark
right so we don't need to do this loot
will be cell
now we're passing this mood we are
telling
the search function to say where to
start okay so look this is a trial this
is a try somewhere
a try i try it's a previous tree right
it's a prefix tree
okay
so now
if i'm saying if i'm saying okay
the second letter
is a question mark right it's a question
mark
so you could match look at this this
first one is e the second letter is
question mark then i can try each part
i can try each part
but look this is e question mark i see
right question my ic then this is the
second letter
right and i want to match what the third
letter to the end which is i plus one
right but where to match i'm not
matching it from the start right it
doesn't make sense if i go back to the
root
so i have to match it
here
the children the subtree
of this question mark the sub tree of
the expression map make sense
yeah so that's why i put these loot of
words n which is here here here here and
if one of these matches well this is
just do a normal search if one of these
match matches
and then
okay so actually look you could the next
next one could have another question
mark as well right if this is another
question mark what happened
then okay the third one is also question
mark right
right so so what happened
this could be question mark again and
then i have to do this we have to do
this again if one of them follow if one
element has the
has matched its perfect match with the
time to otherwise will return four right
yeah okay
[Music]
okay so that will be it uh
any questions so far
what have you learned today so far
we learned about let's try what's track
try
i'm i'm going to i'm going to do uh
give you a few
uh
words and then can you feel the try for
me okay i know be easy a little bit
let's say i have a few words like eric
ryan
eric
fly
ryan like okay
just forward okay can you build a tree
for pathetic ryan eric you're
yeah that's good
way down
yeah
we're done
okay
t yeah t means that means is what is
true right okay good job
and then i'm missing one thing t okay
and why
right
yeah
okay
t yeah
right you're getting this
right
you following this yeah
well done okay so let's say if i want to
look for like
every car can you simulate the process
of everything there
every car
so
we got e
[Music]
okay
this is
depending if you're looking for prefix
if you're looking for prefix
then we just return true if you're
looking for exact match we need to check
if there's a t there right
yeah
make sense
yeah if if we're looking for the prefix
we don't care if there's t
if we're looking at match exact match we
need to find even t
make sense
okay
that's it for today bye bye bye bye
bye-bye that's it good job