good
hello mr mr ryan are you right
okay so let's give an a positive um
let's given a long negative integer like
five
and we want to know the minimum number
of steps to reduce the zero okay so for
one step you can either divide it by two
if it's even
or minus one subtract one
if it's odd okay and if we want to find
out the minimum
so what's the strategy here
let's say five how how do we get the
five to zero
subtract five
no no you can only subtract one divided
by two it's okay one one one one yeah
and they are five nine five steps right
so what's the minimum number of steps
five when we subtract one it'll become
four and then
sorry divided by two divided by two then
it becomes two
divided by two or divided by two all
subtract one that matter and then yeah
and so that's one two three four four
step but if you do this five
four
three
two
one
uh is it the same yeah
okay so in this case
is it the same
it's different but for the top one you
just did one and one oh one okay
one zero okay so now you have done so so
that this one you have four step yeah
one two three four this step
if you
if we just keep subtracting one and then
it'll be
one two three four five five so the
minimum
okay so
what's the strategy here
i mean
what's the strategy why we choose the
divided by two or not subtract one try
do it divided by two
if it's possible yeah if it's possible
if it isn't then subtract
because subtract divided by 2 is always
faster than structured one right yeah
okay so now
so if we we can just write it the
simulation we can just simulate simulate
the process right that strategy is
greedy is that we we want to subtract we
want to be we want to divide it by two
if it's even because that will make the
number go down quicker than subtracting
one right okay
so let's say define
steps okay steps and then number
so answer we have answer equals yellow
wire number is not zero right
look here
if n is n1 if this is the
if this is
what
odd number right if this is odd number
then we subtract one
otherwise if it's even number we divided
by 2. how can we divide it by 2
and
divided by 2 divided by equal equals 2
oh you can shift one position to the
right remember the binary
okay
okay look finally yeah
four binaries one zero zero right look
yeah
alright what's this in binary
uh that is
uh four four yeah four right look two to
the power of two then if i remove one
zero what happens what's the value
if i remove one zero fifty one to two
yeah it's like exactly here so finally
if you shift one position into a right
that's equivalent as dividing by two
okay and then now look
if if this is odd number we subtract one
if it's an even number we divided by two
and then both cases we need to answer
plus equal one right yeah and then
return answer yeah
okay
simple easy yeah
makes sense
yeah look if n n one is uh is is
odd number then we subtract one
otherwise we shift it one two to the
right like that is equivalent to n
divided by two equal and then answer
plus equals one right uh
return and so the time complexity
roughly all log n right because we have
this divided to keep dividing right it's
roughly oh logan okay
so
this is one way of doing it yeah pretty
sim simple and clear right
this is a simulation we call it
simulation because we simulate the
process and try to
do the subject divide division as long
as we can as long as this
even number okay any questions so far
for this one
ryan any questions so far do you
understand this one
yeah
okay so now let's take a look at the
binary for example like fifth uh let's
say
the let's say what's this in binary one
zero one zero zero okay
what's this in binary 2 to the power 4
this is 4 right
16 16 plus 4
20 right 2 to the power of look that's 0
4 so here
this is 4
16 okay
so this is 20 in decimal and maximum
okay so for each each yellow yeah for
each zero we just
have one division because if it's zero
at the right most it's an even number
right yeah
all right it's an even number so we just
need to divide it right so that comes
one
if it's one what happen
[Music]
if it's one will happen
this one
if it is zero if it is zero we need to
sub we need to divide it right if it's
one if it's one look if it's one we we
need to subtract it
right
subtract it but it becomes a zero again
yeah
it becomes we subtract it it becomes a
zero then what happened we have a zero
we need to divide it by again so each
one if each so if we we have a zero
we need to add one if it has one we need
to
add 2 right
am i does it make sense
yeah
can you tell me why this is 1 if we have
a 1 is 2.
i just i was just explaining to you if
it's a zero that's easy to understand if
it's a zero that's an even number now we
just divide it by two then get rid of it
if it's one what happen look if it's
this one one one one
this is fifteen right subtract the last
one subtract zero and then
so you need take two to get rid of
one digit right yeah so we can just
convert this number n to
binary and now we count
we count how many of them i
am right
yeah okay so how can we convert to
binary easy
so we can do this using the bin function
remember let's say this is b equals b
n right pin function binary okay pin
here is another thing it's the binary
stands for binary
and this will give me that prefix a
final prefix
yellow
b something and then look if it's 15 it
would give me 0b 1 1 1 1 okay and i need
to
i need to
get rid of the prefix too so i i start i
need to what
so because the first two characters are
meaningless to me so i have to start
from the second character yeah to the
end
and then now once
let me count how many of them so let's b
com
count
string one okay
and then zero zeros will be equal to one
the length of b
minus one right right because look this
b b
is only containing
ones and zero if one if what if there
are ones once yeah
you know this this number of ones here
so let's yellow i can do this simple
mathematics subtract it from the total
length right so number 10
return what once
times two right plus zero
okay here there's one more thing here
minus one why there is a minus one here
look just away if it's zero here
if it's zero here we already which
reached the target but
but we add one so we overcounted one so
we need to substitute one make sense
yeah yeah because if the input is zero
what happened you the result you give me
is one but
the the truth is it doesn't take any
step it's already zero okay so we have
to subtract one here
look look cll equals length minus one
right so look if we plug in here
all right
right if we plug in length b u here to
here
okay
return 1 times 2
plus length b
minus 1
minus 1 so these will become simplifies
this
return once
plus
well there are two ones minus one ones
so there's only one ones next plus
length b
minus one okay look this function
converted it's we already have these
impedance functions to convert the
integer to binary final string yeah and
we have to get rid of the first two
characters because the first two
characters is always zero b okay we
don't need this we need to get rid of it
okay so
how can we okay so let's review we talk
about how to convert the number back
into the integer
okay let's reveal a little bit i know b
okay so now look
uh 0 1 1 0 1 0 0 how do we convert this
into
how do we convert into decimal so first
of all
if it's zero
we start from the right hand side
zero
zero if it's zero zero but we look this
is two to the power two to the power of
one two right plus two to the power of
zero just skip it and one actually we
need to count how many digits on the
right so that would be one two three
four so two to the power four right so
the number is this yeah and how do we do
it back like 15 how do we how do we know
let's say 14 okay 14 what's the 14 in
this is the decimal how do we convert it
into binary
look divided by 2 7
which is remainder is 0 divided by 2
three which reminder is one divided by
two
one remainder is one divided by two zero
remainder is one
okay and it's zero so now
we write this back so that 14 in
binary is one one one zero okay
yeah make sense
yeah look we divided by two
we had uh how do you call this kung
quote
you know how do you call this what's
fourteen
fourteen is quotient
divided by two negative the divided
the dividend divided by the difference
okay so which one is divided dividend
quotient okay so quotient and then i
keep dividing by 2. i write the
remainder here is the remainder right 14
divided by 2
remains 0. 7 divided by 2 remains 1 okay
i already remain here and then the
opposite way you write this so the
binary is b equals 14. okay
yeah let's write another one like
25 okay what's 25
divided by 2
remainder 1 right yeah because it's odd
number is 1 divided by 2
0 divided by two three
zero divided by two
one
yeah
one uh one one divided by two zero
one okay so the result is one one zero
zero one okay let's convert one one zero
zero
one what's this in
in decimal
that's one
two
four
eight
sixteen
sixteen plus eight plus one
twenty five okay we got twenty five you
got it
two ways of yeah finally just finally
yeah okay okay
make sense
okay now be today thank you bye-bye
bye-bye