[Music]
okay so yesterday we talked about
reducing the number to zero yes let's
review this a little bit yeah we have a
10 and we want to review uh the dlc to
zero so
we have only two operations the first
one is to
subtract one from it and the other one
is to divide it by two right so we
prefer the division yeah because that
will help us to bring down the number as
quickly more quickly than subject one
i'm right yeah so ten that will give me
five divided by two and then four
and then
two and then one and then zero okay okay
so that the only step one two three four
five five step to zero okay
so now today's problem
today's problem is slightly
uh different is that we start from any
number one we start from one and we want
to reach the number
or any number we want to reach any
number and each operation
you are allowed to plus one okay so this
is opposite plus one
or multiply two
right
right so
the if you look at these
these two this is exactly the same like
yesterday and this is the opposite but
we are given a one more constraint here
is that
for the multiply two you can only do it
let's say
uh
n uh let's say
m number
terms okay
okay
yeah so let's say if we if we
are allowed to multiply
let's say if we are allowed to multiply
one time so what's the number of what's
the mean number operations to make one
to ten okay so m equals one you are
allowed to only we are allowed to do
this multiply one time so what's the
answer come on anybody
what
yes sir
we are allowed to do this multiply one
time what's the what's the
minimum
if we start from one we want to go from
one to ten so what's the number what's
the minimum number of moves we can do
this multiply two one only one time
yeah five
five times
yeah okay so what's your what's your
approach to do this
what's your approach
i mean
[Music]
we are multiplying so we are talking
about division so you are talking about
reverse yeah
you start with n yeah
[Music]
right yeah okay so we can make this
problem the obviously we think inversely
yeah inversely we think the opposite way
okay
this is the same so we we have
multiplied two right so
so much if we start with number n
instead of starting number one so we
eventually make this problem like
yesterday we we have two operation minus
one and divided by two but the only
difference is that we follow division we
have n number you can do this at most m
number of times so but
but as you said i mean at the beginning
if we we can do this division we prefer
to do little division why is that
because look a thousand if we do that
division now become 500 and now we
reduce the number by 500
but if you do it from 10 to 5 only
reduce to 5 times
you only reduce the five yeah yeah
so if we do it early
we can bring down the numbers quickly
right so we prefer that so we can do
this quickly right and with these
numbers so if so the strategy is very
obvious that if we can do this division
we'll do the division
bye
so how when is the time we can do this
division when the number is even and we
still have
n number of times for division to do m
is bigger than zero otherwise we can
just remove uh subtract subshell one
until we get a to one okay
okay let's quickly write it we can do we
can write this uh using two different
approaches one is uh let's one is let's
do it in recursion okay let's say ef f
function
we are now at number n and we have n
number of times of division okay
yeah what did that is just say what's n
okay
division n is the number and m is the
number of division okay now look if n
equal equal one then we just we just
stand here between zero yeah if the n is
zero it's one
yeah we already
at destination okay now look
now now what's next look if
if what if n
if m is bigger than zero right look if m
is bigger than zero we have n
uh
we have uh we still have the
divisions to do
we can apply and also now current number
is a
even number right
yeah
but if we have enough we have enough
division to do and then we we are we are
now n is even number alright yeah so
long return one return one
return
what's the time here come on can you do
this using the f function look so if i'm
saying okay so i have one more i can do
this one more division so then i can say
i apply one one plus f
n divided by 2 and m minus 1 right look
what does this mean
yeah this we divided by 2 so this is the
new number we have used one
division
now okay so we have used one so we have
applied one more operation so that's one
here all right okay
okay now now
so what's next so
if
if the and at this point then m is zero
right and
okay now we have to say
if
okay if one
n is yellow
okay so if m zero what happened
so we can't do the division anymore so
what's there what's the answer what's
the we can't do the division anymore so
what's the answer
what was the number of moves to bring n
to one
so we have a number
n and now we we want to bring it down to
one what's the number we come to
division so what's the number of moves
we're done that's that's that's good
return n minus one yeah
yeah easy yeah
okay no if if m
okay so what and what what's missing
here what's the news in here
what's what's missing yeah come on
um
okay so now now we need to do what if n
is uh it's all number okay so now here n
is on our number right if n is all
number then what happened
we minus one thank you very much then we
look here
here we just do this one plus
as
n minus one
and then i'm right okay
yeah look
okay can i repeat this if the number is
one
it is what if number is one we reach the
destination okay
can i have this please
okay okay this is good for me okay look
if n is one return zero okay
if m is bigger than one we have
n
divisions to two and this is even number
then return one plus these look we have
div divided by two so this is the new
number new target and n minus one which
is the division
or that's the one yeah because we have
used one division right if m is zero if
m is zero that we have no we we have uh
so what does it mean we have no
motivation so the only way we can bring
down n to one is by subtraction so
that's a minus one as you say otherwise
otherwise we we
we're not sure we're not sure then in
this case here what's here it could be
it could be one it could be m
bigger than zero or
one
or n is is even uh n is all number okay
so at this here you'll be
one of these right if m is bigger than
zero then i need to do this but n is odd
i also can do this in both cases i need
to plug one and here is the subtraction
okay yeah yeah make sense
okay so we can do this iteratively okay
we can do this iteratively
how can we do this iteratively
so look we can just do this define
let's say f n right so now look we have
the answer answer equals zero
so while
n is bigger than one right
n
okay so let's
m here okay and
m is bigger than zero right right so we
can do this look
what
if
n
is
even number if anything even a number so
what happens if a is even numb uh
this is if n is all number we can only
subtract one so
n minus equals one and the answer needs
to plus equal one right
as
if n is odd number so we prefer the
division so what
n divided by equal to and answer plus
equal one okay look both cases n surplus
equals one so let's move this a little
bit to the you know
outside so we can to make it clear yeah
uh look if n minus look at this is
division we we have used one division so
this here we need to minus n minus
equals one right
yeah okay so now
n
what should we determine what
okay so if
look here
why n is bigger than one and we have
division and then outside
what's outside if the loop terminates
here what's the outside if outside here
what's the condition
what's the opposite of this
so while this condition is true we do
this and if i'm outside what happened
so
so what was this if n is bigger than one
so what will happen here
it could be one right n is equal to one
or
look so the opposite is like n equals 1
m is equal to 0 right
yeah if n equals 1
then we are done right
but if m is 0 it means we have no
division at all
so we can how do we bring down the
numbers from n to one
you just say and what
if n equals zero what's the how many
steps to bring n to one
right
when m is zero and
may not be one right so let's then how
do we bring the n to one
n minus one and minus one yeah yeah so n
minus one n minus one but
remember we have an answer here we have
used answer here so plus answer right
yeah
does it make sense here
which one do you think
is better which one do you think is
better
look this one yeah and divided by two
you can also write it as and shift shift
shift equals one okay this is two hours
if i listen when n is even number okay
one anything in one these two are
equivalent okay these two are equivalent
okay so
uh
this is make sense here this one
okay so what have you learned today so
far
[Music]
so i'm sorry sorry i mean what is it
me and me moves to reach targets
okay so what how what's the approach
here what's the approach here
we are trying to
prioritize which operation
um
[Music]
yeah because we have a number we have a
restricted number of times to do this uh
multiplier if we think it diversely
we you we if we inverse the problem
and the operation will be subtraction
and division right and we prefer the
division we want to do this division as
soon as we can right because it will
help bring down the numbers quicker
am right
okay so look this is n this is current
number let me repeat again the n is the
number m is the number of
division we can do when n is the one
that will return zero yeah obviously we
are attacking when n we have when we
have division and then this currently n
is a even number then we can do the
division yeah and divided by two and we
have one less
division here one plus
if n
look if n is zero means that we have we
can't do the division anymore so we we
can we we need n minus one to bring down
the end one right otherwise here he'll
feel clear what's the case if m is
bigger than one zero
or
n is a
odd number then in both cases we need to
subtract one right and then we we
calling the recursion to to find a
smaller problem which is n minus one m
right
yeah
minus one here okay and here
we repeated it yeah answer is the number
of steps we've taken so far when n is
bigger than one and we have like more
we can still do this division when n is
a odd number
we subtract a one
because because this is the only way to
bring down the number when it when n is
an odd number otherwise
otherwise when we have a steel division
to do
then we can do this division and
we need to
remember to to do what to subtract the
division okay
and then answer the passing equivalent
because it applies to both branches and
when the loop breaks
when the blue breaks
so we still need to print the number
from n because m might not be one right
yeah so n minus one plus answer
okay that's it for today
what's the time complexity by the way
what's the time conversation look we
have a division to print out a number if
we have a division
okay so the best cases is what if n
if n is a
number to the power yeah like 128 so you
always divided by 2 right 128 64
8 four two one right
log in
yeah
okay that's it for today bye bye bye bye