oh
hello miss area all right
okay so we're given this graph right
this is the weighted graph right way to
graph graph is the collection of vertex
and edges right
yeah
a tree is also a graph right
tree is a graph it's directly a cyclic
graph right
directly you know from the parents the
kids exactly means it doesn't have
cycles but
this is a graph weighted graph okay
we can have a weighted graph with
direction okay so look we can have this
diagonal
yeah
oh we don't right it doesn't matter so
here
here if we if we if this is the weighted
directive graph right weighted
and we want to find the shortest path
from the s to e right the cumulative
cost right so which which one is the
shortest one can you can you see very
clear uh
s a
[Music]
look here one don't be don't fall for
that because this is a trip to the truck
right before it asks you to go lease but
look there's a hundred much bigger
weight here
but all humans are quite clever right we
can see this like you know instinct
reflect
reflect and okay so this is the normal
ideal way
so
with the different search okay
that's okay with the death massage it
doesn't work quite well in this case
because the deficit doesn't handle the
cases when the
edges have caused right yeah
and breakfast search
either right the breakfast search isn't
working quite well as well right so now
today we're going to talk about another
search which is called uniform construct
this is very good to handle the
the shortest path from the front to
vertex
we we have actually talked about another
aggregate from the fly you probably
can't
remember right it's a on cubic
yeah yeah look why is that look it's
actually it's actually based on the
dynamic programming look it's like that
okay the shortest distance between
i
to j
is equals to the mean
mean of what mean of shortest distance d
i j
and then d i k
and answer d
plus t
k j okay what does it mean actually it's
very easy look
here
i want to calculate a certain distance
between i to j right yeah
then i can do please i put it in the
loop oh and free times and now what
happened so if i find a path
look if i find the part somewhere this
is k
all right
if i find the path
i want to calculate the circuit system
between i to j but now i found a better
shorter path which is i k plus ikj
then i can replace i j with this pattern
right yeah well done this now this is
100 and this is one this is two
so
d i j is 100 now but i found d i k is on
dk j is 2
so i can replace the i k with 1 plus 2
equals 3. yeah let's let's that's about
it so we just search we just do this for
k in
range
and
for i in range
and for j in range n and then to this d
i j equals mean d i j
comma d i k plus p k j let's say oh this
is the simple
shortest path between any two points any
two vertex right but it takes time
it takes one cubit let's slow that's why
we're not talking about that today we're
talking about uniform close search so
the way to understand uniform cross
search is actually very simple you know
for the preferences to use the kill
right first thing first out right but
for the cost uniform cost search we
replace the q is the priority queue
okay that's the first thing priority
first thing
priority up right yeah so you have the
people you're waiting in the so priority
queue is like right okay so you you you
know first things first our first in
first off now
it it's not like that so you have a
let's say who is taller
first okay so i have a people here yeah
this is the people
play in the queue and then here
john a taller and then another another
guy john
much taller
okay so now the scale
yeah
if the higher priority is the taller the
taller the higher priority length when
we dq then this guy gets gets in front
of the q and this serve okay this is top
priority right
yeah okay so now um
so first of all
if if the if the course is one or one
can you imagine what happened
course it's all become all one will
happen
you'll be
like you'll be like what
what what did i just say we are trying
to replace the preferences
yeah exactly we're replacing the
preference search with the priority
queue right but if the course is all one
all the same
all the same or one okay then then it
actually becomes a perfect search right
so so how can we do this look if at the
beginning we
uh we put a
s in it so s in it okay so s the cost
from s to s is zero
now we take the priority of the high
priority which is the lower cost from
the kill
i put it i remove it i put it in s
okay
when we then when the removed vertex is
the destination that we we quit we stop
the algorithm because we already found
it okay now s is not e so we continue
so s zero so
s can go to a right with the cos2 this
is the only way you can go through so i
put a which is two right
okay so now the next one i want to take
it out is only one element so i take it
out a is two i put a in the visit set
from a i can go to b c b then i can
enqueue all the children so okay so a to
d
will be two plus four accumulate what
cause yeah so it will be six and s a b
it will be two plus three is is what is
five
and then e c will be
two plus seven will be
nine okay
yeah
okay and now
i continue because uh i haven't found a
destination yet so now d is six six b is
five i take the fire because y is the
lowest cost which is the higher priority
i take it out
it's not e i continue i put b here b is
five
from b i can go nowhere so i stop i i i
just don't append and hit and now next
one
b and c which i should take b
because because c i take a d six
d i put it here six
six plus two is a
yes
d
if there's a two direction right we're
still not going back to a because a is
already in visited so we don't go back
yeah okay so c is a
and and then we for for the next round
we take c equals a i
yeah put it here c equals a
uh and go to f and g
a plus a
f is 16 right
c
uh
g will be a plus one would be nine right
g okay nine
yeah so for the next one i don't think i
take a c
but it's in already in the visited so i
continue i skip it yeah look yeah
yeah
so i take this i skip it and now
f and
g which i take a g right
yeah
i take a g i put it in here
t will go to e will be 100 e will be 100
right okay now f 16 e 100
[Music]
actually the cost is not 100 see is it
100 no
it's ssa2421
four two one is nine 109 okay sorry
i f i take x right f16
i put it here
so 16 plus two will be 18 so e will be
18. right look so
now the next thing look i take e which
is 18 right
okay now because i do the removed
remove the vertex is e is the
destination and i stop the action which
is 18 is 18 2
2 that's 8
16 18. yeah let's survive okay
yeah that's the uniform cost search
it's actually quite easy to understand
if you
if you think about references the only
difference is that we are using the
priority queue right now
the
unicorn uniform
cost search does not
i mean does not care how how many paths
right it only cares it's about
accumulate past cost right you always
pick pick the smallest the highest
priority okay so that that's right
quickly right the pseudoscope right a
little bit
okay
define
let's say let's say we have a
shortest path
on a certain path of a graph in a graph
let's define it as uh
uh you know there's a few ways to define
the graph which you can give in edges as
a list of edges okay so let's given the
edges and then we have a star edges
that is star and n right
so now g
the graph will be default dictionary
before dictionary is uh we're using the
adjacent list to install a graph
list
and then for
uh
for each edges it will be given as front
two and weight okay so for a to b we
have a cost in edges
now we can do this g a
okay plus equal let's pass as a b
the the other the the other vertex of
edge and the cost
okay now we have stored a graph we have
processed the edges and put it in a
graph okay now at the beginning q is a
priority queue right so at the beginning
it only
only contains the
from the star which is the
one which is let's say cos zero and
start with s like cos zero
yeah we put s in the q and the cost
from s to s is zero
yeah
okay and then y y and q look this is
quite similar to ppfs and now what will
happen we have we also have we also need
to
store a scene yeah a half set to
remember the set we have remember the
vertex we have we have visited okay
now
wire q
and then we have a current
uh
the current
um
we have a current cost the current cost
and the current will be equal as the
it's not q top pop left right
for the for the priority queue we use
the hip-hop remember
he pop
he pop q
right and then now look if the current
equals the distance
uh equals the
destination and we return the distance
between the cost right yeah
now we
the next thing is to do what if then we
need to check if the current is already
being visited soon now we'll just
continue here i'll just skip this one
and then now the next thing is go
through the
other the the neighbors of the
uh
of the current
so for
and in
in g
uh
g current okay
g current is actually you know the
containing a toughest array of taps
which is the vertex and the cost so we
have uh we need to do this as n is the
vertex c is the
uh is the cost from the cut from the
current to the end so now we just need
to keep uh to push this into the
priority queue hit pau push
q
and then d plus c d plus c okay d
because current cost is c and the new
cost is c so that the new update
accumulate cost is p plus c and then
vertex says n right and then if we can't
visit it
if we configure everything uh the
destination here we just will return
anything we can run or return minus one
it doesn't matter
okay look we look look at this template
can you see the difference between these
and the breakfast search can you point
it out
hip-hop yeah
with the preferred search we use what
q dot
top left exactly and then i know another
difference
another difference with the hippo what's
the arrow to push it
so here here is different right so in
the preferences you'll be killed a pen
right
so this one is picking the
the lowest and then the highest priority
which is the lowest cost right and here
is to pushing the kids of the
vertex into it and all other things are
quite similar okay so this is the
uniform cost search
okay so it's quite useful to find the
shortest path between uh in a graph with
the weighted you know with weighted it
could be directed or under
directed graph or undirected graph okay
it doesn't matter as long as the wages
has the weight okay if that if the wait
the c is all one and then this angular
will be exact exactly like the breakfast
okay
yeah
okay make sense
okay we'll talk about that uh in the
next few days okay
that's it for today bye bye