hello hello
are you all right yeah okay
okay so we're given a real numbers like
one two
two
one three four okay so this is array
numbers yeah
and then we also given a k integer
like two
can we find any two distinct index you
know
this thing
b two and two i haven't finished the
this thing how do you describe this
thing do i
do
this thing this thing means that you
need yeah index distinct free and full i
and j
such such what a array i
equal
array j
and also the distance distance
absolute value i minus j is smaller or
equal k
okay yeah so we want to we have to find
out if we can find two index two values
yeah two unique two values so two two
different values okay two different
index
and the values isn't set for number two
and two this is the same
one and one this is the same right and
the distance i and j
yeah the index distance between them is
smaller than equal to k for example two
so look this one and this one yeah it's
okay right we find it because look two
and two the index difference is one and
the value is the same so you can true
okay
yeah make sense
how can we do this problem i mean this
is a simple array problem so we want to
find as long as we want to find two
index well it can do what what what we
can do about it
about the index we want to find out if
left index pair right i and j so we can
do what
two pointers yes we can do pointers but
most intuitively the i and j we want to
find the pair we want to find such pair
index pair i and j so given
as advancing in array okay so there are
an anime in the race so what can we do
about it
what can we do
we can do what the first thing coming to
my your mind is what
yeah we can prove also what's the time
come back stage
oh n square down yeah we talk about that
a lot
and then the second approach as you said
two points yeah two points that works
yeah but how can we do this two pointer
thing
how do how can we do
i mean
the the thing is that we want to find
out if there are
we want to find out what if there are
two some elements which the distance is
less than k right yeah two or one this
one so does that they're storing the
previous index help like some element
for example like if i i'm here
right the the the the previous index of
one is not existent so let's find out so
we stole the first the one the the last
one uh the last index for one is zero
the last index for two
is none but we store it okay
which is one okay now the second two
we are at second two
so what's the last index of two
one one now i'm at index
two
two minus one
one
it's less than
two
so we found it right so as long as we
walk through the
arrays and then keep updating the
index for the last
occurrence of that element and then we
can check by the wrong way right so
that way we can
solve this problem all right so this
time complexity if you're going through
that one's little bit o and linear it's
much quicker than this o n square proof
of thing okay and then the way you talk
about the two pointer is it's so it's
quite interesting yeah it's the third
method which i'm going to talk about
here so
so let's say we want to find out let's
look
so so look the k right so let's talk
about because we want to find out if
there are elements within
the same within this k equals 2 right
the distance so how about we just
maintain a window of size k
right so we we we maintain the size k
and now we move we move right so we use
the set to content to store all the
elements in in the k size window and and
now we're just maintaining that and
we just shift it moving moving moving
okay and now we check if this element is
in in
it's in uh
okay
yeah okay so let's quickly write down
the three approaches
the first approach profoundly
know for the profiling is quite simple
yeah let's say uh check duplicate
this array okay and then first of all we
want to find out that length is length
a-r-r
and i will just tell you how do we
project for i
in
range
and right
and then for j
in
range you can start with i plus one to
your n or you can
you can iterate uh we can iterate the j
up to i it doesn't matter okay so either
you have this i j player or j i pairs
and i will just check if a r r
i equals a r j
n
okay so now this j is less than i so i
minus j is smaller or k
him return true right
and if we sound fine it returns false
yeah simple
right you see this proof of thing is
quite intuitive right look
intuitive yeah
there are n elements in the array
the i index
going up to n the j index
going up to i and if the both elements
because i and j are different right look
i and j are different distinct
and if i uh equal and an i minus j
because i is bigger than j i minus j is
smaller than k
why do i not put the abs here do i need
to put the abs here
do i need to put the abs what's abs
value
but now i i know i is bigger than j so
abs i minus j is the same as i minus j
right yeah
it's a positive number i know so it's
written to allow
okay the first approach okay now the
second approach
define okay i'm not going to write
different okay so now i have a position
position is a
dictionary okay i'm using this
dictionary to store the index for the
la for the for the element last uh the
last index of the element okay so now i
follow
the index the value index value
in
enumerate okay let's enumerate
yeah we're done okay now look if
look if the
now this value yeah if this value
appears
before right in partition and also
the its value is index right its index
is v
position v yeah
but now the index is i i minus position
v
is smaller than k
then we return
return true right now we now we need to
put the
so we now we we want to put the
index
index uh i for the value v so we do what
plus
v
equals i right and then return to
okay you see
is it all right
i index v is very innumerate all right
okay and then look the value has
appeared before
and it's index
because it has appear before the index
is position v right and the current
index is i i minus position v
is the distance if it's smaller than k
return true
right if not i need to remember
the index for the current value v so i
do this position v equals i return true
if we can find it
right
is that okay right
okay the tank and leg stay away right
you're just going through once
space completely yeah
what's the space on this thing
we're using a hashtag
uh
this is not the dictionary hashtag
now the third method
so the method the the size okay let's do
this okay i'm gonna write it here
so far
we have uh
let's say we have uh
employee
so we want to we want to store this uh
data so
in a hash table okay we want to use the
hash table to store
a headset to store the numbers in this
in a window so let's say
data into a set
now i understand for i
v
in enumerate okay this is the same
enumerability what's immunology in
english
what does it mean
i don't know you don't know in human
right what does it mean
it means
okay that's a very good answer yeah
yeah if numerous things okay okay now
look
so now look if i is bigger than k okay
if i is bigger than k then what do we do
because now
if if bigger than k and then i need to
remove we need to remove
the
now look this is the k side
this is a k size window right if i is
bigger than that if i is here
i is here then i need to remove this
from the window right
so now i just need to do a data
don't remove
i need to remove
a r
i minus k minus 1 okay
right
that's the that's this element
i minus k minus one falls out of the
window right look just imagine we have a
window moving window size with k and
moving moving moving moving
so when i moving then i need to ignore
the
the element here outside the window
right that's what it does
and then now i just need to check if we
in data
if we still have this state any v in the
data will return true
all right
then otherwise we just state our dot
a add v okay and then we turn wow three
times what return four
okay
what's the time complexity if you look
at this
if you look at this this problem
all right right what's the term
convexity
[Music]
right what's the space complexity
when
oh when we are using the data do you
understand this approach look
let's
come on come on
i'm going to use write an example okay
like two
one
three
two
five
six
okay this is the array
and now we are looking for
if we can we can find to some element
when the index is smaller than one
three
smaller or equal than three
okay
array is this number
right
so this is simple yeah the first
approach group
yeah
i
and then j here three moving i
j
i j or or the other way is what i
i j
i j i j so basically we have proof
within the pairs of i j this is easier
yeah we don't need to talk too much
about it it's slow it's intuitive it's
straightforward right you
it works if the data
even the numbers
the number of numbers is small right so
we can prove it
yeah how do you say the number of
numbers
do you have better way of saying that
the data the data set is more right
yeah this one
the second approach we're using the this
headset uh the dictionary the table
the the half table so we're using test
table to remember that index for the
previous numbers okay so now look the
position here number two
we're at two right i equals zero v is
two
is to appear before now right so i i put
it here position two
equals the index is zero okay now
look this is position
okay position
okay now is one appear before no
all right so i put it there one
position is one
it's three appeared before
no i put a three position is zero one
two
it's two appear before yes okay what's
the what's its value yellow what's color
index cl one two but zero one two three
yeah three minus zero
less than equal and three between two
you got it yeah you got it okay now this
approach
this approach
i must state a set yeah a set contains
the store's unique numbers
yeah
set okay so for example set theta equals
this empty theta dot f1
is one theta dot at two
is two theta f of minus one minus one
theta at two
theta dot f two one
[Music]
minus one now this is a set yeah if i
adding another two will happen
because set contains only unique number
it won't make a difference because two
is already there that's that's a
different set yeah it doesn't store the
duplicate it's all the unique elements
so it doesn't matter okay let's do this
say that okay now i v
i
i is zero
v is two
right
if i index this index is needs to be
bigger than what then three yeah uh what
is what's the yeah k equals here 0 1 2 3
here
so when i
when the index is here we need to go to
go into this
right otherwise we just do it we just
don't okay
uh
so okay but probably this is not a very
good example because the the duplicate
value is is here even before the window
okay zero one two three okay
okay so this is the window size window
so you're already there so look if v in
data not then i do this two
one
three this is the data another two two
is already in data so i return two okay
so probably i need if i
if what if i remem i move these two
uh
no no no uh
two
three
okay and then k
let's say k equals uh
two right k equals two and then lead
this way
k equals 2 then
no no no
but it can't find any okay 3 2 then in
this case it's uncomforting okay now
theta
2 0 1 2 so i needs to be here to
to allow to enter in this right right i
bigger than k okay
if we in data no data is empty data at
the beginning is empty
okay data at two okay
okay one is one in the data no so i have
a one
three in the data no okay now here
look we are we are arriving at this
point
is more than k right it's more than k
so we need to remove
these
we need to remove these
from from that set so i remove it and i
check if 2 is in in here
it's not right because i just remove it
because this value is already 4
is already far be far away so we need to
remove it from the set from the window
all right and then i need to add it to
here
okay again
now i need to remove one from the window
and add a five then i need to remove
three
from the window and add six so
at any time the data stores the elements
in the k in the case right so why is
that because the numbers
in the in the set in the window is less
than k
steps away right so then we can check if
it's in the data and return true why
this is quite obvious
otherwise we add it right so every time
we remove these what's this what's this
number
what's this number
so i'm here what's this number
that's two yeah i'm here what's this
number
oh that's right
i'm here this is the one what's here
i'm here what's the
number to remove if k equals 2
k equals 2 what's the number
i minus 2 minus 1 what's the i minus 2
minus one
yeah so what's this what's this window
about one two
what i'm asking is that
i am an i
and k i this data store the data stores
the numbers
within the k step
so i have to remove
this number what's this number
so i'm here what what's number what
numbers i should remove from the data
i'm here what numbers you have to move
they have two two
yeah i'm here what number should i do
say that
what's the number i should remove yeah
exactly like you see because look
it's like a trend
moving right this is a size k
when i move one step from to the right
so this is the number i need to
remove it from the window am i right
yeah make sense
yeah
okay ryan doesn't make sense
okay so which one you think is better
it's the best
there are three blue problem this one
this one
definitely not blue
that's the very good answer but how
about these two which one do you have
preference
or you say it's the same
it's the same because it's the same yeah
just different way of thinking
this is useful
hashtag to store the numbers with the
window k size k this one we're
remembering the index of last appearing
the number
yeah the last index of the number and we
can just do the calculation
okay and this one because look we
because the data
yeah the numbers in the data are less
than k that's not an equal k so i don't
need to do this if uh
i don't i don't need to do this
i minus i don't need to check the index
here because all the index in the data
all the data in the all the numbers in
the data are k less than k that's all
then equal k so i just have to check the
numbers in that right okay so this is
two way of thinking okay a little bit of
the day good job bye bye bye
bye