okay so today we are going to talk about
the two players zero sum game two player
zero game oh yeah oh pokemon game we'll
see through some game
so what does it mean
two player okay two player thing you
have to play you two play everyone so
it's just two players
you know some what zero sum means it
means if i
if i win you have to lose if i win 10
dollars you lose 10
right yeah so that
makes sense
yeah
so the only one
one winner for one to win the other has
to lose
all right so i'll give you an example
like a tick tick tick tock do you
understand
another tic tac toe
it's pretty unfair because you already
know
okay so
yeah you want to play you want to play
stickers
i use this one
different color okay
come on who is going to flat before
[Music]
that's a very smart move to to occupy
the one in the center yeah
okay
um
nothing else
okay
good job
yeah i know i mean
so if we if you both played
intelligently i mean you know smart
right so it will be the draw anyway
right because this is so small and then
yeah the first people occupy the center
because it's it's around here
yeah yeah it has more chances you know
the rows
i don't diagnose that
so look this is the jaw
draw yeah draws nobody wins nobody lose
so nobody we nobody knows who we call it
uh we we just call it zero okay yeah
yeah
so let's go the the score is zero
so this this is a two player zero game
so look zero sum if the jaw is is
uh it's a zero okay so if let's say if
the
uh the first player yeah the first
player will call it asian yeah a player
two players
players so it's just it's a
it's a tupper so
two players agent
agent and then the other one is called
opponent yeah yeah opponent agent will
be
cross yeah
yeah
asian
opponents yeah okay
so hey hey
hey
then then you're eight then the agent is
your opposing team that's right yeah
agent or probably
it's just the term yeah you can say eric
ryan just two players playing each other
against each other so an agent if agent
wins yeah if asian wins the player agent
wins then we give it like
let's say let's give it um infinity yeah
infinity
if the opponent win
we give it minus infinity yeah yeah
so so you see we give a very big value
for a page and when opponent has to lose
right so if look it's added together
it's a zero that's why you call it zero
sum okay
yeah so the opponent is trying to
minimize
minimize the score
the agent is trying to maximize the
score
make sense
yeah any questions so far
is it just is it
what is your appointment against a high
score
no no this is this is the
so let's say two players so your
target
your target is
is different right you are trying to
maximize the score you are trying to
minimize the score if you win you can
lease if you win you got this okay
make sense but that's how we call it
two-player zero sum okay
okay so connect why doesn't it be one
rather than infinity
good question
yes
one i mean
that's a very good question
we use the infinity means that you know
just a special value to say okay it's uh
um you know it's the
it's end the game is ended
right for example if if if
if i have a gap i have i have not ended
yet right so if i the first one agent
put the products plus x in the center so
it's more
for asian it's it's quite good right
it's it's which one is better why would
i put it but
if they've been in the middle they can't
they might be kind of dumb and didn't
win
no no no what i'm saying like okay so
now your agent and then there's your
first move which one is better put it
here i'll put it here
the one in the middle because it's more
you have more angles that's right so
what do you call it this is the better
move than that one right so let's say i
want to put assign this a better move so
let's say i give it a 100
and this i will probably give you 20 off
you know so in this way i can compare
these two moves which is better this one
is better so i would prefer this this
move okay
that's why we say okay the infinity
means the optimum goal right we'll end
it okay
okay so i'm gonna define uh
a few
i think i know how to win yeah i don't
know when okay so
before i define a few few terms these
two two players here again needs to be
like transparent so everybody knows
exactly what happened on the ball right
so not like a pokemon
poke yeah pokemon you don't know what's
your opponent's hand yeah what's the
card on your opponent yeah that's not a
two player
you know something because
you don't know and everything right you
have to guess you have to um
i mean you have to think about
what your opponent
could have right
it could have a me too
center scotch
so let's say divide a few um a few terms
value
so let's call a state okay
what state
what state of the game is the state of
the game uh united states
stay
is the current p look current the
situation everything situation only is
ball on the ball
and then whose turn is it right that's
the calling state okay so state has the
position and then player
yeah yeah player has advantage of it
okay
okay so stay
stay would be the
the crosses and the circles
you know
all about
and whose turn is it next okay
and then we also need to define the
is n
its n needs to tell me if this is
already ended
yeah
it could be a draw or could be somebody
wins so this is ended because it's a
draw and if i say here
then this is also empty because the
crosses win okay
[Music]
okay okay uh
so
i can't put a circle here but because
there are two wins yeah let's say this
one okay
this is ending because the closest win
okay
but this is not only because
you still have one more choice uh maybe
here no yeah oh obviously
okay
now uh the actions we need to define the
action
action will be taking the
state
we'll be taking the
state and
also the
so
okay so no no action is actually the
next the play the possible play uh
players actions
so for example the actions could be
either you put it here or put it here
right
yeah
okay so this is the action yeah
yeah make sense
okay so what's next then we have uh
utility utility utility utility utility
is the
gives that it only applies to the
uh
[Music]
the state is ended so when the state is
ended utility tells me who is the win
yeah yeah who is win
who is winning right so he basically
tell me okay if it's action players yeah
you basically tell me when this is
landing who is wing if it's a draw give
me that you know if it's asian wing give
me the
infinity if it's the opponent give me
the minus yeah okay so i know we have
another one which is called success
success successor
is it successor how do you spell this
word
what's this name
success
it means sock
what's it mean what's this
okay no no no no no it's not successful
it means the next one the next
yeah the next so it takes the state
and it takes the action so it needs to
return the next state so it basically
now i'm currently in this state i know
what the action what's the action right
for example this is the state and i want
to put the cross here right so basically
i want to pull across here
i want to put a cross here
right
and then
this is a new state right so look if
this cross then the next day will be
leased
the state contains the the positions and
the whose player so who's who's playing
next because the cross is playing the
previous so the next one should be
closed right yeah that's the state okay
okay so these are five elements stay
is ended action utility a successor okay
so it's uh
so stay
stay okay
stay started yeah
utility action
and then the successor okay
so
let's uh
let's find out let's uh play another
game okay so let's say we're given a
number n
and in each item
in each one
you can decrement this number by one or
you can divide it by two
if it's an odd number you're just taking
the you know the the four flowing
remember this
uh 2.5
floor is two right
yeah two point
nine floor is two i'm rolling yes do you
still remember flaw
and the ceiling is the opposite opposite
2.1 ceiling will be equal to three yeah
okay
so whoever
whoever has
casino
wins
so let's say three uh let's say 100.
let's say
now
my turn okay
50. your turn you can decrement it or 25
25. okay
let's play 25 you're 25 25.
now i said i said 12. okay
i say
six
okay now i said five
nothing
okay then i said
one
okay so okay so you said yellow you win
okay yeah make sense you want to play
again
which one you don't really get it so in
each operation you can decrement it or
you can divide it by two whoever gets to
zero wins
okay
no no no you can only decrement one or
divided by two
okay let's try again right uh
let's say your turn
same number divide by two subtract
divide 25 25. okay then i said 24 okay
[Music]
yeah
i said
11.
i say 10.
okay i said 9. i say eight is it seven
six six
um
i say a three
[Music]
how to guarantee a win
in the next few days okay this is very
interesting think about it you can play
this with mommy
yeah you can play this with mommy
whoever gets to zero wins okay whoever
gets to zero winning so
so let's say let's use this simple game
to define the laws for a few times
saturday if it's ended the action
the utility
and the successor okay and then we
quickly we quickly implement this okay
is it interesting this is kind of like a
two-player deal
ryan who knows two-player zero-sum game
okay
and then you tell me
it's too noisy
so let's say let's first first define a
class let's say halfling this is called
huffington halfling game
[Music]
okay that's it
so in the init function we're going to
take a n and from n this is the number
we're going to take here so self.n
equals n this is the number we're given
right this is the number like 150.
now let's start again let's the star
state
star state
what's the stars game
the star state will be
returning if i say agent is plus one
right agents plus one opponent's turn is
minus one so it will return a tuple
let's say plus one and then serve the
iron okay this is the star state okay
starting
okay now we want to have a east end this
end if the game is ended right
if the game is ended so we are taking uh
we are taking a stay right we are taking
a state
so the state will be the player and the
number yeah let's say player
let's
break down these the state player number
equal stay okay this is a tupper and
then if you can descend it then we can
say return number equals zero right
yeah okay
start
is end and then
action so what are the actions we can
have what are the actions
come on
what are the actions
the actions
actions what are the actions uh we can
divide it or we can
we can divide it and we can subtract
okay so let's say divide us subtract or
divide we could put it in in a tuple or
array okay
and then we have uh
utility
utility there's so much fines yeah
utility we have a state
again this state
is two things it's player and a number
so we we just decouple it player
number
equals stay
right so we need to make sure this is
and uh it's n is already ended right so
we need to make sure a third
the number
is equal to zero okay the utility only
makes sense when it comes to the end
game and then
so look when
when it's ended then i i will return
return what player times infinity times
times mass dot infinity so
so when player is a
agent it will return max infinity one
player is
opponent you will return minus infinity
okay yeah that's what we talk about
and what that was
successor success success means that
the next one it takes a state it takes
the action it takes the action
so we we have a player
again players
player number equals they break out the
state
now we can say if action
equals
[Music]
minus right if it's equal to minus that
will be 10
to return what
minus player okay because look what's
minus player means even now agent is
playing so the the next one is minus
agent is playing if look if minus agent
is playing
you make it negative then you become
player okay
my case
what's minus one equals what
minus
now now player is one you put a minus
minus one and you put another minus
that's one you play another minus minus
one
minus minus one equals plus one okay
yeah
lastly the next next player playing
right because currently player is
playing you put them minus is the next
player playing and then the number
needs to minus one right
as if
action
equals divide
now we return
one minus player and number
divided by two okay yeah
make sense what else well have we missed
anything no
uh
sometimes we have this player function
play player function yeah player
function player function is just simply
determine the player from the one with
the couple of state okay
already couple of states
so this is a
basic uh elements of the
uh
the game right so we can apply this one
to the tick tick tock top right
is the thing what's the difference
between this game and a tic tac top
that one is writing in the other one is
drawing
so what's the difference what's that if
i want to use this template to apply it
to the tic-tac-toe what should we change
the stain right the state for this game
the state is the number and the player
right
the player and the number but for the
tick tick tock is the player and the and
the ball right
yeah
right and then it's ending we need to
check the the cross for each rows each
columns and two diagonals yeah this one
is ended for the action
instead of returning the minus and
the two two action right
how many action we are look the action
for the tic tac toe is what is the empty
empty slot all right
yes
empty slot instead of minus and divide
utility this is the same right this is
the same right
we don't need to change it but for
different action we just need to
put
update the empty slot right with the
we need to mark
the empty slot as occupied by the player
okay and a lobby okay
any questions so far today
what have you learned are we right how
to play tic tac tok and other stuff and
no no we're not talking about how the
strategy to play to win we today we're
not talking about a strategy to win yet
right so we are just defined again
as a few
properties the start state right
the two-player game yeah start stay so
everybody is
is aware of the start state right at the
beginning of the start stay you know
what happened right on the ticket
it's a
it's a three by three
nice slot
ball it's empty everybody you know
you know everybody know two players yeah
i play this with you we both know it's
empty nine times three times three okay
it's n we both know if it's empty now
usually if it's a draw nobody wins is
zero if you win
let's say it's minus is max
infinity if i win
yeah it's negative infinity
the action yeah the action what a
reaction we can put a
cross or circle on the empty slot right
this is the action
utility when the game is when we
we when the game is ended we know if
it's a draw or something wins right
that's what it does the success you just
take a state
state
and the action and it will give you the
next one so for example if the first one
is the star state and then you say okay
is the agent's term to put across in the
middle then you need to tell me
okay you need to return to me a ball
with the cross in the middle and that's
and the next player is what is a
opponent okay
yeah
that'll be it for today
bye bye
bye