hello and today we're gonna talk about
nerds not exactly okay
hello mr eric hello mr ryan
hello mr teacher say hello
oh okay okay okay so so today we're
talking about the
linked list linked list
link link link list
link list so can you tell me what do you
think a link list will be
a list that's linked
it's another data structure so so
the link list consists of note
a linked note so each note
you can have a value yeah any type of
value
a value and then you also have a next
next pointer yeah pointing to another
one
yeah next
okay so you see this is going
so we can create a new note and then we
can put it into the chain
yeah so it's like uh
you know so it's like
you have a chain and then a note can be
linked to another note
and another note to another
so these these are the note
yeah and the connection is one way or
you
it can be that it can be this is called
a
singly singlet linked list because it's
pointing to
one location uh two to one direction
only
but if we add another one backwards yeah
we can also add another direction to
link it backwards like that yeah
yeah like that then that will be
double link double direction link
w double double link
list double double okay double the link
list okay
so so it's quite similar to
the list in python remember we use the
python here like
a numbers yeah we always use numbers and
we can put this
one two three right four yes
so this is the number this is called a
list
the thing is that in in python if you're
doing this in
and these numbers are stored in the
computer memory you know
computer memory yeah memory like a
memory continuously so you will be
so now this address will be
right there yeah yeah okay so now if you
put another number on it and then it
will be append at the end
right yeah okay so this is called a list
but we are using the single is the
link here and then this this notes in
memory could be
in different places so this this value
will be
some somewhere here and then link to
another place in memory
and a link to another place in memory
yeah so this
next is pointing to the next note okay
so why why what's the advantage of using
that
can you think of any advantage if
compared to this
you probably don't know because because
in lamps in in this list
computer allocate pre-allocate a space
continuous space like
10 elements to store these numbers yeah
if we if there's more than 10 elements
and if you want to
add another one so computer doesn't have
enough memory to hold these 10
numbers so what it does is you will find
another space which is more can hold
more than 10 elements and then you'll
copy all these numbers
to the new place just move it suppose
you have a table
but it's very small you put the five
toys on it
and then i give you another one toy i
want you to put it on the table right
you're running out of space on the table
so what do we do
so we find another big table and then
move these
five toys you know with that six toys
yeah yeah i have to get to the new new
table
so it takes time right it's sometimes so
sometimes this
uh if you append it in the worst case
the
time complexities oh and if running out
of space right
but these things there the the advantage
is that
no matter you can find a space
everywhere so
when you the term complexity to add a
new
add a new node to the end is a one yeah
we just
have to because the link never changed
we just have to allocate one and put it
to to obtain attach it to the end right
yes and then we but
so if you are given this head head of
the link
yeah it takes on time to travel
to travel in a linked list right yeah
because you have to start from the
beginning and then you follow one step
every time to find
the end okay
yeah okay so now let's let's try this
class
so so look link list
so link list we we have note yeah we
define a note yeah
so class why is class object templates
so it defines how we create new objects
class note see what's what's really
supposed to be missing yes and i will
define the constructor
of the class the first parameter is
usually safe
okay so it means that this this message
belongs to the class and i know that
the value means that we can hold any
type of value and then we can point
next no or just next yeah next and then
default by default if we not specify
anything we just specify it as a noun
default value because it's pointing to
nothing at the beginning
unless we specified what a note and then
we can say
we can add a self dot yeah we're using
this set selector value we
given a new attribute to value and then
save next
equals next okay
so let's see let's see defining the
class in python is very similar yeah you
just have
this class and this is constructed in
double uh underscore underscore in
initialization yeah initialization means
that when the
class is initialized is created
okay now we do this we allocate we
allocate two attributes
by given a parameter so so now we can
just do this
we can just know we can just like uh the
first node head
and we can say node we can just use it
node minus one okay
so it means that we create after this
we're creating a node
with the value minus one but the next
next pointer is none right because if
you yeah
because we we are not given anything the
second parameter and then d4 by before
is nine
p equals yeah
yeah so now we can define another one
called defined
at next x and and a node
and a node okay net self value
okay then we can say we if we enter node
so now what can we what what does it
mean
it means that we add a method and then
we allocate a create a new node and put
it to the
current node yeah know yeah we are we're
creating one right
now very oh yeah
and then self dot next
equals new node yeah we're appending
today
[Music]
so now if this it means that if we have
a node there
i have a node head and then we add a new
node
and what you create it will be i create
a millionaire one
for example and then i add it link to it
uh yeah i i i didn't link to it
[Music]
okay now if i write a problem and you
tell me what will be the output
okay so now if i have this head
head headphone head no
head node minus one okay equals
head node and then i have inches
if i have a four i
in range like 10
for example
[Music]
no i i i would write the program and
then you tell me what
what's the answer okay and then i can
say
if i have this uh uh p equals head
okay and then i can say p
e dot at the noun remember and now
i okay
and then this will return the next note
yeah and if i have say p
equals p at the next
note okay now after this then i can say
i can no no no let me say i say
p equals hat
okay why p is not long
print p
[Music]
so do you think what do you what's the
output of this problem
that's it minus
wow how do you know how do you know can
you tell me why
yes exactly that's the opponent well i
am after 10 but he doesn't do
10. yes obviously i
yeah exactly so first of all we have a
look at what it does is
first of all we create a node we have
created now which is minus one yeah
yeah minus one but we point into nothing
yet
and now we we save this p here right
p is pointing to at least and then p
at node i this will be 0 to
1 2 3 to 9 right yeah
what it does is every time i create a
note with this
value zero one two three yeah and i put
i put it here
this is now i i'm zero yeah and then
this p
at link to it and then p now moves to
here and then
one i create a node one and i link to it
and now p moves to here yeah so
eventually there will be a link
minus one zero one two three four
five yeah to nine okay and now
p equals hat head is here yeah p head is
here
p equals hat so p pointing to here and
now y p
is not reaching the end we put the p the
value so which is minus one
p equals p dot x and then move the p to
the next yeah
and then move it to the left window so
it just follows the linked list
follows the note in the linked list yeah
correct
what's the time complexity
yeah if this is n then that's our n
right okay because
we are following we are creating the sp
what's the space complexity
how much space do we need if that's n
then we'll be
on one and
and because we are we are obviously
allocating the space for each now so
let's all n
right yeah so let's take some
connectivity and uh time complexity is
also om
it always works yes so this is quite
interesting yeah you see this is another
data structure i created
a note a chain you can imagine that's a
chain yeah
and i link it together okay yeah link it
together
[Music]
okay okay okay so any questions so far
no say bye bye bye
[Music]
bye