go
hello
hello me celery mr rhino all right what
have we talked about last week uh last
lessons
what what have we talked about last
question just give me a keyword
again
and we talk about
game okay game series okay we talk about
a number halfling game yeah number
hovering given the number
given a number yeah you can subtract one
or you can divide it by two and whoever
gets to zero wins yeah and we also talk
about a quick center right
stick
tap
tick tick tock okay how hard it is
character detector okay
yeah yeah
we
we talked about again
terminologies yeah we have to talk about
some terminology the state yeah state
we have a star state
the state is the describes the current
status of the game like uh you know
what's the
state of the game yeah like who's who is
going to play next yeah starting
we talk about what we talk about
is end so this function will return if
the game can be continued around or not
right
so if the game has
has ended so if it's at zero usually we
give a zero to a game who is uh you know
nobody wins it's a draw okay and then
that time
yeah yeah because the number again
there's no draw right yeah
somebody has to wait for the number
however drawing okay no more hovering
game and then we have a utility function
utility function describes that
the whoever screen in the end game only
applies to that game right and then we
also have what
we also have what kind of elements so
stay
is end utility
and then success okay success
so given a state and a given action and
you need to tell
me come in the next state okay yeah can
you know what's around here and also we
have the action
reaction for the number huffling again
is the two only two action either you
divide or you
subtract right
so these are the basic elements what
else
what else
so
this is the two player zero something
two player yeah each turn each player
takes turn like i play one you play one
you know take turns
zero sum
somebody wins the other has to lose
right i win you lose you win i lose okay
yeah and then it has to be
everybody knows exactly the same
information on the board
on the on the game right so
it's not like a
pokemon right so i don't know what's on
your hand you don't know what's on my
hand but on the chest everybody knows
what's
yeah
share the same information exactly the
same
like number number hovering in the state
is the number
and who's playing next right
okay so today we just do a little bit
review and using these
these uh
five okay these five terminologies to
describe the tic-tac-toe okay
the detector first of all for the start
state what's the title star state
so how do we describe a secret top
i mean how do we describe a detector
um
so what's the top uh square
how many squares
okay so a t-tech sauce okay
so nice square three by three so we can
describe a title by a three by three
array right and then who's next who's
gonna play next uh so we have two
players yeah the first one we call the
agent and the other one is called
opponent right
yeah
okay so the state will be the
at the beginning
so at the beginning will be the empty so
we we can put a zero okay so we if we
put a zero it means it's empty it's not
occupied yet but
that would be confusing because
because
that's that's good but how do you put um
yeah i understand your point so let's
let's just use this here number zero two
means that not occupied not occupied
it's empty
zero with uh
that's in it like
yeah yeah that's that's okay that we
have many ways to describe it but if we
it's across
okay so let's say if we use one because
look usually we use the plus one to do
this agent an opponent we use the minus
one okay yeah because look remember y is
plus one minus one
we have this that we return the
infinity
if agent wins and if opponent wins we
return
minus infinity okay so look zlo means
the not occupied one means the agent
occupied yeah this is agent
yeah minus one means the opponent okay
of course as you said we can use them
just the character string yeah you if
you say okay
empty
is empty and then you put x
or color o this is also okay okay but we
use these just to make it simpler when
we want to calculate like
utility make sense
yeah okay so start staying
start date okay so let's just quickly
implement this okay class
tick tap tap okay ttt okay object
[Music]
this is the construction uh constructor
constructor is called when the object
when a tdt class initially is an object
okay it's a constructor what constructor
means c-o-n-s-t-r-u-c-d-o-r
field stuff yeah it's like look with
object templates
class we talk about this object-oriented
programming class
class is the object template
class is object template and we use the
object template to create objects so
when we create the object this init
function will be called
right so let's say class person class
human
object undefined in it and then we can
say eric equals
person
yeah and then
when we use the object template person
to create an object this function will
be called
so at the beginning
with these uh
this chord we we don't need uh we don't
actually need to pass any parameters
because these three by three this
tic-tac-top game is
it's a deterministic right it's there i
mean we know we all know what is a
detective game it's three by three
and then only
only the cross and centers so at the
beginning so we define a cell
let's say what do we want to call it
great
squares
square squares okay so let's call it
my t-square squares okay squares at the
beginning
zero
times three
and then four
underscore in range
okay so look we define a two dimensional
two dimensional array right
zero at the beginning we initialize the
squares to zero three rows
each one has three columns
and three elements three rows three
columns okay let's now be okay and then
we need to define uh
what uh define the star state okay star
state
[Music]
there so actually this would just
written a tatter attacker
is immutable array list yeah what's
immutable
you can choose it okay so return the
table first one is the player let's say
plus one is agent and then we want to
return a
state all right we cannot stay so
basically we want to return we don't
return this thing so i'm just going to
copy these here okay
okay so now start date we have started
we have implement start right and then
define we have uh
what do we have
we have what is end
so how do we how do we
how do we uh implement this extent is
end
how do we check if a game has ended
[Music]
okay so first of all we decouple the
state into player because this is a
couple yeah for the topper the player
and
and and uh actually okay so we know we
want to check what we want to check if
there are
what
if all
[Music]
right
that's right that's right yeah okay so
we want to find out if there are nine
all the squares are filled right so so
so we can say how how do we check it
okay so we can say look
i'm not going to write here okay it will
be too much
too much code here so we one easy way we
can just prove first because only three
times a week so we can say return
s zero
equals s zero zero
right come on
so first of all we want to check it out
first of all we want to check if all the
all the
squares are occupied so we want to check
if all the squares are occupied so which
one it
yeah
so one way we can do it is because look
we're using one and minus one let's
let's accumulate let's accumulate all
the values absolute values of the
of of the square so if we if the squares
are fully occupied the value should be
equals to what which number
uh
absolute value so i only just
nine where that so that's that's right
so first of all i want to
get the value so i can say okay so the
value sum
i can say some sum
a b x
so so i want to sum up each one so sum
up ah okay so let's say and then i need
to do this
sum uh
[Music]
sum x for x in r for
r in
this s okay
for i in s and for x now i want to sum
it
some days
some days needs to be if if if this is
nine then we depend two right obviously
okay
yeah we can do
right so we want to sum up all the
elements the absolute value we put
absolute value here because
we have minus one and we want to count
how many how many uh slots are occupied
so if the squares are four then all
of the number will be nine okay and now
if not and i can say i can check what if
so i have to say look out for
r in range three yeah we want to check
each
row
right each three rows
if
[Music]
so we go through each row and then if
if r0 equals r1
equals r2 okay so we want we just check
each element in each row
and then return to all right this this
is checking over and then we also need
to check the columns yeah check the
column remember we talked about how to
how to
transpose a metric yeah using the zip
function so we can just ship it yeah we
can say four
for r in
g
star s right so we ship it we transpose
it transparency and i this is the same
if we just copy here
and and then for how many diagonals we
need to check
two so we just we just follow that needs
to check if r0
if let's still 0 equals s11 equals s22
or if s02 equals s11 equals s
s2 0 land return 2 okay this is its n
okay
an action
how do we define the action
action action taking a state
uh
taking a state
taking the action so how do we take
action
so what's the action
action describes that what's the next
move for a player right yeah
so look action so as
first of all i need to decouple the
state player s equals state
yeah so now look i just need to do what
player my current player is player so
the next player is minus player yeah we
we negative we get the sign so currently
is the agent and that's right opponent
if the current player is opponent the
next agent will be the next player of
the agent
but the thing is that the action will be
the all
uh
unoccupied sloths right if it's an
occupy i can i can i can put a cross or
circle there right am right yeah
you can do
your team
yeah yeah i know for example now kind of
kind of stay is asian and the next one
is opponent so so but
for both agent and
opponent
they are also looking like they can
place
they can place either the
cross or circle in the unoccupied slot
right so so first of all i need to and
uh put in the
answer okay this is the list and i need
to go through
four okay i'm going to write it here for
for for r in registry for column
inventory if src
equal equals zero then we can append rc
okay we can see this is action
okay this is actually and what else star
stay is and
action and utility okay utility so how
do we
implement utility function utility only
uh
only applies to end game okay and state
so we first of all
we first of all need to
apparently take the state parameters and
we need to decouple it yeah so player
everybody come on
player s equals stay become a another
state so i want to assure this state is
ended so a third
a
cell
dot is n
this end s okay so now the game has to
be ended
right so it's empty now
so like utility
so if solar utility so so okay so this
this one if it's ended so now i need i
also need to
so
for
we also need a function to tell us who
wins right who wins right so this
function
so so the logic will be similar here so
you're looking for maybe we can reset a
little a little bit is n it's n
instead of return true or false we we
also return a number
even at zero it means a draw if it's one
it means the agent one if it's minus one
autonomy so this is basically yeah
so so basically we're going to use this
bit of code logic here this is a utility
function and the successor is actually
very genetic
generic
template okay successor
tear
takes a state
and takes a action and it just
it just returns the next state okay so
then player
we also need to decouple the state
and then
this retains the action yeah this uh
this is the action action would be
action would be
that what the action will be the the
pixel which coordinate which slots
you're going to place okay so then we
can just pretend we just say
this action action
and
action one
equal equal what equals to
play to play
current player okay column play and then
return
minus play player okay because current
player is agent the next one is minus
three and then we turn the new state
right
okay
so now in this case we just define the
take that token using these uh
side
terminologies the star stage is and
action
utility success success okay
yeah
any questions so far any questions
any questions too much noise
okay
okay come on yeah
okay that will be it for today
bye bye bye bye bye
okay okay you