oh hello
hello mr mr ryan hi ryan
okay we have been talking about tic tac
toe for two days yeah but we haven't
talked about
actually the strategy to play a
tic-tac-toe
game you know as a computer right so
human
as a human how do you play the title
come on if you want to play what's your
strategy
um you if you get to um
okay
okay so the agent is the we talk about
this agent and then the class is the
opponent okay
wait so it's
like every agent gets sick first yeah
okay so first possibility to win okay so
yeah
and then what's next okay so what's your
strategy right and then and then the
opponent either
put only camper around where yeah yeah
and then it doesn't really actually
matter okay so don't pick one come on
it's like you're playing different with
the right hand okay now you're playing
the cross so what are you going to put
here
[Music]
anyway
there's actually a big difference okay
look
this there's only one center it's like a
little bikini you have one center but
look this is the inner meter this is the
corner so which one you prefer the
corner or the middle
five middle five middle
you sure not the corner
corner corner is better right because
look you have two chances of winning
here but we start
with the cross remember we are playing
the opponent here
you only have one right because this one
is already broke right
there's no it's not possible for at
least to win that's uh but for if i put
it here
i might have two
two possibilities in the future if i
play in the middle
i only have one possibility why okay
i don't really like to win everything is
i just don't want the payment to win
okay that's a very interesting thought
you don't want the opponent to win i
don't like to win but you just don't
like opponent to win yes but then
okay yeah so that's kind of strategy yes
yes but that talk
you don't want the opponent to win that
means that you need to win sometimes
yeah yeah and the thing is i don't
really um i ideally go with winning i
normally focus on the employments um
well now okay yeah yeah that's very good
that's very creative that's good okay so
i understand okay so now there are two
strategies here so first of all is to
occupy the center because that gives us
more flexibility in the future for for
example if we put in the middle
then we have look enough we have how
many choice one two
three four four choice four possibility
in the future okay so as an opponent
then i will occupy the corner because
that gives us more
choice okay what's next
your cross you're paying me agent what's
next
ryan what would you put the next across
what would you put
i would put it on down
yeah yeah which one
um
where
where which one here
here or here or here yeah you only have
one two three four five six seven seven
choices pick one
bottom left corner okay what why is that
this is because you also have a chance
of winning but you're also blocking
where okay so that's what that's very
good so here
we have two choice of winning and we are
blocking this one right okay okay and
then what's next
there's a cup left
you put it in the
top right corner because
yeah because look if i don't put it then
i will lose yeah right that's very
obvious okay and then i'll cross
you put it in the top
yeah yeah again if i don't put it down
then i will lose right
okay and then obviously here right
if i don't put it loose i know what's
next
i'll put it in the
left yeah
right right right
why is that why why this world for this
one
because
it doesn't matter right it doesn't
matter at this point because they
yeah you have to put blocky there
otherwise you'll lose okay and then
if we play smart
intelligently the best result you can
get is the draw if you play with the
computer it's always a draw yeah there's
no chance you can win the computer
because this game is so small and then
possibilities
the number of possibilities we can just
compute
how many possibilities for this state if
we are talking about the state there are
there are how many squares are there
how many squares
um
nice square okay for nine squares each
one how many possibilities do we have
for this
one two three
how many possibilities for occupying the
state of each square
how many states
the cross the circle
there are three states for each one so
how many states are there for a grade
for for the t center
come on each one has three possibilities
so there are nine of them so what's the
the total number of states how many
three
three three so i multiplied seven three
to the power of nine right because each
one i have three
possibilities cross certain and
unoccupied so the number of the state is
3 to the power of 9. this is actually a
very small number okay i don't know but
it's a very small number
what's the power of 3 to the power of 9
okay
let me just calculate it what's the
power of three to the nine
huh what's the power of three to the
nine
three to the nine
is one six one one nine six eight three
okay so it's one nine six eight yeah
this is the total number of states yeah
so look this is so small that uh we can
just use the computer to prove using it
okay yeah
yeah we can just try each possibilities
and i know that
that's why this game is
i mean the best you can get is a
a a draw okay so
so to sum up the the strategy you follow
is what okay so let me write it down
okay so
first of all we prefer the meter
we found the meter if there is a center
available we prefer the center okay
the next one
is what
if
okay so the next one is what if
if the opponent is winning if the
opponent next winning is paid for uh us
by placing us
you know
in the squad then we need to occupy that
one right yeah so if opponent is winning
um
okay the thing is that look
so we probably should move this the
second to the first one right
right why why is that look if the
if the thing is that
okay so if the thing is that uh okay so
now
would you prefer the center on here
[Music]
so you see this this rules is not always
true right this is there's an exception
all right yeah there's an exception so
this is called the the rules so we we
can implement these rules this is kind
of strategy
which we can implement
that
we can implement the strategy as the
function rules so how does that work so
look like we can say okay
this is a tree this is a decision tree
we call it decision tree okay so we are
now then we can say okay
is center of variable is center
available
if yes then go play the center
complete the center
if not
if not then
okay then we place the inner center
placement and then the end okay at the
end if not then we can say okay is
corner available right if yes then we
place in the corner and otherwise
continue so this this this is kind of
like the
the graph the
the graph for you to implement the
strategy right so we just check each
condition and if yes we do this
corresponding action right we talk about
the actions yeah this is one kind of
thing okay so now uh
this is okay if the search state is
small it's a search noise uh searches
stay small and not
complicated but if uh you know the chess
ball yeah it's a chess ball they're
different
pieces
you know the chest
you know the chance
chest is eight times a right
yeah
there another few pieces yeah pieces
many pieces so the number of state is
bigger a lot bigger than the tic-tac-toe
for the title we only have two
two pieces but for the chest we harmony
check how many pieces we have a king
we have a queen
we have a you know chromes exactly
i don't know that maybe eight yeah look
and then it's only eight times eight
okay so i don't know if this layer a a
if there are eight pieces then each one
has eight states there on including an
occupied with nine let's say nine so
nine times what
nine times
nine to the power of
64. so that's a very big that's a very
big number which we can't prove us right
because this example is so big like even
using the latest computer we can't just
just exhaust it search everything every
possible situation right all right
yeah so we certainly need a more
intelligent algorithm okay so how can we
how can we represent these uh
this uh state in the search so i show
you we will talk about the scan tree
what does that mean
the game tree okay
a country okay so at the beginning
at the beginning
at the beginning we are here so we are
have empty ball yeah and people yeah
now okay so now
now the first layer is cross so for
cross there how many possibilities are
there come on
look this is a starting point nine okay
so i could place i could place
here
look i could place
here right i could place
here etcetera okay
okay and once this game
crosses peaking here so what's the next
another cross so where can i put the
cross i'll put a circle
these are available right so if i put it
here then the game will become
what yeah yeah i could play place here
so you become
you will become a yeah accessory yeah
you see what i mean yeah
yeah okay so so these will go wrong so
this one
on the first layer the cross
the second the next layer
yeah the next next turn
and the next turn cross etc so each
player takes them okay
yeah
expand text
okay so now how do we evaluate the state
right how do we view it so at some point
here look if we go here go here i need
some
if after
the death is nine
look because they only almost nine yeah
nice lot here look
if if it's somewhere here or can you
tell me what should i give it to
who is winning
who is winning here
x x x okay x is agent
and then this is
opponent
okay we talk about when x is winning
the utility function will give us
infinity
when this is winning
we give it negative infinity when this
is a draw so let's say we draw another
one which is the draw
which is somewhere something like that
okay i'm just
okay so for example
this is a draw right
so we give it a a score yellow okay
yeah so that so these are called
terminal states
because it's the leaf you know this is
like a tree yeah
we call it chemical yeah
what's three remember
yeah like entry
we talk about binary tree but here this
is not binary anymore because they look
how many states for each kid i mean how
many the maximum number of kids is nine
right for the first layer we have nine
kids nine possibilities so this is like
uh
the three with at most nine kids
but this the turbulent note
is that
is what it could be that nine
slots occupy or there's a some
somebody's winning utility function and
and state yeah so look we give a score
to each terminal leaves but so look if
if like say
x is winning uh at agent is the maximize
so
here
very come on this is very important we
top we
the x
x here x is looking for
to maximize the values here so let's say
x is maximized try to maximize maximize
and the opponent here is try to minimize
okay so look this now here
x is x uh x is playing a field right so
you will
i i as a
agent i would that the agent would like
to maximize get the maximize maximum
value of this we know
but here at this point then the opponent
yeah opponent is playing opponent is
is minimizing the values here so look i
i play one i make a move um i need to
choose the maximum value i can get from
this this
yeah this state
and then now i choose one one move and
then you
opponent yeah needs to play again and
you have a few
choice a few solutions a few moves next
and you want to pick the minimum
right so
don't get it
two player one is trying to maximize the
other one you try to minimize right
because we're saying when agent is
winning we give a
infinity score when opponent is winning
we give a negative score when it's a
draw we give a zero okay so let's
perfectly fit into this country right so
at each layer one is maximizing the
other one is minimizing okay and then
now we can we we can
let's say we we can do this okay and
then you need to tell me the score i
draw a tree and then you tell me
tell me what uh what's the score okay i
only give the terminal value
determine the value tell me the least
value okay let's say
i have a node
okay
yeah let's just simplify a little bit
okay another one
and this is this is kind of like binary
yeah
okay
okay let's say
two three five
six seven
one
zero
minus five minus two three
one minus five minus three
okay so now
here
i want to get the maximum here
and i want to get a minimum here
okay what's the minimum of two and three
two two
what's the mean five and six five okay
what's that now i'm here i want to get
the maximum of two and five five
okay you get it seven one minimum
one
zero and five minimum minus five
minus two three minus two one minus
three minus three and now
one and minus five meaning maximum
one
minus two minus three maximum
minus two okay and then now i want to
get the
what was next so this is to get the
maximum okay uh
so this this is to get the maximum of
this now and here that will be getting
the minimum okay so i need probably need
to draw one more layer so i want to get
the minimum here
which is minus two okay
yeah
yeah so in this this way the country who
wins
minus wins is
let's say let's uh this is zero let's
draw okay and then agent is this way
and an opponent is this way and then
it's minus two so it means that this
game is more preferable to to opponent
okay
yeah
make sense right this is like getting
cheap okay so we call it this trick we
call it
min max three
mean max country right because look
yeah one player takes the maximum value
the other player takes the minimum menu
and the maximum value minimum value
maximum value minimum right it's like a
the two player they they are they they
are
their
target is
stands against each other their
purpose is different you want to go to
the south
another one want to go to the north
yeah that's the way it is the agent
wants to go to the right the opponents
go to the left
the agent wants to go to the right
that's why he needs to look for the
maximum value of the of the notes
yeah and then
the minima wants to go to the right left
here so he will try to minimize the
value
minimize the weight okay so look yeah
make sense
okay now that we can we can implement
this using the can
uh
uh mean max algorithm okay let's
implement this
define
mean
max
the first of all we have a okay sale
function and then
stay we have a state
can i please
so we have a depth okay so the number of
the the depth of the tree look entry and
now we have which turn is it
yeah which turn is it
if it's trying to maximize or try to
minimize
okay now look
if
if cell stop is n okay we have a we also
have to pass the state okay can state
okay
if the c of r is n is n is terminal okay
somebody ended here
then we need to
return the evaluation this is the
terminal uh note now we need to give it
a score so we return the utility
function yeah remember your cdt function
it is functional state okay
that means that look we are getting yeah
this is the three countries and then
as here this is ended it's ending this
is the end state and state
now we need to evaluate it right we need
to evaluate remember we talked about
utility function this is only applies to
the end and states
okay and then now
we can do this then we can say if turn
yeah if 10 let's say
if
this is the
maximize it yeah if this is the agent we
are trying to maximize it
yeah maximize it
then we have a score here score we want
to maximize it so let's give it a uh
minus infinity okay minus infinity
measure infinity now we need to try for
action
action in save the action remember save
the actions
from the current state
so we are now doing the action and we
need to give a new state here new state
equals self.success okay i set the
success with the
central success with the current state
yeah and then look this success function
we talked about you given a stay and we
given an action and it will give me a
new state okay and remember this
function will return a copy of the state
okay so it doesn't modify this state it
will return instead it will return a new
state now we have a new state
then i i want to get a score right so i
will score new score
new score equal very good look yeah
look cells don't mean max okay now this
is the question according to
the tree we talk about trees one way to
traverse the tree is to do the recursion
mean
and then that's plus one right so we
have to go going down one more level and
a ten would be minus ten right because
now
look if 10 try to maximize so minus 10
will be try to minimize yeah
and understand will be new state
all right
look there's a p 4 here if you're trying
to modify the original state and here we
need to revert the changes but now we
are copying we retain a new copy of the
state and here will be new new score and
then a new state new score is a new
score bigger than the score right we
find a bigger score then we try to
replace it score
equals
new score
right and then
after return we can just return the
score okay
return let's go
okay as
this is quite similar look
if 10 this is maximized alright and here
what are we trying to do here this this
block of code is trying to maximize and
what's what's here
what's here what should i put here
the obviously try to minimize what i'm
we are trying to minimize here so it
will be the same
similar score instead of at the
beginning minus infinity we are giving
the maximum infinity
maximum and then look this is the same
for act in certain actions then this is
the same
but
here if new score needs to change we
need to change the sign it's smaller
than score and score equal neutral and
we tend to go okay
mean max function we can actually
separate this mean max into two
functions mean five min and five max so
look if tan
mean max now which
if this is maximized so this will be
minimized so instead of the same
function we just minimalize here right
and then in the minimize we change this
here call this function maximize
make sense yeah
so now i'm writing everything inside
this function this function mean max
depending on the parameter 10
right when the turn is agent
you try to maximize
when the turn
is opponent you try to minimize
we can get rid of this parameter and
instead
instead we can we can do what we can
we can call in the max function we call
the mean in the mean function we cannot
mix okay and now we look at this
function return the score we can add one
more thing to return which is the action
so which action takes you you need to
play which move which which store you
need to play
you need to place together explore so we
instead of writing retaining a single
function right written in a single
function we can return
we can return the action as well as a
tuple right
okay
yeah
so if we implement this
the computer
knows how to
exhausted all the possible moves and
then try to get a best move
that's why
this is the game the computer is perfect
and we can't beat it
right as i said because this game is so
small like like
when you play at the beginning yeah you
play using the left hand with the right
hand
the best outcome we can get is a draw
right
if you play this game
again against computer
the best result is a draw
yeah no matter who plays first yeah yeah
because it's so small right as i said 3
to the power of nine right this is so
small i can just exhausted using this mi
max look this is min max yeah so like a
middle would do what he's gonna stay
right and then he can just exhausted
search of possible moves
possible moves yeah
action is like a move possible move and
it finds the best move right
yeah
[Music]
because the num the maximum that's the
maximum that is nine right the maximum
death is nine okay
okay so one more one last thing is what
if this is the chess game right
yeah
this chest the search space is so big
right
so so
how do you play a chess
how do you play how do we play your
chess how do we play we play a tic
tackle do we need to think about our
opponent's move
yeah as i said
we think about it yeah if if we think
okay the components move is next and
your checkmate or your fighter can see
you know three three uh
cross in a row
then we need to
block it right
that's uh that's the thinking the chance
is the same i play one i make one more
you make one move i make another one you
make another one so that's the thinking
right so but but for the chess state
that the you know the the search ball is
so big
so
there's a if you keep thinking if you're
thinking the search base another tree
exponential growth exponential you can
always finish all the searches right you
can't finish it because it's so big so
in excess we can set the max limit to
the search so we call it that
that's
d p t h that's
limit search
we talked about that mentioned that
before right
that's limited what does it mean okay so
let's say let's stop when the country
is
is what is that
like i say
death six okay so what does it mean so i
make one move you make one move i make
another one you make another one i make
another one you make another one and
that's it stop
that's the agreement we're not we'll
look no further because this let's uh
it's too far in the future right so i
stopped i i set a high limit to stop at
death's limit at six then we will
shorten the time to search right do you
understand because look this tree maybe
grow so big you'll be spending time
somewhere like if i said how they mean
like okay i'm stopping here and i don't
care what happened in the future let's
call destiny search right yeah yeah
any questions so far today
what have you learned today all right
fine
what's the key word you can take away
today
which one
laymax what's new max
it's a what
it's a game tree so one layer is trying
to maximize it the other one is trying
to minimize it yeah
okay that'll be it for today good job
bye bye you want to do some dancing bye
bye
bye bye i can't see your face right bye
bye everybody i can see your face come
on stand up please
stand up please bye
[Music]
okay that's it bye bye