you go
how are we all right
yeah we talk about the games in the last
few days we talked about the tic-tac-toe
game we talked about the new max tree
yeah we met it's a country yeah so
what's
special about this country is what do
you still record any of those the game
tree the mean max what's mean max
[Music]
that's that's a very good answer yeah so
one tries to minimize it the other one
tries to maximize it okay so let's i'll
give a few numbers and then
let's discuss about this okay three five
six nine
okay so here
if we want to maximize at this level and
we want to minimize here
okay so i just give a portion of the
tree so
what value should i put here
okay you should put three
the maximum
five okay okay i put a knife here
yeah
okay so now okay so this is the
thing here come on listen come on come
on
so look if if the country is evaluated
from left to the right yeah from left to
right
okay look at this is the magic here left
to the right
okay this is five i know yeah but this
level we're trying to minimize yeah
all right yeah sure so now i have a
value five
so if this value is bigger than five
then this value will be less than five
that will be fine right
yeah make sense
so if this value
is smaller than five
if it's smaller than five
then the value will be smaller than five
all right the value yes did i say this
is x
okay
yeah
okay so now x
x
we know we already have a six here
yeah we already have a six here so we
want to get x maximum it's the
it's at least six i'm right so x is only
six
i'm right
make sense look
i i have i have found we have found the
value six here and at this level i'm
trying to maximize it so x is bigger or
equal than 6. make sense
yeah
x is bigger than equal than 6. and this
level we are trying to minimize it we
have 5 and we know x is bigger than six
what does this mean
so
does it really matter
the values here
does it really matter the values here
let's x is bigger than six
i know x is bigger than six right
so i don't need to visit this because i
know x is bigger than six
if x is bigger than 6 it can't be better
than 5 because we are trying to minimize
here
okay because look at this level
this value here
is the minimum of these two values
i
and now look it's the minimum of these
two values so it's minimum of five and x
but x is bigger than six
x is bigger than six
what does it mean
i have five now i have x x is bigger
than six right yeah
so i don't i don't have two i have to
visit this tree here
why is that it's because you know
[Music]
it's bigger than 6.
yeah
this this value x is bigger than 6. no
matter what value put it here right
yeah it put a hundred
then it's a bigger than hundred if at
least put the minus five
minus a hundred
this value is six
yeah
so if it
it's bigger than six so if it's a six
and i want to get a minimum of these two
i have five here
right so i don't care what what have
what value in these three these could be
a huge
this would be that this would be the tip
of iceberg
type of ice cream cookies
yeah i know another tip of iceberg what
does it mean
what is this meaning in english
[Music]
we don't need to
yeah so we don't the point is what we
don't have to visit these people
and you will save us time right
that we this is
one situation how about the other one
how about
let me just write another one and then
and you can tell me it's quite similar
okay
okay so let's see
we have values here alright right the
trees and trees the country evaluated
from left to the right okay and it
doesn't have to be binary tree
instead it could be many many depending
on
this is one one node is one game state
so one state you have a different
different moves right yeah
yeah but for example for the tic-tac-toe
you have uh
the branch vector could be nine why is
that
at most for the tic-tac-toe game because
there's nine squares nine squares yes
starting from the loot you have night
choice
you have night choice right yeah
okay so now we have
five six four uh five six
four five and then we are trying to
do the minimize here
yeah we are trying to do the minimize
and try to do the maximizing okay so
what's the mean here what's this really
five
okay
four
okay okay again again
again okay i'm trying to maximize here
so this is x
this is question mark
we're trying to minimize here so i know
there's a four so what's this value
four
actually
four less yeah four less
okay and i'm trying to maximize here if
it's four or less in the middle the most
is four right
yeah if it's most is four
we have five here
doesn't matter
it doesn't matter
so that's five yeah so what does it mean
so now i'm evaluating 3 from left to
right once i found this is 4
and i know this value is 5 here
right
[Music]
and
i don't need to evaluate this subtree
here do you understand that
yeah yeah
so this bit
i can just cut it
yeah do you mean do you know do you
understand let's cut it
so so if i cut it it means that we don't
need to travel yeah we don't need to
travel to it okay
right yeah
yeah
this this situation and the one i showed
you before yeah it's similar but
different right so this one look is
this one is x smaller than four that one
is actually bigger than what we still
remember x is bigger than nine right
yeah the previous one example yeah
uh quicker than 6 okay
yeah
okay so we we call this aggregate
we call it alpha beta puni
okay alpha beta
yeah
so it's an improved version of the min
max so it will save us time
so it's alpha
alpha
beta
the greek letters yeah other better
pruning so it's an improved version of
midnight that mean max we just exhausted
all the branches yeah one thing
exhausting yeah we the the first player
maximize the other one minimize and the
next one maximize minimize it takes time
right and now the other part happening
is just remember the gantry
we what we did is
what we stopped searching a branch
whenever we find it it's not
it's it's useless
to
traversa let's not try subtree why is
that because no matter
what's wrong yeah on that branch
you will never be better than the
current
okay so
we we can we can just add it in the min
max angle okay so let's write this mean
max first
you still remember me max yeah yesterday
that's yesterday okay so i skip the
sales so we have a state
we have a state
we have a steps default and we have uh
uh well we have a turn yeah so
instead of two let's make it uh so we
maximize it
we maximize it okay maximize
maximize it okay
yeah
so let me just slide it
so if okay if it's nd stay okay if the
state is is a end state if they
is n stay yeah it's terminal is the
terminal it's a leaf node right it's
lift now
i'm just writing the cup here it stays
the digital or if the state is the end
state then we can retain a score of it
yeah we can return the score which is
the utility function
utility function of state okay
now look if we are maximizing it if we
are maximizing it
then
we need to go through the action yeah we
have a current score okay so we have a
star
score equal maximizing it's a letter
beginning it will be the negative
infinity and we go through the actions
called action
actions
in fact actions okay we have seven
actions given the state and then this
action function will tell me what
possible moves in that okay so then
i will have a state yesterday the new
state
this is for yesterday new state equals
the successor
of the state
and then action
okay stay in action
and we are maximizing since we are
maximizing so uh
so
the current score the current
score equal as min max
min max new state
we are going we are going down we make
one move one is already plus one to do
this next level and then we are
maximizing in this one so the next one
will be
what
minimizing minimizing so would be if it
is maximizing okay then we say
minimizing its fault okay we can just
say four
okay and then now if
new
if current score
current score
is bigger than
score
this is the best doll so far and then
equals current score
and then return return here return score
okay
as is the minimizing okay this is quite
similar except that we change the sign
right we we are minimizing it so
we we we should i change this to two and
then current square should be
score right so now
so we we can make changes in here to
make it alpha beta okay so first thing
is to to we we need to pass to that
value which is alpha and beta okay so
alpha
alpha and beta okay
and at the beginning we're passing this
alpha beta will be like
this with this is window right it's it's
alpha basically it defines the left
boundary
beta is the right boundary yeah
so it's like a window so here here is
alpha alpha this is better at the
beginning we put give a parameter minus
negative and then
a positive negative opposite infinity
yeah at the beginning we give a value
meaning that the store will fall in in
this range
right
yeah so if we keep searching that then
we can
we can push
we can push these boundaries towards
each other we can keep updating it right
so if how do we keep updating it so we
we can do what we can um
first of all we can have this uh
so here here will be our
alpha will be maximum half of the value
so if i put it here okay alpha then i
can change alpha equal i will keep
updating because this is trying to
push you know
to only maximize it so alpha equals max
alpha
and then value value will be current
state current score
okay
alpha i got this
the thing is that if we keep updating
the other and then if the next one is is
smaller than the alpha what does it mean
so if i can say if here if uh if i can
if i if current score is smaller than
alpha then i i i can just quit that's
what because we are trying to maximize
here right we are trying to maximize it
so first of all let me just change it to
alpha beta
alphabet okay so here will be alphabet
so i'm trying to maximize so look we are
trying to maximize here okay
the maximum we're trying to maximize it
so look if
if the value yeah if the current score
is bigger than beta
then i can just break okay
okay i can just spray okay
and then return the score here return
the score this is the maximizing it
so so look we are trying to maximize it
and then if the current score is bigger
than the score we update a score right
but also we push the boundary the left
boundary of our boundary to the right
and so we are pushing the boundary but
in some point in some case the value
if the value is bigger it's bigger than
here
right if the value is here
outside the boundary so i then i can
just
break
break it right
this is the this is we call it the beta
pruning because it falls be on the right
hand right boundary of beta so we we
just stop it because there is no point
to keep searching in the vc all right
yeah
okay so the other the other case is
minimizing it right so this will be the
same except
if this is minimizing it let's say i if
i say if this is minimizing it
minimizing it okay minimizing it
score will be
the positive positive infinity
and then i will change this to two right
because the next one will be maximizing
it right
right and in current score is smaller
than the score i updated the
current score and then you look
here
we'll be minimizing it but instead of
alpha we need to
the mean equals
better equals mean better current score
right
and if
if a current score
uh if the current score is smaller than
alpha
smaller or smaller than alpha okay
actually boundary doesn't matter if you
put the equal let's be o should be okay
as well if alpha is square
smaller than other then we break it
within the
so what does it mean here if the score
force be
false on the left hand
that boundary the alpha right right
because we we are now at this case we
are minimizing it and we're pushing the
beta boundary to the left right i need
to value four speed on the left hand
side of the other
it means that we don't need to continue
right yeah
make sense
okay so this is if you're minimizing it
if you minimizing just
this mini magazines
okay
okay so any questions so far why are we
doing this why are we doing this
any question
so what did i what did they talk about
you talked about
[Music]
about the increase
uh yes and then today
yeah and then we are using this
technology yeah so so
uh it's the other better needs another
two parameter which we need to you know
pass past alpha beta alpha beta okay and
we at each round depending on whether we
are maximizing or minimizing we need to
keep update updating the boundary right
keep updating the boundary which is
other better otherwise less boundary
beta is the right boundary and once if
the value if the current score is either
false on the right on the left-hand side
of boundary or false on the right-hand
side of boundary then it means that
we can just stop searching in a branch
why is that remember if we talk about
that very well three five six nine three
five six nine
okay
so
can you tell me whether this one is uh
so here this is the five yeah we want to
get the maximum here right
and here would be
and then here would be the minimum
all right again again let's talk about
35 this is fine six
i know i got a i know this x value is at
least
at least bigger than equal than six yeah
yeah i don't i haven't explored this
this bit yet but i know
from here i said this value x
bigger or equal to six right
yeah if it's bigger or equal than six
because this level is trying to minimize
it we have a better value five here yeah
so it means that we don't need to
explore this
yeah because there's no point to
explore this it doesn't change the value
of this this uh learner here
eventually i want i want this value here
this value
is 5 i know i know how to feel this
value 5 without exploring it
makes sense
it doesn't change here it doesn't change
why is
that this is maximum five
here is six
i want to get the maximum so this value
x is bigger than equal than six right
if it's bigger or equal than six
it doesn't change the result of five
here because we got a better result a
better value five here this this is
looking for a minimum
make sense
yeah so look this value is bigger than
equal than six so these one
will be
terminated there's no point to keep
doing that right there's no point to
give them it means that this boundary is
what six
uh bigger than equal and six right so x
is bigger than equal and six
so we have a boundary
so we we try it's alpha which is the
beta
which one is the beta which is harder so
x is bigger than equal and six
yeah x is bigger than equal and six
huh yeah so
so i i think this is the right boundary
right because it's false on the right
boundary so let's not want to continue
okay
yeah
okay uh
so there's one
there's another thing to notice is that
you can break
you can put this break after
after the
updating the boundary or before updating
the boundary if we keep we're updating
after the boundary so the result this
whole result will be
that could be possible the value will be
outside
outside yeah the return value could be
outside the boundary so we call it fair
soft
if we
put this before updating the boundary
then the value return will be strictly
inside we call it fair heart
make sense so just this one better and
then
this if statement if statement is to
break to terminate right to terminate
right so if we switch the order that
will be
there will that will make a difference
right so sometimes the value will be you
so to visualize it is that you are here
right
yeah
so
even here if the result value is here
it's within this boundary that is fair
hard because you can't always go outside
but if you say okay let's
you move outside and then you realize
you're outside but you return this value
we call it fair soft make sense because
you're outside the boundary
right
you return that as a value right let's
say that's the difference okay let's
call it fast
fair soft
and then fair hard okay
okay
so this with this alpha beta which one
is better alpha beta or min max which
one is faster
better yeah we're done because we have a
state we have a check if it's four
people outside we just stop searching
and you will accelerate research
without these the same truth could be
huge could be enormous yeah
so it will take time yeah remember it'll
be like something like uh you know
so it's another techniques to to do uh
to to speed up the
searching
remember in the fibonacci number yeah
we use the cash to remember the values
we have calculated so we don't
calculate again and again right so
that's another technique to
to speed up the search right
make sense
so instead
this is a slightly different instead of
remembering the value for a note we just
discard it because we know
there is no point to exploring
that subtree
it doesn't change the
outcome
why do we need to spend time wasting
calculating spending time in the subtree
knowing that it doesn't change the
result
yeah
okay so what have you learned today
what's the most important takeaway you
take it
alphabet
okay can you explain to me can you
explain to me about these
um when you like reduce
the maximum of three and five and five
yeah okay now six nine six and
no matter what happened here six when
you visit six
yeah
um
it must be six or over yeah but then
since six is the minimum is six and six
is already over five so
so we know the minimum one bird
but overall um result is five
we're done yeah i know you know it yeah
keep practicing your
uh presentation skip i know you
understand okay that's it for today bye
bye
bye bye