go
hello mr mr ryan are you right
yeah we talked about a game series this
field that we talked about min max
max we talked about lego maps no no no
and we talked about other better pruning
yesterday
is basically this improvement of the
mean max max what's mean max it's a what
what's it what what about it the mean
max
you know
mean max yeah something on game three
yeah game three so for example this
player as a point of this player's view
is he's trying to maximize it for
example yeah maximize it
and then the other player takes them
this is two players years zero sum game
and he's trying to minimize it yeah for
example this is
10 a
11 and then if we we are minimizing at
this level so this will be eight and
then if this is the
six three four
if you're trying to minimize it there
will be three and then we and here we
are trying to maximize it there will be
a right
yeah
remember this
yeah and we talked about talk about
alpha beta what's alphabet happening
just a little bit um
review okay what's offered better to me
so what's the special what's the special
about alpha pedophilia
oh look
three even
so we are trying to
maximize five here yeah
this is maximized
and then
okay
okay so what's the value of here what's
the value of it
this is try to minimize it
yeah why why is that can anybody tell me
it's because yeah using if you use your
brain
why why why we don't need to calculate
these the values in this because we see
a six we say six so what's what's what's
this value this x here is what
x here is must be six or over x is
bigger than six over if this is six or
over and we're trying to get a minimum
five is the winner here so we don't care
anything
we don't care the values here right
because it's
uninteresting
it's uninteresting to us
make sense yeah
look this could be a huge sub tree here
and at this point because we're
evaluating the tree from that to the
right and we find the value six here
then we ask ourselves do we need to
continue searching here no why is that
because if this is 6
the parent value is trying to maximize
so these values must be 6 or over
if it is this value is 6 over and then
this value is trying to minimize this we
have a better value which is five
no matter what values here
these is six or over and then this will
be five okay this is alpha better
pruning right
so you will help us to
speed up the
the search yeah search on the trees okay
okay so let's uh go back to this min max
thing
so me maxine so
let me just quickly write write the
implementation of min max okay
define
mean
max so we have a
current state
we have a
dash and we have a turn okay so
sometimes we call it color okay turn
player whatever so
let's just try to uh maybe we can say
maximize it yeah
so this is basically a boolean value
here this is a pudding value
yeah indicating
if we are trying to maximize or minimize
the color
blue or red
or a player
agent or a poland okay so they're
playing against each other so this this
value boolean value is used to indicate
whether we are trying to maximize or
minimize in this case and these steps
we don't actually need to provide these
steps here but we are given we we
provide a depth value so that we don't
we can terminate earlier right so so if
we don't provide these steps then that
only the leaf nodes of the different you
know the kimchi might be so deep right
yeah
if you're playing a chest usually how
many moves before a checkmate
one
no no
for the tick tock tic-tac-toe yeah
how many moves
to
for for you know for a game of the
tic-tac-toe to be fully ended
usually
it needs to be
yeah i know but how many moves how many
turns the test how many times three
why is this three no six
six
what i'm asking is that in you know the
thickness of country
now listen up listen to the question
carefully this is country yeah this is
the loot yellow definitely zero
and then if i make a cross here yeah i
might make a cross
so i put it here and then the other
player
put a
circle here
yeah so usually how many moves before
this game is ended
yeah
if two players played
smartly intelligently
you're not a draw
[Music]
nine yes nine yeah because look this
game is so small and then if each player
each each player
is smart enough does not make stupid
mistakes and then the depth will be nine
right this is what i mean the depth will
be nice but for a chest
for a chest
maybe 30 moons smoke 40 or more and the
depths would be huge
considering branching factor you know
branching factor the branching factor
here is nine it's basically the maximum
number of kids for a state right because
i'm standing at the root
and i have uh
nine
kids
right
i have nine kids why is that if i'm at a
loser i have nine kids
because i have night choice to press the
to to put the cloth
make sense this is called branching
factor okay so if the branching factor
you're considering if the depth is huge
then the the search tree the search
space would be huge that's why we put a
depth limit that's
so for example if like let's say we we
only consider the steps up to maybe five
or six right
so one way you can put you can call this
function with the zero and then you
increase up to a maximum test which is
maybe six let me terminate or you can
you can give a value of six and any
decrement until zero then you you
evaluate it okay so let's know what the
depth is for okay
okay so now
at the beginning we just need to
evaluate it so we can say okay let's say
we keep a value from the positive depth
so if that's
equal equal to zero right
or the state is end state so its end
state
is end state
then with return
return
the value evaluate the score of the
i i want to put the equity here utility
function here but the utility function
only applies to unstate so let's change
it to return
the value evaluate score
of the state okay
okay right this is a
look if we are maximizing it
if this time this player is trying to
maximize then i have a score
which at the beginning i put it to minus
infinity okay
minus infinity and then i can say
for action
in action
action state okay action space so so the
action is like the kids of the state of
the
current node okay sometimes we call it
node and then you should be kids
children
right and then then score
will be equals the maximum we are trying
to maximize my score
and then we call this min max function
we met function state the new state
let's say we have a new state so that
would be the action new state
so that will be successor
of the action of the state
and the new uh
action
the depths will be let's say that will
be minus one right
and then maximizing if we are maximizing
it now the next turn will be minimizing
it okay simple final returns go
okay this is maximum and then we
minimizing is similar
so instead of
instead of
negative infinity
here is the positive infinity come on
and then for action
in
action
yeah this is the same come on can you
can you
can you see this part can you understand
this part come on
score
equals minimize okay we are trying we
are at now minimizing it right
mean max
and then this will be the same success
state
action
steps minus one
and look
we are minimizing it so the next turn
will be maximizing it okay so next time
i i need to put uh past the true here
right and then return score
okay
look this is the main max
midnight maximizing minimizing these two
parts
quite similar yeah
the only difference is what the score if
we are maximizing the initial score is
negative infinity if you are trying to
maximize it uh trying to minimize the
initial score is
maximum infinity yeah
make sense
right
and then
i mean that that's uh
can we improve this dude
one one problem of this implementation
can you pick a problem of this
implementation
what i'm saying is there anything you
don't like about this approach
anything
is there anything you don't like this
about this implementation i mean this
works but
come on be picky
which part you don't like it looks kinda
[Music]
looks kind of worse
yeah it's slow yeah yeah it's slow
obviously because we have you learn the
alpha beta pruning yeah that's a very
good point but what i'm saying is this
consider this and this
um
that's a lot of writing why is there a
lot of writing
you're quite close to the answer what i
want because
there is a list
because you have yeah
because you i
write
the same thing but the opposite again
well done okay that's exactly what
we are looking for similar thing the
same thing but the opposite yeah
this is kind of awkward right it's not
very simplified right it's kind of
you know tedious because these two
is similar it's just
as a different player this one this
player is trying to maximize it's trying
to minimize and we have to write two
parts yeah at least these two block of
code looks quite similar the logic
question you know everyone is trying to
make money i don't know right okay can
we
so today we're going to talk about
another approach which is called necroma
max megamax
megamax
to simplify these two branch okay
so what does it mean okay so look at
this
i if there are two values a and b
right
i want to get the two
the maximum of this value a and b come
on look at me look at here okay
yeah a and b two values i want to get a
maximum
it's equal to look to me minimize look i
put some negative sign here
minus a
minus b
[Music]
can we give an example like a equals 50
b equals 100 so what's this an answer
which is maximum
100 right
so it equals minus mean
minus 50
minus 100
so which one is smaller minus 50 or
my minus 100 and i put a sign minus
minus 100 which is 100.
okay this is the same thing okay
we can prove this more
you know
more precisely why is that look if a is
bigger than b
okay because look a max a and b if i say
a is bigger or equal than b okay so max
a b equals a
right now
if a is bigger than b if i put the
negative sign so minus a is smaller or
equal minus b right
yeah
yeah all right
so minus a is smaller than minus b i
want to get a minimum so it's minus a so
actually this one is minus a so i put
another a minus that would be
you know that will cancel out so you'll
be a it's the same thing so we just
prove it okay
so if look
[Music]
based on this then we can change this
how do we change this first of all let's
change the function okay
we have a color
megamax
okay
so stay we keep it that's we keep it
maximizing it
maximizing it we need to keep it
so we need to keep this maximizing it
maybe we do
okay so
this is the same yeah x equals zero or x
n is zero so we don't we don't need to
draw this
right but we keep this we can erase this
bit okay look we can erase this bit
so at the beginning score is
negative infinity and at least it's the
same now
now look
mega max mega max here
so
i just have to do what i just have to
put a sign here right put the sign
and that will be
that that will be it
yeah a little bit yeah do you understand
yeah
do you understand i think that will be
what did i just do
what did i just do eric
yes
what changes do i make to bring to uh
to make the min max into neck max
look it's simplified
yeah i just look as far as this snake as
this megamax is trying to maximize the
value right only the only difference is
that when i pass
when when i pass it to the next player i
put the sign negative
i put the side negative and not a lot of
b yeah
why is that as i said
if i want to max my a and b
this is the same thing as what if i put
us put a negative sign right yeah
yeah
so you'll be uh you'll be a lot simpler
right you'll be a lot simpler right
yeah which because now this one is
trying to maximize and then the other
one is trying to minimize as the other
player's point of view the the higher
value of this current score
yeah
is lower but it's it's lower it's it's
look
this is a
this is a line right okay so the higher
of this a okay if this a goes to the
right the higher value
is
further away from
from the other player right makes sense
look because this is two player takes
them right if if as uh the first player
the first player is trying to maximize
it so the first player is asian right
the higher value if i don't the score
is is goes to the right it's more
preferable for the agent
if it's more preferable to the agent
then
you'll be
less preferable for the
for the opponent right
but the thing is that this function is
all is always trying to maximize it so
how can i do this if it's next
so it's more higher then i put a sign
and as the other player's point of view
it's the same they do get it so this
function deals both cases
right
the higher value the better
yeah the higher value of the better
previously the min max
function the agent
agent trying to maximize
opponent trying to minimize
but now if i put a sign
so both players trying to maximize
but how how does that work why why is
that because because when i pass it to
the next one
a hundred will become minus 100 right
yeah i 100 is good for me it's bad for
you
because i put the sum minus and you
become minus 100.
right do you see this point i put a i
just put a negative sign this these here
i love it this one is trying to
trying to handle both cases okay
yeah and we
okay so can you tell me what's the steps
function test equals you know equals
what does it mean
what's this test
yes
why do we need this
[Music]
if we
if it's like
over
yeah over
it's a death limit that's limited
remember
this uh this third tree
i need to
go around the limited section yeah yeah
look i don't care what happens because
this tree might be huge yeah you go more
and more and more and there are lots of
to to do here but all i can do all with
my computer computational resources all
i can do is to search for the maximum
depth of four five six or whatever and i
said the hot
hot stock okay
yeah
make sense
okay
so
that's it
bye bye
bye
say bye-bye
[Music]