go
hello mr harry are you right
yeah we have talked about the games in
these few days we talked about a
two-player zero sum game we have two
player
to play a zero sum one takes i play i
make a move you make a move yeah i know
exactly what happened on
on the game and you know the same
exactly let's call two players zero some
game
i play to win yeah i win you lose yeah i
lose you win yeah let's do that
okay
is the pokemon car uh zero some game two
player
pokemon
that's poke
like that pokemon do you know
play poker cars
is there a two player zero sum game
is
you're not sure
i mean for the pokemon cards
to is it a two player
no
it could be many player multiplayer but
the thing is that
the player does not know i'm not playing
not really yeah so i play the podcast i
don't know what happened on your hand
yeah
so this is not a two-player zero-sum
game because
the play each player is
all the players do not share the same
kind of information right yeah
you don't know what's in my hand right
that's not to play zero something
we talk about the mean math
max
index is a kind of search agreement for
the in the game tree right so we have a
max
we have a tree yeah we have a three
again uh the note that would be each
note will be the state of the game in
each state
so one player is trying to maximizing it
the other one is trying to minimizing it
okay so it takes time right it takes
time
so for example this one is trying to
maximize this one try to minimize and
it's going to max mine minimizing
okay so main max
yeah i will also talk about the
the simplified implementation of mini
max which is called nega max yeah
megamax the problem of the min max is
what is that
in its implementation we have to
write the same bit of code twice right
so if maximizing we are trying to find
the max value
among each kid
and if it's minimizing you know we're
trying to
find the minimum value of the kit
and these two bits of codes are similar
it's just different
directions right so with the negative
max we're simplifying both scenarios
combining both scenarios in one function
without the
um
if statement if checked so the
so you just both cases will be trying to
maximize the value how how does it work
why is that because look if we want to
get the maximum
of a and b what does it equal
if we put a sign
minus a minus b
if we get the mean
and then b equal to the mean we put a
sign negative sign out
yeah
all right
is it all right let's say
so let's put the sign over minus 10
minus 20. so what's the minimum what is
20 minus
minus 20 is the minimum so minus 20 for
the two sign turns out that'll be 20
that's the thing we're looking for right
yeah this equation how does that how do
we prove that if we saying a is bigger
than equal to b right
max
max a b will be
a right yeah if we say a is bigger than
equal than b no max a b
and b is the same it's the same it's
still it still stands here
it's this thing right okay so if a
a is bigger or equal than b if i put a
negative put a sign look if i negate the
sign so minus a is smaller than minus b
okay
yeah because we change the sum we have
to change the sign changing the you know
change from bigger equal to less equal
right i know which
uh which one is smaller
this one obviously yeah
and then
if we put the negative sign in front of
b
a
yeah which is
exactly the same here
yeah okay we just move it
so relax max
simplify it so let's quickly write the
megamax and then we come coming back to
this other better premium because we
talked about alpha beta pruning but it's
still
we have to use the big if statement to
distinguish between two scenarios
okay i'm going to write the mean max
first mega man
connect max
we have a state
we have a tabs
we have
what
player
maximizing minimizing player agent
opponent
if d is zero if we reach
the depth yeah
or
the state is the end state it's end it's
the end state it's the leaf node
of the gantry
what's n state
and say what does this mean what's
insane
and
yeah and and what kind of scenario for
the tic-tac-toe game what's the answer
in the room or
um
so someone has wing someone has one or
is a draw so that is three kinds of
scenario yeah agent win we give a
positive infinity
opponent we give a negative infinity or
nobody wins we give a zero
yeah so we return
in this case we return a
score evaluation of heuristic score of
the state so let's say score
state
now we're trying to
because this is negan x so we can
combine both scenario into one we we set
the initial score to negative infinity
and i'm trying to maximize in both cases
for
action
in
action okay so for kids in the state
okay so this is the action would be
the actions
of the state yeah what's the next move
prosper and then the new state
news day would be
the successor success of the current
state this is
return a new state with the current
action
and then
score
equals maximum of score okay so this is
the magic and we talked about let's go
equals mathematician and we are trying
to go to go to the next round so which i
need to put the negative sign yeah
knacker max this is where the net net
max what's negative x
what's the negative yeah put a negative
sign and a new state and we pass in the
new state
and the test will be minus one yeah we
if we initially give a
d
depth the maximum test we can search the
tree we set the hard limit okay so this
is the game tree yeah this is the
country if we're saying okay okay we i'm
setting the hard limit
to step three so everything after
we just don't care for the moment
because of the limited resources well
once i got on the computer to play con
connect for
peter and then when i was like uh
just about yes
nearly like to plan to win and then and
then the competitive like
computers like kick me out the game why
is there they can put the kick kill out
again and then yes and then i guess
what's connect4 um is like
um this square and then drop um
control i i don't know what you talk
about um
well i'm not sure if you use different
color if you want them
okay so these are
slots here yeah well it's not exactly oh
yeah
well you dropped you drop these counters
in and it drops to the bottom
and then and then and then and then you
have and then and then you can put some
on top
and then you have to make four in a row
so is it the two player game you're
playing against the computer so you make
one move the computer make one move yeah
okay interesting maybe i can this is
like
i see okay
okay so the computer kick you out again
why is that i don't know i just
okay but i guess that's a different
reason okay
anyway
okay very interesting and i look it up
d minus one and then player player we
need to neglect as a player as well okay
okay so this is the net max so how about
if we what
how about we introduce the the alphabet
accordingly let's let's review a little
bit of beta okay
i say this is three this is five
and then if i have this six here if
we're trying to maximize here
yeah and then here's some something i
don't care
something i don't care if something i
don't care yeah okay i don't care here
so this is three five so i have five
here so we are minimizing here
minimizing it
okay so what's the value here
um
five
sorry why is that because this x is what
we are getting the maximum so x we find
the first kid is six so what does it
mean this note is
x is what people are equal and six right
yeah if x is bigger than equal to six
and we are getting the minimum in the
inspiration what does it mean here look
so this is bigger than six this is five
so what five is the winner
right
even we haven't explored this
yeah
we never explore that we don't care this
is uninteresting and interesting to us
right because it doesn't change the fact
that x is bigger or equal than six
look yeah so
so this is very useful you just
print it print it
so in order to prune this as much as
possible we need to okay so this is the
thinking right a question in order to
have this kind of thing we prefer to cut
up this
as much as we can so in order to do that
we need to
we need to search if we can order if we
can sort the these these the kids on the
same error so do we need to solve the
best
uh explore the best moves or the worst
moves first
yeah i know so in order to have this as
cut-off as not
as possible
it's better we
search we explore the trees with the
moves
that
is the best move first right
yeah am i right does it make sense yeah
yeah because look if i search this first
what happened
there is no cut off right it matters the
order of the
the order of the kids look i can i can i
can search these three this note first
or i can search this no first
right but if i search this no first
there will not be cut off you you can't
you can't promote right because you
don't know right
you don't know there's a five
that doesn't make sense
five comparing to this note
this is better
so i have to arrange the notes of the
same level
such that
the best moves
are export first
make sense
yeah why is that because if i install
the best move this is kind of best
better yeah good good move
yeah
yeah if i explore this first
like then i have more chance
to
to decide to cut it right we want that
because the higher chance to cut it
means that
you can be lazy yeah yeah yeah it could
be a bit quicker yeah exactly okay okay
so with this this is the other that
happened
so remember we we talked about alpha
beta pruning and we can implement it
using the min max yeah but the problem
is that you have to say if player is
maximizing then we do this bit of code
which is similar to minimizing it the
pro look
this is megamax
how is it compared to minimax come on
which one is better me max or megamax
why is that it's because you can
because what compared to if this is the
same as min max but it's the simple
the implementation is a lot simpler yeah
i don't have to check if
and you don't have to write a lot
wait
so first of all i need to
put uh to
to introduce alphabet opening i have
this other and better yeah
yeah alpha better other is basically the
left boundary
better is the right boundary
yeah
yeah everything out
will be trimmed you know the trim
yeah similar the meaning of the pruning
if it falls there it's like a fence
yeah yeah if it falls out of the left
window we cut it further the right
window we cut it yeah
okay so alpha beta so this is the same
yeah so we have to
to put uh to give two parameters of that
yeah
so first of all i have to
do this alpha will be equals max
alpha score okay we keep updating that
we keep pushing the up left boundary
okay look keep pushing the left boundary
at least and then if other is bigger
than beta
then we just cut up right we just
terminate the roof
okay so now look this is the same but in
order to to go to the next one we call
it alpha beta here
we have to update the alpha beta
boundary so what what values do i need
to give to the next one the new alpha
data value
can you guess
okay so alpha beta
the next round will be what
look i put this negative sign here so i
put everything negative
negative
it's a good letter
greek
looks quite similar to a but it's
actually not it's a greek letter quick
you know quick
quick
[Music]
and then put r
look alpha beta and then we'll pass the
the minus beta will be the new alpha
minus alpha will be new beta okay yeah
exactly yeah because look if you put a
sign
if we put a sign alpha is smaller than
even better if we put this line whatever
plus and then
minus alpha is bigger or equal to minus
beta right so this is the lower boundary
make sense
this becomes the
upper boundary yeah
did you get it look
one is smaller than 100
yeah
so minus 1
is bigger or equal than minus 100. you
see when you put a negative sign we have
to change this
yeah
make sense
okay so today we're learning uh so today
we learned what
um we just learned how to implement
the alpha beta in the next max right so
in the negative and we also talk about
the ordering of the moves the action
so in here action action so we have to
we can to introduce we can put a sorted
salty yeah
we can salted this
why is that
we can put the salty that moves
from the bed from the good moods to the
worst moons i mentioned it just five
minutes ago do you still remember
for the actions yeah remember the trees
i want to explore the trees with the
moon
back a good moon first
so why is that it's because you can
discard it later on yeah if i this is a
very good move right
if this is a very good move then there's
a higher chance that i don't need to
explore this
yeah but if this is
worse move
then i can't if i still need to explore
it right
make sense yeah so the ordering of the
moves uh
help a lot in the alpha beta tuning okay
so we mentioned this okay so today we so
okay so last question what have you
learned today
alpha beta this is the look this is the
alphabet
on the megamax right
yeah we talked about alphabet a few days
ago but we we have to
to
this theorem what i mean
implementation if player is maximizing
to this bit yeah
as do another bit
similar to yeah
it's pretty long yeah the trick is what
we put the negative sign here
everything is trying to maximize look
the score is always
negative infinity which is the smallest
number we can think of
and then because
when we change a player
yeah we change the player the score
needs to be negated right
a hundred score is good for me it's bad
for you right so when i pass the 100
score to the next one
in the perspective of you
it's like up minus 100. am i right
do you do get this point opposite
opposite yeah because 100 is good for me
right
so when i pass the score to you it's not
100 to you it's minus 100 because it's
good yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah so this is where the negative
comes from and then we just keep
passing the alpha beta boundary and then
in each round we keep updating the left
boundary until it hits the right
boundary then
we break okay
okay nobody today
say bye to people bye
bye bye
bye