hello hello mystery are you right yeah
okay so today we're given an array of
numbers real numbers
but we have uh even number of numbers in
this array so let's say 2 minus 1 3 4
minus 2 minus 3
so this is there are six numbers even
numbers even number of numbers and now
we have equal number of positive and
negative numbers so
so to put this involved we have n
positive number
and n
negative number okay
and we want to discuss is that
to a rearranging array such that
the positive and negative numbers are
interleaving so one positive one
negative one positive one negative any
sound is the positive
and also okay so the order of original
numbers are maintained for the positive
and negative so
here so we can rearrange the numbers
such as look
2 minus 1
and -2
minus 3 okay look
the order of the positive number is two
three four and then the new array will
be two three four the order of the
negative numbers minus one minus two
minus three and the order of mu the the
negative number in the origin in the new
array is minus one minus two minus eight
okay and they start with the positive
number and the each consecutive numbers
are different signs look two
plus minus plus minus plus minus
yeah
you are interested with
how do we do it
okay the question how do we do it
what's your in your mind how we
rearrange this
so if there are two kinds of numbers so
ideally what can we do a lobby without
it um so i
what can i do with it
so i just
find the first positive yeah first
positive
okay so let's say we have an array of
the same size but let's fill it with
zero at the beginning okay it doesn't
matter or any number it doesn't matter
so there are two four six numbers
okay so now
i give you a hint
if i say i have a pointer
which is the
positive i have another pointer which is
negative because the positive always
comes first so this is the
pointer p is the index value the points
to the
next positive number we are going to
put right this is not negative
okay so how how we have two pointers
yeah
yeah yeah
so i have i go through these numbers in
here two this is positive
so what should we do
so this is two so what happened what
should we do with the p
and we should
put it two
and two two spaces
[Music]
yeah and then and then and then you move
and two faces
and then we point
p equals p plus two four
yeah so we put it four and then it goes
out of scope but it doesn't matter
because we don't have any more positive
numbers minus two
yeah
let's see okay
what's the time complexity
and i need the number of elements what's
the space complexity
and yeah
we need this additional array to store
the numbers we can't modify the original
can we multiply directly here
not really yeah
because what why is it because look we
if we modify here then we need we
we lost the values in the future we
might go because we only we iterate the
number from the left to the right but
but the p the pointer may go faster
right
because it moves two space and then if
we move to space we need to change the
value here then we might lose the
original value yeah
make sense
okay so let's let's try this
define rearrange
and then let's land us
okay so let let's say
p is
the first element the index the pointer
the negative is the one the start from
the second element
and now we need this answer which is the
and
copy yeah
a copy of the numbers rearranged yeah
so let's say we can copy it from nums
we can we can use this syntax
to copy or we can use this
copy dot d copy
to make a deep copy
big copy is the column yeah clone
everything copy including the contents
[Music]
oh we can we can do this or we can do
this if the end uh we can do this we can
do this zero
times
length
nums this is another way to create a new
new array with the
values or zero okay this is a number so
okay
so now
now we have uh we will go through this
number for i in
numbers
right
if i is bigger than zero what happens
if i is bigger than zero now what should
we do
then we should put it in the first place
of a positive
so answer
what
p
equal our
you can figure out this
answer
and
equal sign
[Music]
next t o n okay
yeah that's one way yeah
easy two pointer thing yeah and now we
can do another one but
so these array yeah this array have uh n
positive number and negative number i
know ideally
so
ideally we need to divide this away into
two right
into two one positive one negative and
then we can combine we can pick one in
each right so if i i can find a way to
divide this answer into positive here
yeah
maintaining me away and then negative
and then i can pick one
for from each
and move this yeah this is another way
yeah
so how can we do this look we can do
this
okay so the positive we can do this that
positive equals
x
look
for
x in
numbers
if x bigger than zero yeah easy okay
that makes sense x i want to put x in
the positive this is a list this
complete enhancing comprehension
this is called this comprehension it
means that i create a list
and then i want to put an element x
and what's x actually it's in the
numbers
right in the original number but
x
there's another
condition which is x needs to bigger
than zero okay so what's negative
negative equals one come on
exactly the same but
x
uh
smaller than zero yeah
now i need to go through each one
look i have a partition
i have a position uh positive which is
this number i have a negative
if i put it this way
so what kind of function do you
remember
if we dip it then we'll take one animal
from each right
so then i can say for
x
in chip
positive
negative
and then i can say answer the append
open one i can say x yellow this is
positive and answer
a pen
x one which is negative yeah yeah
accent squeaky pen okay
if you don't write too you can also
write what you can call answer dot
extend extend takes another
array
and i can say
this is the array of x yellow
x one right this is also the same
right and then return
i want to take take
one positive take one negative and put
it in the open in the
on the right hand side apparently
remember that this opens to the right
yeah
okay so now we can have a better way to
do it okay
this is okay yeah textbook you know
using a for loop
we can do this we can do this one
we can do this uh
we can
so this this one partition negative we
can do this
nums
okay
start with zero
two column two
nums
one column two equals first
next and then return and written numbers
okay you might think this is
to understand this this is a total yeah
so what does it mean look yeah this
for example this array already equals 0
one two three four five okay this is a
list
a we know
we know we know this yeah
what's this mean
uh um
so look i here
so this is the list if
normally if we specify
uh index like one then you will tell me
which index there which value will
return single value right
yeah
if i sometimes you see this
yeah we see this
it means take
everything as a new copy it's a copy
here we talk about it
and if i say look from two to five what
does it mean
this is from right
wrong
this is true
yeah so
this is the same as range yeah another
range range two to five yeah parameters
do you still remember what what's the
third parameter of the range
step
star stop step so here if we have if we
have a
have two columns here so two columns
let's say
two columns so we can put the numbers
so we can put three parameters if we
don't put parameters then
if we don't put the first parameters the
first parameter is zero
if we don't put a second parameter the
second parameter is the
end
yeah it's still the end yeah
okay if we don't pull the third
parameter the third parameter is one
which means that equals one
right makes sense
so here means that start from the look
it doesn't have any the first parameter
so the first value is a zero it means
start from the first parameter look
from first parameter from first from
first element to the last element
because we don't have
we don't have these second
second parameter here so by default is
the n
the step is two so me what does it mean
it means
it means i take the first element
i start from the first element
i take
every i skip one element so i skip one
anime so here here here that's what we
mean and this one what does it mean
i take i start with the second element
and then i take i skip each element one
anime so look
this one this one this one
yeah
yeah what is this
so look this one the circle
equals the positive number
the triangle
the negative number makes sense
okay so
um
yeah so
so this is the same as look numbs
nothing nothing two is is actually
equals to zero and this will be the end
of it the end of uh lens nouns yeah we
can put a lens number here
and here is one and the second parameter
is now right
okay
yeah
so
okay this is array and i have uh
i comma j comma
k
okay can you tell me what's i was j was
and in
by default the values of it
i
am i is what
i is
the
star
star and by default if we don't give it
what's the value
what's the first value
zero the j is the
no no no k is the step j is
is say no it's like this
this this parameter isn't
it's not including that it's one element
plus right yeah look two five
you will get me give me the iterator of
two three four but not including five
yeah this is the same
j
yeah yes
by default it's the end of the if you
don't specify you will be the end of the
list iterator or whatever okay
by default
it is
well if we don't give it what's the step
for range two to five two three four
so what's the step one yes exactly so
now you understand when k is minus one
it's not reverse yeah yeah
got it one k is one minus one is the
inverse okay
and then k cannot be zero okay there's
no point if you put a zero step
yeah
listen yeah
it should be one positive or negative
but never zero okay
okay so
yeah two parts so this means that
i start from the first element i skip
every
skip one element each will be the
positive i will re-assign the positive
numbers
this one i start from the second element
i skip one anime each there will be no
negative number and then return the
numbers which one you think is the most
fancy one or
which one do you like
[Music]
which one
the last question which one
i like
um
do you think this is cool very cool i
like that one because
we're not gonna
[Music]
little bit bye bye
bye