hello
hello mr missouri are you all right okay
so we have this array real numbers
can you find the
index uh the numbers that's the left
side the sum of the left side equals the
sum of the right side
the earliest the smallest index
so let's say if i
zero
two and zero so what do you mean
so if i pick this number yeah
the sum of the
the numbers before these four is five
right
yeah the sum after on the right hand
side is
nine okay so this is not the index we're
looking for so any index that
the the sum of the that numbers on the
left equals the sum of the numbers on
the right so which is the index the
smallest index
yeah so what's the what's the sum on the
left nine what's the on the right
nine yeah so we're looking for zero one
two three so you need to tell me three
easy
get it
so this is the equivalent way we need to
find the smallest index the the earliest
index that the numbers on the left
sum
would be equals to the sum on on the for
the numbers on the right okay so look
there's one thing to notice here this
number excluding the sum yeah so if you
if you the index here we are not summing
we are not adding this we're excluding
this number on the left and normal right
it doesn't count this number right
okay
okay so this this approach what's the
what's uh
what's the what's the approach you think
in your first thing in your mind what's
the approach
you don't know what's the approach how
many possibilities do we have why do you
say hello
come on we are looking for the index so
how how many indexes are there poster
so that could be a approach two force
right
yeah so we can try each possible
number right
yeah we can try each possible number
okay let's do this
and then you need to think in mind
what's the term context okay
define like say index find
find index
numbers
okay then n equals lens numbers
okay then
for
i
in
range
and right
so what's the left what's the sum look
this is the number yeah this is the
number
uh two five zeros uh what's the number
okay two seven zero two five five
something like that so we're going
through the index for each one and if i
say this is the index i here
yeah
so what's the sum of that bit
this bit
sum
if this is l minus one numbers so up to
i minus 1
up yeah but we're up to i right yeah i
not including it right and what's this
bit
what's this bit sum
i plus 1 yeah i plus 1 i plus 1.
okay so we can just say if
some
number
up to i
equal equal
sum
numbers
i plus one
then we return i right yeah because
we're going from left to right so the
earliest we find is the smallest index
otherwise we'll determine minus one if
we can't find any right what's the time
complexity
[Music]
you sure one
square oh it's good why is that can you
tell me why he's always
[Music]
when you submit you need to go through
this yeah so look i try this index i
then i need to go through to some of the
numbers and then to something okay so
this is all n squared
so can we do better can we do better
obviously yeah otherwise there's no
point
yeah this is the proof of thing
everybody can
come up with it right yeah
so do you still remember this keyword
accumulate
accumulate let's say
okay let's say
2 5
0 5 2 2 or maybe 2 one
accumulate what's accumulate
accumulate we talk about this accumulate
is they look look
2 plus 2 4
2 plus 2 plus 1
is five yeah so it means that the sum
of the first i numbers so what's this
what's next
um five and then 10
14.
okay so now we have these so if let's
say
what's the sum of the all the numbers
here
oh what's the sum of all the numbers in
in in our way
uh it
uh what's all the numbers
come on we just have to look at the 14
yeah this is the number of the
of everything here
or we can just say sum sum all the
numbers this is total yeah
so
and these equals what this equals to
this accumulate this accumulate
numbers
and then
minus one right the last number is the
sum of everything right
okay so if we have these we can go
through this in one time right so what
why this is useful this is the core
prefix sum accumulate prefix sum yeah
prefix yeah so look if we are going from
here right we know it's 5 up to this
point is 5.
so we know this total is 14 right
so so look
yeah i know the total number is 14 and i
know the sum of the first three numbers
is
is what
is is 5. so what's the sum of the
the numbers up to the end what's this
bit
this is five what's the what what's the
sum of this bit
what's the sum of this bit
everything here is 14. here it's five
what's this bit what's the sum of this
speed this is one
sorry
right
nine nine yes fourteen minus five is
nine yeah okay so this is nine
so it means that this number here is
nine
right
plus ten plus twelve yeah
not this one i'm i'm saying okay okay
okay so now look if we have this number
we can so basically we have total this
is this we have
calculated total minus the prefix sum
is the on the right and this is the
right bit
but we have to get rid of this thing
first so so the prefix sum minus
minus this number if it's equals to
least sum then we tried it all right so
so look so put it this way put it this
way
so here we are here
uh so we are here we are here we are
here
the left fit is five right these the
first four numbers the sum of the first
four number is five
minus this the the the fourth number is
zero so the first three number is
five minus zero right
the the sum of the numbers next to the
on the right hand side of 0 is what
is 14 this is total number minus
minus 5
right
is it minus 5
14 minus
five
okay so this is nine okay so that's not
equal that's not equal so uh
let's know so
this is not the first example i give in
at the beginning right yeah you didn't i
think that's the problem okay let me
rewrite the example
two three two two two three four two
three four okay okay okay so yeah that's
not the same okay but but the principle
is the same okay two three four zero
five two two okay let's say let's just
do it okay
two three four
zero five two two okay and the
accumulation will be
two
five
nine nine fourteen
sixteen eighteen right this is
accumulated i came up to this one now we
are at these which we tried each poster
index and if we say we are here
right right here
so
this the prefix sum of the first the sum
of the first four number is nine yeah
yeah
and nine minus this number zero so that
would be the sum of the first three
number which is nine minus zero which is
nine this is the sum of the first three
numbers yeah
okay
the sum
of the
the sum of what the the sum of the these
these numbers
this number these are the the numbers on
the right yeah which is
18 right 18 minus 9 right
another it's it's 18
so this is the sum of the the numbers on
the right is 80 minus nine right yeah so
which is nine
right so look we have a match nine
equals nine so let's say this is three
make sense
yeah
yeah so look we just look it up so so
the previous example why is this slow
one squared because we have to calculate
the sum
yeah yeah
yeah but now we don't calculate
instead what what do we do
this one we just look it up right but
the the number on the right is just the
math subtraction i know the total
numbers the sum of the total numbers
i know this bit when i write i need to
speed so the the subtraction would be
the sum only right right
okay so let's do this
okay so let's say
okay so accumulate okay so let's say uh
total we can say total t
t equals sum of all the numbers yeah
first of all we get a number yeah
right and then the prefix okay let's say
p equals
okay let's put a zero at the beginning
and i'll tell you why okay zero plus
i put a zero at the beginning and at
least
accumulate accumulate
numbers
okay
so p we put the zero so
okay so what's the last value of this p
what's the last value of this p remember
accumulate what's the last value of that
[Music]
yeah so instead of looking we're going
through these ones we're going through
this twice so instead of that we can
just do it once then we can say t equals
p
minus one okay
that's our one improvement so instead of
going iterating the array twice we're
iterating once yeah because when we do
this accumulate
the last value is the sum and we get the
sum for free right we don't need to go
through again right
now then i can go through this uh index
for i in range
range length number
yeah because that we're going through
the numbers and then we just have to do
what we just have to do
we just have to do if if the
p
i
equal equal the total minus p i plus one
okay
what does it mean along with the 10 i
we can actually otherwise leave a minus
one okay
so what does it mean let's say
two three four
zero five two two again this example
yeah so the accumulated function would
be
two
five nine nine
fifteen sixteen eighteen okay look i put
the zero at the beginning i put a 0 at
the beginning from p
and i go through these i go through this
i over here
if p i equals t minus p i plus 1 right
okay so now i'm at here
t i t i minus one
it's not equal and i move to the next t
i
if p i which is two
p is what it's 18 yeah t is 18 which is
80 this is 18.
okay so
so look if i is at this point
yeah
zero one two three and i plus one is
also nine because eighteen minus
eighteen minus
minus nine equals nine right look p i is
nine
p i plus one is nine also nine t is
eighteen so look
then we found the match yeah now we're
doing ten i okay
the the
the reason we
we added zl at the beginning is that uh
why is that
because that it could be possible that
that's the
the
if it could be possible that if we start
from the first number and the numbers
the sum
before the first number is 0 because
there's no number before the first
number right
there
so
because the index when i is the first
zero it means the first number yeah the
first number so if it's the first number
then the numbers there's no numbers
before the first number so the sum is
zero so we have to capture these right
okay so what's the time complexity in
this case look
oh and
oh and why is there no one
why is it different than the previous
one
it's cause that you
um
so
this is our n now we put it up in a p
this is array and then look
p i
prefix sum
instead of calculating the sum we just
look it up that's a one constant right
do you see the difference
the previously previously what's the
previous one this one is what previous
one is what
sum
the numbers
up to i
i
this is one right
but instead i put it here i i do this
accumulating
so i only need to do this once and do i
need to change it i know no right i just
have to look it look it up right
okay this is one way okay another way
quite simple
is it quite simple i i i think
you'll be very very simple yeah quite
similar idea but instead of doing this
lookup we can just do this
we can just do this
it's quite similar here okay let's say
two three four
zero five two what's the total sum
what's the total
so the sum is 18 yes some numbers
when we do this sometimes what's the
time complexity we're going to it's
calculating all the the number the sum
of all numbers what's that oh oh and
yeah we're done because
you have to iterate over all the numbers
in order to find the sum yeah yeah
that's obviously if you don't visit the
number you don't know the sum right yeah
that's always okay so let's total number
is 18. okay
okay so that i have not left it
i have a writing
yeah right that is
is the t equals t equals 18.
okay so what's the first number
what's the first number no no okay
what's the first number
two okay
so two
so left left plus equals two okay plus
two
so what happened to the right
subshot two yeah yeah subtract two so
it's eight sixteen
okay i put a three
on the left
plus three equals five so i have i need
to remove three from the right so
basically you can think of these as the
left and right
left and right you move it move it so
what you increase the you put this
number you increase one number on the
left side so that needs to be taken out
from the right hand side
can you imagine
yeah
make sense
so look
plus 3 plus four plus and then plus four
which is what
nine yeah
and i need to get uh
that one subtract nine
uh
thirteen and now thirteen and now i need
to minus four
which is nine okay then i found the
match one left equals right i found it
makes sense
okay can you explain this method to me
again
can you explain this message to me
exactly perfect that's the perfect
explanation the right gives the number
to the left so the right the number
needs to be deducted from the sum of the
right it needs to be active to the left
right
so so
when i when i have a match
let's see
okay so so this is quite similar quite
similar to the second approach okay
okay so look
uh so right let's say right at the
beginning is the sum of all the numbers
yeah this is 010 right and then left
equals zero and the beginning is zero
right
let's equal zero okay
so now
for the index and the number yeah for i
see in numerator what's in numerator
come on
it is index and the value yeah we're
done index and the value
okay now
the right
needs to
minus equal c right we take a c out of
the sum of the right right
right and then if left equals right
that will turn i yeah this is the index
then otherwise left
plus equal see right
makes sense
yeah and then return minus one there
yeah you got it right look first of all
i take the c
the number from the right hand side
and then look there's a t-4 here so we
need to check before we add it so
why is that why we need to check it
before
okay two
why why is that because because one
because there's even a single number
like two
a single number if this is only single
number what's the sum sum is 2
right
right minus the first number is yellow
right and left is yellow so if look if
it's a single number the earliest index
is zero right
right any single number will happen
you have to do that
look any single number look
this is i the sum before the first
number is zero here this is zero on the
right is zero so any single number the
earliest index is zero so right look
so right minus equal the first number is
zero left equals zero if you if you do
this first what happened left plus
equals c then left will never be the
same as right make sense
yeah do you know if there's one single
number what happened if you write minus
equals c right is zero and then you give
it to the left
left is not yellow
left is two
so left is not equal to right
yeah you see the problem so that's why i
need to make sure left equals right you
get it
yeah look
only one single number the sum is two
right minus c
what what's the value on the right
right is nothing yellow
yeah what's the value of left at this
point no no i haven't got here
what's the value of that
nothing okay so we should return right
because look if the i is the index the
sum before the first number is yellow
the sum after the first number is there
okay
yeah if we add it to c then c
the left is two
right so you they will never meet then
we return minus one you get it
yeah what the time can brexit
come on what what what's the time to
next thing
right this is our one
this is our and we're going to inc i
saying that c is there okay
right we take this value
out of the right we check with the left
if can if it's the same
then we find it
right
yeah
why this is okay because we are not
we are not counting this number the
index the value at the index i
make sense
so
yeah and if this is not the case we will
move it to the right when we move it to
the right look we move it to the right i
i plus 1 i plus 2 when this is not the
case this is i minus 1 we move it to the
right and we need to add this number we
need to add this number
yeah we need to include it in the left
and then let's still on the right
yeah so we want to move it
when we move it we need to
first of all we need to erase this
from the right yeah but now we need to
check the left and right bits
right look we are not counting this
number we need to take it out we may not
and then we need to check the sum of
left and right if it's equal or not if
it's equal great we return otherwise
otherwise i need to include this number
to the left right
all right correct all right
yeah
that's it for today bye bye
bye bye come on
do sometimes and please
do sometimes
[Music]
bye bye