okay so what's binary tree we talk about
binary tree
yeah boy what's banner say come on
it's a tree tree okay
a tree which is fine that doesn't make
any sense come on boundary tree is a
binary tree
it's a data structure yeah that's the
point between here so
[Music]
it doesn't have any cycles
it's a graph it's like a structure it's
a graph
in it it doesn't have values in it but
that's fine so why which one yeah i
couldn't know a variable anyway and
what's the what's which one is the root
i have the top one okay i know rule
doesn't have any parents of it which
which no what the what are the notes
that doesn't happen in kids what do we
call it leave there
and
how many
no what's the maximum number of kids
that
knows in the binary you can okay you got
it yeah we're done okay zero
if it's zero then it's just a duct yeah
it's just not it's not it's not forming
a tree okay so my today is a tree but i
know there's a tree yeah it's kind of
it's a very special treat
what's parents if i said parents
financially what's it
like you get like this
[Music]
so can you write can you
say a very very ambalanced tree binomial
tree so it's a stream by another
it's a stick yeah
okay so it's a stick like that yeah okay
this is extremely unbalanced all this
way
okay
so can you draw a tree which is balanced
uh
yeah this is better okay so a final tree
is balanced if
the note if the height of it's left at
on right differs no more than one okay
so at any case at any note
the difference of a height in it's both
left and right tree is no more than one
for example
the depth the height yeah the height
so t that
minus t right
the absolute value is smaller or equal
than one for any node yeah what's what's
this absolute value
what's this absolute value remember
what's this
x
x axis
a b x x what's absolute minus b equals
one
yeah sorry
so look this is the
it's a line of numbers so in the middle
that's zero yeah this is infinity on the
left on the right
so absolute value is like the distance
to this zero okay so for positive
numbers
absolute x is x for the negative numbers
the absolute x is what
for the negative number
the absolute x equals one okay ryan
anybody
no no for like negative numbers
positive is absolute x equals x this is
the distance to here
if x is negative what's the distance to
here x x is negative
x
minus three what's minus three you say
three what's negative
x is minus three so what's the distance
to the
that zero yeah last thing what's x
what's less thing x is minus v so what's
what's that thing what's do you think
what's equal three
that's x
yeah what i'm saying if x is positive
this is x if x is negative so what's
this
[Music]
okay so you say positive version of x
yeah okay so x is minus
okay okay x is minus three so what x
equals the three come on
x equals minus 3 so what kind of x
positive what's that what's your idea
with uh you uh get rid of the negative
sign okay so what if i get rid of
negative sound so what should i do with
x
you shall
wha what should i put in the inner wrong
come on
negative
okay so that's what i'm looking for if x
is negative
absolute value of x equals minus x okay
okay
yeah so
so do you get this point yeah what's the
definition of the
balance binary
uh
balance what's what's the definition of
balance financially come on i was just
explaining
okay i i'm going to write a few balance
trying to show you and tell me okay
or if not in the video
making the house sir
at least uh parents financially no yes
no why is not yes of course this is you
see
yes this is two this is one right yes
over this
is this
yeah
how about it
any note if the left and the right it
differs by no more than one so what's
so if we look at the root
what's that yes i'm sorry
no why is that
come on don't guess yes okay i'm here
what's the
what's the depth of the left left
shoulder
including right one two three what's the
right subject
nothing okay so what's the difference
one
sorry how many no what's the depth of
the left sub three okay that's okay two
what's the test on the right subtree
nothing so what's the difference
what's the difference okay two so it's
not a balance
okay
okay one more the last last one
is
that's two that's one yes
okay okay that's it
so
okay so we first of all we we can what's
your approach i mean
what's our approach
of doing that
what's our approach of solving this
problem i mean we are we need to check
every node for the depths of the left
chop tree and the right substrate do you
still remember how do we get the uh
to the left sub the depth the height of
the
final tree yeah
do you still remember
define okay we use we can use the
first uh the
recursion
okay
look
okay can you complete this function come
on every line come on come on
[Music]
this this function returns the height
the depth of a
of a
tree with the root
so
if not root
will return what
come on
the height what's the height of it
an empty node what's the height height
the depth
this is one
this is one note one so this is two
this is three so empty
is what
is nothing what's nothing
yeah
[Music]
okay so now
we want to return the height okay so
return the height so if i know
what's the height of this knob of this
tree
three
one
one two three four yeah this is the
bigger okay so look so this we want to
this is the rule here
this is
ryan so what's this what's the height of
this bit
if this function is set
what's the height of this bit
yes so how do we call it if we have this
function to return the
the height of the this entire tree we
pass the root into the depth function
that will give us the height of the
these three so what's the height of the
left tree
what's the root of a left tree
death what
yeah
and what's the right
and what's the three of these whole big
okay so look at the left
equals depth
through
right
yeah
and then we should return what
pretend what now now the speed is left
now this speed the value is right
so what's the what's the value for this
note now
you should pick
which one
the what
what's what's the height of a tree
defined
most maximum okay so prevent
maximum
left
right and i need to press what
let's try to ask what
plus how many the test
[Music]
so we we know like the tree that the the
level the the the depth of the tree on
the left is left right is right
and if we have one more note what's the
level going to be
so plus zero one one okay why you plus
zero plus zero is nothing
e
so look we have this yeah
okay
so this is a useful function for us to
determine if the tree is the binary
balance
now we just have to keep please look if
this function is present yeah
so how do we check if it's balanced
if we are given this function
b a
okay so if the root is numb or if not
root
then we return true okay
if the empty node is balanced
okay then
if this tree is balanced
the left three
must be parents right
the right three must be balanced right
am i right
make sense yeah if that's true it's not
balanced then the entire tree is not
balanced am right do you agree
if right three is not balanced the
entire tree is not balanced
okay
so
then i can say we can
i need to say
is balance i call itself balance
is balance
right
[Music]
okay
these three needs to be balanced these
three needs to be balanced and
the depth
of the left and the right
is no more than one right
makes sense so at any point at any point
because we're calling itself at any
point at each note
at each note because look it's balance
is calling itself it's a recursion
right so we need to make sure every node
in terms of every node
then the depth of the left tree and the
right three
is no more than one the difference so we
need to put here
the depth
of root of left
uh
to the left yeah
and the depth of little y
minus test right smaller equal than one
okay smaller than one
yeah
the time complexity for this one
you tell me if
is it oh and or no or more come on look
i'm calling it i'm calling i i need to
check each note and for each note i need
to recursively call this function
to find out the the depth of the
left and the right tree so
so
one question for each note do we have to
visit how many times we waited one note
for example if i want to visit how many
times i will visit this note the last
term
one more than one to answer
[Music]
look here i'm calling this function
experience
because look it's balance new the left
we call it we definitely visit this
right and accept new left
definitely visit it
right so this complexity okay it's a
little bit out of scope because it's a
little bit complex okay it's all n log n
okay because this is the balance
you know usually
balance three
[Music]
the problem is what the problem is that
for each node we are calling this
function this will take another o and
turn in the worst case
right
you know we take another one time to
find out the depth for each note right
so this is the top-down dynamic top-down
recursion because
we
top down yeah we're starting from the
top down
for each note
i need to check
i need to check if the depth of the left
and right tree is no more than one and i
need to also need to call the recursion
to check if this subtree is uh balancing
okay so this is top down look i want to
find out if this loop the tree of
starting from is the balance tree right
yeah so then i need to go go down the
tree and to leave
to leave to find out if the tree is the
better so this is top down right yeah so
we can do better we can do better
so
so yeah look at this function here look
at this one here i'm talking about this
one here yeah just this function that's
yeah this function don't think
i'm not singing
okay
so look at that what's this thing to you
he's doing that
again
sorry
yeah cutting the tabs yeah okay so and
at any point if we we going from the to
the leaves yeah to the leaves
and then if we go up go from the bottle
to the up
in this direction how can we do it look
if
all i have to do is to add one thing
here
to check right so look
uh
if this function still does what it's
supposed to do to return the height of
the
the final tree right
but if at any point we find out look we
have already known the left and right
here
yeah if at any point we find out that
the difference between the left and
right is more than one
then we can we know
it's not a balanced binary tree right
because dependent explanation the
definition is that for each for every
node right for every node it has to be
it has to be satisfying that the depth
of the left and the right is no more
than one
yeah
so here
then we say if
absolute difference okay absolute value
abs
left
minus right
is bigger than one right so this is not
a balanced value so we need to set it
somewhere let's say self
the answer equals true we set it to true
and then we can set it to first here
seth
dot answer equals four okay
and then
and now we can just return self to
answer make sense
so so
yeah ryan do you understand right
okay
yeah so
so
what's the time complexity for this one
look if i just adding a check
here
if i'm just adding a check look what's
the difference the blue one the green
one
so this function is to get a checklist
yeah look look at this is the function
that's root and then it will be here and
here right
but at any point in terms of this the
understanding of the root and then now i
know
the left and the right three the depths
are left and right
and at any note because look at each
note this note each note will be visited
once and we at each note we know the
left and right
yeah
so even at that point the left and right
the difference is more than one now we
know it's not a balanced planetary and
we can set the flag somewhere serve the
answer yeah
okay
oh we can read oh can we we can rewrite
this function yeah we can rewrite this
function to return okay i'm not going to
explain it uh expand here if it's a
similar idea so we can return this
function for example to return
if the left tree is the balance tree
the tougher yeah between the topper the
left tree is balance and the left height
the height
[Music]
okay
if the when we return the height we
return it with balance three or no the
first value of the total the second
value is the height of the
height of the tree and we can return
these two values for the uh
so that will return
written one return a value uh
it's balance let's say it's balance b
and then that will be c okay
and then
and then here we can return return a b
as that minus y is smaller than equal
than one and the the second value of in
this cycle will be the height
right and then if not b then we turn
four
zero if not c then we don't return force
yeah okay so this is another similar
idea yeah
so and then we can return the test route
the first value which is
which is indicating if the tree is
balanced or not the second value of the
tupper will be the height the first
value will be
indicating if the tree is the balancer
right this is uh also okay
make sense
so which one you think is better
it's good you can remember the shorter
one
yeah
we talked about this before yeah
computer depth long long time ago in the
first
maybe 50 days
yeah
okay
let the time complexity for this one is
one okay
all right because each node is visited
only once
the space complexity is also open
because we are using the recursion right
this is kind of top down bottom up yeah
right because it will be originally n
which is yellow and then
and then you build up from the bottom up
right
make sense do you understand
yeah
okay let's say for today do some ending
please do something
ready steady go
are you okay
yes yeah
come on
bye bye
bye bye bye bye