[Music]
okay what do you call this a x squared
plus b x plus c equals zero well equated
a not equal to zero and b a b c are
unknown a constant yeah and x is the
only i know it's right yeah conservative
equation yeah
if a is zero it's not created it's a
line if a is zero
b thing is gone so b x plus c equals
zero let's let's align
a line if you draw it as a function it's
a line yeah yeah
if we place what what do we call it
what do we call it if we if we if we
plot the quadratic equation on a
x y
axis every important thing
yeah it would be something like that
it would be you know like that
or better
okay
so when a is facing up uh when a is uh
positive the whole thing is facing up
yeah it could be something like that
when a is negative
you'll be facing down right
well if if this graph intersects with
the x-axis
yeah we call it look if it's something
like area so we have two intersection
points that's the root let's then lose
the root of the equation so you have two
equations which is x1 equals 2 times a
minus b plus
b squared minus 4ac and the other one x2
equals
2 times a minus b minus
b squared minus 4ac okay so we we have
this we have uh
through these
in the previous video so i'm not going
to go into details this time
so look so in what cases we have this
line this particular line equation has
the intersection with x-axis
we look into this term yeah
yeah because the
square root of something yeah is
something that x needs to be bigger or
equal than zero right if it's negative
it doesn't have a real root what i'm
saying here is real root okay
real root
so this function
has imaginary root which is the other
topic okay so if x is bigger or equal
than zero here so b squared minus four
times ac needs to bigger or equal than
zero okay so one question if it's b b
square equals
minus four ac is equal to zero what
happened
if it's just one if if this term is zero
what happened
what happened what happened with the x1
x2
yeah we
uh if this is the same what happened
with x1 and x2
you'll be the same we're wrong so
you'll be less than
when we look at the graph in x y axis
what happens what happens when it's the
same
it will
it will be what
if these two points become one single
point what happened
what's this what what happened what
yeah yeah we're touching yeah this this
this thing will touch okay the equation
will touch wow
okay
okay okay and the symmetric axis
for the symmetric axis is what look look
look at this this this thing yeah
everybody look this thing if x1 here x2
here right
okay actually this is x2 this is x1
so look this is in the meter so
this meter thing is x equals minus
2 times a b over 2 times a look this is
the axis symmetric axis yeah because
look x1 x2
is
has the same distance close to this
x-axis yeah symmetric okay
this is symmetric axis
okay this is a conjecture yeah we talked
about this a long time ago okay this is
the mathematics
so now today we're going to talk about
this continuous
continual fraction
so what's what's this 1 plus 1 over one
plus one over one plus one over one plus
i'm going yeah what's the value of this
we don't know right it's hard it's hard
to look but look
if i said this whole thing to x
yeah
x equals 1 plus this right
okay so this is infinity it repeats
itself the pattern repeats itself okay
so look what's this bit
uh was this uh one plus
what's this big
one plus what's this
x
uh actually no no actually it's this bit
yeah
these bits
one okay x equals one plus this bit okay
this bit
yes because i set the whole thing to to
x
so this this thing
listen
is it
the same as x
yeah
okay so if i said this to x though x
equals 1 plus 1 over x
right
x is not equal to zero right obviously
right this thing is never going to be
zero if i times x
so that will be x square equals x plus
one
make sense
what's this function look
what's this function
x squared minus if i move the right
terms
terms from the right hand side to the
left-hand side
minus one equals zero okay
what's this
quadratic equation
quadratic equation a equals one
b equals minus one c equals minus one
okay so it has two roots right yes two
roots so x one equals two times a
minus b
plus
b squared minus 4ac
is b squared minus 4ac will be plus 4
okay the other the yellow root is the
same
but changing the sign okay 1 plus 4
right
1 minus square root of 5
is
negative right
square root of 5 is more than 1 am right
yeah because square root of four is two
right square root of five is two point
something
so look the x2 is smaller than zero
right
so is is this
a positive of negative number if you
look at this one
looks like looks like positive or
negative come on guess
do you see a negative sign here
somewhere no okay so is this positive
negative
yeah it's obviously possibility one plus
one plus look even this thing is so
small
yeah
this whole thing is bigger than zero
right
this whole thing is bigger than zero so
this whole thing is bigger than zero
plus one is also bigger than zero so
this is smaller than zero so means that
we don't use this so the value is this
one so which is two times one plus
square root of five
okay
yeah
what's this
what's the square root of five what's
the number of square root of five
what's the what's the value of square
root of five come on
so i i i think there's a minus sign here
okay uh
no it's not a minus sign okay two point
something
two point something yeah
okay what's the square root of two point
something i think it's something
let me
2.236 okay
so
plus one
and then divided by two
okay it's 1.618 okay so this value is
1.618
something what's this
golden ratio exactly what's golden ratio
remember
this whole thing
this whole thing is
one okay uh let's say this whole thing
is the
a a plus b the longer the longer this is
a okay and this is the shorter one which
is b
so
a plus b
divided by a is equals to a divided by b
okay i think so yeah
so if we
if a is one for example
if if b is one okay if b is one
okay so this a square equals a squared
equals a plus one a squared minus a
minus one equals zero
okay look this is the same thing here
okay
yeah 1.618 okay
so
uh
so if i change this one to two whatever
so let's say okay it's the same yeah so
instead of one i change it to two
so x equals two plus two over x right if
i times multiply x at the same time so x
squared
equals two x plus two
x squared minus two x minus two equals
zero so what's x
two times
a a is one yeah
b
my two times a
minus b okay two times a minus b
minus b is two
plus
minus b squared
plus 4 times ac which is
minus
b squared minus 4ac
okay what you're doing so this is a okay
so that would be 1 plus minus
okay square root of 12
is square root of 4 times 3
is 2 times square root of three okay so
if i divide it by two again that will be
square root of three okay so this one
this number
square root of three is one point seven
three two something yeah minus one yeah
uh
yeah
uh we use the plus yeah because it's
more than one if we minus it'll be
negative
so plus it will be two point three three
three uh
seven three two okay uh let me just
start the chair
let me just have a chat queen square
root of three
okay one point seven three two okay
so if i want you if we wanted you
to
calculate this using the python curve
yeah how do we do it
how do we do it
we can
let's say x equals one over one plus one
plus
okay
anything okay yeah
so define let's call it f
okay
so
n let's say
we call uh we want to iterate this n
time sometimes so look if
if n equal 0 then we just return we can
determine what
we can just return
if we're not iterating we can return
we can get rid of these that would be
0.5 right yeah one over one plus one
okay
okay oh we can keep this turn so one
over
one plus one zero point five yeah it's
the same
otherwise we return what we turn
return what
one looks
look 1
divided by
1 plus
1 plus 1 come on how do we do this
iteratively
how do we put this iterated one plus
f
m minus one right
come on you see this i want to kick you
at least basically
i want to calculate this
so n is the number of times we iterate
okay if n is zero then we just return
this bit yeah
this bit is 0.5 right 1 over 1 plus one
otherwise
i would i it's equals to look one
one point zero divided by one plus
little thing
okay so this whole thing
this whole thing
yeah one part this whole thing is f n
minus one right yeah
okay
do you get it
look this function f9 only depends on fn
minus one yeah fn minus one depends on
fn minus two so i i could i could put a
cache
here
but it doesn't
i mean doesn't really matter right
because in order to calculate n you need
to f n minus one and f and minus one is
called
each fm value is only called only used
once we're not using it
okay
so
look if we we want to we can we can pass
the parameters one here look this is one
right all right
so instead i could i could put another
parameter a
okay
and then this one i change it to a
here i change it to a
here i need to pass the a again right
come on look at me
and 1.0 look if i could read the list
1 over 1 plus so you'll be
a this will be a a divided by a plus
what a divided by a so would be one okay
it'll be like that and then if we if we
change this to a okay can this leads to
a
et cetera okay
we can do this iteratively yeah
it'll be easier to do this iteration how
can we do this
let's just write an announcement okay so
answer equal zero
four
underscore in
range
n
[Applause]
so now i just need to iterate how can i
iterate this
answer equals
what equals what
answer equals what a
divided by
a plus answer okay
that's it written answer
how how's that look i already have this
answer right so in the next iteration
i will be 8 divided by 8 plus answer
all right look at me why this is working
right
answer equals zero right
and an answer equals a minus a plus
answers look this is this bit is answer
yeah so in the next round i can use we
use the answer
in this a divided by a plus slab right
yeah
so
why why do we need to care about this
these values come on
why do we need to care about this on
this
do you know why
why
we want to calculate this value
yeah because this is a good
approximation if we keep doing that this
is approximation of
getting the value of square root of 5
here and this is getting the value of
square root of
3 okay
yeah
um yeah
so look
long long time ago yeah
we don't know the value of square root
of five how do you get how do you
approach me the square root of five how
do you calculate the square root of
three
how do you approximate
yeah we talked about this before yeah so
square root of 5
is
between four and
square root of nine nine yeah so it's
between two and three right yeah
it's already between two and three so i
can i can i can do this two plus
something
something square equals five okay
yeah
makes sense
so look this what's this 4 plus s square
plus 2 times a times b which is 4x
equals 5.
this is a very small path
so it's so small that we can ignore it
for now so let's ignore this term for
now so 4 plus 4 times x equals 5
x equals 1
0.25 right so x means 0.35 so we have a
good x estimation is
x is 0.25 so 2 plus x is 2.25 okay
this is the first estimation right now
we can keep iterating this yeah
anyway look
look at this one
a plus b
square what's this
what's the value of this
a plus b square remember equals a
squared
plus b squared
plus one
let's have a square plus b squared plus
what come on so c squared two times a b
come on we talked about this before yeah
yeah
so look
2 plus x
x is the part that comes with the you
know
is the square root of 5 yeah 2 plus x
squared equals 5 so equals 4 plus
s square plus 4 times x equals 5
but because x is a fraction part so it's
so small that we know it for now so x is
0.25 and we can keep iterating it so
let's say 2.25 plus x
square equals 5 right you see
yeah so again we can square root of
these square root of this and we get an
adjustment term for that and we can keep
iterating it until we get a good
approximation
but for this one
we can just iterate for a few times for
few rounds and then get a good
estimation of square root of five and
with this one we get a good estimation
of two right
yeah
do you get it yeah
any questions over any questions
come on any questions
look if we run this if we run this then
we'll be
uh that would be a very good estimation
okay
very good estimation of the square root
yeah
all right
that's it for today okay okay let me
show you
the thing on my computer
okay look we have this look
yeah we have implement list a f and g
if we call this function a hundred times
iterate times we got a very good
estimation okay
we get a very good estimation okay
that's it bye