hello hello hello sir miss lauren all
right
okay so what's graph
it's a graph okay graph is a collection
of the vertex and edges right
g
vertex and edges
so
can you guess what is a connected graph
what if
i say a graph is connected what does it
mean
anybody
the vertex yeah this is the
vertex anyway any idea
is this a connected graph
why is that because
yeah it's not connected yeah and how
about this one is it connected
yeah
this is a connected ground yeah and it
doesn't have cycle yeah so we can call
it a tree right
yeah directly a cyclic graph okay
it's not
it's it's not directed okay it's
undirected actually okay
okay so today given a graph which is
connected okay make sure we understand
this connected
and
and directional graph
and direct idyllic graph okay so this is
kinetic and directed graph uh connected
you know
i can do by has cycle somehow yeah you
can have a cycle
given this given uh
a graph how so how do we represent the
graph remember we have two ways of
representing which which one is the
adjacentness yeah
ryan are you all right yeah
adjacent this another one is adjacent
magic
these are the two ways to represent the
graph data structure using the computer
right adjacent is
so look at what adjacent is so we can
say
node one
links two two three four right so it
links two two three four no
no two
links to one six yeah so this key
yeah all right
key
keys are the note the values and the
list of vertex it connects to right
yep
yeah
okay so three
what should i put here
what you have here three
[Music]
and then six would be
two okay so this is called adjacent this
key how come who doesn't have three
we're done where wow that's a very good
spot yeah yeah you're right good job
adjacent is the keys are the vertex the
values are the list of the vertex it
connects to okay
yeah
the adjacent metric adjacent metric if
it's one two three four five then you'll
be
like that okay so if this you'll be
you'll be a magic yeah you'll be magic
so adjacent magic so let's say
one
one to two so
okay so if this is one one to two so
this
connects to two one two three one two
three
okay one two four here
two two one two two one
two six two six okay you got it so so
look if this is magic m i j
means manager means if the vertex i is
connected to vertical string okay so if
it's undirected
if undirected so which means that m i j
equals mji okay in a
you know adjacent metric
so
what happens if mij equals mji in in
this metric what happened
if mij equals mji so what does it mean
it's going to be one
it's going to be met with the diagonal
right
mij and ji so it means that it's
undirected block okay
because if the vertex one goes to three
also there's a way to go from vertex
three to vertex one okay
yeah
so today easy given a connected
undirected graph yeah we're using the
adjacent list for example
and then we're given this any node for
example
we want to clone
we know what's come on
clone what's going on what's this one
what does it mean chrome
copy
okay so when we talk about copy we have
two kinds of copy deep copy
or shallow copy yeah
deep copy
and shallow copy
we mentioned this before yeah what's big
copy what's yellow copy
what's the copy what's yellow
copy
is so what's deep and shallow d is d
angelic deep
shallow
so usually shallow copy is like you just
copy
the aliens aliens yeah alias
it just it doesn't actually copy
everything shallow copy uh deep copy
copies everything
yeah so it makes exactly the same
but a separate
but shallow copy
may not yeah sometimes it just
copies the alias and then if you
multiply
okay so let's say at least a equals
one two three
if b equals a
this is the shallow copy why is that so
it means that
okay one two three a points to here
and then b equals a b also points to
here okay
so if i say
a a0 changes to yellow
then b0 also changes to 0 because they
all points to the same copy right
but if i say the d copy then i can say b
equals a remember we talk about the list
comprehension we put a single column
or we can use the copy
library dot d copy
and that's the separate copy that in
that case
a will points to a one two three
b will also copy another one two three
so if you change a zero to zero
it doesn't affect the value of b right
because they are separate they are
different
right i'm right yes
got it so if i say okay eric i make a
copy of you
okay suppose brian you are like
exactly the same copy of
eric okay you are two indeed independent
copies
yeah
okay
you got it
yeah
yeah so so
you understand yeah you understand
what's the okay can you give me an
example of the shadow copy
for example you're standing in front of
a mirror instead you're standing in
front of the mirror
the copy in the mirror
is a shallow copy right
am i right
yeah yeah because if i touch you here
in the mirror
i also touch the one in the mirror yeah
cut it
yeah make sense but look if i touch it
ryan
i didn't touch you right
you are
independent individual you are deep copy
of each other
okay so today we're going to keep
copying a clone clone usually we mean is
a big copy all right we're going to
clone a graph
okay so remind me what how many ways of
we can traverse a graph
usually you know
or three remember we talked about this
again
two
from like 99 times
maybe more than that
what kind of
traversal what kind of
we're done question search transfer
search yeah we're going to do this okay
so today we're going to focus on
different search okay i know tomorrow
we're going to do this research okay
so look if we need to go out we want to
copy this
using different search okay now one i'm
here for that one here this is i copy
one
okay then he has he has a a list of
vertex connects two so i i will
i will clone
the
each node okay
yeah
i will close each note but using the
definition then i will connor
maybe i would go for two first and then
six first
yeah and then go back and go to three
and then go to four
go to five
okay but since this is undirected if you
all have three
you don't want to go back to one right
so in in that case how do we solve this
problem we don't want to revisit it
no book we're done using a
headset okay let's say we visited so
that's the
one important thing to
to when we do this definition perfect
search in the graph usually we need the
notebook yeah the hashtag to remember
the vertex we have visited on the right
otherwise we were coming going back yeah
we're going back in cycles yeah and then
it will never end all right
okay so let's quickly write this in a
little bit
so how do we define the notebook in
person
there are a few ways okay
define okay let's say clone
chrome graph
let's say we have a graph
uh
maybe we just say a vertex a node okay a
node
a node a note
so let's say we want to define
a clone here
we're given a note
so
we want to
this is the note we currently want to
know we only copy and we also need to
provide a parameter which is the hash
notebook right so the notes we we can
reference once we copy it
right so let's say we have a
memo okay remember at the beginning it's
a dictionary empty dictionary okay we
can move this memo here
we can move this mammal here it doesn't
it has no problem we can move it this
inside the scope of the local function
that's fine so if not note yeah if let's
not notice empty will just return
return
now okay
and then if the node has been visited
in memo
then we return
memo
node okay
yeah look
if this note we have been
visited in the memo we return it all
right we create a copy here we have this
cloned copy let's say we just say
copy okay this is a copy
which is node
and then we are currently copying this
node so now the value
okay
and then the second parameter is the
the neighbors the list of the vertex it
connects to adjacent lists yeah so at
the beginning is empty here
now this is the key part here once we
have this copy we need to
put it in a
visited step we need to remember it
right
yeah otherwise you come come up we need
to come back again and then we don't
want that right so let's say we need to
put it in uh
put it in a
notebook
note equals copy okay we remember it
and then we just we
look
here we are in this node here
and then we have a list of nodes
we copy these nodes so now we we want to
copy which nodes
all the other nodes connected to it yeah
all the vertices connects to it so then
we can say copy
stop let's say neighbors yeah neighbors
how do you spell neighbors
n e i g
h b
r
b-o-r-o-b-o-u-f i think one is american
okay
[Music]
english british english poi is the
american issue okay
neighbors equals then we don't
copy all the neighbors then we can say
clone
calling this function clone yeah
recursion clone
x
for x in
in know the neighbors yeah
okay this is the trick here
a line return copy return copy
and now we can just return
clone
note
okay
yeah look
can we use the cache function remember
we we
when we do this dynamic programming we
usually put a cache here right yeah
if we put a cache here what does it mean
it actually means that before this
function
is returning the value
we need to put it in the memory so
basically you'll be putting here right
yeah there's a difference look if we put
a cache here it actually means the
moving this line to here before before
returning
right
all right
then that's a problem why is that
okay look there's a problem so this
doesn't work why is that it doesn't work
okay this doesn't work
so
why we need to
save it
right after we create a node we love
copying the neighbors
right so look
we are here means that we have just
copied these without copying the
neighbors
now we put it in the visited set or
immediately before we copy in the
neighbors yeah
if if i move it after then there'll be a
problem
there will be problem look if i move
this
after the copying
after
the neighbors are copied
there will be a problem
can you tell me why
if i move this
move like copy
move the segment in
yeah
move it move these
right after the neighbors called
neighbors are copies there will not be a
problem why is that look
okay let's say
here yeah that's one two
three
yeah look i copy one
yeah the neighbors are two and three
now if i haven't saved it i if i wait
for two and three
to be
copied
clone
and then i put it in a
visited in the memo
then
there will be cycle why is that look
because two
if you want to copy two you need to copy
one and three but look one relies on two
two lies on one
so that would be your problem why is
that i wait for you to finish and then
you again wait for me to finish
so there will be never ending
there will be never ending do you get it
because one said one
the vertex one says okay
let's copy two and three and after two
and three copy i'll copy acron and i am
mark as
i can mark one
has been seen i've been visited
but when he when he needs to copy two
then two will say okay i want to copy
two now let's let's wait until one and
three are finished
but the thing is the one needs to wait
for two and two says okay i need to wait
for one
what does that mean
they're just waiting for nothing yeah
everything you say okay wait and ryan i
wait until you
finish
the play
playing uh yeah playing games
and ryan you say
okay
eric i wait until you finish homework
right
yeah and then you you say aaron you said
okay i i i start homework before uh uh
after you i played again so there will
be cycle that will be your cycle right
and the recycle
yeah
okay so now to how to break this cycle
then i can say okay i start with copy
one right
okay i'm not waiting for two and three
and i say okay one is visited
it's visited even i haven't copied
actually copy the content of two and
three
right so when two
is visited yeah two is visited and then
you'll check okay one
i always i check one i need one to be
cloned
but one already been marked as
visited so that's okay he doesn't go
back again
so there's no cycle right
so here we don't use the cash because
using the cash it will be eventually the
same as moving this
before right before
the content the the right value is
recurrence this variable okay
yeah
hold on look look at this
what's this copy the neighbors equals
clone which part is the recursion can
you point it out
which part is the question that
yeah yeah calling itself come on
yeah clone x what's x x is in the note
neighbor so i want to clone the
neighbors
i want to clone everything in the
neighbors okay yeah yeah
this
what's this definitely your preferences
yeah using the publication yeah
therefore search okay the time
complexity is one
if the n vertex and m edges the clone
can make this element
no no no
yeah and all present and vertex and
logic
and vertex
m edges okay
okay yeah that's it do some endings
okay that's it for today bye