hello okay hello eric and brian
okay hello okay please
today i'm going to talk about the data
structure called stack
do you know stack
can anyone describe what is the stack
it's a tower it's a towel can you draw
it somewhere
color okay
eric you want to draw
tower okay and lots of things yeah
yesterday
um loads of houses windows
okay yeah yeah yeah okay
okay let's that's why it was mean by
state yeah
okay similar similar so a stack is uh
it's uh it's probably simply a stack is
the data structure we call it data
structure
data structure so data structure is
is a kind of structure to hold data yeah
to hold data
so this stack is actually it's it's
quite similar to what you have
put here but it's like it's an
a list it's a it's uh
so so for example like if you put a
plate
yeah you can put a bigger plate yeah
put a big plate
[Music]
okay okay you do a better job okay
coward okay okay come
yes yes okay so the point here is
i put a plate on top of each other but i
every time i want to take a play which
played i take the first
the top one right yes i cannot take
these
right without taking these and that yeah
yeah
okay so so so this is one property of uh
one important one important thing about
a step is
is what first thing
first in last out
okay we call it
first thing you have now the plate look
you put the plate you put this plate
first you put the second plate you put
the third plate when you take it out you
take the three first
and then you take the second you take it
the second
and then the last take you take the one
out okay
okay so the first thing lasts off so in
person
in person we can do this we can do this
like let's let's let's call it
let's call it what plate okay let's call
it plate
plate when we define what we can do
equals what a bracket yeah
empty so first of all it's empty okay
so now what i want to do is i want to
put one plate first
so plate stop
append yeah
what's the meaning of a pen describe
append describe a pen
no yes it's quite open what's it what
does it mean
to put something yeah put something at
the end
okay so what does it what does it mean
here so one is
one is when a statement gets executed
ryan ryan listen eric
these plates will contain one
okay okay and then after this place
dot a pen
two now what will it happen it will put
this
two at the end of the this data
structure yeah
two okay and then again i can put this
three
and then what happened it will become a
okay now this is interesting part how
about i do this
play stop pop
so what do you think pop and then i get
the x
i assign it to x so what do you think
what happened
what do you think what happened here pop
a pen pop pop is like to take it out so
what happens they
will damage you take
the biggest number out no no first thing
that's all
first thing that's off so i i put it
first one
two three so this one is the first thing
in right yeah so it should be the last
style so what should be coming
in first sit down otherwise three three
yes good job so x
will become three left one
and look look like eric i
think it's pop what is the meaning of
pop
take out okay so this will be gone
okay and x will be three okay
yeah so then let's try again place
[Music]
the append four
what happened what happened
you put the four leg yeah you put four
here
okay all right
and then again i thought this y equals
place
the pop
after this okay why because playing
support what happened
y equals place the pop so what happened
now
the y is four y
is four yeah we're done and this will be
erased from the
stack right from the plate got it
yeah so if you keep doing that then the
next element to take out is two
yeah and the next element to get cut out
is one so next functions to c
to to check how many elements are in the
plate
in the stack do you know what it is why
do you have lens number four
length yeah we call it lens stands from
lens yeah you know the word lens
yes length is the size okay so length of
this plate
now it will become two right
yes okay okay so do you know
how about if you want to reverse a
list how do we do it reverse it
we can use this first in lassa okay
yeah look let's let's call this
define reverse okay
yeah say properly please reverse
[Music]
reverse let's let's for example numbers
at least the numbers okay the llamas
okay yeah so how do we do it
how do we do it it's numbers already i
know we want to reverse it
okay then we can do this let's call it
the
reverse is in the answer okay answer is
a list
okay so now what we can do
y length
numbers
is bigger than zero yeah even less
element in the list
what do we do we we
we take a value from the end from from
the end yeah from the
end which is lambs the pop am right
look now we take this for example the
numbers is one two three okay
now length lumps is three right
three is bigger than zero we pop it so
we take these three
make it one two and x is three right
then we do this answer dot append we
append it to this right
okay x and then it goes
long and the next one is two and then
the next answer will be three two and
the next one is one
three two one and then return what
written one we want to write down
x return x no no no
what we have to written answer we're
done okay
so do you get it does it make sense
yes so today's you need to remember
the step is first thing now
or we refer it as f i l
o what do you have to do and look
we are creating a list and then we pop
it we check these numbers we pop it
when it's not empty we pop it we take
one animal from the end and then we
append it to the other list
and we return this okay and do we want
to put it in the computer
okay good job today