hello hello hello hello mr erwin hello
mr
brian hello hello this is
mr teacher hello teacher welcome hello
hello hello sit down properly yeah sit
down properly i think that's okay i
don't need to turn me off yes
that's okay but then we can't see very
properly it's okay it's okay
it's okay it's okay yeah okay sit down
okay
so remember yesterday we talked about
the link list
the link
so remember the chain yeah we have a
note
then we have a value one for possibly i
will point it to the next one
yeah and the points to next one
okay and then it's etcetera etcetera
okay so suppose there are lots of them
you just see yeah yeah so if you are
given
so today if you're given uh the head
normally you say the head of the link
list
think i just keep thinking you said cat
head and then look at the last last note
does not have a next pointer so his next
will be
num right his next will be now so can
you tell me
how how to find the meter of it meter so
today will be
meter of the increase meter of the hour
can you think of a way let uh how it
uh how we compute the middle of the
linked list
no i will just check here
yeah any any thoughts like if we
if you are only given the head of the
head of the uh of the linked list
and then you you how do you get these
oh yeah oh yeah you just see one two
three four five
and what's the last one like yes
the last one is five and the first one
is one
you have one at five and you divided by
two right
yep
[Music]
but you don't know how many are they all
right yeah you need to count them
yeah yeah okay so yeah you're given
then the first one and then last one
and then you add them together then you
divide by two
add them together okay so i uh
i think your idea is to go through these
lists once and find out how many notes
yeah and then for example if i turn
those and then you know 10 divided by
2 is 5 then you can get it right
yeah you can follow and you can go
another time yeah either way another
times and then you you'll find a meter
yeah that's a great great idea yes
do you get it no so there are links you
want to find the meter first of all you
can go through once
and find out how many nodes are there in
a linked list and once you've got the
number you can you know
half of it right which is the middle and
then you go another time
which is the middle of the increase
yeah so do you have a better idea i mean
so
this you need to go through this the
linked list twice
right because first of all you need to
first time you need to go through these
once final how many notes and then you
go through the second
yeah so you need to go 1.5 times
the banana no no no okay so
we just need to divide by two yeah
that's a good solution
but we can do better how can we do that
so we have
two pointers we can have two one is fast
the other is slow
no solo every time they are this one is
twice as fast as this one
and this one when they reach the end
this very one was
yes look this fast will be like a rabbit
the slow will be
taller and the rabbit is twice as fast
as tortoise
so look if this right hand is total and
what left hand is
a little bit so like look okay
yeah like the knees knees twice yes yes
and then moves one okay you reach the
end so this is the middle okay
yes it's supposed to be
yeah yeah it could be least or this it
doesn't matter okay so look
uh one yeah
this twice yes and then twice
[Music]
then then that than that
well i'm confused but but now the the
thing is that
the rabbit is twice as fast as
[Music]
oh my god this is a bit tricky to do
probably not using this okay
so let let's do the middle define
weight mid of the linkage and we're
given a hand
yeah what's missing here
okay so now we have a fast first as well
which is also equal to we don't need
that projector
wait wait wait okay instead of just one
thing
yeah then we're going to do it in the
coding part right now
yes and then then why
why
[Music]
so why
and fast fast and fast next okay
first and fast the
next fast is not
now and first but that is not long
yeah i know but because of the heat and
then look then fast
equals fast top next
next yeah yeah it travels twice and then
slow
equals slow down next
and then return what when the first stop
next
is
what's the complexity still one right
yeah and but you only tried was half uh
once one time right how does a login
no there's no lock then you know it's
just one thing to this list
okay yeah yeah good okay so now let's
turn on this
thing
[Music]
wait wait wait okay okay okay
can i can i can i can i
can you can you
what's the thing you what's the thing
mean
okay
[Music]
is that is it okay is it okay yeah it's
okay sit down sit down please
no okay this is so loud
no sit down okay this is my channel okay
welcome hello
this is dr live youtube channel of
teaching kids program
okay now
let's do this coding okay let's let's
define a note okay let's define the note
okay now remember we we want to uh
now we can look look class notes
remember
and define define node
in in this is yesterday but we're doing
this
again well we need to
define the linked list and then next
uh next note
[Music]
that's okay it doesn't matter equals
remember yeah remember yesterday we
talked about this we create a new node
which is node
which is why there's a gap
that's okay that's okay yeah yeah that's
okay self.next now
equals equals new node
and and what return you know right
right yes okay wait wait
oh now look now we have list then we
have a head
head which is the now let's do it
known as minus one the first half yeah
and then we
range in we create a link list range
10 okay and then what
we want we don't want to we we have a p
p equals hat please please
while you're doing eleven then thirteen
then line
twelve yeah yeah it's eleven that's okay
p
equals p add now we add the now
with i right and then now we have a now
now now if we print this if we print
this we'll get our answer yeah we gotta
please now if
we do this if p equals hat and then y
p if we print this point p dot value
p equals p dot
next no right next note so what do we
expect this answer will be this
no you see your printer from minus one
tonight right
yes yesterday yes yesterday yes that's
that's okay now we want to not we want
to
we we want to find the middle of it
right
yeah so let's let's do this first
let's do this define meter of the
link list and remember fast slow
equals head head right okay
why fast is
not non and first
next is not none right
okay and then fast equals five stop next
dot next right right and the slow will
be
slow the next all right yeah and return
slow right
yeah okay let's let's do it look
let's do it so there's meat uh the meat
note is meat of the head and then let's
let's put that what do you think the
meat will be
the minute will be five five or six
i i don't know the price
is six oh oh oh oh not not invalid
okay dollars ah i forgot the dollars
i forgot the dollars why do you need
dollars
at the end no not money columns color
not dollars
columns okay this is out of the way
can you no yeah
oh next no okay sorry i i think it's
next no no
not the next please i read
next no next no
[Music]
it's next no not next oh
next no
can you please you're on youtube
okay four is it four it's four
it's for the middle zero minor uh yeah
ten meter zero four four is the fifth so
it's okay
but if you if it even like let's do it
uh
because we got a minus one at the
beginning right yeah
if i do this if the first first element
is one
okay then i start from the second
to nine okay so
one two three four five six one two
three four
nine nine the middle one is eight right
a bit noisy
it's okay one two ten
two one and then two to the nine okay so
now you will be
five right yes you will be five five is
the middle
got it okay so let's do let's
let's uh see this program today
yeah so that's yesterday's class and
then we
we define this meter to get the middle
one
okay any questions so far oh it's pretty
clear look
okay it's pretty clear okay any
questions
no okay so say bye bye
bye bye bye bye bye okay bye
bye bye
okay bye-bye see you later