hello mr area are you right yeah
okay well we talked about the graph
the other day yeah actually the day
before yesterday we talked about how to
clone a graph
the clone is the fancy word for copy
yeah
but for the copy we have two kinds of
copies deep copy and shallow copy
they copy is basically copying
everything yeah
make exactly copy so once you put a copy
like let's say a equals one two three
and then if we say b equals copy dot d
copy or we say we can use this
this is a d copy so a and b
both points to a list of one two three
they are independent of each other
yeah
so if i say a
0 equals like
4 for example it doesn't affect the
other copy right because it's totally
independent of copies
we talked about how to clone the graph
using the different search yes
definitely
the trick here is that because this
graph is
undirected connected graph right so so
we have the cycles for the graph yeah we
have cycle graph
cycles forecast so in order to avoid the
you know
endless
entities
and recycles yes we have to remember
we have to make we have to remember in
in the headset okay i said
so
we make a note here look we copy make a
note here and then we immediately mark
it as visited and then before we
clone
its neighbor it's kids it's neighbors
okay
so this is stephen search
what's the other way we can clone
traverse a
graph
what's the other way
okay
[Music]
we are talking about this is stephen
search calling itself that research
yeah what's the other way of traveling
the graph
um
so
let's say if i have a graph like that if
i have a graph
like one
two
three four
five
okay
so let's say we have got this way
if i start if i if i'm given this null
here what's the perfect search order of
this graph one two three five four
one two three
five four yeah whether yeah or you can
say one three two
four five it doesn't matter here because
the
yeah
because this the
the graph right the graph doesn't have
it's not like a binary tree you have the
left and right yeah expensively for the
graph you can say okay i visit this
first
as long as it's next yeah three two four
five okay so in order to implement a
perfect search normally what kind of
data structure can we use
do you still remember
q and in python what how can we declare
a cube eq cq what's dq mean
what
yeah what does it mean double ended
it means
so
we can look double ended means that we
can
pop and push in both both ends
both sides okay
so
let's
let's revisit the breakfast search okay
okay for example is this one
first of all i put the one in
yeah
okay
now i take one out
so what should i do
you should
push in two or three two and three
okay so now what i what should i do
what's the next to pop up
yeah but what's to do with two and three
so what should i do with two and three
okay two and take it what and what
should i do next
four four alright what should i do next
doing three
yeah
okay so let's just quickly write this
and then we can we can see how we can
clone
chrome graph and directly okay what
squat by the way graph
did i say that structure it's the vertex
and edges yeah they still remember yeah
okay so let's say let's let's implement
this question search clone graph
uh so we have given the node here we're
giving the node
if not now
if we're given the empty thing we just
return yeah
easy return
okay all right
so now we have a q equals t q
and now we put the node in
okay
yeah
there you are what you doing
so now look
wire
cue
but we have we need to have a
have a
notebook hash set to remember the notes
we will be visiting here so let's say we
begin with putting a set
so this is kind of a standard uh
template for the process search using uh
eq so first we take a note from the
in front of curia this is like q this is
q
and then we take it out with current we
take this current out okay
currently equals q the power
cube the power
for black
okay so now we have a no no we have
having the kids yeah so we have say
we we have uh we have to iterate the
kids of it so for n in
in current the neighbors yeah the
neighbors oh we call it the children
yeah it doesn't matter
the name let's call it neighbors
neighbors
[Music]
a-i-g-h-b-o-r-s okay then
if n not in
not in scene
okay
then we we sing
the add
n n right
and then we need to push the n to the
append and to the
to the q so what should i put here
open y
open what what are the keys
yeah
i know we want to return if we visited
we want to return the loot okay no
okay
so
so we
this is just a template to
to visit the traverse graph that graph
now we we have to
clone it we have to copy why we
translate it
so first of all
first of all
see this is a set let's change it to
uh um
see let's say let's say we have uh
we have a dictionary we have a mapping
yeah we have a table hash table so this
one is a paper
so we have a scene
so since this is
changed from the headset
the headset is the lock stores the
number of nodes we have visited but
instead we wanted to store
the
mapping from the original node to the
terminal okay so the key will be the
original node now value would be the
copied no no let's copy so
at the beginning now
i should give it a clone this is i let
me copy here
look uh node know the value
and then the neighbors would be empty
this right so
so look we have we have just copy one
node which is that node yeah so then we
instead of reading the node we tell it's
copy which is same
no okay
yeah
now
now i
i have to do something here right so
instead of
now look the neighbor the neighbor is
not being seen the label is not being
copied so we have to copy here so that's
right here scene
node
scene
but now equals node we copy this now
yeah we're using this syntax end of
value
okay
q dot 10 okay uh
now
i have etched okay so actually this
needs to be moved uh predom when it's
not seen so i have to write it here q
dot append
okay okay
so when we only append
we only push the note
back to the queue when it's not being
visited right when it's visited there's
no point to append it right
so now here at this point we are here
so we should do what we should we should
please sin and this note here
into
uh into the neighbor of the current
right remember this current thing
this current thing okay this current
thing at the beginning when it's copied
it's given is given an empty list and as
a neighbor so we have to do
to this current
the neighbors
neighbors
don't attend
so
because
n is the neighbor of current right so
what does this mean is that okay so we
we already know we already copied
make a copy of current
yeah many copy of current which is is
stored in the same current right
remember this has map this scene
seen yeah the keys
keys this original note original note
like a note
and then the value would be
la
copied no right so this is no dot
value yeah
okay
so scene current this is the copy this
is the copy of the current node
and its neighbor needs to
append
c
n and look
n is uh n is the neighbor of current
right
yeah look n is the neighbor of current
okay so
so what is copy
sin
n is a copy c n is a neighbor of
sin current yeah simple as that yeah
look
the original note is current it has a
neighbor n right so i'm already copy i
copy this current to sim current
right so i already copied n to c n so
what's left to do i have to
append
these to the neighbors or that right
make sense you see this is the graph i
copy this one too right this is original
now i copy and i don't know which is one
dash
and i copy another which is two dash
this is end this is current so what's
next
what's next
there is
edge missing right yeah yeah that's
missing look at this this just copy the
note
this is just copy the note right but i
have to add edge
if i am i'm adding an edge how can i add
an edge what
how how do we represent the edges in in
this kind of graph where is the edges
being
added which one is the edge added how do
you how do you how do we know you know
one is connected to two
things
which property of the node look now has
a value and has the neighbors neighbors
yeah neighbor is the list of vertex it
connects to right so here same current
the name of the open
scene
and which means what scene current
has the edge connects to sin
and
right
okay
okay so then that's uh lots of uh
how the edges are represented using this
kind of wow which is called adjacent
risk rotation is like a vertice
is a vertex is the key and the value is
the list of vertex it connects to that's
the adjacent magic adjacent list okay
[Music]
uh the time complexity is still the same
yeah use as compared to data search all
n plus m yeah where o in percent
o in person where m
n is the number of vertex m is the
number of edges
right yeah no more edges
okay that's it for today good job
bye bye
bye bye bye bye
[Music]
okay that's it