hello mr and mr wright are you right
yeah okay baby
okay so we're given an array of numbers
like 2 4 3
1 2
okay
and we're going to solve these numbers
using two
approach so we're going to solve the
numbers that start at the even index so
in even indexing
so let's certain these number we're
going to sort every two numbers starting
from first one
increasing
so a little bit one four and
the numbers start at the odd index okay
so the second number is actually the
index one so this is all indexes one two
three okay so that's zero one two three
okay
so
we're going to sort the numbers let's
start at the
even index
increasing and the odd index decreasing
so eventually the arrays will become
four
two
one
three okay
doesn't make sense yeah
okay i'm going to give another example
okay so you need to tell me what's the
array going to be like after sorting
all right
one
two
zero
five okay this is just this one so
what's this going to be like
[Music]
okay so we're down look these these two
numbers increasing so zero one these two
numbers decreasing
five too okay
so
yeah make sense yeah yeah so ho ho we're
going to do this
yeah anyway what's the only way you like
anyway well the first thing to do is to
do
it to play games
is to uh
um
check the
index check index
okay that could be one way how can we
check the index but we're going to
eventually we're going to
we yeah so the first thing to do is to
find the
just to split the array into twos right
once containing the numbers starting the
inver index the other one starting from
the odd index right
yeah and now we can sort those
arrays two arrays separately and then we
can merge them right that's the one
approach all right
okay now let's do this
okay
okay so let let's say if the if these
numbers is empty okay if this if the
numbers is
and we just return okay
now the odd index
or index equals how can we pick the
numbers only for the odd index do you
still remember how do we pick the
numbers let's start with the even index
plus
yeah you remember two yeah every two
means every other element okay so the
number remember this thing
remember listing a column b currency
start at a index a and the index b
but not including it
every
c step okay
so all index we start our index star
with the second one right so one until
the end
and every other element right even index
start with zero
ah they still remember start with zero
and the end every and
every
other element that's why we'll put a
step to here
right
do we note if they have the same number
of elements
um
no no yeah that's that's uh that's for
sure because the number could contain
odd numbers or all numbers and numbers
or even numbers of numbers right yeah
yeah
so
so okay so look
let's say
one two three four okay
so after this the odd
will contain
okay maybe we i put another five here
okay odd number will contain
two
four
right the even number
will contain
one three five okay
yeah let me start we start with the even
number right so yeah so what what do we
do now so we have even numbers and all
numbers so what do we do now we know
[Music]
them yeah we saw that we need to solve
these numbers increasing so first we
need to solve this number increasing so
the numbers
so so let's say we want to solve the
even numbers increasing and then the odd
number decreasing yeah so let's say we
put a sort here
sorted
yeah
even number increasing the odd number
decreasing started
we give a key we say reverse equals true
right
which means that we want to sort it in
reverse order which is from the largest
to the smallest
right alternatively we can solve this
number and we can reverse it do we still
remember how we reverse and a list
minus one yeah or whether i or if we can
do it is that two pointer thing
yeah
you know two points i think one two
three four five
[Music]
so we have that
now we
okay so we have left we have learned
numbers ready now the next step is to
merge them yeah so how do we imagine we
pick one number from each yeah
do you still remember how we merged two
saltines
i
bridge how do we merge two certainties
how do we measure two points i think
pick one from each other and then move
yeah yeah
so we can do this answer
because i'll empty this
and then let's say
i equals j equals you know y
i smaller than
we start from the even number length
even
and
j smaller than lens odd
and then we pick one from the event we
pick one from the other answer
dot append
even
i answer the append yeah we pick
we pick in turn
one we pick one even number and then we
pick one other number okay
yeah
and then we move the pointer i plus
equals 1 j plus equals 1
okay so now come on yeah as you can see
you can see that
possibly okay possibly the even number
could have one more
yeah could have one more
element than the odd number right
all right
so look at then we can we need to say if
i
is smaller than lens even number
okay then we append
the the remaining
even number okay so which is answer
dot append
even
what even i okay
or even minus one because it's always
the last one
is is it possible that the odd has more
than more element than even number
okay one two
three four
it means that the numbers start even
index so this yellow one two three it's
no means let's
okay but that's a good question
like okay
yeah so what the one question is a
little bit come on one question is that
if reason
come on if the array has five numbers so
we have three
numbers let's start with the even index
and two start with the
odds right is it possible the odd has
more
elements than the even yeah
no
okay let's say six numbers and if there
if that the original array has the even
number of numbers then both array will
contain the same element right if i have
one more element
if i have one more element do they have
a does they have to do
i mean does it have to be even
that's what i'm asking
you know yeah
one two three four five six
so that
yeah
so that that's the
even index
if i add one more
let's see
so look now even has four other has has
three hey you are you're saying that um
yeah yeah yeah okay if i put another
more
so look one three five seven and two
four six eight the same i know if i put
one more
one three five seven nine
okay so the even
the even array is off is always
more than the odd number
all the same yeah why is that why is
that
because the even in that start with the
first one right because the first index
is always even right so the event gets
to pick first that's why we only
we we can only uh
we can only have more even numbers you
know or equal even numbers than all
numbers okay
yeah
make sense
the other way of doing this okay this is
a bit lensing another implementation so
we can chip it
look what's different what's different
what's a dip
like what i'm wearing
so if we dip it right
yeah we can tip it okay so hope we can
tip it so we can rewrite this this bit
so we can say
four x y
in chip
okay
start with the even number yeah
chip longest okay
why is that because the
the even and the odd may not have the
same length okay so cheap long is
even
odd
and i can say answer
not a pen
x okay so i have to check if x answer
doesn't appear x if y
answer don't attend y okay
i know b return return answer right
baby
we have to check if the x is that it is
not long right because the chipmunk is
may produce the lung
okay so look here
a equals 1 2
b equals
three four
five so the deep longest
deep longest will produce
an array of one tree
right
look that's how it did
look
you're looking cheap
one three two four
but look there's no element here but how
to chip with five
so you have a lump
five okay
that's the cheap longest
if we don't have enough element at the
corresponding
five right so we use the nine so but the
chip
if it's a chip function it will just
return one three two four right but if
it's the cheap longest yeah
your pet
will pack the actual element with the
number
okay let's eat that
okay actually the most uh quicker way to
implement this is this look because we
already have the other even here so we
can substitute right we can do this
we can just do this
nums
the second one every other element equal
okay so this is the tuple assignment
okay i want to replace
i want to replace the elements in the
numbers array start from the first one
every other element come on look at me
and i want to replace the elements
start with the second element every
other element skip one
equals what equals this this is the
topic right so we just have to
to
do this okay
yeah you see
okay
which one you think is the better
we choose this one the shortest one
which one is the shortest one
um
numbers what did i just say here
and we talked about this the other day
right remember
[Music]
yeah
do you get this one
okay so can you tell me how can we solve
this problem
bye
n is the number of elements in the ray
okay so actually we sort it twice also
on divided by two log
log n divided by 2 yeah
plus this yeah
plus
but we we're going to simplify this
right look y side of n divided by 2
this is constant yeah
log
look log a times b equals one
equals one
equals log a
plus log b
so log
a divided by b equals log a
minus log b okay
yeah
oh yeah look so this this one
log n divided by 2 equals log n
minus log
so this is a constant we drop it
yes so you can actually log in
so login
login plus login
half
so half is actually o and login okay so
still nothing
okay
so one more thing one more thing come on
come on
what's this
what's this what's this
okay so this one so okay so okay the
number is this one yes zero one two
three
four okay so can you tell me
numbs column common two is which tune
which numbers
which number means this one
um
zero to
four okay and num one column column two
yeah exactly so that means that means
that this one i want to replace
yeah
replace these three numbers
with the salted one with the
oyster even which is salty and this i
want to remove i replace this number
this number with the sorted reverse
reverse equal to okay
easy yeah impression that's easy okay
let's using the python syntax
this
this this comprehension
yeah but we know that the general idea
is what is to
separate the array into half right
separate into half and then
sort it both and then
merge it
okay when we talk about how to merge to
saute this yeah how do we look if this
is too salty this look
one three five seven
at least i thought it is two four
six eight okay we have two salty bees
and another ten okay look okay ryan
this is a this is b come on how can i
sort it these two arrays uh smudge to
sort it away
you take the smallest one okay i move it
[Music]
always take the smallest one okay that's
it for today
bye