hello
hello mr miss
okay so we give it an array of numbers
like one five two three okay listen
so we want to find out if at most by
removing at most one element can we have
the remaining numbers strictly
increasing so you can remove atmos yeah
you can remove at most one element
and then remaining
remaining needs to be strictly
increasing
yeah
what
what what if it's already increasing
that's a very good question yes if it's
already
increasing then we retention because
look amount what's a month means that
you don't need to remove it you can
remove zero
so
do i return yes or no
yes yes why is that because you didn't
really move yeah i can remove it and
then it will be
one two three strictly increasing okay
what's strictly increasing if look one
two two
is this strictly increasing none
two and two this is not strictly
increasing whether okay how about this
one
let's say one five
two three
one okay
so
can we have the strictly increasing
array
by removing at most one element no
yeah there's no chance yeah because look
if you're gonna do five one two three
one it's not stricken
if you know one one five three three
it's much cheaper increasing okay so
what's your approach to do this
what's up y'all purge yeah
any idea um well
great
uh
fulfilling yeah so what's proof of thing
we can
i mean we we can just try
they are n numbers we can how many
choices can we try
how many choices
and obviously yeah with another number
so we can try and
and
we can try
and removing the number right so we can
have n choices to remove each number to
see we remove that number and now we try
to see if the remaining is strictly
increasing yeah yeah right
okay so
first of all how do we check if this is
a way how do we check this is strictly
increasing
defined let's say it's salty yeah it's
it's increasing okay it's increasing
it's increasing okay
so how can we check these the numbers
are in strictly increasing all right are
we given an array here
how do we check if this is strictly
increasing
how do we check if we want to know a
number is strictly increasing
one by one and then we compare one
compel
and then
yeah yeah so we just come back look one
is more than two yes two smaller than
four yes first more than five yeah five
smaller than three no return four easy
okay
yeah
so look
and equals the length array
and then
we want to return what uh we turn
uh
we just do this effect for
i
in range
and minus one why is the menthol because
i need to i need to check the number and
the number next to it so so look if
a r i
is bigger or equal than a r i plus one
right if this number is bigger or equal
to the next one and we return fourth
right
yeah
otherwise return true right
look here look
yeah make sense so we're traveling from
the beginning the index and then if we
find out this number is bigger or equal
than the next number it means that we
have a
we have what we have a reverse we have a
noun increasing we have a non-increasing
order so what do we have
if there are n numbers what's the time
complexity
what's the temperature
um
very obvious okay okay so we can
simplify this yeah this is okay this is
very traditional very class classic you
know textbook but in python you can do
it simple you can say we can
i want all okay oh this is the keyword o
means
means everything inside needs to be
satisfied so our
o-a-r-r i need to be smaller than a r i
plus one
yeah
four
i
in range
and minus one okay so this is the
opposite uh
so look
which one you think is easier to
understand
the forms the same thing look
the right one
right one okay
this is yeah this is the
chicken so
we are checking the violation here right
yeah if we find something that violates
the increasing then we return false
otherwise if all checkpoints will return
true but here it's more like human
language return all
all means everything in there needs to
be true right or
so array i is smaller than array i plus
one for i in range right so everything
this condition is true okay so similarly
we have another
uh similar keyword called any so if we
say return any it means that if
one of them
at least one
occurs to then return true okay make
sense
o means everything needs to be true and
means
you know if we find
one that's okay we return to okay
yeah okay so now look we have this o-n
and we go through this array
to remove it so we can say four i in
range
and now
look this this one yeah the array is one
one two three four and the index is here
index index so how can we remove this
number if we don't know the index i
what's the remaining
if i remain if i okay then i put a 0 at
the beginning if i want to remove this
one okay this is ar
and i index is 1
i index 1
one okay so what's what's the array
after removing one
you'll be what
it remove you'll be what you'll be
current array will be
array
up to
i up to i not including this one right
after i this one
is here
before right
and then i want to
concatenate the numbers right after i so
plus
this is i this is i plus one right i
plug two i plug three i plus one okay so
look all right
look we have n choice yeah
so if i want to if we want to remove the
index number at index i right so the
remaining
the remaining numbers is current which
is
a r up to i plus a i plus one okay so
what's this
what what does this cr
mean
current yeah what way it is
what's this
so
do you understand this being i for i in
range n
a r up to i means this b
a i i plus one means this b so if i put
these two together what does it become
what do we have
um
no no no no can we increase
so we want to check we want to prove us
as you said yeah we want to prove us so
by proof of thing it means that we can
try removing the
element
and element yeah we can try removing the
first element to see the remaining is
sorted we can remove the second one
remove certain one so we remove the
element index i so what's the c of r
means
c y was a
i want to remove this index element
index i and then this is a r up to i
this is a i plus one so what's if i put
these two together what what does it
become what's this cr mean
uh it's the
array
i plus one yeah so
it's the same thing as removing
removing array removing array i yeah
yeah
and then and then we just check if
increasing is increasing right
increasing we have defined this function
corr then we return true right
okay otherwise return first
what's the time complexity come on
we're done look this is the one we have
one choice
but for each one we need to call this
this takes another one time n times n
over n squared
easy easy peasy okay that'll be it for
today
no no no we have a faster approach for
that
one five two three okay let's go back to
this example
yeah yeah yeah
what's the longest
increasing subsequence remember we
talked about this
longest longest increasing subsequence
longest one one two three okay so what's
the length of the longest thing
three okay
and how many numbers are there four
right
i remember this okay okay i'm going to
give you another one
two
ten
three four
six what's the longest subsequence two
three four six six
what's the length
for what's the total length
okay so what so what's the pro what's
the what's it what's that do what you
just did and then check if uh just one
yeah
so that's a quicker way of doing it is
that okay so ideally look removing one
we want to check the remembering is
strictly increasing so it's the same
thing as i let's find out the longest
increasing subsequence of these
if the length
of the longest increasing subsequent is
n minus one
or more right yeah
it's essentially the same as removing
one right is the same thing then this
two problem is the equivalent right
right am right yeah all right does it
make sense yeah
okay so do you still remember this
longest increasing subsequence yeah we
talked about that like uh 100 days ago
yeah
you probably don't remember yeah that's
fine i'll remind you okay hey my shoe is
broken
so for the longest increasing
subsequence we have two approach one is
one square
yeah one is one log n okay so let's go
over uh go to the longest increasing
subsequent with the
os square approach which is dynamic
programming okay so please still
remember what's dynamic yeah
[Music]
okay so let's say if we have f function
f i
f i means the longest increasing
subsequence that ends up index i okay so
e equals what maximum
of
maximum of what f j
f j plus one
is
is the number a r j is strictly smaller
than a r r
i
and also
the index j is smaller than i okay
for for
you know for j
is is belong from the zero to i
okay so that's the dynamic equation so
what does it mean fi means
s9 means the longest increasing
subsequence that ends the index i okay
look f0
f1 is here so the longest increasing
subsequent ends that that second number
so if we can find if we can iterate the
numbers up to array i yeah
if array is up to array i and then if we
found an array j
j j the index is up to i index and and
right actually these two are the same
yeah so we we don't need to
write it twice so j 0 to i
if array j if i found out if we found a
number
which is smaller
if we now find a number which is smaller
look 5 is smaller than 5 1 is smaller
than 5. okay so the longest increasing
subsequence that ends 5
is the long is equals the longest
increasing subsequence of
ending at one plus one right
yeah because look i found this is f i
right this is f right and here and then
if i find another one
you know j which is smaller than i so it
means that i can use the previously
i can use the fj previously
longest increasing subsequence the
engine and j and plus one number because
array j is more than an array right make
sense yeah
oh
well that means belongs to
in you see okay let's say x belongs to
0 to 10 okay then x the integer right
would be zero one two three four five
ten okay
yeah
okay or you can say in let's in
in actually in
in okay
in
so if we implement these
that would be one square okay let's
quickly implement this do you get this
idea everywhere do you get it yeah
you don't do do you want me to repeat
again
do you understand yeah okay okay sure
okay
so
dynamic programming okay the simplest
idea is that okay
okay
how many how many pens are there how
many pens are there right how many pens
are there
okay and if i put one more how many
times three that's dynamic okay so f and
look look fi
okay so fj right m j is two and then i
have another one f i coming i put it
together so f j f i equals f j plus one
because we don't need to calculate
this portion again f i again right
because we save it
let's let
spirits of dynamite programming me mo my
jason i want to be mobilization
what does it mean in english
be my mother shouldn't be my name
memory stuff here memory memo we have
memo remember remember
my mom okay that's it
okay let's try this
can you not touch my keyboard please
define okay let's say uh
i don't know what's what's the
uh
name of the function let's just call it
i don't know 402 okay
array right
and then n equals the length array
and then we have our f function f equals
at the beginning one times n okay so
what any any idea why we need to put a
one initially f f the value would be one
the longest increasing subsequence at in
each index is one
and the beginning is one right yeah each
number is a
longest increasing substance right
and now we can say for
i
in
range
n right and then for
j
in
range
i right
if
array
j is smaller than array i
right
then we can say
f function f
i equals maximum of f i
f j plus one okay
now look
the longest increasing subsequent the
length
return
will b
will be what come on
will be the maximum of fj flf function
right what is that and can you tell me
if lease plus one is bigger or equal
than n then we we can remove one number
and get this okay
okay
can you explain to this bit and then if
you can i give you two pokemon cards
okay uh you have to um
[Music]
what's the problem what's the original
problem the original problem is uh
do you find a strictly
increasing subsequence so you uh figure
out if you
um almost
won
um
and then it will be strictly increasing
yeah so
so at most one yeah this is what it does
why this is max f is the longest
increasing subsequent it's because it's
maximum
why why what's f
is
what did i say long is increasing
subsequence
of what
[Music]
one one look one
two three okay so what's the f value for
the this is the original value
what's the f value
one two three okay
okay wait wait wait wait how about one
five three what's the longest increasing
subsequence oh one
no no no
what's the f value
what should i put here
no it's not three what's the f value
the longest increasing subsequent that
ends at current index
one
two what's there
what should i put here
what's the longest increasing subsequent
that ends at index three
three
long the lens the long two why is two
because because you count uh
one and three yeah okay so okay so you
understand what the f so what's max f
f is
maximum
yeah i know what's the longest
increasing subsequence if i look because
f value is only gives me the longest
increasing subsequent that ends at each
index right and i want to find out the
longest increasing subsequence the end
for the full array so it can it can end
at any index that's why i put that max f
to get the
longest increasing subsequence of the
whole array first one right
because that's what we said we need to
find out if we can
find you could if we can have a
increasing subsequence or increasing
array by removing one so that's one way
they come from right we have an array
okay what's the time number
um
oh n square yeah
you see yeah it's not better right it's
not better but this is another idea okay
but we we talked about the longest
increasing substance by greedy using the
bicep left bicep right do you still
remember binary set left final reset
right
it's a it's a what is a two functions to
find the
final index to insert the element okay
look
array this is array one two
two three three three four okay so
bisect left
by the left
a if i want to put that number three
if i
everybody look this is a sorted array
and bisect left yeah i want to put i
want to find out which index i can put
the number three in
so by saying left you will tell me it's
here right
you'll return zero one two three so if i
insert that displays
right
all the elements before it's smaller
than me right smaller than three yeah
that's what i said left and how about
biceps right
you know if it's a if it has a
equal
number you will be the first one right
by the right you'll be here
okay slightly different look please
because if i put the number three and
here yeah a3
here
that
let that position i want to put another
three here right so that would be on the
right of the
block of three because it's the same
yeah if i only pull the three
using bison left
it'll be on the left it'll be bisect
right yeah do you get it yeah
why are we using bases
right because we we have all log n
complexity four
for both two yeah first operation okay
so
we are using these and then we can do
this we can keep keep tracking of the uh
longest increasing subsequence okay so
let's say let's go to this one five two
three again okay
okay so look all right
longest increasing subsequent at the
beginning is empty
okay one
where do i put a one in the
here
it'll be there right
so i put it one here
five
where where is the where is the fight
going to fit here on the right of the
one right yeah so if it's more than that
i'm pretty two where is it where's the
two going to be in the
in here
between right
so it's here right
so i will
remove it
and put it as fine why can't we do it
look because we keep tracking of numbers
increasing subsequent and we find a
smaller number
it's less than five right i can replace
it
do you get it look it i i don't care
what happened the longest increasing
subsequence in the future but i know i
know
is that i
the result will not get worse if i
replace five is two i'm right
yeah because two is smaller than five
yeah if you have a longest increasing
subsequent you know something like that
i can replace it with a smaller number
too it's still
stand right all right
makes sense
so let's let me okay i'll just replace
it okay i know three where it's going to
put
on the right
so we have the longest increasing
subsequent which is then three okay
and it's
bigger or equal than n minus one so
yeah we can remove it okay let's do this
do you get it
yeah ryan look at it okay let's do this
d502 okay
uh
all right
and then you need to tell me what's the
time complexity for the last question
okay
wrong is increasing subsequent because
at the beginning empty okay
for
i
in
array
and the index is what
index let's say x
equals bisect
left
bicep left five cent right are from
bicep
uh package bicep it means binary you
know
binary actually i don't i don't know
what spices stands for okay buy is for
binary
set probably
i have no idea okay by the left
list
and i okay look then if this index is
equal to the length but if this
insertion point
is at the end of the partition at the
end on the right you know at the end
right at the end of this
then we can just do what we can just
list
the append
x y
as
this
x equals i
yeah
and then return
length of list
is bigger plus one is bigger or equal
than
lens ar right
yeah
okay
um
okay so
the same thing what's the times on black
state what's the time that i see
come on
what's the time of messy
the time complexity
[Music]
is this
this one
oh i love your weather oh and okay
okay
yeah we're considering these as as a one
okay often it's a one okay
and then changing the value at index x
is all one so a constant and can you
tell me what what's this speed
this should be similar to the last one
right all right
what's this bit length this plus one
equals dense ir
you just answered that five minutes ago
what's what what's wasted
yeah this what's this last one what's
this
the list
what's what's it it's my list what's
this
it's a list
what does it mean
it means
increasing subsequence and then i wanted
the lens of longest increasing
subsequent plus one bigger than that can
you extend this to me
this is the idea of using it
[Music]
yeah
if it's bigger than a lymph
yeah why
why this works
you haven't explained that well to me
i mean what
what's the problem what's the original
problem the real problem is uh
you have a
[Music]
it should relationship be personally
strictly increasing yeah okay so that's
the same as finding the
longest increasing subsequence of the
array
the length okay so the longest
increasing substituent of array which is
so look
here the list will be one
can you tell me what that is here
one
two
three okay and the lens is what
three
okay three and then i need to plus one
that will become
four
and the four is bigger or equal than the
length of the old thing that means that
if i remove one element and i can get
the rest remain remaining uh numbers
strictly increasing okay yeah
at least it's the most efficient
overnight yeah okay that's it for today
bye-bye bye-bye bye-bye
bye bye