follow me sorry mr ryan all right yes so
you learn about a fraction yeah
which one is that numerator
numerators
numerator yeah yeah you made it very
high the denominator is very low
the denominator is already out of the
game
down the top
[Music]
okay okay
okay so what's the simplified fraction
for example is this is this a simplified
fraction
yeah okay
is this a simplified
fraction
no
okay so how do we check if the fraction
is simplified like b
a over a so
if any of them is a prime number
it's a prime number
not really it's what do you say any
number is the prime number
b or a is a prime number that is a
supervised fraction
i give you example like point number
five yeah
okay so how about ten
five this is a prime number but this is
not simplified
yeah if the denominator is a prime
number
something to do with the plan
so what
what's the simplified what's not
simplified so look forward to my uh
no no no no no
look what p over a
yeah so if we can divide by something
that's a mixed fraction
yeah okay so look if b is divisible by c
a is divided by c and c is not equal to
one
c is an integer but not
is it not equals to one
so
then let's uh
then that's that's one
that's not a
simplified fraction right so in other
words we want to find out that
if b and a
are cosine we call it
if they can divided by the same number
yeah
if they come divided by the same number
we call it cobra
like three and five that's two times
because they're they're only projects
yeah yeah yeah oh yeah
not quite not quite the same look
compromise
girlfriend
so three and five the only positive
number can be divisible by them is one
right so we call it program three prime
is essentially the same as gcd what's
gcd greatest common divisor so kopran of
look a and b
are compliant if gcd of them is one okay
is that clear if a and b are co-prime
then it's a simplified version a
fraction okay let's say
three
over eighteen is a simple five fraction
why is that because the same number six
yes because the three and eighteen the
gcd is three yeah okay
yeah yeah as long as it's not equal to
one then it's not a simplified
fraction okay
so today's task is easy so we are given
an integer n
integer n
we want to find out
the
the the fractions the simplified
fractions
between zero and one
okay not e bigger than zero
less than one okay this one you see open
parenthesis
open parenthesis means excluding right
it's good
square bracket means equal right so if
this is zero one square bracket it means
that x bigger than zero equal to zero
smaller or equal to one okay so but we
are talking about these cases which is
between
zero and one
okay
but
not equal to zero and not equal to one
okay so we want to find out we're given
a number and we want to find out that
the the denominator a the simplified
fraction e over a where a is smaller or
equal than n right
and then we find out the number of
we want to find out the number of the
simple simpler fraction yeah yeah so we
can just
so we can just repeat how how do we do
it look
so look we given this integer n right so
we can bring forth the a right
prove us from one to a from uh from one
to n
and then we can prove of b
from one to a all right
yeah
so
gcd do we still remember how do we get a
gcd
like 27 and 18 what's the gcd on both
yeah yeah wow that was quick
how how do we get the knife
remember this divide 8 27 18 we divided
by 18
and remaining
nine yeah
all right
so it's we just swap here so that will
be 18
18 divided by nine
so by zero once we get the zero
this is the
greatest common device okay let's try
some example okay some more example
[Music]
maybe 24 and 36. eight
what's the
so how do we do it
divided by 36
the remainder is 24 right
so we move it here we move here so it
becomes
36 24.
36 divided by 24 remaining
12.
we just move move b
yeah yeah
24 divided by 12. three poisons
okay i'm poisoned okay 24 divided by 12.
zero so look
you see so
so we this is the way we get a greatest
common divisor okay
so actually the in python we don't need
to implement this in in the math library
we have these we have uh
we have this math.gcd we already have
this we don't need to be rather weird
yeah but if you really want to
implement it define gtd
a b
okay
so
wire y p is greater than zero then we
can do
a b equals b
a divided by b remaining okay and then
we turn
return a right okay let's the greatest
common device that we talked about a
long time ago
yeah
okay
y b is bigger than zero a b a
b will become the a
and then b will be become a divided by b
the remainder okay
okay and then we can also implement this
using the recursion right like i said
okay that's not a
that's not a topic from today today
we're going to
talk about what
finding the number of the simplified
fractions when the denominator
is less than equal to n right so we can
just come from here we can prove over
here
prime
okay so one question what is coconut two
numbers a and b are coupons a prime
number
what's cobra can you give me an example
a and b i think
okay so what okay so as we know the
numbers they are not those prime numbers
co-prime
coupon look
one
of one and three
one is no prime number
okay so
what's cooper what did i just say what's
girlfriend
is 4 and 12 cobra
no right
okay is
3 and
nine cobra yeah
yeah um yeah
no
so what's coconut i just said i was just
saying like
it could be divided
[Music]
yeah so we can simplify so what are we
looking for if we can find out if the
gcd these two number is
is what number then is the code
if it's
simplified
the greatest common divisor of two
number if there are there are two prime
if
if the
greatest common divisor is what number i
was just talking if we can't find
anything i learned what number
one yeah that's what i'm saying if it's
the greatest common divisor
or first number is one
then it's cochrane okay
okay
okay now we can implement the first
thing okay
define okay let's say if i simplify
simplify
parallelize simplify fraction okay
simplify fraction
we give it an n right
so let's put an answer in the uh
in
in the list okay answer equals zero for
i
in range
n okay
let's say
we iterate with the denominator for
denominator in range n star from one
okay because the denominator can be zero
all right yeah
what happens if the denominator is zero
what's one divided by zero
you can't divide by zero
that's not the thing yeah denominator
number yeah
okay
e1 to n plus one okay and then
for the not
denominator yeah nominator in range
up to one over
up to t right up to d
yeah
and then if the gcd
and d
equal equals one right
then we can implement this answer easy
yeah
return
answer okay okay yeah
no b look a little bit
yeah all right right
the time complexity look d
iterates from one to n right n
uh okay uh we have a duplicate variable
name here let's say denominator
numerator numerator
okay
so the term convexity is o n squared
times
look this is o n o n
by the gcp the term convexity of gcd
gg ib yeah
the temperature is locked
upper bound will be the minimum
of a and b okay
so you'll be all
o n square log mean a times b okay
let's see overall time complexity for
this argument
any questions
now so can you explain to me what's b
speed
what's this for d in range 1 to n what
are we doing here
we
denominator
we pull something the technology yeah i
know what's this
we put in the numerator and what's this
um
what's it what does it mean
what are we checking why are we taking
this
ryan
ryan come on you're on the pokemon town
so you need to please me okay so
what's this
it's full
we are
that the numerator this bit
look 4 is the proof of it's a for loop
yeah d from 1 to n and the numerator
goes from 1 to the
to the maximum denominator and then the
greatest common divisor if it's one
normally and
uh
if the numerator and the
numerator the greatest common divisor is
one it means it's a simplified fraction
right now we increment the answer yeah
yeah okay
okay
yeah
okay so
uh
okay one more question okay one more
tricky question okay
let's say
uh
and 48 what's the greatest commenting
riser
wow
[Music]
how how do you get that so quick
how do you correct something
okay divided by the remaining is what
remaining is 24 right
yeah so you 40 a
24 and remaining is zero so we get the
24 okay
yeah it's still remember how we get this
greatest common divisor yeah
yeah
okay that'll be it for today good job
bye bye