hello mister missalan all right
yeah we talked about the exponential
function and logarithmic yeah
exponential
what's exponential function can you give
me an example in mathematics
x to the power of 2
2 to the power of x yeah y to the y
equals 2 to the power x yeah
and so look this is the x is x y so if
we call the numbers here this is 0 0
two
three
four and then accordingly the y axis
one two three four five
this is minus one yeah
minus two and goes the other way is
minus negative
okay so 2 to the power of x if we when x
is 0 2 to the power of 0 is 1 so it's
here 2 to the power 1 x is 1 2 to the
power 1 is 2 so
yeah
when x is two two to the power of two is
four yeah so one two three
one two three four
uh
well two to the power one is two so zero
one two so it's here
two to the power two
2 3 4 okay here
so
2 to the power of
of minus 1 is actually equals 2 to the
power of 1 1 over 2 to the power 1 right
so it's
half
so when
x is minus 1 is actually half
so if you call this function to the
power x it's like that
okay exponential okay so we're passing
this one okay
this this curve never hits x axis yeah
it never has x's because 2 to the power
of x
is not never equals to zero right
excessive
and the inverse of it we call it
logarithm
yeah logarithm
this logarithm
yeah when we talk about time complexity
what's the time complexity to solve an
array which has n elements
yeah this is where the n
log log coming from right so look look
the the inverse we are talking about the
inverse of exponential function is
logarithmic so look
look inverse so what's the inverse
what's the word inverse yeah the
opposite yeah the opposite
so let's put the y equals x function
which is very obvious it's like that
yeah
yeah so the log element function is like
that so it's the
opposite look this curve
mapping here yeah passing the one
so it'll be something like that
yeah
and this is the inverse logarithm okay
so
to put it simple yeah this way look
2 to the power x equals y right
so if we do it like this
log
logo 2 to the power of what
so 2 to the power of x equals 1 okay
look 2 to the power of 3 equals 8 i know
we can say log based on 2 a which is
equal to 3 because 2 to the power 3
equals 8. yeah look it's just swap yeah
swap the input and output right
yeah now we call this inverse function
so log
log anything
y equals zero yeah so and x is one right
so look two
one
or anything one right a one equals zero
why is that because a to the power of
any number to the power of zero is what
if a is not equal to zero okay
so if i say what's the num what's the
value of three to the power of zero
what what did i just say
[Music]
any number to the power of zero is
is passing this point yeah
so any power to the power so what's the
a to a to the power of zero equals one
yeah you see
yeah
okay this is the opposite yeah do you
get this
so far so good yeah
okay
look great
okay so
so
this line again never hits y axis right
this is the same thing because this line
exponential never hits x as it
at least the opposite will never hit the
y axis because look
when when you see when
x is zero so look this is zero yeah
x is never zero because you can have
nothing
which
you you will find nothing a to the power
of not uh you can't find anything that
to the power of anything equals zero
that's what i'm saying never equals zero
yeah
okay
okay so today yeah this is the today
we're going to talk about logan function
a little bit more so we want to prove we
want to put what we want to hit this one
we want to prove
log base a
yeah base a
they say
b times c
equals log a
b plus log a c
okay we want to prove this
log base a
a to the power what equals b times u
equals log to the power
look a base b not a uh
base ac okay so how can we do this
first of all
we set these
we set x equals not
a to the power of b
a to the b okay i don't know how to
pronounce this actually
a base b log a b okay y equals log
a c
so we can do this x equals that so it's
the same as what a to the power of x a
to the power x equals b right
and this one
a to the power of
y
equals c all right yeah all right so
look b times c here so if we say log
a b times c and we put these together
right we substitute this b and c so it
will be
a
x
times a y right
yeah what's this
a x
times a y equals a
to the power of x plus y i'm right
but
2 to the power of 3 times 2 to the power
of
four equals two to the power of one
three
there are three twos times together
and then times four two times together
equals two to the power
many two how many twos
no no no look that's three two look here
three two two times two times two yeah
there are four terms two times two times
two times two how many twos
times together
sorry
seven yeah it's not times square it's
plus together three plus four right
yeah
so look this one equals log
a a to the power of x plus one so what's
this value come on you can you can give
me the answer log a
a to the power x plus what's this answer
what's this a to the power of what
equals a to the power of x plus y so
what's designed very obvious
yeah x plus y easy it right
so look x plus y so a so this bit is x
plus y right yeah
yeah all right
yeah
so look this bit is x plus y right x
plus one so this bit
log a
b c
equals x is this one yes because we
already know is x
a
uh b
plus log a c okay so we just prove it
yeah we just prove it okay i'm gonna
give a
quick question okay
look
come on face
space of
let's say
face lock 10
plus
log
10 5
what's this answer
what's this
what's the value of it
come on
what's the value of i give you a hint
what's the value
[Music]
what did i just do i just proved
this equals left right log base
a b times c
and what's the value of this
what's the value of these come on
located
equals log a b plus not ac this is what
a b is not a c so what's the value of
least bit it's hard to calculate these
two yeah but if we
see it together what's the value
look 10 7
70.
how did you get 17
what nothing come on come on don't worry
look 10 10 2 5 so 2 5 b is 2 c is 5 b
times c
t comply with ten ten a is ten not ten
ten what what's the value
what's the matter sorry a hundred
why is that hundred four
what
10 so what's this value come on you
don't get the speed yeah do you get a
speed
you think do you get a speed
kind of okay so i'm telling you this
this bit is here a b is here this is
here
i know what's what's this
what's b it was c
b equals two
c equals five okay so b times c
what's a
okay so look ten ten equals one
ten to ten to the power of one equals
ten
one
one so it's the answer is one come on
cut it
yeah you have to understand yeah can you
tell me what what's your answer like 120
how how did you get the numbers
you you get it
you see look it's hard to calculate this
value right you don't know 10 to the
power of y equals two you don't know
yeah we don't know i need to use the
calculator 10 to the power equals five i
don't know
you know i need to use the calculator
but all i know is that this one
yeah yeah
all right
i i look ten turn
log two
log ten two times five equals log ten
two plus log ten
five okay
okay similarly similarly okay we talked
about this similarly if we change this
sign to minus
if we change this term to minus
and now all i have to is to b divided by
c here right
yeah can you imagine we can we can prove
this as well look again we set this to
here
and then b times c b divided by c so it
will be
log
a
a to the power of x divided by a to the
power y right so look
power y equals a to the power of x minus
y can you get it look 2 to the power of
a divided by 2 to the power of 2 equals
how many 2 left two to the power of a
divided by two to the power two
how many twos left four
no no no similar mistake then this one
look
imagine they have a twos here
six yeah you see there are a twos
and then you are dividing by two twos
so look turns out how many that
six so it's a minus what a minus two
yeah so a to the power of x divided by a
to the power y equals a to the power of
x minus one right got it
okay so here
so so look this one so equals x minus y
right so if we substitute back we get
this we can get log log a
log a
b c
b divided by c equals log a
b minus block ac okay okay similar okay
i'm going to give a question now okay
lock
face base
minus block 10
okay okay maybe maybe look 30 minus not
10 20 equals
log3 okay lastly
equals one
yeah
one
yeah what is the one
thirty divided by three
yeah because look at those ten equal
this is equal to divided by two yeah
yeah yeah you've got a trick yeah yeah
ryan
yeah you've got a trigger it's one yeah
they're getting now
so what's knockoff here
[Music]
what's the lock
something something
okay so vlog
3 27 what's that what's this number
[Music]
not 3 27 no wait three three yeah
because three to the power of three
equals ten seven you collect yeah
yeah happy
[Music]
okay
time