so let's let's say we have an integer we
have number like one
three zero
it could be negative like uh minus 305
and we can rearrange the num digit to
make it as small as we can get okay so
what's if we arrange
but we can't have this leading zero okay
so we can't have like 0 1 3 okay so
what's the smallest number by
we can get three sorry 103.
103. okay
[Music]
wow
okay so that was correct that was that
was all right so let's say we have
another example
uh 102
okay so uh
like that okay what's the smallest
one
uh one zero one two three four five six
okay okay that was correct and how about
okay what's this
nine eight
minus
okay so
okay so that was correct that was quick
so how how would you do it i mean what's
your thoughts about doing this
okay for the negative it could be easier
so what's the negative what's this
decreasing order
yeah but for the positive we can't have
the zero in the beginning so what do we
do so we take this
say we like skip the zero and then and
give it up for the second number and
then i and then put the
plus
yeah okay so for example this one we saw
the digit that would be zero one
one two three four all right
and so first the num zero is one so we
put a one and then we put a zero and
then we put the rest yeah yeah wow
that was quick okay okay quick
yeah so let's implement this easier it's
very easy
define let's say find
smallest
let's say n uh
okay so if n equal let's special case if
it's zero let me just do this yeah
okay
then if let's say if n is smaller than
zero right
smaller than zero so we just said we
just saw the digits in decreasing
numbers right
all right right
right
so first of all we take the
we
we take
we take the number we converted a string
and we break down
into a
array of digits so what does this mean
we actually look if n is one two three
so str n is
a
string type of one two three and then
putting the list you become
one
two
three okay
why do we need to do this because in a
string we can sort the string directly
strings are immutable what's immutable
remember what's immutable you can't
change it you can't change it so that's
why we need to convert it to an array of
of digits so we can solve this yeah then
we can sort it yeah we can sort these so
now we just return
uh first of all if it is smaller than
zero we need to put a negative sign
right
now all we put it will use the abs which
is essentially as negative n
then we just return
we give a minus sign yeah
minus sign plus
sorted
okay so
first of all if we give this sorted
sorted b c s and then reverse reverse
equals true right reverse equals true
then you'll be reversing and how do we
convert an array of string into a string
how to can we
concatenate it into one two three
sorry how do we do it look from here to
here
remember
what's what the function do we need to
use
we need to use
john yeah so we join
join
journey state salty yeah join this bit
uh john here
[Music]
yeah and then that will be yeah
that's for uh let's for the negative
cases so look if we don't put a reverse
equals true we can sort it and then we
can how do we reverse it if this is s
how do we reverse it
reverse it
um
now okay so now
we do these airs okay as positive
so the same s equals least
str
n right because it's positive we just do
the positive and i know we need to sort
it yet we need to sort it first
yeah
look we can sort it look this function
dot thought written nothing okay return
nothing if we want to directly use the
soft thought value we need to use this
iterator sorted
s okay you can put the parameters
reverse equals true or you use the
column kind of minus one when when we
get it and we reverse it once okay and
then we do it sort it now we just need
to go find the xy uh the value here for
i
in immune rate
[Music]
first non-zero that would be 10
return
uh
s up to i
plus c plus s i plus 1
to the n okay and then obviously this is
the uh
i mean the this is this is an array so
we have to join yeah we have to join it
um so look this one is from a string
return a string time and if we want to
return the integer type we put that we
just convert it to an integer right so
if c not equals
then
we can
we can do this s up to i this is the
index up to i right this is uh
up to i uh possibly we need to join it
and plus the
uh
[Music]
okay so s is
yeah
so
s up to i this is the array up to uh
so let's say we have uh
um
that example yeah one zero
one two three minus and then
we have one we have minus zero so look
we could have multiple zero at this time
so that's why we have we can we need to
concatenate anything up to the
up to
index line where index i is the first
non-zero which is c right so concatenate
so when we sort it will be minus
zero
one one two three okay so first of all
we wanna find this i which is non
yellow right and we put we get all the
yellows before that and then we put
these character and then we put all the
characters after index right so here
and then we
obviously we need to join yeah we need
to join
we need to draw and return
and then we we can convert it to the
string yeah right
yeah so look this is okay and we can use
the but it looks like we haven't
returned anything here it could be
i mean
but the thing is that we
do
do we expect the return here i mean
so does it return does he ever come to
this point
does it ever come to this point because
look i only i'm only we're only
returning these in this if statement and
there's a chance that is there a chance
that the if statement
is not being
executed
so
does it ever come here the thing is that
no why is that because if any zero it
just written here right so this case
would be the positive number
right would be positive so here that
would be positive b here would be
positive let's say
if it's positive then you will come here
for sure right
all right doesn't make sense
yeah because look this is looking for
the first non-zero characters long zero
digits
but
but if if we are assuming that the first
non-zero
digit never exists
then what does it mean
if you come and find any first non-zero
digit now what does it mean it's a
yellow right
yeah i think with zero it's here
yeah so we have really solid so
so
he would never come here you'll never
come here okay
but we can use that look at this this
function we are we are actually looking
for the first nine digit uh characters
uh digits so we can use the next
function next we'll be doing this
exactly the same so we can turn this
into i this is the index
next
next one
next let's say x c
for
x okay for x t
in enumerate
s y
if
c not equal
right so this function will give me the
index first index that is num that
contains the non-zero
digit right so then we can do this we
can do this here we can
integer
uh this is positive case okay then dot
join
the join
s up to i
plus
plus one
s up to i
plus s i plus one right
as
uh s
actually here it will be
uh because we add so we we need to put
the s i first yeah s i
plus
john s up to i and plus s i plus one to
the end okay
uh okay so there's a mistake here okay
so because look
we find the index of uh we find the
index of the first nine digit
long yellow digits so then we have to
put it in the beginning right
yeah we have to the beginning so this is
uh pretty beginning so it should be
put in beginning yeah okay
does it make sense eric
okay
uh
okay so
what's the time complexity if there are
n digits in the end
if this this number has n digit okay
what's the what's the
what's the if there are n digits
what's the time conducted to solve the
okay
okay so here okay i'm going to write it
a little bit messy here right if c not
equal zero that would be ten
first of all we want to convert the
integer we put a c at the beginning
plus
dot join
s
up to i
plus s i
plus one to the n okay all right come on
okay i'm going to explain it one more
time okay
i see enumerate is index is the content
when c is not zero so we find the first
number
you know
because we already started yeah so we
put this num digit at the beginning
right all right yeah and then we put
put the
put the thing up to it at the beginning
uh at the end the next and then we'll
put them
put a remaining at the end okay so let's
say
let's say we're given another example
minus this is positive case yes okay
positive case two zero zero
two zero zero one three four okay so
what's the smallest number you can get
by
by using the digits here one zero zero
wait one zero
zero
two three four okay well yeah that's
correct why is that look we have we
first of all we saw this digit by
you become zero zero one two three four
right
we
we have this family's first none yellow
digit we put it at the beginning one
and i will put this
this is i right so s i
plus s i up to i which is which is 1
which is 0 0 right and plus s
i plus 1 to the n which is this bit
yeah
ok
make sense
yeah look this is i so we have to what
are we doing here is we find this i
index
all right s up to i
is the zero the zero could be many zero
it could be one zero or could be
not
none uh could be nothing okay
up to here here
and s-i plus one here to the end right
do you get it
yeah okay that's it for today good job
bye