go
hello hello everyone
okay okay too loud okay we got um today
we're going to talk about something uh
interesting special it's a turtle
programming and we know the tattoo yeah
you know you we have a canvas and then
we can control we can send a command to
the turtle
yeah so
to do that here we can import so we can
import front from twitter
import everything yeah the
how do we pronounce this this y chart
star everything it means everything okay
okay and then we look remember the ft
for what yeah
for what
backwards yeah fd4 for what forward 100
then you come up with uh
yeah you see you will come up with the
these
uh okay
you come up with list so i just have to
uh i have to
okay so i have to make
change it to these windows to be able to
capture these okay
uh okay so here ah it's too big okay so
let's make it here yeah yeah
okay yeah yeah so you see the
it's it's drawing a line yeah drawing a
line that turtle is drawing on the line
yeah got it yeah
actually here yeah drawing online
so uh maybe i'll put it here put it here
okay so now look
the turtle is facing right yeah and this
is yeah and we can ask it to hide it
height or for high tutor yeah
ht and then it's gone yeah the opposite
will be short third st it will be left
right
yeah turn left 90 degrees or
left or
lt 90 degrees
uh just
look at the turtle yeah you'll be
turning up right
for what another hundred
yeah
okay and there's an a command called
home so it means that when no matter
where is the turtle then it will be will
be sending the turtle home right so if
we press enter then you'll be going home
right home is the center right
yeah
makes sense okay so we we can set a
color so let's say we can set a color
color right so color let's say color red
and then look the turtle is red now
right then we can do what we can put a
circle
it takes one parameter the second
parameter is optional so let's say
circle 100
so like you will draw a circle
you see you see the animation right next
circle because we have uh the speed
let's see the the total of the tether
speed which is three so we can set it
too fast let's say we
put it to a fast speed fast and then
let's draw uh
so what so uh let's kill the screen
first yeah clear means clear everything
and then let's do the circle again
you see is it faster
i don't even see the difference you
don't see the difference let's see the
speed let's see the speed speed is done
and let's set the speed to 0 which is
the 40s
and then let's clear the screen again
okay then look at the circle look
instant yeah yeah that's the speed there
species the fast fastest
okay so now we have talked about
the basic comments basically we
we import these commands this is from
turtle programming the logo right
remember we talked about the logo before
right yeah so we can control uh twitter
to draw on the
canvas and we can we can also set a fear
uh fear color
i think it's fear color let's say green
oh for your color feel color maybe
green
yeah okay if your color is going without
underscore okay fair color green
then we can begin here
then we can say circle
do another smaller one which is 50
okay and then that's the end here
okay now you will feel the last drawing
shape to green right
got it it's eyeball
oh yeah very creative yes looks like
okay okay so now let's let's say let's
say we want to draw a
uh
square with a hundred so how how would
you how would you draw a square
how do you draw a square forward
yeah how would you draw a square uh
[Music]
90 degrees and then we want to report
repeated four times yeah so remember
this we are in python yeah we are in
person so basically we can use the
python for loop right right yeah we
don't have to use the the for loop the
repeat command in logo remember
previously we use the repeat in
in in a repeat repeat for this is the
logo command yeah ft 100 rt90 degree
right this is the location
right but instead we don't have a repeat
here but we have a four loop for
underscore in range four right
okay then what's ft a hundred
rt 90 degree okay and then that's it you
see
nano blue square right yeah and then
look we also sometimes we don't want to
leave the marks for the turtles right so
we want the turtle to be
to have his feet up so it doesn't leave
any
uh
marks on the canvas so we have a pu pens
up
yeah so let's say clear
first turns out
turns up
okay now ft 100 look it doesn't it
doesn't draw anything
right you skip right because the pens is
up yeah now we we the the opposite is
pretty sound yeah or pd
and f300
yeah
yeah got it
so we can use this to draw a dashed line
right all right
yeah okay let's let's do this
four let's set the color to
the first color is the color of the pen
the second color is the fear color okay
let's say to black or blue
okay then f4 for in range ten
so what do we want to do so we first of
all we want to paint up
pens up yeah
and then we want to skip
10 we want to skip 10 and then we're
going to punch down
all right then we want to draw another
10. yeah
okay let's see you see you see do we see
a dash line here
yeah
okay
yeah make sense
okay okay we talked about the circle
command and circuit command the first
parameter is the size of the circle the
second parameter is the
the how how much uh
how big no no it's the portion of the
circle you want to draw for
if we don't specify the second parameter
you'll be drawing a whole circle but if
we
let's let's send it to home first okay
here
let's say if we want to draw a half of
the circle so we say 100 and then 180
because the circle is 360 degree right
so 180 is halfway so look that's a half
yeah you see
half of it
and i want to
let's okay let's say we want to draw
like three quarters of the circle so
what should i put with the second
parameters
no no half is 180 so 120
i mean three quarters
three
quarters now one quarter is ninety three
quarters is
twenty seventy
yeah three yeah two hundred seventy yeah
okay
yeah okay so this is the circle comma
and we can also have uh what we can also
to do something more interesting like
like like what we can draw
a star
yeah do you remember the star
repeat five times
100 but we need to turn
144 degrees and that will give us a star
yeah
okay make sense
so
yeah you can see we can uh what else can
we do i mean but you know we can use the
turtle to draw and then wait a few
intervals yeah we can do this animation
why why because the
uh
that's the speed yeah we show the speed
is let's say to
slow okay so if we say circle 100 then
the the
turtle will be showing the animation
he'll be moving but we can draw
something
erase something
yeah and then draw another yeah so
another useful command is undo what's
undo mean
uh you undo what you lost yeah yeah look
undo
yeah it's unto okay and then we can do
another undo
uh one two
and two is it
i know yeah
okay
yeah that's undo okay
so uh probably there's a eraser yeah
we don't have right and another eraser
here okay uh we do do we have a reader
that's interesting probably no we don't
have read okay what else do we have let
me just quickly check okay so
let's say we have uh okay so let's let's
say copy a few commands to see
okay let's see let's copy these copy
these
uh
okay
what do we have
no no oh
oh
oh oh wait wait the
program crashed let's launch it again
okay let's launch it again okay
let's see what happened here
make it bigger
so
first of all
let's copy these
what's this let's say from tutor
import everything
color red
yellow the red is the pen of the color
the yellow is the filled color okay so
you give me these
yeah you give me this that's fine
uh
let's move it to the right and then
all right because there's a begin
begin fear
y uh true
let's say fd 200
left
170 degree
if
abs position this is the position if
it's smaller than one now we break
okay
and then
oh oh look it's drawing look look it's
drawing is it drawing
yeah it's in this animation ah that's
why it was stacking for for a while
dummy
wow you see sorry doing something nice
here so what what commands do we have
her here okay so we can set the
history it's done and we can do what we
can do the end field and let's feel it
and here
okay look look yeah it feels into the
yellow yeah
okay
that one is tiny yeah
okay that one is tiny okay so uh let's
say let's clear it first
and we can set the heading set heading
heading let's say i said heading 90
degree then you would tend to the
string north right it's it's yeah this
is the absolute value so you can say
it's a hundred eight 180 whenever no
matter where your turtle is heading it's
always pointing to the same because that
you turn left and turn right this is
like a relative degree right yeah yeah
because let's say
if you turn left 90 degree what happened
the 90 degree is not the absolute value
all right
do you get it yeah
okay
so what what else do we have uh
pen up and down pen size installed reset
clear yeah we have a reset what's reset
it says set everything to the beginning
so including the color yeah the coloring
is being reset
uh
yeah okay
so any questions so far
okay you can
you can
look backwards 100 yeah backward 100 is
the same as forward minus 100 yeah it
supports the negative
parameters as well and again backward
100 minus 100 is the same as forward 100
right
yeah
okay okay so let little b then we can
close these by
buy
buy and then we'll close this window
okay
yeah happy
okay that's it for today
we're gonna see you look i don't see you
bye
bye okay bye-bye oh yeah
bye-bye