hello
hello hello hello guys okay so today
we're going to talk about this um
this this bash bash bash
patch script okay
so look this is the window yeah this is
a window usually this is windows windows
operating system yeah it's a huge
graphic user interface that allow us to
interact with the computer look this is
the photo and then i can create a new
photo right let's say eric and i click i
can create another photo called ryan
right
[Music]
yeah and i also can create some text
text wise say hello all right yeah and
then if i click on that and i put
something in okay probably
chinese that's okay hello let's say i
put the hello in okay you can't see here
okay so this is the way that uh
we interact with the computer using the
graphic user interface yeah windows yeah
you can use the mouse control it okay so
today we're going to talk about some uh
commands that we can use we can do the
similar tasks using these uh scripting
like the command line you know the
command line look this is a command line
so it gives us a prompt
right eric are you okay yeah look this
is justine is the username yeah oh yeah
this is
desktop
come on desktop this is the
this is
where it is so it means that now i'm
operating on this desktop
and then there's a column and that's the
path that's the photo path okay so look
if i if i do this list a s means list
yeah so if i do this look it has eric
folder right and photo and hello yeah
which you just created and we if we want
to see the content of hello then we can
see cat
yeah this is command cat
cat is is cat yeah cat hello
yeah
and then you show hello right because
this is our created look you know you
probably noticed that i didn't actually
type in the hello.txt what what i did is
autocomplete look i press h and press
the tap
tap key and then it will auto complete
the rest for us right so it's a quick
way to complete this completed uh the
command okay so let's say you look at
this is the card the account is the
command to to display yeah look i want
to make another photo which is called
mkdir yeah
let's say mkdr test
okay so you see look we have got a new
new photo test here right
look we want to remove the test photo
then we can do this rmdir
test okay now we remove it you see it's
gone yeah
yeah
yeah okay so now look we can copy the
file hello.txt let's say we can do cp
for copy
hello.txt let's say i want to copy it to
a.txt
and let's say
let's say we have got the a dot txt and
then if we
cut the content a dot dxt
it will be the same okay then we can use
the vin it's a text editor to edit the
file
yeah look this is a file yeah then if we
can do this
anything with this is that and when we
want to save it
we want to save it we just press press
one oh no no we press the
we want to save it oh yeah okay that's
it
let's see we will just press the
esc and then we press the wq wq in
command okay to save exit all right then
let's see the content a.txt look this is
the content you see you see
it's updated yeah
yeah okay let's remove this file rm
a dot txt so look rm is a very powerful
command it can allow us to remove a
photo and also a file if we want to
remove everything we can do this remote
dash
r means recursively everything including
the subfolder files false means false
you know just don't remove without
asking even asking i want to remove
everything in every photo right
then we'll be gone look everything's
gone right okay let's make it back
yeah
yeah let's make it back okay so look
this is uh what have we learned so far
so we have uh
then the ais yeah yes look we can add
stash air means to
list one item per plan yeah you see so
you give us the
give us every look oh yeah yeah yeah
oh yeah okay listen listen
okay so what have we learned this
file
what's the command of cat
um
cat display the content
remove the photo and the files remove
dir
means that only remove the directory if
it's empty if it's not empty what
happened look let's move let's copy a
file color and then let's copy under to
let's the second parameter is the
designation under the average yeah okay
so now if we go into the eric so we will
see a hello yeah we just copy yeah right
now if we say here we want to remove the
directory of eric it won't allow us to
do it because it says direction not
empty right we have to remove we have to
this i'm glad
okay i'm not removing okay okay another
command is cd if we want to go into the
eric photo like like right here yeah so
we use the c
cd means the change directory eric okay
then we are here yeah look you see this
path
is passed is updated and we if we want
to go go up
go up one directory we use the cd
yeah cd dot dot means go up one
direction and then now look we're going
back to the teaching directory yeah okay
like if we want to clear this screen we
use that's clear
and then everything is gone yeah
okay okay
so we have learned what have we learned
come on come on we have what have we
learned a ls
cat no no please don't don't air s cat
cd i am i am dir cat and cat what what
else
m k d i make a diot yeah
and the i am this is text editor okay
and okay so now let's
another command which is usually to
display the command to the console which
is called echo what's echo mean a
command copy no no no echo what's echo
copy
to display copy let's say this hello
eric and ryan okay look you see hey
that's copying
okay okay
point point to the screen that's exactly
the same thing okay yeah come on
okay look
look this is echo yeah right we can do
this look
let's say we can say name we can set we
can say the variable like name
name equals eric okay then we can say
what hello echo hello
name okay look i use the dollar sign i
use the dollar sign
to
to to say i want to display the content
of the
name which is it will give me like hello
because i already said name equals array
got it
yeah the dollar sign means that this is
the variable okay what did you say
now another command is that look if i
want to input this look i can use the
arrow key up
to
to to to show the last command yeah
alternatively i can control r which is
as
uh you you allow us to type in a few
keys to search let's say i want to say
ar and look c u i c
yeah you will have a a few commands for
us to choose okay
hello
okay it doesn't search pretty well right
it doesn't search word pretty well
hello okay this is command that allow us
to search but anyway so let's say echo
hello uh let's say we want to put these
hello arrogant writer into a file
so we use the list greater means
redirection we want to redirect it to
the file which is called what a.txt
right
okay then
a dot txt will be created with the
content hello everything right
there look press it and then look we've
got a.txt right yeah yeah okay
a dot txt oh yeah look look cat cat a
dot txt what will happen
a dot txt will happen uh a dot txt will
yeah what's the content of a.txt
that
what did what is the previous command
hello eric all right and i want to put
it in a.txt cad is displayed the content
of ada yes so we put so we like uh get
out yes you see
eric okay so look i want to copy a file
cp hello to another file a.txt so yeah
yeah
then okay you'll be there right another
command which is called date
date what's day
what's the meaning of date uh the day
or a day yeah look it gives you the
house it gives us the date yeah and the
time the time day yeah it's
so
so what's the difference between this
way of controlling the
computer or and this way
you're using a mouse to click
which one do you think it's more
powerful which one is more user friendly
this one is more powerful right
this one is more user-friendly right
yeah yeah yeah yeah because graph user
interface is for like non-programmers
like mommy yeah mommy just like to use
the mouse to to click yeah to do the
daily work but this is for computers for
us engineering yeah because we can use
the powerful commands to
you know to do more complex
task which cannot be done in graph user
interface doesn't make sense
okay
yeah make sense
yeah for example i want to display look
look i want to display like uh hello
hello ten times how can i do it
we do it like 10 times okay so we can
use the four here here we have four okay
so okay so what's the syntax for i
i i i i
tend to sequence
10.
uh
okay so this is this command is not
quite
uh i forgot the syntax actually it's
that command
oh okay okay it's 4i in
sequence one ten
one
two
okay echo hollow
[Music]
uh okay so it does okay maybe i think i
think a bit you your brain went a bit
okay
what's that one i think one
one
ten one okay one two one okay
uh
okay so i forgot let's let's say see the
command of
seq what does this say
uh first increment last okay so the
parameter sequence is not right okay for
i in
in
sequence first increment last right boom
echo hello
you give me ten times yeah you see yeah
but you go wrong last time yeah i know
but look
the command i show is mine is to show
the manual of a command let's say man of
cd change directory uh it doesn't have a
man
[Music]
cd right no no because these commands so
simple that they they don't there there
was even there wasn't even a menu for it
that man removed let's see if they don't
remove okay okay look remove the fire
supply directly you see
yeah it gives us the the manual the hep
yeah it gives us what's this command
used for and then the options like look
with dash f means first yeah and then we
show a dash r because it removes
directory in the contents because yeah
got it
yeah
okay so so
so clear means everything yeah
uh so okay so to sum up what have we
learned today
so that's a summary
summary
let's say cat
which is still the command of the file
cd changes directory cd dot means
changing the up one directory up
and echo echo a line which we can echo a
variable right
yeah and what else remove remove a file
imdi remove a directory
and what else
uh
mkdir make dial tree yeah
okay and then what else
we have a s this is the content of the
file of the photo yeah
what else
uh
okay echo yeah we have
shown echo
sequence oh yeah that's a good good way
sequence generator sequence now first
the increment
and then and and we also show uh
a for loop right
yeah and what else
what commands do we
oh yeah yeah good idea clear clear
screen yeah let's see oh yeah i'm so
smart
okay okay okay what else
what else
uh noida okay let's save it okay look
this is we have uh
let's see i'm kettle name clear here cp
yeah i think that'll be yeah that will
be that will be i think okay a little
bit let's cut a summary yeah look at the
summary look yeah you see catastrophe oh
yeah we also show the the direction yeah
look the last bit is that look we can we
can echo aaa to a dot txt
and then we display the content of a.txt
which is a
yeah look if i do another one alright if
i do another one echo bbb
redirect to a txt and then a dot txt
with we only contain the latest one
which is b tdt but if i want to append
it i can use two
greater so look look look
b
a dot txt contains bbb yeah if i say cc
yeah there are two greater than yeah
to a dot txt and what's the content of
a.txt bbbcc okay let's do another one
echo ddb
bigger bigger a dot txt that means i
want to append ddd to the content of
a.txt and let's show the content a dot
txt look yeah
yeah look single one is to replace
yeah single
greater sign is to replay double greater
sound is to
append to at add yeah this is one
one good difference
okay that will be it for today
okay bye bye