hello
hello mr mr ryan okay so what's this
uh
we have learned this before yeah do we
have it michael beat yeah so this is
actually a very useful
very powerful
device little device okay yeah
yeah
okay so it's it's like this one this one
look yeah this one it's a it's tiny it's
a tiny and they say how many dots on it
twenty-five five rows five columns yeah
it's a it's a little device by bbc if
you look at it it says bbc micro bit
okay
this is the
uh emulator so
so you see on the left swing yeah this
is kind of this little version on the on
the computer so you can see how
uh the code works okay
so we have a bunch of tools here the
basic input these these are very useful
that
you know it allows us to just drag and
drop you know with this
drag and drop the
the the stuff yeah the stuff the logic
to the this is the code area which i
choose python uh you know previously we
learned about javascript yeah the person
we have learned python all these days so
let's just try to use the price so how
to prove how uh to show how it works
let's say
we we can just do this let's say basic
dot show string
and let's just
print basic is module and that's your
string hello
yeah so if we click on this
then you will have this hello yeah
got it
yeah okay so i have got this little
device here
it's connected to my usb
yeah but then i i can
look this is the code yeah which is just
one that shows hello and then if you
look at here
uh
okay so should i please die
hello
okay hello yeah if you see hello yeah
and then you prove that it works all
right in this in this simulator then we
can download it it's pink yeah we can
download it yeah he asks us to pair well
that's fine we just download the file
download down
and then we can just drag and drop these
files to the usb
micro bit
yeah and then it's it's downloading to
the little device microphone here i
can't see it yeah they can't see because
i'm not showing that window but it's
just a window to show the trends
downloading to the microphone okay and
that's it and you see hello hello yeah
you see hello
yeah
this is it yeah this is it okay so
that's how we get
write the code test it on computer on
this uh screen and then once everything
is okay we download it here and then we
can play yeah you might also see this
there are two buttons pizza yeah two two
two buttons these are
pizza which is just right then you have
to catch them yeah when you press a you
go left and b you go right okay yeah
normally we do it like that okay okay
yeah yeah we did it maybe we can we can
do it tomorrow okay we can do it
tomorrow look look
these this is the screen which is output
and a and b is the input and there are a
few pins yeah which you we don't have to
worry about you know these these pins
are connected to the hardware you know
some other hardware but all we care now
is a b this is the input two buttons
which we can see
it's an input yeah you can use as a
joystick controller and then this is a
screen and then if you can connect
with this pin sometimes you can connect
to a speaker and you can connect to a
camera right yeah connect to a sensor
etc okay so let's do something
useful for example if i want to say
press a then we want to show the
character a and press b we want to show
the character b on the screen that look
here we have the input look here yeah
and then here it says
run code on button
pressed and now we can just drag and
drag here yeah you see and this is the
curve you just generalize that on button
is it defined yeah we need there python
yeah input
button press button a on button press
now we can say
basic dot show
show show string
a okay
and then similarly similarly
similarly what do we do we can just
press do another copy and paste
and then we can say on button b
and then here on button b yeah
and here on button b
okay and then we can here it's nothing
yeah but look press a
a
press b b
yeah do you see they look we define two
functions
button a and button b button a
actual button show a button b should be
input on button pressed looking event
tells us what is this function for you
do something when a button a b oppose a
plus b is cross down and release again
so okay this is very interesting you can
you can control when two buttons are
pressed together yeah yeah okay
so so look if i if i download it to that
to here then you'll be this you'll be
working here you yeah
okay so
yeah
do you get it now yeah look these are a
few more interesting things
don't worry about this math because we
learned about this programming python we
can just do all this math stuff yeah
logic yeah logic if else yeah this is
quite simple to you right yeah we know
the python if if statement yeah the mass
yeah plus minus multiple divide this is
basic yeah
arrays here we talk about arrays so so
these just are useful you know for kids
yeah but not for you right yeah because
you learn a lot right yeah got it okay
your kids are as well okay and show test
yeah it's your test this is easy
okay the other thing we want to talk
about is ldd so how do we control this
little dot 525 on the screen so we have
this led
dot plot okay this is unplugged actually
dot plot
plot so if plot zero zero is the first
stop so if i do that then the first
first dot
yeah it's turned on yeah okay
all right let's try plus one zero so
look x y
so x y x is horizontal y is vertical so
x y so you'll be brought the two dots
yeah okay
do you get it yeah okay so now we have
another one called unplot so let's say
we want to unplug the aed.unplot and
plot
one zero
so actually you only show
one dot right because the second dot is
plotted and then we unplot it
immediately so we can't see it turn on
right so we see this this is actually
very useful
so we can control it so how let's say we
want to control a dot
okay a dot
going from left to the right up to the
down and then we when it goes to the
bottom
and you go back to the first one right
so how do we do it let's say x equals
zero y equals zero right
yeah so we have something here which is
called control
uh
one code uh
do we see one code
every
a few seconds or probably where is it
once probably a once i know
no
uh loops no loops oh run code every
interval okay so this is useful let's
just put it here look every interval 500
let's put it as 200 milliseconds on
every interval so let's say
global x
y okay so this is to allow us to control
these two variables so what do we want
to do first of all we want to plot
for the location right after the
location now we want to
actually let's unplot it first and then
we want to x plus
x is horizontal yeah x plus equals x
plus equals one
then if it goes to the right so if x
equal equal
0 1 2 3 4 5 if it equals 5 it means that
it's beyond the screen it's on the right
hand side so what we want to set is x
equals 1 then y needs to plus equals 1
right because going down right then if y
equals 5 again then y means to go back
to
what go back to the zero right
and then we need to plot it again
right all right let's see how it goes
it's not quite right okay so either f1
is not functional this is weird okay so
led plot okay
yeah yeah that's a problem i i have no
idea at the moment x plus equals one if
x equal equal five
means that x s
x is on the right hand side on here
right just right here then x equals to 1
now y needs to plus equals 1 y needs to
move to the next row
right and then if y equals 5
y equals 5 0 1 2 3 4 5 and y 2 equals
zero it seems all right then a d plot x
y
uh
what does it say why it says e is not
either fn is not a function
uh
no idea so
what does it say
what does he say why it says e dot fn
uh
on every interval
so let's say what's that what's the
perimeter of the second one okay right
now you're here
okay what does it say
interval number
to weight in repeat okay so is 200
and then the function which is the on
every interval okay that seems all right
right so unplugged aed and plot x y
and
x plus equals one okay so is there a
problem with this one x
ah x
x equals one okay so that's the problem
if x equals one
if x equals five x equals one
y plus equals one if y equals five no y
equals 0
then we plot it
i don't see an error do you see an error
here
let me just
maybe just refresh the screen
probably
refresh the string to make it better
yeah okay so
uh you see it's moving but why is it
staying on the
on here
is it x equal one ah that's right wow
that's very good
good catch oh yeah you see then
yeah
okay
okay so you see that's how we control
the bits yeah and then send it okay
let's download it download it
downloading
download it uh
okay and i'm going to wait
i'm going to drag this to my copy
and then you ask me to confirm wait wait
no you know you know you know you know
no yeah okay wait 17 completed
17 completely 60 85 okay
you see the dots you see
yeah
okay
okay got it
do you understand wow that's a very good
uh spot okay this one but you get a
point yeah
variables yeah we have talked about the
variables here at this here
the mass okay radius radius we don't
have radius you know at the moment
in in order to use the radius we need to
plug these into some special radar
devices
hey this is the thing we talk about we
actually can actually
change the brightness okay change how
how brightness this finger dot is yeah
okay make sense
okay so let's say we
what else can you do with this thing
single
device with 25 peaks what can you do
just like
okay
[Music]
okay but let's that's a big problem
let's wait until tomorrow yeah yeah
apple catching yeah easy
but have you have it oh yeah it's
interesting for today yeah
okay that's it that's it say bye bye say
bye bye bye
bye bye