hello
hello mr mr ryan hi are you right yes
okay so we today we're going to
talk about making a simple game yeah
which is called the apple catching yeah
so just imagine this we have a
screen little screen with 25 pixels yeah
25 pixels somehow this is not showing
uh
let's just refresh this a little bit so
we have these
25 pixels 25 pixels and we we're going
to make a game that has the random app
falling from
the
top to the bottom and then we have a
little piece
at the bottom to catch it yeah when we
catch it
the score will be incremented and if the
apple
falls down to the
bottom then the game is over yeah the
simple logic is there okay
so
first of all
in order to do this just recall last uh
lesson we we we have a running picture
yeah from left to right from top to
bottom and what we did is to
uh plot it yeah we have a plot
zero zero for example that would plot a
pixel in the first
top left right so we we basically wait
delay or
basic the
uh pause yeah there's a function called
pause pause 100 a thousand means a
second yeah a thousand
and then we unplot it
and plot it and then
when we unplot it then we need to
plot the second pixel uh the next pixel
yeah so basically if you you've combined
all these commands you will pro first
one yeah
yeah delayed a thousand i don't know
it's i think a thousand a second yeah
and unplug the first one and then plot
the next pixel so that that will give us
that kind of this animation right so the
animation is basically like you draw
something on one pixel
you wait a second
yeah wait a few seconds interval and
then you erase it
yeah and then you move to the next pixel
to to draw it and it looks like an
animation but this is too much
too much work yeah we can use the
uh
have a useful thing in micro b which is
called spy sprite okay so we can say
uh you know pixel dot
again dot create sprite so let's say
so we create a sprite at x equals zero y
equals zero so that will give us a pixel
on the top left
yeah now we can ask it to move
move one pixel to the right by default
the direction is to the right so if
you see it moves to right here
and we can ask it to move again
now you move two pixels yeah got it
yeah so look
i i just have two
two so i don't need to erase it
i don't need to erase it instead i just
asked it to move so look this sprite is
kind of that object right it's like a
a thing that you know pig pizza is is
very
uh
it's not really associated with any
object right because pixel is there you
can draw you can erase it but this pixel
is like a sprite it's like an object so
it has something it's an object right
you can ask it to move and then
yeah different viewpoint yeah so look if
we have this picture we can have
different you know delete yeah obviously
we delete it then you'll be gone right
if we didn't go yeah did it
what else do we have it's deleted check
if did it move 10 right so it has
direction you can ask it to turn level
right yeah
change set get is touching okay this is
very useful so we can do some this
very useful
um
collision detection so we can check if
the pixel is touching the edge yeah if
it's touching the edge the edge is the
boundary yeah boundary here
or it's touching another pixel so this
is we're going to use this touching so
we have a picture like apple and we have
another pixel is
yeah yeah you you can say you and then
we can say if it's touching if it starts
it means that we have successfully catch
the iphone right
yeah okay
yeah look at it
yeah look at lots of function and
there's a few functions we're going to
use which is change y by
by one we can just say change y by one
oh we can set the directions to falling
down and then we can move right so it's
the same set brightly yeah how how dark
or bright say directions x right turn
left and right yeah we're going to use
this turn left and right when we descend
a snake again you know when we have a
snake we can ask it to turn left and
right yeah but for today just the change
y will be sufficient yeah change will be
sufficient so so normally we would
define the game using the object
oriented objective like you know class
like game we want to do this
okay
and we define this init function
constructor yeah
yeah but unfortunately it
in micro bit it doesn't support these
kind of complex syntax so so we just do
it by
declaring the variables on you know
beforehand and listed everything left so
first of all we need to have these the
apple right so apple
yeah we define the apple
but the apple
we
uh first we want it to be
random position and random position one
two three four five but on the first row
right so let's say
game.createsprite x is the
zero one you know zero one two three
four so we can have uh
rent in this is to give us a random
number from zero to four
and then y will be zero
yeah so here you will every time
uh okay so there's a problem with this i
think this is the let's refresh this a
bit because i think this is not our
problem
hopefully
we'll come back
is it line 3
no no no
interesting so what happened i mean
so
this uh
[Music]
let's just turn a little bit
monster python okay why is it not coming
back yet
come on come on
okay look it has javascript here you can
look if i switch between javascript and
python look you can automatically
convert your code between javascript and
python yeah you know look look every
time look it now it's on the
last column yeah if i
it's the reset button it's this restart
the simulator if i do this look every
time it will be different right yeah
that's the random tradition you see
yeah because the x is the random integer
so what does it say a random returns a
should random number between mean and
max included
yeah
it's a random number what's random
it could be anything it could be
anything yeah mean max okay so that
these num that basically means that we
want to place uh we want to create an
apple pixel
which is placed randomly on the first
row which is this yellow and then x
position will be one of the five yeah
okay now what's next we have a u yeah u
yeah
let's say u yeah oh oh what
about we usually spell to catch
so but we wanted to place
our bar on the meter of the last row so
that would be
two and
four right
so if you do that here right that's a
little ball yeah look zero one two three
four
zero one two so it's two four okay
yeah this is about okay so now
what is we have this bar so we wanted a
function we want the game to
to to run yeah so we need a few
functions which is the
which is what uh
define
first of all we want to say move left
yeah or move left move left yeah
move left which is what so move left we
want the bow
to move minus one right
yeah so look if
if you keep
moving to the left if it hits the
boundary you'll stay there you you won't
go beyond the boundary so let's okay we
don't have to check if the pixel is is
on
you know it's falling on the left of the
screen right it's going on which we can
just say move to minus one right
define move right
all right
so bow dot
move one right yeah
yeah and then now we need we need to set
it uh associate to the button on button
a press yeah
button a press we want to if we want to
go on move left yeah
a button
move to the left and now we want it to
button b
we want to move to the right right okay
let's test this a little bit look
okay so now a
okay you won't go any further b
you can go any further yeah really
yeah okay now we want also the if we
want to own button press uh a and b i
think it's a and b
yeah a and b pressed together we wanted
to reset the game yeah so reset again i
haven't
uh written this function yet but let's
just put it here
to do it later yeah reset them okay
let's let's just put the placeholder
yeah
okay so now when the game is going so we
want the airport to keep falling right
yeah
so let's say define
uh
game men loop
band
so like apple should be apple should be
falling here apple should
be falling and this is a comment okay so
now we want to say basic
forever yeah
basically forever what does it mean so
it means that the game will will keep
doing this main loop here
right
yeah so now the apple should be falling
down right the apple should be falling
but before that we should wait a few
seconds yeah so let's say we have a game
speed falling speed okay speed falling
speed
falling speed will be
at the beginning will be
let's say um
okay
yeah yeah but we we have we we have to
come up with the concept how to to
control the speed okay so first of all
we have again i think and we actually
have oh look look game dot score yes
this game kendo score thing okay so at
the beginning like i think game the
score is zero okay so so we set them and
we also have uh have to define a game
over thing yeah but we we just put it
here for now game over
so forever look basically for i love
blue so now we just need to basic
the uh
pause
okay the plus
plus let's say just get current speed
okay get currency
pause get current delay okay delay
with the speed current uh speed
falling speed
okay so so we have to come up with a
function to you know we want the apple
to to fall as far uh
faster and faster yeah if you catch 10
apples the apples be falling faster
right if you catch
20 apples
that will be faster so how do we control
this variable so get current today with
the game.score okay
yeah
vendors go
and now we just have to do something
simple like if i get currently layer we
will just we just define this function
we want to uh we want to get to get a
score
variable okay so let's say
if let's just make it simple okay if
score small we can tune this function
later if we score eq smaller than five
yeah we will catch less than five apples
then we won't basically return one
second delay yeah within one second
today yeah one second today
yeah as
if score smaller than 10 right
bigger than five we only return
uh 500
at half second yeah otherwise we only
return
200 milliseconds here okay so
obviously this can be
implemented in many ways right so for
example if you catch one liter apple
that would be increasing the speed a
tiny bit yeah yeah that's one way but
we're using this we can come back to
this function later okay
okay following one one uh
phoning it and then what happened then
we need to say apple
dot
change
uh change by direction by one right
right so it's falling down right
right look then if apple
apple is
if what if apple is what this is
is touching edge right it's touching
edge
first of all we want to check if apple
is touching touching one touching
bar okay or you can say if bow is
touching apple okay similar it's the
same yeah if i touch you it's the same
as if you touch me
yeah so if let's say if bao is touching
apple
so if bao is touching apple then we what
what do we do
so we need to increment the score right
again the
score
score uh set score
cisco
game dot score
score plus one right we have what catch
one more airport right
right i'm right so but now what should
we do we should generally uh
we should move we should move uh upper
back right move upper back to the top
back to the top
okay it looks like
it's it's actually generating a new
apple but we we only have two objects
apple and u so we we just reuse the
upper objects to move it back to the top
makes sense
yeah you understand that meaning you
catch the apple right
apple is gone but here the apple is not
gone we just move it back to the top
yeah but it's the same thing to the user
right
okay so so moving back to the top so
what what should we do now we can say
apple dot
one uh
okay it doesn't talk uh if type of dot
set
okay it doesn't come up please okay i i
need to get this off
set
set uh
go to i think yes go to yeah go to
the second parameter is zero it means
the first row and the first parameter is
the same is that we can
yeah we can put this here yeah so
it means go to the top right
yeah and then low b here that will be
return okay now
if touching the edge so if it's touching
the edge that means the game over right
came over so we have came over
okay return
otherwise what should we do otherwise
otherwise we don't do anything right
yeah
all right
does it fall down no it doesn't fall
down that's weird okay so there's
something wrong with it
uh upper the change direction by one
post delay uh
the current delay
interesting why is not moving down
why is it normally not uh airport don't
move okay okay i see
apple don't move wait why is it why is
it moving
let's just test a little bit what is it
going down
let's just
comment this out yeah
so it doesn't actually this function
doesn't
make the apple going down so oh change
direction it's not changing like this
it's set by
okay set
set uh
change
change y by one okay so i i'm looking
for this function change by one okay so
it's not changing directly because it
changes direction it don't actually move
it stays there right
so it's uh
i i need to
put it here yeah okay and then let's do
it so you keep falling down
okay falling down yeah falling down
falling down from that phone it up catch
it score okay generally another one if i
don't catch it this time what happened
come over get more so what what should i
do with the game over and then i can i
can just
i should do what i should come over so i
should writing thinking yeah yeah yeah i
came over but i i would say
game dot show score right just go
okay so
let's say does it okay okay i'm going to
move a little bit to the right okay
okay that's the score yeah score equals
equals one yellow yeah yeah okay
yeah so basically that was yeah okay so
so let's reset again let's reset this a
bit okay now i'm catching this apple so
my score should be one okay
okay now i i
intentionally missed the apple okay so
what happened the score should be one
right
hopefully it should be one come on come
on
one yeah you see
yeah
okay so
so we get it so okay i think that's it
right so we have a few functions we
second so what do we do with every
second
so if we press a and b we should reset
again so we should again
this function is complete this one
so how do we reset the game that's a
very interesting
point if uh upper is
okay so why you keep doing this pause
pause change y touching touching
okay even every second i basically i
would just create a rewrite list a bit
yeah
so i will just rely this stupid
okay
so
let's do
okay look we have two more iphones
okay so that's not right because every
time we create it so recipient would be
apple dot delete first okay delete first
and then bar
we need to delete it first yeah
okay let's try this logic
reset uh
what reset kev
oh that's not right
why is r because the release set game i
the second is why is it not working in
this case
so probably i
i'm looking for a game
even the level of life wow lots of this
useful function okay game over ah we
should use this game game dot is game
over instead
so we we should just scan the show and
then come the game over and now make
things easier and then look at mandop
then if game is game over it's already
game over i should return right yeah all
right
yeah
so every second we have again the
uh
what else resume oh he even has this
pause and resume button
right so
let's don't worry about this for now
let's try again
okay
why is it
because of this i think it's probably
that let it just comment this oh i don't
get it at the moment
okay
why
what happened
pause change is touching go to
okay come over
look if
if
that's okay
the semicolon is allow python to put two
statements look you can say x equals 1 y
equals 1 here right then you can put it
2 in the same 9 x equals 1 and then y
equal 1 yeah
yeah that's the use that's the use usage
of the semicolon but it doesn't affect
anything so like why i just don't
understand why you would just just go
quickly what did i just do
huh what did i just do
three seconds it doesn't affect ah game
over show
[Music]
but you just immediately done that
yeah but that's a function
the function only
happens when
apple is touching the edge ah okay okay
because apple is touching the edge so
apple is the the top is also the edge
yeah so it when the apple plays on the
first row
then you're immediately touching the
edge you immediately came over right
yeah makes sense so so we should do this
so we instead of touching that we can
say if apple dot
y
uh
dot
y i think
republic
yeah equal equal four right
yeah
okay then let's target
yeah you see
okay
okay now let's take it let's restart uh
it doesn't do it okay because i haven't
i haven't reset the game so
let's put this back yeah please back
apple dot did it
uh did it and then bow down
and then we also need to reset the game
yeah we said
score
set score equals zero right because at
the beginning the score is zero right
yeah
and then
game
resume
restart resume
i think it's resumed right resume
when we create it now we resume let's
try this logic a little bit try
okay that's i move this
okay
okay that's fine okay no no i i don't i
won't miss it
okay
game over and if i press this one okay
three seconds uh fails custom undefined
nine twenty seven
return two hundred
this is not right why is this
fair custom and define sim error okay so
i i believe this is not my problem
yeah let's try again
reset again uh why the second views
did it
probably doesn't like this one let's
just directly try this reset button
huh how do we reset the game
how to do this again let me check the
uh
how to really set the game
um probably we don't we just don't don't
reset again
yeah we don't need to uh okay okay
to
score we just need to
we just need to
set the score to zero
a little bit we probably don't need this
game
let's just do a little bit
we don't need to reset we just set the
score to zero
we just set the score to zero and i know
okay
we second okay
and then we
set a score then we need to upper needs
to
set y to zero to move to the first four
okay first first row okay let's try this
look
okay reset again and then move to the
top yeah okay and uh yeah a little bit
yeah okay so now it falls to the end it
come over and i press this one okay
interesting so it doesn't actually reset
but still it's kind of like a setting
okay maybe this is the higher result
okay so we don't worry about using these
to reset actually this is the result
reset the simulator
i see yeah yeah yeah so a plus we don't
actually resend the game
in in we don't actually reset the game
in in
in
in the logic we just use the simulator
to reset the game
i think that would be three seconds and
because we're calling the game over at
game over
so probably we can do this game
resume yeah let's let's try if we have
okay
come over let's move to the right game
over yeah and then reset no it doesn't
affect so how can we bring the game back
to the live
because we're using this uh
uh another way another way because this
shows score and then
again the
pause
we use a pause and lb
pause when the game is passing now we if
the game is paused is is
post then we just return yeah
okay and then now we can do this resume
button let's try again
okay
okay you fall down fall down hold on
and then press i get no it doesn't help
okay we reset
okay
we set this bit
okay now it goes to the top
okay so i actually i don't know why why
this it shows the score ah it shows the
score it pause
okay now it's zeroing the score yeah it
paused
score is zero
okay it's there and i'll press this okay
now it works because the yeah it's
working because this is the line 16
showing the score it was still showing
score it can't be interrupted
right so once it's slow it's there and
then
okay it's there then if you want to lose
that game press this and then start
again yeah
okay so now we can do this uh with the
score so probably we can come up with a
function to make it faster and faster
when the speed um
so let's say let's say let's come up
with this function
okay let's come up with the
yeah the score and the delay equals 500
minus time
you know when the score look when the
score is incrementing
the score is one the delay
when the score is zero delay is 500 when
the score is one
delay is 490 when score is 2 delay is
480 so it's becoming faster faster okay
now we have to set that limit
maximum
the
the minimum today is 50 then we can
replenish it okay now now you'll come
you will become faster and faster okay
let's try again look
let's just try okay okay faster
okay two you see it's faster
yeah you become faster and faster until
i lose it yeah come on
actually i can if i can make a logic and
i press level you you come up from the
right okay do you understand
yeah instead of going from left to right
okay i probably can't catch it anymore
okay i can still catch it i can still
catch it
i can still catch it i can still tell
you'll become faster and faster yeah
because of the apples i catch the score
is incrementing oh look at the score is
implementing the delay is the
decrementing the delay is decrementing
it means the epoch 22. the apple is
falling faster and faster yeah the
airport is falling fast faster so let's
what i'm saying that when the move minus
one you will he stopped at the left
boundary and one moved one it would stop
at the right boundary but instead i
could i could do what move one right if
move one and then look what i'm saying
is that if i can say bow
dot is touching if it's already touching
the edges right
touching the edges then i can say about
dot set
x would be
to the beginning yeah look
look okay all right
yeah touching the edge and the phone
yeah you see look
i can i can
oh wait we said again
uh let's just uh
okay
oh oh wait wait wait
if the logic is not power equals i'll
return return
i need to return it
okay let's try again
while i press the
b will come to the left
move left minus one more y ah but
we are touching okay i make the same
mistake because it's touching the edge
right so what i'm saying is about
if bar the
dot x is is four then
yeah
if bar
dot x
equal zero then we say okay so now look
what happened
i can go to the right right and i press
right you come to the left i press left
you come to the right you can do do you
see my point
yeah so look
i catch this apple i press again and
come to the left yeah this is the way to
run up to wrap up your bow from the
other side right okay get more where we
talk about that yeah this bit a little
bit trickier
get current delay and more scores faster
less delay
and on button a press left on button y
press uh
on button b press uh go to the right and
this is the main loop of the logic got
it so basically
okay if game pause now just don't return
anything and that possibly falling so
first of all we make a delay we wait
today and then we change y by one so
we're falling down and if it's touching
the apple
we set the score increment score right
and then we move back look here we don't
regenerate the add problem right we
don't regenerate
so what do we do with this
when we when we eat the apple what do we
do with wrapper
we put it we we increment the score we
move it to the top right yeah and return
if if apple dot y equals four for the
last row right it means that we haven't
catch the app we haven't called apple we
haven't eaten apple but the apple is
size four and only ground so in this
case we need to written
game over yeah
make sense that's cool yeah okay let me
look if we look at this is the logic if
we turn into look look if if you do this
visually
yeah look this is visually we are doing
it on the code right doing individually
you can see how the
button ap plus then do this so yeah this
is visualization of your logic forever
yeah just pieces
yeah yeah it's just my password you put
all these puzzles together then they'll
get give you the game right but instead
what do we do with that we just use the
python right use the python
yeah okay
yeah make sense happy okay so the last
thing i'm going to i'm going to download
this yeah give me one of these please
so i'm going to put this here
download here yeah and i'm going to
download download press download
so give me download yes download again
is it downloading
is this is this the
let's download again it's downloading
okay so look it's downloading yeah micro
bit eat apple yeah we name it
so we open it so this is the game uh
yeah we just download it and then we put
it into the micro bit
micro bit
yeah and then it's downloading and once
it's downloaded so we can just play
straight away
here
yeah i'm gonna play straight away it's
still downloading it's still downloading
it's blinking look at the lights is
blinking okay now it's okay look here
look apple is falling here you see and
let's go yeah
okay that's that's
okay
okay some something happened it's not
moving
uh wait
let's reset okay let's place that just
reset
okay look you see
yeah yeah it's actually working yeah you
see
how cool is that
yeah
you see
yeah okay okay
that will be for today good job bye bye
bye say bye to people bye
bye