remember what
we talked about yesterday
today we're going to find another
interesting program which is
interesting to check if the link is has
cycles cycle going
[Music]
does it have cycle yes okay good so
today we're going to
again given this hat and then find an
ethereum to see if elise has a cycle so
any idea how we do it
uh i think because that
that then tv and and then
you can you're gonna do nice and your
department will say how to cycle right
so how do you do that how to do that
specifically you do one
two three four five and that one again
so that means it's
a cycle because we already bought
yeah okay you mentioned something which
is interesting but
we need to remember which notes we have
represented
can you please say okay no running
please it's
youtube come on so look remember what we
have talked about the hash table the
notebook
before yeah so when we visit the note
we put it down our notebook and
before we visit the note we check if
this note has
been written on the notebook yeah if it
is then it's a cycle it has a cycle
right because
we have been visited the first time it's
okay look we're here
we put it in the notebook we travel
travel i know you can oh no visit this
we found this now already appearing on
the notebook
yeah then then
it has a cycle this is one approach so
what's the terminal density
yeah what's the space complexity yeah
well because we're using the
uh we usually have notebook right
notebook the most
you put uh at most you put the n uh
notes on it are you okay yeah okay okay
are there any solutions remember we
talked about the fast and slow
yeah remember does it have in this case
[Music]
can you think of where using the faster
so without a notebook
[Music]
so look three three
wait look this first is the
red one slow is the black one okay
so first two step one two i'm here
slow here okay two step one two
slow here two step one two
slow here you see
so if they meet if they meet there's a
cycle
right if they don't meet they suppose it
can't be a second
am right yeah because fast is always
cool forward
yeah they go forward and then if they
meet you know
the meat collide in here it means that
there is a cycle otherwise the
left is always faster than entertainment
right yeah got it
okay so now we can yeah what's the time
capacity of this one
what's the space complexity no
a one because we're only using the fast
and slow
these two points at least are constant
because no matter how big
the the the link is right these
i only use two right slowing down yeah
okay do you understand yeah the space is
all one because we we're only using two
points and no matter how big the
link is it doesn't change but the
notebook is different
if we're using a minion uh if the linked
list has the minion items and then the
more book
the notebook has to be and at least
store a million items right because
you're putting the item on their own
notebook right yes yes okay
so now let's do one
one the first first implementation yeah
defined
has cycle
head what's missing no
problem so now we have a visit remember
we talked about the set before yeah the
notebook yeah set
read it set yeah why
hat is not long
why is we are not reaching the end right
yeah now we have to check if if
head in this we have visited this right
yes
return left two
right yeah head equals
head dot next next return false
and then here we turn fast right yeah
so that's what that's one approach okay
then i'll hover let's do it
this second one okay and i mean let me
do it yeah
let's take someone uh
the second approach we don't need this
we don't need this
yeah we have a fast
slow or equals head
head and what why
fast
fast fast is one fast
is not noun and okay i don't have space
but you know fast is not long
and fast don't next is not known
right then fast equals fast dot
next dot next right because we'll travel
two step at a time and that's now
because what slide dot net
yeah and then we need to check we are
fast
[Music]
yeah so which one do you think you like
it better i like
both you like both which one do you like
both yeah both pick one if i have two
you have to pick one which one i have
the big one
uh the font has cycle head
yeah the v i think the
s equals i think the black one okay the
black one because it's simple with the
list yeah
yeah my police has a cost of using a
notebook oh n but this one is all
a one right yeah both of them are fine
this one is shorter right shorter
implementation okay let's do it put it
on the
tv no no no
tv
yeah yeah turn on the lights please turn
off the lights please
can i see it yeah it's perfect it's
perfect can you erase the
things
oh is it is it oh no it's up there so i
need to
wait yeah this is better
oh it's a bit a bit
can we see it yes no no no please no
freezing please
is it blue
are you okay yes out
whoa yeah i think this is fine this is
fine
[Music]
okay now now we can do this coding right
can you see yeah
you can see here okay let's login first
login yeah so remember we have uh this
note
note yesterday yeah yeah yesterday so we
don't need this
uh let me just remove it yeah that way
it's a bit blurry
what that's okay wait the
top bit is the big burry that's okay
never mind
it's only a bit neat
no yeah it's very clear it's very good
okay now
look at the first one
sit down define them
right the version one okay
all right yeah yeah and then
we use the v to set
and what do we do why cat
is not numb right
if hat in this
return true right oh we forgot to put it
in a
in a if
right can we check this first right can
we check
that has cycle can can i
cut no seeing it right please
cycle one and then if we do this head
so it should pretend it should
you should put uh print the force right
yes exactly so how can we check how can
we check
how can we check if it's uh i mean let's
see
if if we point us for the cycle how how
do we do
it if we create a list with a cycle
let's see
uh look we can do this p dot next now
let's point
to head next no
all right okay so now you have the cycle
yeah does it have a cycle now
now now you have two right yeah because
we continue
and let's try the second let's try the
second
second approach let's cycle twice okay
well let's do it remember the fast and
slow thing
yeah the fastest is closing let's cycle
like a two eyes head
fast slow equals head
head yeah they're pulling into the head
why fast
is not numb and fast
stop next no one knows
[Music]
right all right and we have to check if
they meet
in the middle somewhere in the middle we
can chew
right and return first all right
[Music]
and if i check this hey if i
if i put another
can i can i ask you to sit quietly
please
me too i am so your printer
2 2 ok if i if i remove this
so if i don't make it a cycle uh
why you're not making the cycle then you
will put your pin too fast i'm right got
it
yes does it make sense does it make
sense
do you want to see this problem one more
time look two versions
this is the wire
people nothing look yeah this is the
version of today her cycle one has cycle
two
okay that's yeah
that's that that's uh good yeah isn't it
that's good isn't it
really neat writing okay okay so um
this was flying in the air
okay so what's flying in here
any questions today any questions
[Music]
no questions okay you can say bye bye to
the
people
[Music]
please
okay bye