go hello
hello mr mr right now right yeah
okay so what did you learn yesterday if
we learned about apple captain gaming
yeah yeah yeah okay so now and look this
is the source code yeah let's go uh
reveal this on it yeah we can press
yeah yeah yeah yeah you see we can press
left and right yeah so this is move left
and then we set the button a to move
left
this is the game over yeah i changed a
little bit look i call this if not game
is running we just return yeah okay if
not game is running then we just don't
do anything with the control
uh reset the game yeah we said the game
we saw the game so when we press the a
and b together if the apple has not
fallen on the ground we just ignore it
yeah just to avoid people making me stay
by pressing the this a and b together
when the apple is still falling right
yeah that's what it means and when we
reset the game it sets the score to zero
sex the apple
to a random position
yeah in the top row and resume again and
then ap this is the step move right okay
with a bit more right
get
current delay you know the faster higher
score less delay faster apple falling
speed yeah got it
okay so this is the main logic so now
today we're going to let the computer
play
right so we don't want to play yeah
we're not working with the player
[Music]
yeah so how do we make the computer play
what's your strategy if you're a
computer what do you how do you play um
like
so first of all we just
if like um
you just
go for like the
quick quick quickest the shortest path
yeah like if you're there and then
if you're here i never i was
so basically yeah the emperor is here
the airport here and this is your bow
yeah this is about so if it's on the
left you just go left yeah all right and
if the upper is here and then the bow is
there
if the upper is on the right just go
right yeah this is one strategy the most
simplest one is just towards it and just
remember that we can wrap the
the bow right so what does it mean it
means that look if we uh let's place a b
if we go left and you'll go from the
right if you go right from to the most
the rightmost place you
turn your left up to the left yeah so so
we can we can actually add these
to the check so first of all let's say
define
a
computer okay computer play
okay this is the function
we want to call and then we just put it
here
yeah okay
black computer place okay so it
now it does nothing but we can do this
yeah
so this is actually kind of the most the
simplest artificial intelligence yeah
artificial intelligence it's called
decision rules if
left is shorter we go from to the left
if right is your good right
right
yeah so if
decision rules decision tree is
basically something like okay
if something then do something a
prediction if something condition and do
something for example like if
today
is april
someday in april right
then tomorrow
before barbecue
that's right or something like that yeah
this is if
we have the barbecue yeah yeah we can do
it
this year as well so barbecue so learn
prediction yeah we're going to do that
okay so now look
look here okay but first of all if it's
the same look at the the position like
this x apple right f of x
f of x yeah the horizon position equals
the
f of
x yeah
uh x okay and then
if
first of all we have to check look if
if the vowel
dot x
equals f of x
right so if we are right
if we have the bao is right after the
apple
below the apple so what should we do
what should we do in this case
look if apple are here
and then you are just right below it
what should we do
nothing yeah just do nothing so we just
do nothing
and then return yeah because
do nothing it doesn't need to to
uh to do anything right
so another way is that if power
dot x is smaller than f of the x air x
right so the upper is on the right hand
side
right so we can just move right right
simple as that
yeah
let's move left there that's the simple
logic without taking without considering
if
we can con we can actually grab our bow
from the other
the other side right
okay so so can we try left look
does it work okay now
yeah you see
okay
make sense
yeah it's actually doing that right yeah
yeah look but you will go for the look
the apple is the
ball is here the airport is here
it will actually move right instead of
move level because move left is the
faster right but it says okay because
it's on the right 11.
okay okay because it's too far yeah yeah
it's too far to get it right this is the
this is the thing right because if
if the apple is uh here okay so let's
say if apple is at least four two right
and then we are on the left
so what will happen
it takes one two three four to go to the
right but at that time the apple has
fallen on the ground
it doesn't catch it in time right
so that's why at least accurate or
sometimes but
it's not
super smart right yeah it's not smart so
we can fly
that's why i lose but so let's but
that's the basic version right that's
the basic version so first of all we
need to define the cost of moving that
and cost the moving line right
right so how do we
check if the costs are moving left and
close to moving right
so first of all we say close
so let's look if about
so let's say instead of
let's just do this okay custom moving
that moving right cost
of moving right
is
is upper
x minus about
x all right
yeah it's on the right hand side but but
again we have one more choice of moving
left so
cost of
moving
right okay okay uh left
left
cost of moving that you can still move
left equals
equals what it was what
so so let's see this this let's do this
a little bit here so um apple is here
right apple is here and i'm here the bar
is here
so you can move left move right the cost
will be the distance will be least minus
this right but you can also move to the
other hand side right
yeah and what's the cost
it's 5 plus
it's phi plus 1 plus the
these
so how do we get this
so what's the
mathematics look how do we calculate the
mathematics
so the distance is it equals this
distance right equals distance
plus this distance yeah all right yeah
so what is the equal the overall this is
five
this is five right five pixels
is it five pixels
five pixels so overall five pixel
and
we want to calculate the distance
between these and this
right so it's actually 5 minus this bit
this bit is 5 minus this
this bit is these right so it's 5
minus f of
f minus apple
upper
pi minus alpha is this actually this bit
yeah yeah
because look this is five
minus apple
is this bit plus
plus this yeah so plus
plus the power right the position yeah
so that that's the simple mess yeah
so it's five uh
yeah five minus f plus plus okay
so it's five
minus
up
plus
wow
i could possibly do this as a second uh
x
just to save the variable so we can just
use this
instead of calling this method to save
us
time okay
okay
this is the cost of moving
uh left and close moving right
yeah yeah exactly okay so now look this
is closer moving left custom moving
right but
uh
okay so that actually look because this
is position we have to put it here right
yeah because this is the position of the
lunar but on the other hand only on the
other hand side when the apple is
smaller than
bar x so it's the opposite so
it
so if apple is here
i know your control is here
the cost of moving left is
this is simple yeah you just calculate
the difference there
okay so
the
cost of moving that
equals equals one equals the power x
bar x minus f of x right
look this is now about about here here
is
is than f of x
right on the right hand side and then
now cos
of
moving right equals one
so it's the same it's actually the same
so
so look if if cursor moving right is
this big plus this big okay
this is the whole pixel yeah so it's 5
minus these
plus this 5 minus power
so 5 minus five
plus pepper
okay so let's do this
okay now what should we do
i have we have calculated two uh
two variables moving the glucose from
moving right and the costs are moving
left and what we prefer which way
which way we prefer
look there are two situations basically
this is just to check which
the position the position if if the
apple is on the right hand side or on
the left hand side of that bar right
and now based on this i have two
i've computed two
uh cost one the cost of moving that and
the cursor moving right so which one we
should choose
choose which one the bigger one or
smaller one
yeah of course the smaller one the
bigger the better again so if cost of
moving left
is smaller and closer moving right
then we move left all right
all right
all right all right so we can just move
right right
okay that might be a situation the
moving level equals to moving right now
we don't care right yeah okay let's try
this to see if it works okay
so you you'll be
you'll be super clever look look it
turns on the other side right you see
yeah okay very slow
don't worry
you will be moving the apple will be
moving faster and faster
right
faster
okay so let's wait a little bit look
look now it takes this shorter cut yeah
yeah instead of going
all the way
so you would never die so this this
version will never die
it will never get more over right
okay look
because it's always picking the
shortest
yeah 30s right
wow
so i i ideally eventually will be like
yeah
so look look it's getting faster and
faster
wow the human being cannot make such a
uh
cannot react so fast yeah look look how
can you play like that
the computer will never never
never uh
yeah yeah the computer will never make
the mistake right yeah yeah you see so
do you get it look this is the computer
play the artificial intelligence the
basic
is called decision rules yeah decision
rules so basically it's based on
checking the field condition and pick
the best right so so what's the cost of
moving that what's the cost of moving
right okay now okay moving that is
is
the cost is smaller the distance smaller
quicker now we keep preferred moving
back otherwise
at the beginning we we implement a very
basic one which is just that just check
okay if apple is on the right-hand side
we move to the right if apple is on the
left-hand side we move to the left if
apple is
right above us
we do nothing
this is decision
tree decision doing so
artificial intelligence you know what
artificial intelligence
the intelligence of computer
yeah how the computer thinks okay look
easy
yeah
okay
make sense okay the last step is we just
put this
yeah we'll just
just download it and then let's see if
we download it here
download
okay download and then
it
okay and then let's copy it to micro bit
complete 20 43
is
and that you downloaded the wrong one
okay
yeah okay so
that that's the basic that's the it for
today okay so
what have you learned today about how to
make computer play yeah artificial
intelligence yeah artificial
intelligence ai yeah decision rules this
is the
basic
one the most simplest hey the computers
are lost
how how did you do that you never
oh yeah yeah i know i know because i why
because i haven't turned off the control
so look i you can still press
the control right
when the computer play so you you you
just intentionally make the computer
loose right yeah then computer will lose
it okay
okay that's it for today say bye to
people bye-bye
[Music]
okay okay bye-bye