hello
okay so today
today we're going to talk about this
problem okay the eco 2175
767 okay five three consecutive what's
consecutive numbers
it means
can you give me uh three examples of
three consecutive integers integer you
know
one two yeah one two three okay so it
adds up to six okay so we are finding we
given the number 33 then we want to find
out if there are three numbers that
added up to these 33 and these three
numbers needs to be consecutive so
they're next to each other right so you
see
three things
and if it can't be made such way so then
we return this empty array okay and then
the input is a very huge number
okay so
okay so what's your thoughts i mean so
okay so let's see
i
mean um
so yeah so we have a number three
numbers yes so let's say a okay so
what's this previous number let's say
let's assume the middle number is a
what's its previous number a minus one
yeah and a plus one okay so if you added
all these together what happened
how many is
three yeah because minus one and plus
one comes out so that's three eighths
okay so that's three a is equals this
time let's say we have a tablet so what
does it mean here
if these t can be what so what's your
approach okay
any idea how do we do it how do we solve
it
so let's say okay it's 27 can you find
the three numbers added up to 27
consecutive
um
come on like nine ten
okay
okay okay and then how about
empty probably well not really 45 14 15
16 yeah 40 50 60.
okay so what
what can you get from these two
did examples divide it by three yeah but
if it can be divided by three then
that's the middle number if you can't be
divided by three like 16 so can we find
any three numbers yes
yeah okay so we can just do yeah so
first of
all each number can be divided by three
divided by three then
it can't be divided by three okay then
when we just return empty
yeah and then let's say the middle
number is
number divided by three okay so i'm
gonna do ten
meet minus one mid and what's next
minus two
numbers last one
i know that's it yeah got it yeah submit
you see accept it when we passed
yeah what's the time complexity if you
look at this do we have any dude what's
the term complexity so what's the time
complexity
a one constant where that one
yeah because it's we just do the
mathematical calculation we can actually
prove us but it's take taking a lot of
time so let's just comment it out a
little bit so look at this three cheaper
quote means the comment uh
multiple lines of code is common okay so
we can just try for from the first we
improve what's the first number and then
we'll try from one so let's say from
first in red
so start from one and up to let's say up
to
meter yeah because they can't go beyond
me though that's not sure yeah
then if first class first plus one
that's the middle number plus first plus
two that's the third number equal equal
number then we do ten
first number first plus one first plus
two right yeah otherwise we can
empty yeah yeah this is blue force yeah
okay if we click on that look
what happened you take too much time to
run right because it's too slow because
we have to try
you know a lot of
different options
so i think it's taking time look time
limit excited
yeah because look when the input number
is
73 i don't know what's new 376.
okay what how how big is it seven
million
yeah seven minutes 369 000 if this is
the input then it takes
you know
about half half of it to dry yeah
for the computers just to iterate what's
the time complexity if you look at this
oh and yes because we just iterating
which is faster look you go wrong
yeah
okay that's the previous one yeah yeah
yeah that's the previous year okay so
did you get it what have you learned so
far today
about how did they go to record youtube
i think i think the input range look it
says input oh it's zero so it's a same
yeah so it'll be
okay minus one okay so it's the same
yeah because zero divided by three is
zero the previous one is negative one
yeah
got it
oh
this is not right okay so this this this
is not right right
because look we try from the first
number so let's say minus one plus zero
plus one
uh okay so this blue force is not right
okay because okay good point that's a
that's a very good test cases because
this this algorithm is not quite right
why is that because the input is you
know it will return empty but
so why is it because we try the first
number right so we try the first number
from zero but
but the first number is negative one
right got it yeah
so we can we need to try try let's say
we need to try
i don't know if because we need to try
from
minus one
the first quick fix is to do this try
the first one and they will be okay
right yeah because the first number
could be minus one right yeah
accents okay
okay that's it for today
bye bye