hello hello hello guys hello hi
okay so today we're going to talk about
probability yeah what's the probability
probability and probability
you're going to get thingy percentage
yeah we're down percentage so it's
basically the
the number of times that one even occurs
yeah so you basically the number of
times
an even occurs yeah
event occurs so yeah divided by okay i'm
gonna divide it by total number of even
yeah something very roughly okay for
example like uh
uh so if you flip if you flip a coin
what's the probability of the coin being
the text
um
50 yeah because fifty percent so there
are the total number of events that
could be
what
so how many possibilities are there that
two right so one the coins being tail uh
heads is fifty percent one of it one of
two okay
okay so the dice yeah we're going to
roll the dice so how many possibilities
of rolling a dice
how many six yes and how many the
percentage of rolling a six
dice and roll it twice uh two times
what's the problem
well okay so
yeah yeah one is basically one over six
times one over six yeah times one over
six so rolling or two six at a time and
how about if i had to wrote it one more
time like uh rho is three times what's
the probability of being uh three sixths
in a row
what's the probability of being a 360 in
a row come on um
216. yeah wow you're quick a mess yeah
so basically okay
okay so basically you times one over six
power to three yeah okay so now so
listen
yeah now listen listen up uh so what's
the probability of rolling three dice
but at least there are two six in a row
so you'll be something like six six
something
okay or something six six oh
yeah okay
okay so now this question mark here okay
this question mark here is not six not
being six okay so what if i wrote a dice
and then what's the probability of it
not being six
five
y five over six yeah exactly because
one over six is the being six and one
minus one over six so basically this is
one minus one over six yeah yeah easy
okay so
yeah so we just have to add up these
three odds yeah three odds yeah so
what's the probability so what
look
are these two the same the probability
of being
something 6 six or six six something
yeah okay so we what's the probability
of going to six the first six seconds
six
as we say one over six times one over
six yeah
yeah
yeah and then what's the probability the
third one not being six
um
okay and then look at this one is the
same yeah this one is
the second one yeah because yeah all
right the odds of
the second and the third one being six
is the same yeah as the first one and
the second one six all right what's the
probability of triple six three six yeah
times that like bad right yeah
okay
yeah got it
i know what's the probability of rolling
a 2 6 in a row or rolling the 260 yeah
in a row so it's adding these together
yeah yeah i'm right all right
make sense so let's see what's the
probability of
the
print yeah print okay so we just have
two
this one yeah
this one
adds this one okay in times two
and as this one yeah
okay
all right
okay so let's see okay so this is the
probability roughly five percent five
percent three and ends with two and the
two okay okay now
it's a long one yeah that ends up two
this okay so this digit you know it's
it's uh
it's so small so tiny so so trivial yeah
so trivial okay so that we can prove
this we can prove this accuracy using
the blue force first basically we just
simulate rolling the dices so for the
first one
in range one to seven right because
there's six possibilities if we roll the
first one then we can control the second
one in range again one two six one two
seven yeah because one to six you know
yeah why the last why this parameter is
seven do you still recall
the range function
yeah so it's up to seven not including
yeah
okay for third in range one seven the
third digit okay now we just have to to
check all right if
first
equals second
equals six right
i think this is can you find that
or
second
equals
i'm not sure can we if we can we can we
write this like that okay so then we
have this event even uh
just two six
uh two six
plus equal one okay
what's the total number of uh you know
possibilities
do you still recall
knowing three three dies at a time
what's the total number of possibilities
okay so it's one time six times six
times six yeah so basically we just want
to
print the two six
yeah because this is two six divided by
total right
okay so let's see if this is the same
okay
uh 2 6 is not defined yeah we have to
define it because at the beginning this
is zero yeah yeah am i right
okay so look it's the same yeah first
equal second is the same okay
is it the same yeah it's the same yeah
you see it's the same again it's right
now yeah yeah it's the same okay
yeah it's the same yeah okay so what's
the time complexity of race one
for this one that's a very trick one
what's the come back time coming back to
the other oh six times six times six
six seven six times next whether oh six
times six times six so we don't say that
so which is what
okay
no no no there's no n here what's wrong
there's no cubic oh one cubic is one
yeah
yeah or one times one time one can
become because it's constant why why is
that because the problem is fixed we are
rolling three dices that's it you can't
scale
up okay so let's yeah because it's
simple
it's a simple math well that's a simple
matter
yeah look at this
two
because look we are just iterating
the total number
okay look
that we are iterating this total number
of times which is 216 yeah yeah we're
just iterating that
number of uh loops yeah
so that's the number of iterations that
these piece of curve runs so it's all
one it's it's fixed there's no n right
so it's constant it's constant okay so
we we can make this problem a little bit
more interesting like rolling uh and
dices right not freedom allowing
analysis to to find out the probability
of being two to six interval okay so
that's too complicated for today now
we're going to deep dive later in the
future right so in that case we will
introduce the uh
variable which is n right n is the
number of dices do you understand yeah
yes do you understand
yeah
okay so let that be for today good job
guys say bye bye
[Music]