hello
hello mr mr ryan okay okay okay come on
come on okay
okay so today we still talk about uh
uh probability yeah probability of
rowing three dices and we want to you
know she's growing three dices here
growing three dioceses
but we want we want to calculate we want
to calculate
the probability
of increasing crisis okay increasing
numbers well what does it mean for
example one two three or two three four
yes strictly increasing yeah all right
yeah
uh four five six okay so this is the
kind of five six seven yeah no no
there's no seven right because the
thighs
yeah there could be one there's one up
to 12. why is one or twelve the dice is
only six six points yeah but they're
different times one of them goes from
there
okay okay original come color can you
sit tight please come on
okay so what's your thought
you um
first thing is that we want to so these
these three uh sequence yeah they are
unique right so like each number is each
size is unique all right yeah
okay so what's the probability of rowing
the
three
unique
numbers for the first one the
probability is we can pick any right
yeah
one what's the second if we pick the
first one what's this
probability of picking a second
number which is not the same as the
first one
what is it
so look what i realized i wrote a number
what's the problem
and what's the third one
which is not the same yeah for six okay
yeah so now after this i i will have we
will have we will have three unique
numbers yeah
numbers yeah this probability yeah yeah
yeah so three numbers how many
permutations it how many permutation
[Music]
three three numbers one two three how
many kind of permutations you remember
permutation six yeah which is what three
times two times one yeah three bacteria
so what we need to do is that
this probability just needs to divide it
by light right so
so let's calculate it to see
to see okay to see what's the value okay
let's just do this
uh
print
queen okay 0.1 put in this and this is
the probability of rolling three unique
dices yeah and then we need to divide it
by six yeah because this is the uh
permutation because look why we divided
by c pixel that the probability of
having three unique numbers there's only
one sequence which is squishy
yeah like two three one you can only
find one strictly increasing number
which is one two three all right because
they're different right
can you have
two no right
no right am right okay so let's do to
check this and see if
yeah
baby okay so see what's this number
okay so this is around
point two percentage okay okay nine
point two percent okay again
we put it the most boring way we can
iterate we can emulate all the possible
situations we just check if the first is
smaller than the second and then smaller
than the third one right
range one seven yeah can you tell me
what's the next four seconds in what
yeah
range one seven
four third one
again in range one seven yeah
yeah and then
look if
first smaller than
what
all right come on can you can you remind
me what to do next the first smaller
than second
smaller
yeah and then we want to call this
count plus equal one okay
cnt what's the total number
what's the total number of the situation
what's the total number if wrong three
status what's the total number of
possibilities
how many kind of choice is six three
three one is six two is one
five
no what i mean total number of
possibilities rolling one dice is six
six possibilities rolling another dice
to two two numbers
six times one
what huh okay two what do you mean two
what's the number of possibilities of
rolling one dice is six what's the
number probably 36. what's the number of
possibilities in three dices
yeah 260.
yeah okay i know we can print cnt
divided by total so this should give me
the roughly the same number yeah you see
what's the first
one
the last one is different yeah
okay
okay let's see okay look at look it's uh
different yeah okay so this number
rounded up to that you know the
mathematic calculation the floating
point calculation in computer has these
rounding errors all right because we're
using uh
using like four bytes or eight bytes
yeah to represent
a floating point number so for example
if i say print 1.2 minus
0.2 is it equal to
1.0 you will tell me first i believe
oh it will tell me true
yeah that's true
that's true okay let's try this one
okay so why is it two
13 point hours
14 point error
is 1.2 minus 1.0
0.2 1.2 minus 1.0 equal
yeah yeah
okay okay yeah yeah okay you're right
yeah okay
so
so sometimes it has these uh floating
point arrows yeah floating point errors
we have four there but this in
mathematics is is true why is that
because we can go
we can just check these uh you know
running flow python floating point error
okay price and floating around error
and then maybe we have a
better
uh
okay so one per better understanding
yeah you see
okay this is literally much more how the
underlying platform handling from for
okay this is normal case is an ultimate
performance international it's a problem
causes when the internet okay when uh
when the internal representation of
protein power which use a fixed number
of binary digital event to represent a
decimal number okay
yeah i see okay so
maybe we can search another one which is
called uh ieee floating point uh then
you will tell me how
i
i e i triple e okay so what does it look
like
so yes you see so this gives the
how do we represent uh 32 bit is 32 bit
is 4 bytes how do we represent a
floating point number so we are not
representing a number like minus
248.75 this is a string and we represent
it something like minus something to the
power of something yeah do you
understand yeah
okay so so it has these four uh
arrows yeah errors look the first bit is
sign positive or negative exponential
meant inside
okay
okay so that explained that that is
something that we might come into
you know we might discuss a bit in more
details later okay but you for now you
just have to know that
the the number of the ways that computer
handles the floating point numbers is it
has this position errors right because
they only have these four bytes or eight
bytes four bytes for a single closing
number eight bytes for double numbers to
to store the the numbers yeah yeah do
you get it because look for for the
integer for the integer same as the
integer like integer has
one by f
one bar is eight b it's if it's if it's
uh one bike it's 255
right zero to two hundred fifty so it's
one one one one this is 15 right all
right and then one one one one okay
there are eight ones one a ones the so
this is what this is what this is 255
okay if i print it
if i print it it would be 255 this is
actually one bite
one bite okay yeah one bite has eight
bits right it's big each bit is zero and
one there are two yeah do you understand
okay so if it's one bit what's the how
many numbers we can store if it's one
bit
two right zero and one how about two
bits
what's the maximum number we can stop
two bits you know one zero one
zero zero zero one one zero one one how
many four yeah yeah
how many how about three bits
you know one zero zero zero zero zero
one zero one zero two do you get it
so it's can't remember the pattern
you don't need to remember a pattern the
thing is that each one look each one
each one has two possibilities
so it is a
two times two times two so right so how
many eight common
ones are there they are eight so it's
two to the power of eight
right so that's 250 do you get it yeah
so it's like that we have eight buckets
each one has
has has two choice
right
all right
it's the same it's quite similar than
rolling a dices
right the first the first size you have
six sixth possibility right
the second one you have another six
possibility the third one has another
six probability so how many total number
we can represent using the
a dice
six times six seven six yeah yeah that's
the that's the multiplication and it's
the same thing here yeah okay
okay so look at these we are iterating
the dice yeah we just simulating the
situation so then we we try to roll the
first dice and we roll the second dice
and then we roll the third eyes and we
check if the first day is smaller than
the second dice is smaller than the
third day then we increment this counter
and we divided by the total number of
occurrence which is 216 and that gives
us the possibility yeah okay so which is
around 9.2 percentage am right what's
the time complexity if you look in this
for loop
what's the tank of
velocity
what's the time commercially
uh what oh what whether because the
input are fixed yeah input are fixed
there's no n here right it's all one
constant the total number of iterations
we are going to simulate is 216 am i
yeah
yeah okay that's it for today come on
bye bye
[Music]