[Music]
okay so
we want to draw remember we talked about
the total graphics so we want to draw a
style like that
okay so it's actually
better it is something like
that
and this is the star okay so let's just
start yeah forget about this this is
look looks like the tilted yeah
okay so
how do we draw this how do we draw it i
mean using the logo yeah logo
graphics so if the total is here that is
here
yeah or a man yeah
so if this side is 100 100 meters go 100
meters
then you'll be pointing
the where and then in this tennis angle
suppose there's an angle
something angle right we don't know yet
and then we go another 100 meters yeah
this size is also 100 meters
and it'll be pointing that way and only
10 and then which is the same yeah this
angle is less than angle
yeah again again again repeat five times
and repeat
five times
fd 100 meter
turn right angle we don't know yet okay
so today we're going to find out this
angle
this is logo we can use the turtle yeah
we can say impression we can say from
turtle we talked about this a few days
ago import
we just need to function fd
to forward and then right
to turn right for the tester to turn
right all right
so
in python we can use the for loop for
underscore in range
five times
then fd 100
and right angle okay we need to put an
angle
in degree
okay
makes sense so far yeah so far so good
yeah
okay so
so
what's this this thing what's here
what's this ow what's this
upside down
five sides
this is pentagon okay so we call this a
polygon as well yeah probably again
very good yeah when n is bigger or equal
than three
when a is three that's not right
p o l five
okay well okay when n is three it's a
triangle yeah
when n is
is closed
yeah it could be square it could be
rectangular it could be
parallelogram gradient yeah or literally
kite yeah many many yeah many a diamond
or okay
what's that
i see okay okay okay so look four sided
many many shape okay and then five sides
it will be pentagon
okay six sided
hexagon
seven sided
head chicken okay
i don't know how to draw i remember
anyway i decided okay
again
okay
[Music]
okay a nice idea
i don't want the gun no no again no okay
and ten
okay so what's the
what's the internal angle the sum of
internal angle sum
of
total internet angle internet
into interior at internal angle
okay
what's the sum of it what's the sum
of the
internet angle of the
of the triangle
anybody
anybody comes
alright
anybody what's the size 100
80 yes 100 how can we prove that
we draw a parallel line
yeah
why we draw this look draw this the
least angle is equal to this angle
this angle is equal to this angle
so what's the
angle
180 of the line yeah look this is 180
this is 90 degrees okay
perpetual perpetual line 90 degrees a
straight line 180 degree
so look this angle is equal to this
thing this angle is equal to length so
the triangle 180 degree
all right how about square how about any
four sided square
these what's this what's the sum of
total 3
how do we prove it because um two
triangles
two triangles exactly look if we
separate it
ryan
how many triangles do we have
um
240.
two triangles each triangle is 182
triangle
360. yeah look at for any false id i can
just
cut it into two triangles yeah all right
so why can't it look this triangle
180 this triangle 180 so all these
things yeah okay how about five sided
depends how many triangle can you do
uh
okay
how many triangles
can we separate these pentagon
three yeah three
hexagons how many triangles
two
oh yeah
okay
so what what do we get
for anxiety if n for n side is
how many triangles can we have
for anxiety how many triangles
and
anxiety how many triangles okay look um
minus two way down minus two n minus two
okay so the number of the total the sum
of the total integrity degrees n minus 2
times
180 yeah
this is the equation okay
pentagon
n equals three five yeah five minus two
three three times 180 540
hexagon
mexican home how many has hex can n
equals six six minus two
times a hundred eighty seven three
hundred that deck again
what's this again ten
ten minus two eight eight times a
hundred eighty
um one thousand four hundred and sixty
okay i'm the final number one thousand
four hundred sixty one hundred four
hundred okay okay yeah
[Music]
okay so one thing we learned today okay
this is very northern n minus two i'll
write it here yeah
yeah
you should be able to tell your friend
what's this yeah
okay you should be able to take this is
very important yeah triangle n equals
three 180 degree
square n equals four four times minus
two
yeah because this n minus 2 is the
number of triangles we can partition the
polygon
all right okay
okay so look
this one look what's the difference
between these
this square okay
and it's dark what's the difference
what's the difference between these two
um
can you tell me the difference come on
what's the difference if i want to use
the something to differentiate these two
shapes yeah in order for it yeah this is
the only difference i mean this is the
one that stands out from the rest
because it has
so what's that in bit
can you describe okay look look these
are it's over 180 degrees we're done wow
clever yes
yeah if we have a one internal angle
which is over 180 degree we call it
concave
concave pumpkin
concave what's concave
means that if there's internet angle
which is over 100 otherwise this one
all the internal angles are less than
180 yeah so we call it convex so these
are two different okay
yeah concave and convex make sense
concave polygon pentagon
this is convex concave
um
okay and how about
this one almost
one two
three four four one two three four five
okay actually i throw one more one but
let's contact concave yeah okay
exactly okay both of these two are
called simple polygons simple
you know simple polygon is that it does
not intersect with each other this is
not a
this is not a simple polygon because it
intersects with it does not have hole so
it does not have a hose
so it does not have a hole this is not a
simple formula yeah
not intersecting with each other like
this yeah because
these two con are called simple polygons
yeah because it does not intersect
without each other okay
exactly okay we
talked about the shape yeah these are
the shapes okay so now the most
important thing of the day is what we
want to find out is this angle
the star
because remember we want to find out
this angle
yeah
okay
so
this is the pentagon okay so if each
side is equal then each angle is equal
right look but this is triangular if i
say this these three sides are equal
what's the what's the degree of what's
the angle of each angle
what's the angle of each angle come on
60 we're done because look wow a plus b
plus c equals 180 f a equals b equals c
so three times something equals 180
that's something the angle is 60
what's the angle of each of these
independent which each side equal
what's what's the angle of this can you
tell me
um
ryan 100
what's the internal sum when n equals
five
five minus two times 180 equals
540 orders five angles added up to 540
so which 108 yeah 540 divided by 5 yeah
because i find angles so it's 108 okay
this is 100 this angle is 100
so this 100
this angle is 72 right because these two
added up to
80 yeah yeah so this one is 72 i swear
so what's this angle come on
you almost almost get it
look okay i'm going to i'm going to
put a simple version there
look okay
first of all
let me let me write something yeah
okay yeah come on this this is a this is
d this is c
and let's say this d okay
if i tell you
angle a plus
a plus and b equals 180
yeah
come on everyone
and what's the angle of
what's the end of acd
angle a plus angle b equals 180 what's
the end of acd here
come on
ryan come on ryan
do you get this come on ryan you you
probably know this
a plus b equals 180 oh no no actually
it's not 180 it must not be a hundred a
hundred okay
a plus p equals 100 degrees
eight
and what's the end of this um
look i like it
[Music]
okay
look
because this angle
look because a plus b plus c
is 180 yeah yeah and then is c
a c d equals 180 right
look at that both have this c
right so this angle must be equal to
a plus b okay okay
okay so no no look if you understand
this right
72 72 so what's this degree come on 72
32 what's this
um
[Music]
144 okay so what's the
so look so how do we
how do we draw a star repeat
five times
fd 144
uh a hundred this is the size and right
turn right
144 yeah all right yeah
145 look harry how do we get 144 this is
we wanted here we were facing facing
this direction and i want to turn
look at me 10 144 degrees
go straight
10 and under 544 degrees here go
straight
wait look at me okay
yeah close three and ten
yeah and ten okay so this is the 140
vertical
yeah yeah okay so this is what we
learned today so what have you learned
today come on what have you learned
today
anybody
angles yeah we're down this angle n
minus 2 times 180 and we also said then
concave convex
simple polygon okay so can you draw or
concave polygon any polygon
concave polygon
how many lines it doesn't matter when
you want to draw a convex product
that
you said it was is
concave yes
what's this
dot
let's count
okay
okay let's concave okay
any any other this is uh okay this is a
rectangle which is con
convex okay and this is concave if i
look i can always
yeah
mirror it and it'll be
convex
yeah
okay pac-man
okay
yeah
okay so that will be it for today bye
bye
bye bye bye