hello guys hello hello hello
okay so today we're going to talk about
prefixes
suffix yes prefix
suffix
and suffix so in impressive
and we have another one ends with
ends with
yeah
so for example
a b c d
abc that will return true right yeah
and this
these two functions are both case
sensitive means that if you change a to
capital a then you return four yeah end
with
android is the same as a b c d dot end
with c d e learning tell me it's true
right
okay
so
so um these stars we said end with how
are we implementing it for example how
are we implementing it
how do we compare the two strings with
the star uh the star was function like a
b c d e f
and how about a b c d e f g
h okay so this function this string
let's say this is the prefix string
which is s
b equals that s equals that so how do we
check if p is a prefix of s
how do we check
uh
until we reach the prefix the end of
prefix then in return true right if we
have a mismatch let's say if a b x here
so what happened here a b a a match bb
match
x x in no match
that will return false right
and how about look this letter p if p
the length is bigger than s what
happened do we need to compare
no because it's
it's impossible for a prefix to be
for p to be a prefix of s if p the
length of p is bigger than s m right
right makes sense
yeah that's very obvious yeah because
look if i say
okay
if i say p is this s is this is p of
previous of s
um
no
why is that
because it's bigger it's bigger yeah
obviously yeah so we don't need to
continue to compare right so for the
surface it's the same yeah so for the
suffix is the same let's say
i wanna switch p was p uh abc and
this is
abc okay so let's look s is this
suffix so what happens i start from the
end right
it's the same
it's the same okay and i reached the
beginning of the p so then it's a suffix
right if in a meter something is not
matching then i can say it's not a
suffix right
yeah
yeah this is kind of using the two
pointer thing two pointers to compare
right
but
the time complexity is of n
is the number of that characters in p
okay we just do this daddy oh daddy yeah
oh daddy okay
uh
okay so that's one thing let's implement
this
i log in
okay so look this one
in person we also have this we also have
this fine to find okay
which is called ryan is the best guy in
the world abc top five
abc to find b
that would give me
give me the index the first occurrence
of the of the substring okay so
how does this help in finding the if
with the prefix if it's a prefix so we
are finding look string.5
string define the substring okay first
substring p
yeah
what does this do
we are trying to find the first
occurrence
of the p substring in the f so if this
function returns zero it means that the
p is the principle right because we
already found we already currently at
the beginning of the
s string yeah
but if this function if this p returns
other value like -1 it means the p is
not in
the s
right
or look a b c dot 5
5 a
you tell me it's yellow
abc the 5
b you will tell me is 1 abc 05
x you tell me is minus 1 because x is
not in a abc all right so we we can use
this function s dot prime t if e column
z alone then it's a prefix
easy
yeah
that's one way okay uh
so let's quickly implement that thing
the thing is define
[Music]
is prefix p
s okay
we just use the previous thing
if the length of prefix is bigger than
length of s we obviously become
obvious p is not a prefix of s so we
return force right
and then we can i equal zero y
i smaller than length p
right if
p i
not equal
s i what happened
return y
if we if we move him
if we find the mismatch we return
and then we need to move to the next
character which is i plus equals one
okay
i passed one right
otherwise if i reaches the end what
should i do here
um
return what we can try return to yeah
we'll finish it yeah
this is perfect for the service
preferred service is easier
if service we can just do this if he
is fixed yeah perfect
ps if we still have the original prefix
thing so we can say return
return if prefix
is previously within less pns yeah p
column column minus one
s
yeah we reverse first p yeah look why
this is working look
a b is a a b c
so we also find out look at that the
suffix yeah let's say original string is
a b c d e and then we want to find out
if c d
the suffix of that right all right we
want to find out if this p
is cd is a surface of abcd so we reverse
both strings
so p reverses those string p reverse
will be edc right
then
s reverse it or log b e d c b a right
look
edc
is the previous of edcpa so that means
original string cd is the suffix of abcd
all right
yeah make sense right and let's look at
it
yeah
so it works both ways so
let's say we we have the suffix we have
a surface function
and we want to know the prefix we can
reverse first string then call the
prefix right it works both way okay make
sense
it will both ways
so uh we are here
we are here we are here uh i i will be
equal to the length of the
uh
p minus one
and then i i will have another one k
equals the length the end of the string
minus one
and y i is bigger or equal than zero
then i can say that and that will be
uh if it's uh not matching that will
detain false otherwise i'm decrementing
it i minus equal one and then k minus
equal one okay
yeah
so this suffix just comparing the
letters from the both ends all right and
then if that's them the movie movie
movie
until the end of the suffix
make sense
and we obviously we need to check if the
suffix
is bigger than the
original string now we don't need to
continue right because there's no way
for a
longer string to be
to be suffix or prefix of another string
make sense
yeah a little bit
okay so now
this is i know we can
uh
the time complexity is still the length
of the prefix of suffix yeah if it's the
entirety that will be o and no voila
okay
space complexity we're not using using
additionally
uh linear space so let's space
complexity will be a one
yeah
um
that i think that that will be okay any
questions so fast for today
what have you learned
about the prefix and stop it
yeah