okay okay can you be a little bit
quieter please
okay so today we're going to show you uh
how to draw a chess ball a chessboard is
8x8 yeah and then the black squares and
then the y squares they are interleaving
with each other okay so
so how can we draw a square do you still
recall how do we draw a square with the
size n for example how do we how do we
ask the turtle to draw
four and then yeah repeat four times
every time we go
90 degrees
okay first of all let's define the
define the
square function yeah squares with size n
so what do we do we repeat four times
will be the first time
so each time we for what for what is the
function from the third package for what
size n
and then
we and
right is turn right turn right 90 degree
okay so let's see square
yeah easy yeah easy easy funny
okay so how do we draw a fierce square
end field and begin fear and inferior
that's one way okay
easier
okay so for example i say square
sphere yeah square field
n
so first of all we begin here
and then we draw a square we call this
function and then we end up here yeah
end of here
okay first of all let's reset okay and
then to draw a square here
first of all you draw a square and then
you try it was trying to fill in it yeah
that's one way the other way would be to
draw to to draw to ask the turtle to
draw from size one draw a size one
square and then draw a size one size two
squares or size three square you'll be
much slower okay
for example let's let's redefine this
function
and
and then for the size yeah
current size i in red start from one up
to n right
and then each time i draw a square with
size i
i love it also okay okay let's reset
and
then square fear
let's just draw 15 yeah you see
is it you're trying to
first of all you create the size
yeah it's you try to draw a size
one square size two square size three
until you see the animation so the the
third is actually quite busy so it's
kind of slow okay it's kind of fun
okay so
how do we draw
how do we draw a
chess ball
i mean first of all it's
it's white uh
okay so it's black square and then
white square and then black square and
white square
black square like we just did and then
do a white
square
actually you don't have to feel it so
look the thing is that look here i'm
here yeah i draw a black square and i
need to
go
i feel it but now i need to move the
turtle
yeah so i go an unit and and it says and
i draw a white
and then i go go for and you don't have
to
yeah so i actually look this a pair a
pair of black and white so i need to
repeat these four times right so that
will be one side and then
when i reach the end i need to turn
turn the other side and the turtle needs
is now facing right i need to ask it to
face right left and then you can start
drawing
all right you can start drawing another
pair of the another four pairs of black
and white square
am right yeah
so look
look if i draw the black here white
black white black white black white the
rhinos the square will be white right
and then the other row the next row on
the right hand side will be
black right yeah because it's
interleaving so you don't want to have
two continuously
consecutive the black squares or y
squares right so uh
okay so first of all let's just we
implement this uh with the
uh it doesn't matter okay let's just
uh implement this a little bit okay
okay so this is the one so let's do this
okay so define chest chest and
this end
and it's the size of the chest yeah well
we want to repeat four times yeah
because four times two rows four times
two equals eight right
in range four and then for each each row
each row i will have first of all i will
repeat four pairs yeah
and then first of all i will draw a
square which is
n
and then i will go forward
yeah and then i can draw an appear which
is square field yeah n
yeah and then i need to go and grow
another n unit
now i'm at the end at the end and i need
to turn right turn right yeah
turn right and then i need to forward
the two two times of n why is that
because because it was only here right
here and he needs to go here
go here
and facing left
so turn left
then i need to turn right
turn right of the 90 degree
okay and then now i'm starting to
drawing from right to left
starting to draw from the right left so
another four pairs of the black and
white
okay
yeah a square first of all is a square
and then go another end
jumps to the next position to draw a
field square
square field
and then i go to another
end unit and then prepare for
at the end i need to
turn
turn right nine eight uh
turn the opposite i tend to the opposite
turn right dot 10 left 90 degree okay
180 degrees
okay let's do this 15.
first of all i need to reset it
let's make a color blue okay
actually it's black yeah oh you already
this black we don't need to change the
color speed minus one make it a bit
faster
chest
fifteen
okay so you see it's actually animating
look it it yeah it draws four pairs of
black and white squares and it goes to
the end and it turns around
contouring from the right to the left
yeah okay
drawing from the right to the left
actually
is this one square on a white squirrel
do you start on the black square uh it
doesn't matter
ah okay okay yeah yeah it's i i actually
don't know but actually we can just swap
these two yeah at least we can
every time we can
uh here we always start with the white
square you see
yeah so we start with the y square and
then here
uh this line is actually drawing is here
right yeah you see all right so if we
swap the square and a square here that
you'll be the opposite
okay you actually notice that it's quite
slow here because it's the feeding
procedure is a bit slowly we can we can
replace it with the
uh after this we can replace it with the
let
we with the begin field okay now it
should be all right reset
let's reset it okay speed minus one okay
and then let's
uh
let's revert to the previous version
which is this one yeah
begin here and then let's do the chest
again 15.
is it it's much much faster right
yeah make sense
do even faster no i can't but this is
the thing yeah i can
i can i can i can do
i can
make a like uh
30 make it twice big
but it's
but it's actually oh i i didn't change
the speed okay i probably should change
the speed let's
let's reset
speed minus one even bigger okay
uh 50 maybe you will be going
over the boundary
oh no okay
yeah
uh
it's open screen it's off the screen
which one is off screen yeah yeah yeah
but and this command window is also off
the screen let's just pull it a little
bit so you see the command here okay
yeah
so okay to sum up how do we draw a list
we first start with the y square and
then draw four pairs
and then we're here we need to turn
right turn
turn the opposite way and then start to
draw the white square black square again
here and then when we're here
one on the second row
then we need to do what we need to
turn the opposite yeah so basically
basically the the the turtle will be
going this way this way here this way
yeah you see the circle going that's how
it draws okay make sense yeah
okay okay that will be it for today bye
bye bye bye bye
bye