hello guys hello hello okay so today
we'll be cooking okay i'm going to show
you a graph which is made by this
twitter and the spiral yes spider so
so can you imagine if i do this
repeat 100 times then every time
i would go
for what
i times two
and every time i would turn right
91 degrees so can you imagine what
happened
can you imagine
so every time i look at the i would be
incremented from
uh it will be iterated from 0 to 99 yeah
and every time i will the first time i
will go
zlo the second time i would go
two
that's one the third time i would go
well
four right so two four
six eight ten yeah every time you'll be
like two
two two to two more and then every time
i would turn 91 degrees 90 degrees the
right angle right 91 degrees a little
bit more so i can use this angle to turn
wrong and run and run i'm right
so
eventually you'll be showing the spiral
okay let's do this
okay you see
yeah method is a
drawing yeah
okay
that's cool it looks cool yeah let's see
so it's good keep drawing drawing
and then you can see this spiral spiral
okay
yeah this is actually a very famous uh
shape when you land the turtle
programming yeah so it's it's quite
amazing that
we can just use this simple loop yeah so
look at this it's quite simple yeah so
repeat a hundred times and every time i
i ask the turtle to work a little bit
more
every time and then after that to turn
91 degrees right yeah yeah if let's see
if we do this uh 90 degree what happened
let's see if we just do this 90 degree
whoa
you wouldn't even turn here let's see
90 degree 90 degrees is the right angle
so you'll be like that
all right okay let's see
so it'll be quite straight here
yeah make sure
yeah
it's like uh
a maze
yeah
it's like amazing
well not
really not really not really amazed not
really amazing okay so but yeah
but you see the difference yeah 90
degree and then 91 how about 89 89 would
be similar to night night
yeah yes yeah exactly let's give you a
hundred no let's try the
981 degree okay that's a very good
experiment
a times two
you'll be uh
you'll be
spinning the other way right previously
it was a little bit tilted to the right
now it's a little bit to the left
yeah
okay it looks messy now
yeah but if you turn that away you'll
see quite similar to
to
to the first cases when you show the 891
degrees am i right how about you do
something like a hundred a hundred
what's a hundred okay so let's see 100
okay
so actually we can make this uh if you
want we can we can do this we can put
this in the function and define spiral
and then you that will be degree you you
you're asking for that so for i in range
let's say make it 100 fix
fd
fpi times 2 and then 10 wide degree yeah
this is the parameter with passing now
we first of all reset and
spiral 100 yeah
good
oh you see because it tends overturn a
little bit yeah so it doesn't look like
a spiral anymore it looks like a flower
maybe
yeah
yeah got it
it looks messy
looks messy
looks still quite cool
quite cool okay looks like flower you
get it yeah we define a function we pass
the degree
we pass the degree as a parameter we
know we call it spiral is the 100 which
is passed as a degree and 10 by the
degree okay makes sense no it's not even
the square yeah yeah okay okay yeah
that'll be for today easy yeah easy
peasy bye bye bye bye bye
bye bye