oh hello guys
okay so today we're going to make this
yes look a flashing screen yeah how cool
is that how cool is that yeah
so
how do we make this flashing screens how
many pixels are there 25 yeah so we just
need to go through each pixel 25 pixel
yeah and now we're randomly randomly
choosing uh setting is on and off on or
off yeah and what's random what's random
uh just random things
random yeah it's not it's just what's
random come on can you explain to me
what's random
sorry
yeah yeah so can you use the arrow words
to describe the random
random random okay so each it's random
yeah well it's really unpredictable
unpredictable that's a good one okay so
unbelievable yes so just the computer
just make up anything randomly
unpredictable yeah just give give by
odds yeah you throw the coin to the
fro flip a coin and there's a chance
that they could face up or for free
stuff right so here it's the same yeah
for the each piece there's fifty percent
you'll be on fifty percent will be off i
know obviously we need to set the
brightness yeah the coin doesn't have 25
that's right okay so well but we have 25
so okay so you can imagine this is 25
coins here all right and when we
light a pixel so it's facing up okay so
so first of all let's do this basic stop
forever yeah we want to do this forever
okay so it generates for us so we just
need to go through each pixel yeah for i
in range 25 pixel okay 25 pixels
so
now i okay so i from 0 to 25 right the
first row first pixel is 0 1 2 3 4 5 and
the second row will be 6 5 0 1 two three
four and the second note will start with
five yeah so so the rows will be i
divided by five yeah
and columns will be i modulus five all
right
yeah look so how how do we do this look
the rows
you know what do you guys say
the row look at the the number i will go
from zero one two three four five six to
twenty four and the rows will be
i divided by five the columns will be i
modular phi okay so can you explain can
do you understand this bit the line
three and number four
yeah do you understand yeah okay yeah
okay so now we've got the status equals
the random in okay run give a random
number with zero one okay
okay
okay now
now if the status is on
then we we obviously we want to plot
project plotted close column yeah
if the status is off we want to unplot
it all right and plot it
yeah
actually this is the row column okay row
column
you're right yeah okay so look now a
little bit look let's let's click on
this look look you see
yeah but each pixel is is roughly the
same size yeah we want to make it some a
bit dark some a bit bright okay so we
can do this
set brightness yeah and there is a
number from 0 to 255
so to 255 is the
brightest yellow is the darkest so we
set the blended in from 0 to 255 okay
yeah and a little bit look some are a
little bit smaller right let's see it's
not always the same size do you get it
yeah
yeah makes sense okay so the most
important thing here is the number three
and number four okay i feel like you
know quite understand this a little bit
so look
so i will be a number okay so that i
would be the number from 0 to 24 yeah
like that yeah
like that okay
okay so now
rho i divided by five so this would be
the first row zero zero zero zero and
then the second row at least in row will
be you up one one one one one and that
will be two yeah this is the row
okay do you get it that's the row i
divided by five
one four yeah
uh that's the i okay and then column
what's column column would be
would be modulo 5 right so that would be
what module 5 will be 0 1 2 3 4
0 1 2 3 4 0 1 three four yeah three yeah
make sense yeah
do you get it do you understand do you
understand this bit okay can you tell me
what what's what's this bit
what's this big um it's basically row
yeah basically yes we want to iterate
the rows and columns well actually we're
not iterating the rows of current we are
there's another way of doing it okay
instead of doing this okay just remember
we can do this i'm commenting out we can
for r in range five we can just
just iterate iterating the picture the
columns yeah this is the same thing yeah
so
uh
this is the same thing as the previous
one okay just two different ways of
doing mistakes
okay
okay so look
that would be the same yeah that would
be equally the same yeah got it
that makes sense look this way
this way we are iterating row and a
column so that would be
that these two variables are partitions
are known by the iteration this is the
yeah but this one we are iterating with
a single variable and we convert the
single level to
to it all right yes so
so
to sum up to sum up yeah so we can do
this look we can look this is zero zero
yeah so we if we number the pixel will
be zero one two three four five six
seven eight nine etc okay so that's the
first way we're converting these the
number back into the rows and columns
but and for the second method we're just
iterating the row and the column yeah
row number zero column that'll be that
row number one i'm gonna be right okay
yeah okay well that will be it for today