[Music]
okay so given two string this is s this
is t we want to find out if s is a
subsequence of these objects
yeah it is true what's subsequent yeah
we talk about this all the time
yeah
e-r-i-c
yeah we're done okay so what's the
subsequent subsequence is that
this is the string and if we move
none or more
you know we remove some numbers of
characters and then you will become
these they'll be subsequent yeah not
continuous but if it's continuous we
call it substring yeah
we talk about this yes
some string sub array yes sub least
substring
these are continuous so we have uh if
you want to proof of it we can usually
do it with our n
square right or n square because what
all we can do we first of all we can
so
so how do we get this o n square
do you still remember oh it's good we
can first of all if a sub inverse sub
list substring is one characters if
there are n characters in the original
string so let's let's speaking one index
out of n right okay
and how about if there are more than one
character that would be
what picking two numbers out
of side okay so cn1 is n plus cn2 is n
times n minus 1
divided by 2 right so this is in a scale
of o n square right okay
okay so substring now we talked about
these such things
a long time ago we can use the two
pointer yes you still remember
how do we check it how do we check look
how do we check these
this is a
sub uh subsequence of these look we have
two pointers
yeah
look at me
two pointer i and j okay e is not equal
to a so we move here okay e is equal to
e so we move both
okay i see because i is not equal right
so i'm i move here
move the t
yeah and then i is equal to r i move
both so
to to put it simple if two characters
pointing to the same position uh tom put
the characters at us at both
pointers
and both both the string are equal then
we move both pointers otherwise we move
the t yeah got it
why this is working
why
but
and at the end we what if this this
pointer position reaches the end and we
have a match all right so to sum up we
want to move
we want to move
when we have a match like e
if e equals to e okay so here i'm here
yeah e is equal to e then i move both
right i move both
okay
but now i is not equal to i so what do i
do
skip skip which one i alright yeah
because i can't skip this one yeah
because i need to i need to find a match
right so if i find a match if i don't
find a match i can't skip right that
makes sense yeah
but if i find a match i can skip off
i can move people right so as long as
this reaches then a little bit there
yeah
that's what we have talked about let's
quickly implement this okay so it should
be quick
define
is
subsequent
s q okay so if the length of s is bigger
than q then we return one come on one
question
first obviously yeah because if the
original string s is longer now you
can't find a subsequent in the next
string right that's very obvious yeah
if length s is bigger than length p q uh
actually is t
t we just return four right
okay
length y i equals zero j equals zero
and then
y i is smaller than the length s
and
j is smaller than length t right
look
if s i
equal equal t j then what what do we do
look
all right this is i this is j
so what do we do if we have a match we
move both points right
so i plus equals 1 and then j plus equal
one otherwise what otherwise which point
we need to move
all right so which one do we need to
move come on
this is as this is t if we this is the
eic this is something else so if we
don't have a match which pointer we need
to
then we move
uh
j j plus equals one
okay and then
in what cases we need to return true
in what cases we need to return to after
this if
i
obviously yeah so the time complexity is
oh
the longer one yeah so which is what the
longer one no ln
n plus n right and it's the number of
string in the s
the number of characters in the s m is
the number of string in the t
but
but we know
we know what x is smaller than t right
so we can obviously say it's oven right
right
yeah
the time complexity will be lm okay
uh is it no
is it om no no no no no
the term complexity will be the shorter
one which is our our n
n is the number of string in the s
because look there's no
is it no more
okay so okay so
so let's uh
so what's the time complexity what's the
tango velocity come on in what cases
look if i
in both cases j will plus equals one
right in the worst case in j would be
plus one
in both cases so t
t is the number of string in uh yeah the
longer one yes the longer one yeah
because it could be the case is you
can't find even a match
right you'll be like a and then this
this character and the t will be b b b
right
so what happens in this case so you
can't find the match so you always move
this right
yeah
right make sense
does it make sense the timeline let's
see so the time connection will be the
time taken to
iterate over all the characters in in
in the t right so the time number six
okay
okay so
this is two points i think so how can we
do this using this um
recursive okay how do we look using this
because
every right yeah
so it's quite similar idea look so look
i have a string yeah i have a string
i have a string look language is e
something something something okay and
then i have another
this is s yeah
t equals what t was what e something
something something
okay
so look
look
it's as a substring of e
if i have a two-pointed point here right
yeah so is it the same as
as s
as
uh because the first character is the
same right so this question is the same
as
if
if s1 as
one to the n is the subsequence of the t
to the n one to the n right why
why make sense
right look the first character is the
same both is the same so it's a match
right
yeah it's a mess so i just move it right
how about if it's not the same
how about it's not the same
if s is like e
something something and then t equals f
something something so
so what's this what's this what's this
going to be so look let's take consider
the first character it could be only two
cases if it's equal or if it's not equal
right if it's equal then it'll be like
that right so we just have to find out
the smaller problem which is from the
uh first current and second character
and onward right
yeah but this one if it's not equal now
what happened
right
then what's the pro what's what's what's
the green core what is the equal
yes keep well done forgive each one
one to the n right yeah
all right so that's two cases all right
yeah two spaces okay so that's right how
we just write it yeah
that's two cases
[Music]
come on ryan what did i just say
what two cases
one thing come on pay attention okay
so let's say define
uh
is subsequent okay subsequent as t okay
but first of all we need to define
define uh look at
uh we need to do a if length s is bigger
than minus t what should we depend
if length s is bigger than f then still
should we return
anybody
[Music]
false obviously
okay now we define a f function
i and j where i
i
where i is the
s index yeah t j is the t index okay now
look
if i goes to the end
what should we do if i
somehow goes to the end
what should we do return true or false
if i goes to the end
the i is the smaller one like every and
then
yeah
two yeah obviously if i goes here then
i'll be
that will be true obviously yeah
okay then oh if j equals to the end if j
points into the end between two of us
if j if we are running out of characters
if j so
okay now two cases do you still remember
if
s i equal
t j
return one
reason why if s i equals t j
but
this is s i
s i equals t j e r i c and then e
something something if s i
s i is here yeah t j
t j is here
so what is z equal
come
if both characters are equal what do
which character we need to skip
f1 can you tell me
okay
so look come on
i
is the current position of s j is the
current position of t
if both characters are equal we skip
both right i plus one j plus one if the
both characters not equal like e r i c
and then t t something so these two is
not equals which one is skip t
skip t t t is j yeah three plus one but
how about the first one t
okay yes and j is the
is the pointer it's position for the t
okay so this is i j plus one okay
yeah yeah
okay so look
this is actually the same as two pointer
things but written in recursion yeah
because including why this is working
come on
why does this work
e r i c okay come on here
let look if i have e e
ah
something okay
yeah look
here
so i have a match here
so i can just move right
i don't have to wait for the second e to
match all right as long as i match first
e then i can skip yeah i don't have to
match the second also the year right
does it make sense that's greedy
do i have to wait wait for the next one
it doesn't matter really right
does it make sense
because look as long as the final match
like as long as i find the match i can
just move move i skip
to the next box yeah amongst the pointer
to the next okay this is from the left
to the right can we do the from the
right to the left
anybody
maybe
the answer is yes look
how look at this is either and how about
let's say e
let's say
a
[Music]
so what do we do
and
instead of checking it and we do it
checking the beginning right yeah you
got it you got it you know this
algorithm right
yeah it's the same yeah so so what now
this is backwards so we can just do this
right if i is smaller than what would we
do
[Music]
we just have to say we uh return
f we start from the first one f zero
okay
and then we can do another one okay two
another one i'm going to write it here
if i smaller than zero it reaches the
beginning return true is the same yeah
if j smaller than zero return fourth
obviously yeah
if s i equal sj come on anybody what
should we do if s i equals straight
return
return one f y
come on this is plan on g
how about this is moving to the left
moving to the left right
i minus one j minus one otherwise
written what come on here is f i j plus
one so what happened here if moving to
the right is f i j plus one and moving
to the left
as what
i
yeah we're done okay look
both way works okay and if we could call
it instead of zero zero from the
beginning we call it from the end
so return
f length s minus one
and then
t minus one okay
yeah
start from the
front uh from the right this is start
from the left okay so this is actually
quite the same
as the the two points i think at the
beginning yeah if we have so the core
idea is that what
if we have a match
we move two pointers otherwise we move
the one which is longer right
we move the pointer for to the string
which is longer right because
because we can't skip
the
we can't skip the check of the sub we
can't skip the pointer for the first uh
for the first string right because we
have to match it somehow right
yeah and how to how to check if it's uh
have a match or no we check if the
pointer of the eye which is the shorter
one moves to the other end yeah either
from left to right move to real or from
the right to the left moves to the
beginning right the time complexity is o
m where m is the length of the longer
string right longer string
okay so let
any question so far any idea any
questions
any questions
um
where is this lit
okay
let's see
bye bye
ryan bye bye
bye