oh hello hello guys
okay so today look we're gonna do a baby
tweet okay baby tree look at this it's a
tree yeah so how do we draw it i mean
any idea i mean look at this tree so we
want to draw the tree
wait wait wait so okay it's symmetry
yeah symmetry yes yes i look
i so
i can go i can draw these
trunk yeah
and then i can i need to draw the left
tree and the right subtree right and for
the left subtree again it's a small tree
right so basically you know the tree in
binary uh in in data science uh that
data structure is the
binary is recursive right do you still
remember yeah recursive so so we have a
so how do we define a tree class three
nodes right remember
object this is type of object and then
first of all we need to define init
constructor yeah so we have
a left tree yeah left tree
and then right here
so the left and right are the
the type of three notes yeah so
we can do it dot left equals left
something like that yeah this is the
three notes so basically the left trees
and the right trees are also type of
tree it's recursion defined and
and for the tree tree is the data
structure meaning that we can hold data
metadata in the three nodes right so
okay so
come back to this
we want to draw this tree
so first of all we draw the trunk
and then we need to turn that like let's
say 30 degree to draw the left tree
right and then we turn right
60 degrees to draw the right tree yeah
you need to draw it wise yeah and then
that'll be and when the tree size you
know one or three sides look this this
chunk for example this is this is longer
than that than this right so we can
decrement it using a uh portion right
percentage
right so after that when the size is
smaller than like for example like
smaller than 10 then we return we don't
want to keep continuing right because
the chunk is so small we don't
need to
drawing it right yeah so okay so first
of all we need to import
data import
import the
a few phones we can import everything or
we can you pull forward
forward backwards turn left turn right
okay
yeah
and then we also need to uh for example
we can reset we can
import color yeah color green
speed are you all right yeah yeah yeah
speed and then okay so h is the angle
yeah and angle of the angle of the you
know the heading heading so
zero means the right
horizontal right yeah
90 degree means to the north okay
okay and then we can define a tree so we
want the three or three this is the
recursion function or first of all the
size of the trunk size of the chunk yeah
so size of the
size of these size of chunk current size
of trunk and then the
t would be
something a constant
maybe we don't need to define the size
okay if uh 3 equals
three is the size and then
look if size is smaller than let's say
10 if it's smaller than 10 then we just
return we just don't continue yeah
because every question we need some
point to return
yeah then we need to walk forward with
the size okay so the ft size is this bit
yeah i want to follow this side yeah
okay and then
and then i need to turn 10 uh turn left
1930 degree yeah so i turn turn left 30
degree before making that way and then i
need to draw the right left sharp tree
left side subtree with size equal
size smaller let's say 60 okay 60 so
this size look every time the size is 60
percent of previous one so if this is
this if this is 100
yeah
if this the chunk is 100 this is 60 and
if this is 60 these the length of these
is 36 correct so every time i i draw a
smaller tree with a smaller size yeah
okay and then i need to turn 10 wide and
60 degrees okay so can you tell me why i
need to 10 by 60 degree where are we now
so you'll be turn now i'm here now
turn right
60 degree before facing that way drawing
the right tree yeah so again i need to
draw the
uh
right tree yeah right subtree yeah
yeah
right
can you can you look at the spring come
on
and then i need to turn this come back
to the north and then i need to back the
size i need to go back to where it
belongs right
yeah
okay then let's try it try to do it
reset okay let's reset and then we can
10 left 93
okay and then you're forcing now no see
another three 100
see
yeah you see it's drawing yeah you see
yeah that's how it draw the left tree
first and then draw the right tree yeah
so for each left tree you draw further
the smaller left tree all right we can
cut and then change
let's make it green and then let's draw
again
does it override yeah really yeah
make sense
so this 60 degree we uh
0.6 is the percentage of the
size so
so
let me expand again so this size is 100
right so this size is 60. these size at
least this size 36 and 36 times six 0.6
times 0.6 together so each each time
it's a smaller one right
yeah eric where are you are you right
okay i can see you you're there okay uh
so
okay so look turn that turn left knight
30 degree yeah and the draw is smaller
size and then turn right 60 degree and i
draw the right side and then i need to
go back go back to
uh go go back to where
this point so you'll be turned up to 30
degree and then go back yeah so this is
where the last two right
makes sense
yeah is it interesting
okay okay that'll be for today bye