it up
hello mr miss alright alright
do we still remember that english yeah
english like
english
in the increase yeah one is ahead
and then there's a full stop then we put
it now here
okay
learning this could be one direction or
both direction if we call this finger
one direction if not points to neck we
call it singlet
single yeah
if we post points that both way we call
it doubly yeah make sense yeah
okay so today given a single is given a
single english yeah
thing click
we want to delete
the meter of it
delete the middle of it so what's middle
so the first node is the index is zero
but the second is one two three four and
we want to we want to delete the middle
which is the the the last index like
and divided by 2.
this this means that to get a flaw right
look what's decimal that's wrong
let's see this make sense
like this
ceiling three point two
equals four
four
[Music]
three point two equals three okay make
sense yeah this means the rounding up
this means knocking down okay so this
corresponds to the
ceil this corresponds to
flaw
or in we can convert it in okay
yeah
so
look three divided by two 1.5 ceiling
ceiling uh
which is what
okay so actually we the this is to be
the number of the floor nodes with one
two three four
four four divided by two so that we want
to remove this node right we want to
remove this node this is the middle one
even there are four nodes and these two
is the middle of it because according to
this yeah the number of nodes divided by
two
gets flow okay how about
the odd number of the nodes
one two three there are three notes
three divided by two
four equals one
right so the one what's one
one is this this is the meter zero one
two okay
make sense
do you still remember how do we find the
middle node i think this uh how do we
find the internal let's say we want to
find a meter now
how do we find it
any idea how do we find the middle now
how do we find this meter now
yeah two pointers okay what are these
two pointers
it doesn't work this way right because
the point at the end you can't point
both ways
right
when the end you can't go back there's
no way to go back so
two pointers yeah i have two pointers
they still remember
that's right one is fast the other is
slow fast those two steps at a time
right here
look
right hand fast reference though okay go
one two go
go
okay you can't go any further you know
which is then so let's slow
this is the meter okay
[Music]
what's this one
turtles
that's the third
character this is one word and another
one is tall
something like that right
yeah
uh having a race yeah already runs very
fast but reddit is very proud you know
our rarefield is very
um
yeah and then grab it
thinks okay i'm so fast yeah i can win
anyway so rabbit just takes takes a nap
but the turtle is
keep walking keep walking keep walking
past the past the rabbit and the wind do
you get it so what do you learn from
this story
i mean i mean
don't look down on your opponent right
because if you are recommending a rest
then your opponent is not an opponent
will eventually you know
win yeah
they get it
okay so yeah you are raising a very
interesting point which is the fastest
low pointer so okay so suppose we have
at least i have already
i have already known this point how do
we do this now
how do we get anything out of this chain
so what do we need to how do we delete
it
do we need the access to the previous
now
yeah if i have access to fingers now
i can point here the next
to
this thing.net right
so eventually i'll you'll be sent as
cutting off and then i can figure this
right so if this is previous
so i can just say previous dot next
equals
previous dot next equals slow down the
previous the next is original point is
too slow right then i report to slow
down next
and then i can remove the snow
make sense
yeah okay make sense so we need to keep
checking on the previous by walking so
so every time we walk you know that fast
yes now
don't here but the previous is here
the previous i always we always remember
the previous right update okay and then
let's quickly write it and it will be
easy
it will be easy
so we have to handle a special case what
special case when the note is one only
one note
if this is one or how we if we remove
this what then what's the middle note
it's itself so if we remove it it will
become
if there are two nuts
what should we return which now we are
going to remove
which is which one is the middle now
[Music]
second yeah because there are two no two
divided by two
flaw
let's equals one zero one okay index gl
one okay so you become
one okay this is two special cases
okay let's let's do it define do we move
meter
and we have this hat
if
when
if not
we can
return just return head yeah if we are
given nothing we just return it as it is
if
not
head
dot next right if there is one single
note
now we just return
head on next yeah easy yeah
all right this is two special case if
nothing will return nothing if there's
only one single note then we turn one
thing around now okay
previous no equals nothing first and
then we have a fast equals low
equals head
okay
wire
fast
dot next
okay why why faster next
uh why faster than we do what slow
uh fast equal two step at a time yeah
first one next to next right
yeah
that's fast and before we move the slow
we do we need to put it store the value
of current as slow into the previous yes
so previous equals love yeah
okay now
okay faster next right so here the first
drawback is num so it's the the last
note so we we do what look
previous
done next
that's how we did it premise to next
equals slow the next because slow is the
middle now now right yeah all right
this is previous
this is
slow which is the middle this is the
middle yeah we want to remove this
middle now
yeah this is those next yeah slow down
next
so next
okay so look previous stop next equals
next so what did i do now so look after
this
i changed it here previous the next
equal slowdown x yeah
then i can i can delete this now right
yeah
did it
df look this is a new new thing you need
to learn today
d
means to remove it to to remove it yeah
uh so remove it so
so just did it uh slow yeah and then we
just return the new head which is the
head
okay
yeah
okay so alright ryan
this bit this bit
yeah you see this bit all right
this bit this bit yeah
this we have learned it before yeah this
is this thing
so today this is the new thing
yeah so
i mean
actually
here we need to how do we keep how do we
delete it we want to delete this slow
slow the middle now we we need to know
the previous now right yeah we need to
know previously and how do we find the
meter now faster and slower yeah the
lighting and tighter rubber rapid
speed 2 the tatters bit one yeah
all right when the rabbit reaches the
end the turtle is where is the position
of the turtle
oh in the middle in the middle yeah in a
minute so we are in the middle
in the middle so we before we move it we
need to have this previous
yeah previous previous does the previous
equals though remember the position of
the meter and then
please
uh
okay so i think
previous equals slow okay there is one
slow equal slope of next okay
yeah we
need to move fast equals faster let's
not slow okay
i know we did it we turn it low b yeah
the time constant for the end
we're not using any additional space
here instead we can move one stage okay
yeah a little bit guys say bye bye to
people
[Music]
bye bye bye