go
hello mr mr right now you're right yeah
yeah okay so we talk about uh
geometry metric geometry
geometrics
for question today okay
so
what does it mean it means that you're
not trying let's say yeah give a
simple example two
one two three
four eight sixteen
thirty two sixteen times two to each
[Music]
81 it's a if odd number how come it's
even all right so it's 200.
okay so uh omega progression is like the
first number is a and the second number
is a times q
the third number is a times q to the
power of two yeah take something and
then a time two cubic
yeah
so okay so if you write these two and
then i'll beat threes oh yeah a times q4
etc
q not equals to zero and q not equals to
one right
make sense
if q equals one then all the numbers
will be a right
if a q is zero it doesn't make quite
sense right so in the first number
will be zero
it'll be a there is zero
okay so
so these these eight numbers are one two
three four five six seven eight numbers
add it up to 255 one good way to
visualize it is you put this number into
binary so the binary this is one this is
one zero this is one zero zero this is
one zero zero zero yeah et cetera so if
you add it together that will be
what
one one one one one one one one yeah
this is this this in binary is one
is one followed by eight zeros
yeah one two three four five six seven
and
minus one right so this number
all right this number
two to the power of one two three four
five six seven eight
minus one this number 256 minus one
equals 255
okay this is the number yeah
correct okay that's how we get it but
but if it's an ana geometry progression
geometric okay how do you pronounce
these geometric geometric
matrix is geometric geometric okay
for example like
9 27 81
[Music]
wow that was quick
okay i'm not sure okay let's check okay
but before that i want to cut
we want to learn how to pick your names
yeah but this a what's the a in here in
in this series three three which is a
equal three what's the q
q equals one
sorry
three three not sorry three three
q
q q what's q q is a
n minus divided by m
yeah
the subsequent number nine divided by
three is three twenty seven divided by
nine is three
243 divided by 81 what's the answer
um
what three come on
i was just checking i was just checking
if you're listening
divided by three
so
the next number divided by previous
number is always always q okay that's
what it says
okay
yeah yeah okay now now okay so we want
to know okay so basically look if we
have this a1
plus a2 plus a3 plus a4 here kn we want
to know the sum that the sum sn equals
sum of a i where i equals
i equals 1 to n right so we want to sum
it we want to sum all the numbers yeah
yeah so like how do we get it as n
equals this right so sn
s n equals
so s n equals this right
then i can times q because q is not zero
so i can times q to both sides so what
does it become
q times s n equals
q
times a one plus q times a two plus q
times a three plus p two to the q times
a n okay
yeah
what's q times a y
q times a one is
what a
one
a two a two okay q times a one is a two
yeah okay q times a two equals one
[Music]
so if i subtract these from sn so sn
minus q times sn equals sn minus d
single
so sn minus this thing a2 plus a3 plus
a4 theta a
[Music]
sn
minus qsn how many sn are left
uh
common terms s n so that's one here so
what
to the two a
minus three a equals one how many a's uh
minus one name yeah so
one s n
subtract qsn how many sn
um
one
minus
q yeah subtract common term
okay here this is a tricky part
s n equals a 1 plus f s n is here yeah
yeah i want to take away let's look like
i want to take away these a two a three
a four a
tier a and plus one from here so what's
left
you get it sn is this pic
sn is this big
i want to take away a2 a3 a4 till a n
plus one from sn so what are the common
terms here
what are the common terms
um
yeah a2 a3 a4 yeah
a yeah
until a n
but a1 is left right and a n
so it's a
one minus a m plus one right yeah
okay so what's a sn
s n equals a one minus a n plus one
divided by one minus cube
right what's a n plus one
a n plus one equals a
times q
n right
yeah yeah makes sense look
a two equals a times q1 yeah a3 equals a
times q2 right so a n plus one equals a
times q right make a q n right
so that equals what a
times
a 1 minus a 1 times q
n divided by 1 minus q if i have extract
the common terms equals
a y minus q n
divided by one minus q okay so let's
let's let's do the equation this bit
okay
okay so let's come back to that question
yeah what was that question
what's that
3 plus
9 plus 27 plus 81 plus
243 yeah
yeah
your answer is what three hundred three
six three three six three okay i'm not
sure let's check this what's a
three yeah
so three times one minus what's q
what's cube 90 is three three three nine
divided by three is three three three to
the power of how many terms one two
three four five
to the power of five divided by
one minus three all right so what's this
answer so it's look we this is negative
minus 2 right minus 2
so
3 to the power 5 is bigger than 1 so i
can just reverse the sign so it's
3 to the power five minus one right
what's three to the power five
how many three five what's this
what's this number uh 243
243 okay 243
minus 1
242 right
divided by 2
121 times 3
okay
yeah we're done okay so how about the
first one one plus two plus three let's
give another plus four
plus t uh to
128 okay let's use this equation again
let's use this equation
a what's a one
one times
one minus one can you wrap up the minus
one two minus two
that's a very good question because look
1 minus q and actually if i look 1 minus
q to the power because q to the power of
n is bigger right this is negative this
is negative
yeah so if i reverse the 2
this speed it will be q minus 1 and then
it's the same thing
q minus n to the power n this is the
same man
yeah
2 over 3
i put the minus sign it's the same right
if this is equal right
okay so look
a is one
a is one right a is one
uh where are we a is one q q is two
right
two four divided by two is two
two to the power
ah that's okay two to the power a minus
one divided by
too what
what's this
[Music]
divided okay so what's the okay
okay
okey-dokey
oh why why this is not right this is not
right what's good one one plus two plus
four plus
uh
plus
a plus six uh sixteen clear 120 how many
how many are they
how many how many terms are they
there are eight right
okay so why why this is not right okay q
minus one q what's cube q is two right
a is one
q is 2 q is 2
q is 2 okay q is 2.
2 minus 1 a 1 is 1
a 1 is 1 how many terms are there q q to
the power of to the power of n
q is two to the power of a minus one
okay okay
two to the power of a is what
yeah oh yeah 256
okay this is minus one okay that's right
two to the power of eight two minus 256
minus one 255 divided by one okay i
forgot to minus one that's why it's like
you got it okay i'm going to i'm going
to write the equation here and then you
need to tell me the sum okay
i write down the equation you don't have
to remember it but you need to know how
we're getting it
so sn equals a
q
n minus 1
q minus one okay
okay let's i'm going to write another
series okay number series
uh
geometry geometric geometry progression
um okay so let's say
five
plus
five times plus 10.
no no that would be too easy
plus 45
plus what's next
yeah
time three
what was that
405 okay okay what's the design what's
the what's the sound
what's a a one is what
what's kill
three
three what's n how many
one two three four five
minus one divided by what's cube
three three minus one okay this is okay
let's let's confirm
two that's two five
uh
times three to the power of five how
many threes
no no no three times to the power of
five how many three
43 yeah minus one okay so that's one
three two 202
divided by two 121
times five
six oh five yeah
yeah okay let's add the number together
let's see if it's six or five okay if
it's six or one then we're done
605 okay
okay
yeah
that's mathematics today okay yeah
yes
wait wait wait look
to come back to coding okay you'll be
easier i quickly write it you know to
calculate so we just we just need three
parameters a q n yeah
and define
define uh let's say sum
okay so we just click a at
a1 q
n right
yeah so x equals zero
for
i
in rank
n right n s plus equals
a1
times
[Music]
times what times i times q right it is
simple as that because the first time
the first term is a1
a1 plus plus i times q right we got a
one plus i is zero at the first time so
it'd be let's do a1
and we can
s you get it look i is from zero to n
minus one so so we're adding a one and
the second one i will be one a one plus
q
uh is it
no no no no no no no
no no no no no no no it's not it's we
are adding a 1 plus a
times q
plus a 1 times b 2 okay so so it's not
look
this is a 1 times q a 1 times q 0 right
q1 so is a1
times q
to the power of i right to the power of
y how do we say to the power of i
q to the power all right we can do this
double star
[Music]
a to the power of b
you can write three way you can say a
times times b
in python okay or you can use this
power function master power
a b okay
make sense look away
so look
a one
because look the first time the first
term is a one times q zero q z what's q
here
q to the power of zero
no
a two to the power of 0 is what 3 to the
power is 0 equals 1
1 any power a to the power of 0 equals 1
a not equal to 0 okay
when a is not 0 any anything to the
power of zero
is one a hundred to the power of zero
equals one one
two thousand to the powers you know one
one
everything
yeah
one one one
because in mathematics
it's invalid
yeah there is no such thing as 0 to the
power 0. it's not defined
got it yeah
okay
that's it for today bye bye
bye bye