no q-w-e-r-t
u-i-p okay and how about the second row
okay so let's yeah i have a few words
yeah
[Music]
um
so we want to find out we're given a
list of words we want to find out which
words can be typed using only one rows
of keys right there so that's the
highlight
[Music]
a-a-i-a-s-k-a okay
so how many of these can be typed using
only one row of keys
ah
[Music]
alaska
yeah uh last case
dad okay okay yeah okay
okay
so yes so
how do we
how do we solve this problem i mean
that's code
yeah how do we solve this problem
okay how do we solve this oh
yeah yeah we check each actually
actually we go through each yeah each
one and we check the characters
in it we just go through each character
to see if it all belongs to the first
row second row of the row okay yeah
make sense yeah yeah yeah okay so
look there's a these words can become uh
can contain the uppercase letters so we
should be
uh carefully when checking if the
character is in first row second row
server okay so let's let's define this
first row
okay so uh so we can just do this yeah
so first of all first second the road
fall
hey what's the house where which one
asks
alaska so
uh
yeah let me just sounds more like a name
can you can you go sit down really
we are given a list of words
so first of all we have to define three
the keys in the first row which is e q w
e r p y ui
okay
the second row the second row is
a s t f g
h j k air
and the central
is
c
x c v b
and
m right okay
so we
these are the strings so we can
we can convert these strings into a set
hash set notebook why why can we do this
what's the advantage if we put a set
here anybody
what's the advantage if we convert this
is a 0-1
where the lookup term yes which is super
fast look if i string we can say okay
yeah first right if this first is a
string then the local term is linear
right so you have to go through
each character to see if it matches the
scene but if the first is a hash table a
headset then the lookup term is constant
yeah we talk about
hashtag hashtable right hash table so
basically we have that we won't convert
anything
you know so what's hashtable what's
hashtable
is so so we have something here and it
goes through a hash function
hashtag function and then it tells us
the partition where to store
where to store the items right so that's
one constant term right yeah okay
so can you not sit there otherwise
people will not see
the whiteboard okay they will just see
you
you are working here and there
okay
so now okay so the answers we have the
answers obviously so we want to go
through each one for w in
r in word you know what
and then okay we define the function
first if check if this part this is a
single row if you check w then we append
it to answer yeah okay
apparent w and we return w
okay so the key thing here is the check
we haven't defined this check function
so how do we check as we said we want to
go through the characters in
in
word okay in word okay
so w right
so what what do we what can we do we can
say if we
return
or
all function okay or
x in
first row
x in first row 4
x in
w
right
so let me o means that everything inside
everything in there in the all function
needs to satisfy that means all
and what's annie there's another key
word called any what's any what's the
difference between all and any
um
or is like
like if that
it could be any of them
and then any could be like anything
and all is like comparing two and it
could be like any of them
anything is any if one of them
matches
then you return true oh means that
everything everything in
in that
right so oh here what the what means is
all x in first for x in w right look x
in w
x and w look
w is a string it's a word x is the
characters all are characters so it
basically means all the characters in w
needs to be in first row right
so needs to be first one so return all
and then all
of
all
same thing in second row yeah
or insert the row right
this is a three conditions even
either the characters from one first in
either the character from the
front w needs to be from first row or
needs to be running on secondary order
needs to be like on the server okay
so that's all so but before that we need
to convert this to lowercase to lower
total will be lower w
lower means to convert it to all
lowercase okay
the other way is we we can compare we
can convert it into set look
remember we already have the set of
first serve yeah if we convert it if we
convert it here if we converted w let's
say
[Music]
a equals set w
now we just have to check if at least a
if it's a subset of first
or if it's a subset of second or it's if
it's a subset of sir so we can use this
return
a dot is subset
e subset of first right
or
a dot is subset
of second yeah
or
a dot is subset
third okay
anybody can you tell me
do you understand this one a is a set of
the characters in the world and i want
to just
want to compare that if it's a subset of
the all the characters in the first row
or the second row also right
okay look what's up look
this is a subset this is a set a
subject
subset is the smaller one
yeah
this is a subset okay so what does it
mean s is a subset of a
everything
everything in s is contained by
a bigger set a right
so can you tell me okay s dot e subset
subset a
does it between two of us
x dot is subset of a does it return two
of us
huh
what do you mean first
come on just give me
why
okay yeah but why you say it's false at
the beginning because i don't know
okay okay how about a subset b subset is
subset of s
is it two of us
yeah because a is correct
how about this
the left is a the right is s
s is a subset of a
false okay how about s if it's this this
one yeah is this s is a subset of a
true
is a subset of a
okay right yeah okay
uh
how about a and s is exactly the same is
a a and s
this s is a subset of a
false
true it's true because exactly the same
then it's also a subset okay yeah yeah
look this this circle could go as big x
anyway
what subset means the
the elements in one set is are all
contained by another set right so this
is right
yeah
okay any questions so fast not really
okay okay that's it for today bye-bye
[Music]