go hello mri all right
okay so today we're going to talk about
how to rotate this uh array okay away
like one
two three four five six seven that's an
array
yeah we don't if we want to rotate it
once then
what we do is we take this element from
the end seven and we'll put it in the
front
so that will become
seven one two three four five six
yeah and then if we rotate again
well we become you become six seven yeah
we remove the one element from the end
and put it in front
one two three four five okay
so that's k equals one and then k equals
two equals that and k equals three will
become what
one more rotate well what we this
already come
i put take the take one from the end and
put it in
one two three four
yeah exactly okay
yeah that's the
today we're going to talk about rotation
we want to rotate an array with the nums
yeah and then we'll use k k is a
positive number
okay so let's say if there are n
elements
and equals the length of the dams
so is
for example in this case there are seven
elements right so
so if k equals n k equals seven as well
so do i need to rotate it seven times
how about fourteen times
um
yeah why is that can you tell me why why
if n equals seven and we want to rotate
the seven times
why we don't need to do anything
because
n equals k yeah because what if we
rotate the k times what happened
oh my god
k because k is
n yeah
k is the same thing and then yeah i know
what happened i mean
and then
we're done that's excellent very well
done yes that's excellent so base for
example like if n equals k then
we rotate that seven times we'll be
pivoting seven times then you will come
back to one two three four five six
seven right so if we do say eight times
that's that's the same as rotate as one
time if there we we we
rotate the nine times is the same as
we'll say two times so basically k
rotate k times is actually k
rotate the same as k rotate as
percentage n what's percentage
yeah what's percentage do you still
remember the symbol
percentage
modulus yeah
modulus okay so this is k like the
modulus yeah because look
n modulus n is zero okay okay
okay so then we can do this uh
we first of all we
we make sure this k
is between zero and k
k minus one right because
when you put a k modulus n the result
can only be
and different
different cases you'll be the result
will be between 0 2
and minus 1 inclusive
okay that's the
modulus
so we can do this we can do this uh by
rotating it so we can do this just
simulation simulation so
rotate one time we take the element from
the end and put it in the front
okay so let's say first of all k modulus
equals n so k modulus equal n is the
same as
k equal k minus n okay it's like it's
like k plus equal 1 what's what does
this mean
k
equals k plus 1 right yeah
yeah so look this is the same thing
another one k
multiplies equals 2
that's the same as k equals k times 2
right
yeah
okay so now we just have to
we just have to do this k times 4
underscore in range k
this is a numbers yeah numbers so we
take it from the end which is nouns dot
pod
that's the part so one two three we
we do this num stop top
so basically we don't support you will
take these three out of the numbers and
put it in the x right so now what's next
next is to put this x in the front in
the front so we do this
nums
dot insert
insert x right you see so first of all
we take it from the end and we put it in
the front but insert insert the first
parameter is the
place so we want to insert at the
beginning so which is the index field of
x okay
so
that will be i know we return numbers
yeah
original numbers but but here we are we
are operating on the numbers directory
directly so we're doing modifying the
array in in place so the problem of
these is that
what's the problem with this is because
these num insert takes o and time
this is uh and lam this is the array at
least so any operation on the right hand
side is constant for example like you
append
or pop this is constant but
as long as you want to insert on at the
beginning right insert at the beginning
that takes on time insert a pen let a
pen on on the left or you remove an
element in the middle that's o in time
so the time conductor is okay times n is
okay n right let's know
one way to apply uh
to improve this is using a double ndq
right so for example ndq
what we get for free is the o1 constant
term in both direction yeah you can you
can append
you can append
pop
open left top left let's both of one
constant time right so we can change
this by uh so if if this is the
this is the
uh dq so we we can do this num
so equals dq
num right so we make it a we make it um
so first of all we make it uh
actually that's that's not
directly modified here let's make it an
another another a equals dq numbers now
we can do this x equals
a dot pop
and then nums the insert to the left
then we can say a dot append left
append left this is one constant time x
right now the time connection is okay
but
we have to change this
now we want to assign it back to nums
right
so we can do this nums
nums
equals this we change the dq into the
array this egg
okay and then we can present
within arms yeah
okay
this is uh using the double ended cube
yeah we're using the double angle to do
it
okay so
another way of doing this is look one
two three four five okay let's see
then if we rotate two times that's going
to become
four five one two three right so if you
look at this
look if you look at this
yeah one two three four five two four
four five one two three so this is the k
we want to put the last k element
in the front
all right
yeah we want to put basically we want to
we want to take the last k element and
put it in the front so what we can do is
what one two three four five then if we
reverse this bit that'll become five
four
three two one right so five four six two
one so now the first k numbers are
reverse
right
and
the next n minus k numbers are also
reversed so we just have to reverse
stupid uh the first of all is to reverse
the first k numbers and then we reverse
the n minus k numbers yeah that's one
way of doing this
how do we reverse a list or such string
we can use these what kind of syntax do
you still remember
what
[Music]
yeah how do we reverse this how do we if
chronologically
but now look
we we want to re this this gives a new
copy so we don't want to do that we want
to directly reverse
reverse on the list so first of all we
reverse this array and then we reverse
the first k numbers and we deliver the n
minus k numbers so
we in order to reverse this we can use
these two pointer yeah so look
two
two pointers we swap yeah and then we
move them towards each other until they
meet in the middle yeah that's the
classic uh uh reversed uh
accurate for for a list or a string
right so let's quickly rewrite that
let's quickly write that
so first of all we can say divide define
reverse the left and right okay
so wire this is you know this for a long
time we talked about this for a very
very long time why the left smaller than
right
why the left and right
no meet
then we have to
swap nums air
nouns are
equals nums
we want to swap two things
all right do you still remember
we're done that's very excellent yeah
yeah and then
when we swap it then what's the next
thing
what's the next thing so look at what
that is
and
what's that
um
join
the look l r here so i swap these two
and then what's that what's happening
why the air is not r
[Music]
yeah so this is the classic uh reverse
function so the time connection is our n
if there are n elements here obviously
they're both both until both the pointer
meet in the middle that's going to take
most end operations
actually and operation
so now we just have to do this with this
reverse
we just need to do what
first of all we must
reverse the numbers from 0 to n minus 1
then
again reverse the first k numbers here
okay numbers
zero k minus one
and then reverse the
n minus k numbers so if it starts from n
to k to n minus one right so three
operations first of all is to reverse um
uh
first reverse the entire thing
because the first k numbers reverse the
uh minus k numbers right and minus k
numbers
okay so
so one two three four five
as we said
we want to take at least
four five put it in the front so four
five one two three so we can actually do
this very easily without the reversing
but it's a trick for the person yeah so
we can just say
nums
eric what's the noise the k
up to k up to k
and then nums
k to the n yeah so basically this
this is this part
yeah equals what these these will be
equals to
uh
to to this bit yeah to this bit so it
will be equal to
nums
uh minus k to the n right and then this
bit
will be
nums
uh
how do we like this
um
this one we want to say the first k
numbers is actually
to
uh
to minus k right so counting backwards
right and then now now that will be
minus k to the n
yeah
so it's minus 2k to the n
so what how do we interpret this minus k
minus k to the end will be set to the k
power so here will be to lead speed
yeah to this bit
so y is minus k
minus k
minus k to the end
uh minus k so my this is k minus k is
this bit
minus take to to the bit to the end
right hmm
uh
okay so so
minus k so so let's interpret this
numbers k to the end nums k
this is the original ray okay k to the n
k to the n so
k to the n is least bit
yeah this bit
equals num to decay
to to up to k so you'll be up to this
point yes and then numbs up to k up to
case this bit
equals nums up to k so it's this way
okay
yeah so this is basically the same as as
these but we write it in python which is
um
you know you know more elegant it's use
the least comprehension yeah
comprehension okay so let's see three
ways of doing this
so which way do you think it's
you can do it i mean you like it the
most which way
which way you like
there are three methods the first one
using the
list right the pop and insert that's
going to take
okay end time right okay and time
the second one using the double ndq
which is we because we we have improved
uh
we want to get this one constant term by
inserting the element in the beginning
so that's
one okay right the third one
the third one is reversing
reversing this is o and time right why
is that look yeah we're downloading
so
i mean okay and on um but look k is
smaller than n right because we we do
this operation right so
k modulus equals x
oh okay
yeah since it's shorter and faster
whether k k is smaller than n yeah but
remember we use this if if we don't do
this the k might be a minion right okay
so i have one two three four five seven
so let's rotate it a million times do
you actually want to rotate it a million
times
no because there's no point if you
rotate after seven times you'll be
you'll be coming back to the origin
right you just have to we just have to
find out which right k modulus input
right so after this k is smaller than or
equal smaller than n like smaller than
and
n times
so k is smaller than n so the second
operation is okay the third operation is
oh and why is that because we are
reversing the whole string
and then we're reversing the first thing
it's actually
it's actually largely o
n times two but we drop the constant
okay
and this one as well this one is the
nicer way of the third operation okay
it's not easy to
to find out which corresponds to which
so num look for example numbers k to the
n
is this big i want to divide this speed
so let
that comes to
that that would be overwriting by numbs
up to minus k
uh
not up to minus k so is up to minus k
this is minus k here
so actually it will be this big okay so
basically that's why it's saying okay i
want to rewrite this bit
using this bit and i want to write this
bit in this bit
yeah so it's the same thing here
okay no videos for today bye bye
bye bye