yo
hello mister miss arena all right yes
so what's the step we talk about stack
that thing first
out okay
fuzzy now yeah
first thing that's like
fascinating
and then now if i want to take it out i
need to take two offers and then take
one right yeah
okay so let's say if i have a sequence
like put push
push sequence one two three four five
okay and then i have another sequence
pop okay
listen
so for example you'll be four five
five four three two one so is this
is this sequence one possible one
possibility of
of uh
you know is one of the probability if we
push the elements in such sequence
is it
so one two three four five and then how
can we get the five four three two one
that's easy that's a very easy one okay
how about yeah you know four five
four five okay
how about four five three two one
not really four five three two one how
can you get the four wise which one yeah
yeah oh
you got one yeah and then you put it in
put three
put four
and then take out four yeah
[Music]
that it's not possible
so let's make it simple okay let's make
it simple let's let's consider that i
know why it's not possible
okay
um
um two two one three four five
okay wait two one three four five two
one three four five
why
why this is not possible
two one three four five let's do this
all right two one six one five oh my god
i shouldn't
yeah because you why the y okay what
four two one three so five so it's one
two
take two
pick one for the three
take three
put the four what is possible yeah oh
god damn it it's it's possible
try another
[Music]
yeah
take three out for the four take four
hours two
one five it's simple stuff yeah okay um
um okay two one five five five five no
no
five you're very close to it i mean okay
so by the way these animals are unique
okay we we talk about it you need
yeah
so the push and the top that
pop contains unique elements unique yeah
and then
one two
three four five yeah i take five out and
then i count because i have to take a
four right
that's a good way that's good so
so okay so
that's very good so push and push
contents only unique okay and then top
also is a unique element and
the number of elements in the push is
the number of anime in the top okay so
how do we check how do we check why this
is not possible if by looking at this
why this is not possible
because you put this because first thing
i lost out yeah so this one is first so
it obviously be lost and this one is
lastly obviously before um
okay and so this will be first but
bring you the one two three four five
and then this is obviously the end of
the two and
[Music]
yeah but that's not quite why is that
because look because you can't take out
one because if there are two numbers if
there are two numbers
one and two so you could be one two or
two one right
yeah
one two or two one so
it's not if you if you look if we're
looking at these two only two numbers
you count right the problem is one the
problem is this one why is that because
look if you take if you
take five out
and the next one is four
right
the next one is is four you can't take
you can't take uh
you can take one out
you can't take one out
without taking four three two right
yeah
so put it this way put it this way if i
have any money if one two three now the
pop pop element i want the three here
i want i want to put the next element
the the next element here if i even if
the pop sequence is three something
so i i need to take this i do i i need
to take it all right everyone yeah why
is that why is that why is that
get it because after
what happened if i don't take look now
this is the same
then because then um you can't take 201
now
uh
yes okay
um
yeah
okay so the thing is look yeah yeah look
if now the top of eddie a total steak is
three and then now the next element to
pop out is three if i don't take the
three out
what happened then you can't take out
two and one out no if i put any element
something element x here right
if i take x and four for example
right
right so so if i don't take it out so
the next it can't
if i push another element out then the
three can't be taken without taking the
form but we are done we want the four we
own the three first right
you get it
this is the key part okay listen no no
please don't do that no
look
now the top of element is top of the
stack is three
and then the next element is three one
to take out if we if at this time this
is the best term if we don't take it off
it means that we need to push some
element to the top right if we put it on
all right so what does it mean if we in
in the future we want to take the three
out we need to take the four first
right
make sense
so that that doesn't work right because
we want to take a three hour if this is
the good time okay i'm telling you that
this is a good time to take the three
out
but you say okay i don't want to take a
three i want to wait in the future but
when the future i push another element
so what happens if you want to take a
three hour you need to take the phone
right
you want everything
so with this approach is that if as long
as we have the element
top of the stack equals to the top next
four element we just take it off
otherwise we will miss the chance
right so at the end we just
check if they are
uh
if we just check if the stack is empty
right then that will be
good enough okay let's do this
and then after that
and then we're going to walk through the
steps and then you can understand how it
works okay so first of
let's say define
valley
okay valid
uh
stack sequence
stack sequence yeah okay we have this
push
we also have a problem there's they are
the same
same number they contain the same number
of the
equal they are equivalent equivalence of
the numbers okay
so now we have uh this i i equals zero
points to the
this is in that point points to which
element we we are about to pop next and
we have a stack st stack equals at least
which is a stack then we go through the
sequence of the push for next number and
in
push
right so first of all
we need to push st dot append append put
it in the right sp open n okay and then
now look
we need to check right
y let's st
means that
come on look why the top of this white
stack is not empty and
and the top of the stack st minus one
is
equals to the next port element right on
the top everyone
also
also actually actually i have to add it
actually we especially check if i also i
is smaller than the length of the pop
okay
so just make sure it doesn't go outside
the boundary
along with the wall we just do and we
just do what
i plus equals one we move to the next
one
and st dot top
and then at the end just return
it return we can return two things
return length as t equals zero
all right this is all
oh oh i put the comma here or not st
this is the same thing
or we can do i we can do this i check
equals the length
of top okay
okay this is the angle okay
let's do this here
one
two this is the push here push it until
three four five
and then the element is four five three
two four five three two one okay
and then we're going to check if this
this is the wonderful possibility of the
popping
popping from the stack if the sequence
is one two three four five or one
pushing element okay how do we do it
look
all right
that's t
this is the stack i equals zero
why can we use the stack as emptiness
right
why can we use the list as an empty
state
because we can take what st probably
probably say
yeah first thing yeah okay
okay now look for push
all right look yeah we're here
s t dot attack i
apparent n so what do we do
what do we do we take we put the
everyone look look at me we put the one
in the stem right
everybody come on let's put that one in
this step
and then here go here
look what's this what does this mean
here we're here
right here while the stack is not empty
and
i is smaller than the stack size yes
length of top equals five yeah by the
way length of top equals five this time
and the top of that xt minus one equals
the prop
[Music]
points the first element to pop right
come on this is very important right
here
okay so what do we do
we just don't enter this loop and then
we go to the next what's the next
element
two
we put a two here yeah
is the two
the top of the step two equals to four
no right sorry don't take so what's the
next three
yeah i put it in
and the same it doesn't equal to four
right
four i put it in okay here this is
interesting now
at least i'm pushing the four now and
after four here
these four equals the top of the stack
right xt minus one right
yeah
so what do we do
we take it off yeah we take it out and
we we we take it out and we move this i
i plus one here
yeah
okay again
five is equals to the top of that no
right so again i put you the five here
okay look five
five
equals the top of the stack right
so what do we do
what do we do
uh we um
what do we do if it's the same what do
we do we pop take it off and then i
move to the next alright so it looks
three
equals three equals the top of the three
what do we do we take it off
move to the next
yeah two you guys lost over two
take it off
take it off so
at the end
the stack is empty
so it's a valid sequence right it's a
very secret otherwise it's not okay oh
let's let's do what's the what's the
secret it doesn't work five one
two three four yeah
okay
look at this five one
three two four yeah okay okay come on
listen okay let's do it
one push it in yeah
the top of the stake equals five now
right
push your two
is it the same no no three
no
four no
so look we want to compare the top up to
the left right right no right five yes
right so what happened we take it out
and move it to here
yeah
one the
but there's no more elements to push
and then so we just go out yeah the
stack has four elements so what does it
mean these two elements can't be pushed
why is that because we want to push the
we want to pop one
but one is at the bottom
you can't pop one without popping four
three two one
right
first and two but i want to we want to
make sure one is the next to pop but the
top of the stack is four so it doesn't
work this way
makes sense
so the gritty part is here look
why the stack is not empty and
i smaller than that okay obviously we
have to check this eye pointer if it's
smaller if it's smaller than the pop
element okay
if it is then look as long as okay this
is the key part today as long as the
next element to pop out
is the same as topple stack
okay look then what do we do we take it
out we move it pop it yeah we take it
out of it
it's not it's the same we take it out
from it and at the end we check the
length of his legs yeah okay the time
complexity
the time connection what's the tango
next thing think about it if there are
an anime
you know
if there are any elements what's the
timetable
um
this looks like
look at this looks like
uh these are any inner look but it
doesn't affect the overall time
complexity why why is that why is that
why is that because look
they are at most
and most anonymous to pop okay as long
as popping
as long as finish and then that you
won't be as this loop won't be executed
again make sense
why is that look this eye pointer only
goes forward it doesn't go backward
right
the eye pointer is the points to the
next element to pop out right
and it only goes forward right so it
only has a must and
and it's duration
after any iteration you won't come in
again and then
uh
yeah and then the first outer loop only
uh iterates and
and times okay
yeah
okay
okay let me give a quiz a quiz and then
you can see if it's uh one two three
four five okay and then
how about
three two
four one five is it possible
is it possible
come on come on you can use this okay
let's do it again
one put yeah two
three okay it's the same now take it out
and move it to the next okay two take it
out move it to next
and then
then four
four take it off move to next
next
one take one now you have to take one
yeah
yeah and then five five okay you get it
yeah perfect okay let's see for today
good job
[Music]