go hello hello guys hello hi you've been
playing rubik's cube for a while yeah so
today with our surgeries is to count how
many different possibilities
for the configuration of lubricant
so look that's one a little bit cute
how it looks like inside you see it
looks like so how many of these how many
colors
yeah how many of these
um they're six six so no matter how i
change they they don't change right so
the positions don't they don't change
the
yellow the opposite will be
white yeah it doesn't change right so so
the different
the different permutation of the
logic cube is just basically i put these
pieces back in yeah i put it back right
yeah so the first question is how many
of these hq how many of energy cubes
energy cube 12
yeah so hq these these are executed
three four in the top
four in a meter and four in the bottom
that's 12 yes and how many corner kills
eight
yeah eight four in the
top then none in the middle and four in
a
in in in a bottom okay
so for example let's
put the corner cubes first yes so if i
have like four cubes there are three uh
three
so which one is the
corner yeah you see these like confused
cubes so i can
i can the first how many possibilities i
can put the first
corner cube in
how many oh hey yeah i put let's say i
put it somewhere here right yeah and
then i pick another one
yeah how many possibilities i can put in
seven seven etcetera yeah okay so how
many possibilities if i put it on a
uh
eight uh lubricant right corner cube
is it a times seven times six times
what's this
i need to think what's this no no you
don't need to give me a number but this
is actually bacteria remember this
bacteria yeah
okay so the same thing for the education
h cubes how many possibilities
is the same yeah the first one is
yeah how many how many possibilities for
the adjective if we want to put the
execute i pick the hq yeah take the add
cue
and if i put the attitude
this one's poisonous
i am to put it in one of the 12
positions and then the second one will
be 11 right and the third one will be 10
right yeah so that would be
1 that would be 12 factorial yeah
okay so
so
but the thing here okay there's less one
more thing is when i put a corner cube
how many possibilities i can twist it
how many possibilities look i put the
corner how many possibilities i can
twist this okay three where that and how
many possibilities i can twist uh
two way done so so
so for each one right so for each one
for for each corner cube i can have
three
uh three
twisting three three configurations so
that would be
how many of
how many of the corner that will be 8 so
that will be 3 2 to the power of a right
and at least this age each edge has two
right
because look at you can just twist it
simply simply do this look this is yeah
twisted
so that would be two possibilities so i
time i multiply 2 to the power of 12.
make sense
yeah
okay so
this is the number
that
this is the total number of different
ways
i can reassemble this ruby cube
right right you got it
you get it okay so here let me let me
talk about it again okay so this is the
number of ways i can assemble this
lubricant by putting these pieces back
for for this one
square factorial is the number of ways
we can put the hq
a factorial is the number of ways we can
put a
corner cubes but for each corner cube we
can have three twists right that's the
level three to the power of a
for each
for each uh h cube there will be two two
possibilities i can twist the edge
yeah one way around that'll be two to
the power of two so this is the number
of the total different ways i can
assemble the loop cube but
these are not sometimes it's not
resolvable yeah do you know what's
solvable ruby cube and the other one is
not solvable yeah
and only like if you twist the corner
you can't really solve it well done okay
sir
that's here
yeah if i twist it look this one
yeah this bread is supposed to be here
if i twist it
you can't solve it right there's no way
to solve it so
so how many possibilities so how many
these one have three three uh
twists only one of them yeah only one of
them can be solvable right
this one let's look over here this edge
if i twist the edge
i know but if i this is the complete
soft softball and then if this is
already soft and i twist twist the edge
it becomes not stoppable right yeah
doesn't make sense
yeah i know but
this is the same thing
right so like only
half of it
is not solvable how is solvable okay but
this one look this one is more tricky
i swap i need to
add this cube
right
back
yeah i put it back
so look i swapped the two edges cube uh
alright this is the this is the thing i
so from a song of a loop cube i i took i
so what do we do from a song of software
look here we we swap any two pieces and
then let's not becomes an unsolvable why
is that why is that
so from a silverback do you have a
uh
ruby cube yeah i mean it's a soft
already and then if we twist if we swap
any two to edge pieces it becomes
unsolvable why is that because you you
can't just walk two
uh two pieces without
uh without affecting other silver pieces
yeah okay so let's halfway so we need to
divide this by
by 12 right yeah so if we divide this by
12 all right this is the number of
solver
solve the rubik's
state permutation look three of them uh
one one with us
is solvable because we can't just twist
that we can't we can't just twist the
corner cube
half of it
is solvable because we can't just talk
we can't just solve this uh h cube
and half of these
is unsolvable because we can't just work
yeah
we can't just swap any two pieces
without affecting other pieces
okay so v this number look how do you
pronounce this number a big number
quintillion
this is this number if you calculate
this number
that will give this yeah so what's this
number
quantile 43 container 255
quadrillion yeah and three
trillion 274 billion 489 million
850 thousand thousand okay so this is
the number of different states
for
of different possible solvable states
for a lubricant why speak right
can can we use the computers
to prove us this big number
no right because it's so big yeah look
it's 43 followed by how many digits
oh how many digits
18 digits okay so it's four point
actually four point is around four point
three times ten to the power of eight
nineteen yeah four four four point three
okay
so this is actually quite big number
it's not um
it's not proof possible okay yeah
yeah so okay so what have you learned
today come on mess
a little bit cube how many different
states yeah this is the number okay so
queen queen queen yeah
4.3 43 companion possible states okay
yeah that'll be for today
good job bye-bye
bye-bye