hello hello guys hi okay so today we do
some counting problem yeah so we want to
find out the rubik's cube okay so
uh the so probably what's the do we have
a size of ruby cube like one times one
something like that normally yeah it's
like just like a cube yeah one times one
yeah so how many squares in rectangle
follow one times one times that one uh
lube cube
the zero rectangles and one
one square one square into size so how
many sides are left six so that'll be
six okay and how about two that's two by
two okay here i said that two by two so
how many
how many if let's consider the size okay
squares for how many like squares for uh
five yeah and very much
yes yeah four five because there are
four little ones and um
one bigger one yeah so oh
yeah five times six thirty and how about
the squares oh how about rectangles
um four four yeah one two
three four okay
yeah okay okay and then how about the
three by three okay three by two which
is basically here three by three i can't
get four times four
three by three i can't get this through
quickly yeah no no let's consider the
three by three how many squares let's
say how many i'll give it four times
four
eleven
no wait one
okay so there are nine little ones
and then these one
four medium ones
and one big one right yeah but for the
square i'll follow the rectangles you'll
be much trickier
yeah
one two three three four five six
and seven eight nine
ten eleven twelve no
one yeah two
three
four
five oh yeah because yeah seven yeah
eight
nine ten
eleven
twelve
14 15
6 weeks you're over counting right
yeah but how do you get sorry no can we
get more than four okay so four times
four how so you'll be
much tricky right because it will be
much tricky to count it yeah well anyway
i think it's 22. yeah it's 22. why
one two three okay four five six
seven eight nine ten
12 13 14 15 16 i see 18 okay
um 19 20 to 1 20 oh okay okay yeah it's
almost a little bit complicated but
basically we need to count the
rectangles yeah the tango is the
different sizes
yeah all three
squares yeah yeah yeah okay okay so
yeah yeah but yeah horizontally
vertically but the thing is that
if i tell you
to i increment this n for example like
four term four five times five six times
six it will be harder more harder for us
to count it yeah but luckily we can use
the computer to count how we can come do
it we can
we can do we can do what we can brew for
us one corner yeah
on the over the left lock left top left
corner
and then pull forward
another corner yeah and this the second
corner needs to be on the right bottom
side of the first corner and now we just
have to check the edge
if the both edges are
the same then it's a square if not then
that's a
rectangle yeah okay so
you want to give me the answer let me fi
i was just saying that with the computer
we can we can find it we can counter
squares number of squares and rectangles
uh easily right but with the human
you'll be harder right so how do we
actually do it we just need to prove us
the top left corner and the right uh
bottom right corner of a square you know
it's a square of rectangle right and we
count it yeah we just have to check the
edge if it's angle equal okay so that
will be easy let's do it okay
so let's do it let's define curve
and then n yeah if n is smaller than
if it equals zero then obviously we need
to do what uh
if n is zero okay if n is zero we return
zero zero we return two values yeah
return to value which is the number of
the
edges and the number of squares number
of the rectangle okay now this is the
tricky part we go through we need to
uh
we need to count
yeah we need to count these
so first of all we need to count we need
to start with a
a a with the top left horizontal yeah
this is the number of the
columns oh we can say it's number of
rows yeah it doesn't matter so this way
a and b so the coordinate of the first
uh
first coordinate is a and b and the
second one will be c and d yeah
okay
so now we just have to put this answer
answer squared equals zero at the
beginning answer square is zero
rectangle
rectangles in the four by four
four by four okay and
one side yeah
okay okay now okay let's call
let's do this okay let's fall a in range
up to n plus one what why is it up to n
plus one look for the three by three
yeah look zero one two three right it's
up to n right so because they're three
by three n equals three there are
actually four choices for the first one
yeah but yeah there are four
possibilities
uh and then for the second row uh second
one b will be range and plus one
for the third one c will be the
the the second coordinate yes c in range
a plus one we start from a plus one
right because it has to be on the right
bottom side and then n plus one
and then for b will be in range b plus
one up to m plus one uh up to n okay
actually
for the first continent it doesn't
go to the end right because if we go to
the end what happens if we go to the end
there is no such point as the right hand
side right you'll be out of boundaries
so we the the first coordinate you will
be just these on this part on this uh
on this uh region yeah you'll be just on
this region okay
uh okay and then now we we iterate all
possibilities and what's the edge if
t minus b yeah equals
c minus a what happened
if t minus if the second coordinate
if t minus p equals c minus a that would
be a square right yeah because the both
sides are equal right
yeah yeah so then in this case i have
squares plus e2 right
otherwise
it's a rectangle right yeah rectangles
plus this one
okay then i have to return let's just
return the side a single side and we can
multiply by six right so return the
squares and then rectangle
okay and first of all let's see if
this makes sense with the small numbers
here so let's say point
between the
what between the
zero zero if it's yellow then you should
return zero right
uh okay let's let's look for n in range
up to four okay zero one two three okay
then print
and and then
count n okay yeah and let's see what's
the answer
is it right zero zero obviously one cube
is one zero two is five four right all
right three is fourteen two twenty two
yeah it's correct yeah yeah fourteen
fourteen
fourteen squares or three by three will
be q on one side and twenty two
rectangles okay
do you want me to
can you give me an answer for five times
for the
five times five are you looking for the
five times five
i'm
solving it yeah you're solving it okay
so that count let's just quickly give
answer five times right how many squares
and how many rectangles on the five
times five rubik's cube on one side okay
let's see this answer look the computer
can just do this so 55 squares and a
hundred seventies return that's a huge
number let's say 20 20 10 20. so you we
wouldn't be able to call these right
look
wow look this is huge yeah 2870
squares on a 20 by 20 rubik's cube on
one side 41 and 250 rectangles wow
uh okay i don't know if that exists okay
but let's we can do this mess
uh it takes time why is that it takes
some the time complexity is what can you
know look at this how many loops is
there
what's the time complexity
yeah i went to the powerful look and for
each n times you need n times and n
times wow actually it gives the answer
okay
it's a huge number yeah if it takes time
because
if i put a thousand and you don't give
me any answer in short amount of time
because it's too slow yeah
why is that because we already
put a check here yeah if it's yeah it's
a special case yeah we wouldn't be able
to we don't need to count it if it's
zero by zero yeah because it's just zero
or nothing yeah all right we don't need
to count it and at the beginning for
line four number five is the count
counter for the squares and for the
rectangles and then for a and b a and b
a b is the converse coordinate c d is
the second coordinate so basically we
are professing
each possibility combination of these
two two locations yeah and now we can
check the side once we have this a b and
c d
location we can check the size right if
the both sides are equal it's a square
if both sides are not equal that's a
rectangle right
yeah okay that will be
that'll be for today okay bye
bye bye