yeah okay so this is the final tree
yeah final three this is one three by
the way final three yeah two final means
two one kid one parent can have almost
two
yeah and that is not which doesn't have
any kids we call it leaves at least one
doesn't have parents we call it
how many um
parents can
not have
[Music]
how many parents
one yeah and most one yeah this one
doesn't have parent it's called load
okay at least one so either
for a binary if it's you know if it has
zero or two
two kids we call it um complete final
three okay complete financing yay
okay
complete
okay so so let's see this one is this
it's least complete yeah one three six
is this completely balancing um no but
it has a hole yeah okay and if we put
complete this hole it's also a
perfect financing because because every
every level is yeah every level is
completed and it's called perfect
biology okay so if i stand from the left
hand side looking from the right yeah we
talk about this on day 92 yeah so what
can we see
you can see one two and four okay if we
stand from the right hand side looking
at front to the left
okay and then if i put in another one
hey what can we see
in both sides
so that will be one two four eight and
here will be
one
three six a right yeah easy yeah is it
yeah yeah okay so
we talked about buying a breakfast
search yeah breakfast travel level by
level what's that what's the
best research
order
for this binary um one two three four
five seven six eight yeah okay how about
the deficits we if we go for the left
hand side
if we travel the left subtree first and
then root and the right subtree we what
we call it in order right this is in
order
left node right in order
oh
you know for the different search we can
have different order yeah we can have
this node left right or
left and right no okay so this is
preorder this is in order this is first
order one one good way to remember this
come on one good way to remember this we
just check this
n which is the loop
yeah where is it it's in the middle we
call it in order
in the first one we call it pre-order in
the middle we call it inorder you know
last we call it post order right so i
can't remember
look at this one and it's in the
last so it's post in the first one keep
on thinking like the last one is green
uh-huh okay
in this one in the pre okay so sometimes
we go also called reversed you know we
can do it reverse for example reverse in
order would be r and air yeah
the reverse uh
reverse preorder will be r uh
ln and rf and then reverse
okay
so look if we do this step for that
because you know differences what do we
get for the recursion
uh pre-order
one two four
five three seven eight six yeah yeah
how about
how about a post order
how about a post order um
four
five okay well what did we talk about
one two three this is copy over sorry
yeah this is
one two three four okay for first order
i think we are talking about
this one right so it is what
four five
two
eight
seven
six three one one yeah exactly
okay
so for the preference search we use the
queue right so we put in the queue for
the test method you will use the stack
you know most of the cases we use the
recursion which is uh faster to
implement okay so i'm going to enter in
the preferences first define let's say
you know it depends on left or right
let's just say view like view of the
tree view of a tree
and then we have a root
and first of all answer yeah answer
equals
an empty list yeah empty list
so if not root
we just return yeah we can answer
this is a special case we have to handle
yeah
so now let's say put it in the queue
q equals how do we implement how do we
use the cube
double nd
thank you
so what do we need to put in
here
we put the loot we put a note in the
queue and when we dequeue it yeah dq
means that take the element out of a
queue yeah pop it from the other topic
from front right first thing first out
yeah first things first up so we need to
put put the kids in right
look how can you go through this with me
come on
can you go through this with me how can
we this is answer yeah answer
yeah i put a one here yeah
this is one so i take it out
so i take it off right i take it now i
need to put it in the answer yeah
because this is the first time right
yeah
okay
now what happened one has the
the kids two and three
yeah so which two should i put a two or
three depending on
which
which side i'm standing at is from left
and right
let's say i want to
first i want to get the left left left
side view yeah
[Music]
so i need to put a 2 in right come on
look at me
i put a two
yeah
but i have to put it in a queue two and
three in here
and i take the two out
i take the two out i put the kids four
and five
but four
well four is this is the left hand side
wheel so i put it here right
and then three i think you know i don't
do anything before i take it out i don't
it doesn't have any kit five doesn't
have a kit okay
yeah
so but
but if i
want to do this twice right side view
the only difference is that
the kit
instead of the first kit i take the last
kid
right
yeah all right
this makes sense yeah
so why
why are q
so
first of all first of all i need to take
it out karen
actually no actually
actually what do i need to do n equals
the length of a q
this is the com this is the number of
the
kids
number of the notes in the next layer
yeah in the next level
and yeah
okay so now i answer the append
append
q zero
if it's uh if you want to retrieve the
the first note or q minus one which is
the last note yeah and then for
i
in range invent
and
if
q
i
yeah q i don't left if it has the left
kids and then we put the kid in here all
right
q uh
q dot append
actually we can do this x equals q dot
pot
pop left okay
yeah kill the pop left
and then if x to the left
kill the opponent extra left
and if x don't write
[Music]
okay let me go through this again okay i
think this is the little bit
the problem here
okay so
depending here depending on
from left or right q0 means from the
left q minus one
meaning
we want to
take the right side view right side view
this is just the very standard graphics
search with a search
now n equals lens cube n is the number
of the
n is the number of the
what of the notes in the next layer yeah
so we can append q dot
we can append either the leftmost or the
rightmost
kit with the uh to the
to the to the view yeah to the answer
then
every time we we can secure we can take
all the kids on the same level
top them out and then push their kids
back to the cube yeah
so another way of doing is this look if
we we can we can do this inside but here
we have to check if
if if i is 0
or
if i is
if i is the n minus 1 right depending on
where so inside this inside this we can
check if it's if the index is the first
one or the last one yeah this also works
okay
yeah
make sense
okay so buffer search
okay now let's go back to the test step
research
so
how
how do we
how do we use the definitions to
to solve this problem
[Music]
okay i'm going to show you here
temperature is a little bit different
okay
one
two
three
four
five
six
okay
for the definition
when we're traveling with this
what what information do we need
to
to you know
what information do we need we need to
you know
when it's a lot
yeah it's something like that yes
yes okay so depending if we want to go
to the left left side view yeah so we do
this pre-order so every time we go to an
we go to a new level so obviously we
need when we define this deficit before
dms we have this loot and we need to
pass the level
and the beginning is here
right so when we pass down the tree
we go to the left the level plus equals
one we go to the right the level plus
equals one right
yeah but we need to store these stories
in uh this january right
the first time we depending on
on if we want to do this left side or
right side view if it's on the left side
view we want to update like that
the the key it will be the level yeah
key will be level and the value will be
the
the the the note right
so it depends if it's the left side view
the first time we visit a level we
remember it but we don't and then the
subsequent visit we don't update the
value right
and if we want to go to the uh do the
right side view we always update it with
the pre-order right all alternatively we
can swap the pre-order pre-order is this
one yeah the
one two
four you see you see how i go one two
four right so i do the different search
with one two four so this is the exactly
the left side view right but for the
right side view it's it's not right for
the right side view i need to do this
one three
on the other side oh i can do it one two
three three one of these is this yeah
one two
four
one two four
and then
five six three
yeah if i want to use this sequence to
do the right side view which is one
three five six
you see
one
three five six you see
okay
so how do we do that we use a dictionary
yeah we use the dictionary
so uh
so if not loot obviously we just return
we don't do anything
yeah depending on what we do load the
left
yeah do the left level plus one
right and then now i visit these three
so i can do what i can
here this is the code if i have this
data here
data is a dictionary dictionary default
additional area
default additional which is the integer
the value default type will be integer
the level
so then i can do this data
data level yeah level
equals
load
double value and then i can do
i can travel the right tree
level plus one right when we go go down
the tree in the next level we have uh
we have to update the level right
because look this is that was yellow
level one level two
when i travel the left tree
plus one well i'll travel like three i
plus one
yeah so once i
do this once i
do this dfs load i give a beginning
level which is zero
then
here
okay then you tell me if i do this
the data level will be the left side
view or right side view choose one
right
yeah why is right
why why is that
what we're looking for
[Music]
good answer that's what we're looking
for because we keep updating
we keep updating
one
two three okay so this let's take this
example one two three what happened
what's the sequence
one three two three right
okay so the the order of which is the
note is one two three so the order of
the look there are two nodes and number
one right
so data level one equals two
and then data level one equals three
so what's the data number one what's the
data number one here and at this point
we are updating when we traversing using
default search we're updating the date
like dictionary the level the key is the
level okay so listen to me here
data one two three so what's the data
one what's the what's the final value of
data one
three yes three because look we first of
all theta one equals two but we
visit the tree
in the pre-order so it means the three
gets visited
last
so what does it mean it means the last
the last val node visited will be
updated will be used as the right side
view right yeah
yeah
if we want to do this opposite so we
need to swap these two right we visit
the right tree first and we reach the
level three or alternatively we can we
can check this if
the first time we update it so if level
in data
then we do this
if level not in data
if we don't the first time we visit them
a new level we record it then you'll be
two the three will never get
the chance to update
right make sense
yeah so once we get this the answer we
just need to push the answer to it so so
for
i in sorting we need to sort it
sorted the data the keys yeah the key
the data keys will be the levels
the levels insulted answer will be zero
one and then we answer
the append
append
data i okay
then that will be the answer for the
definition for the levels left side view
or right side depending on how do we
how to
visit how to visit the final tree
all right why are you lost
a little bit
not too much not too much if you
understand what i'm talking about here
yeah it's depending on look if we want
to let look here this this symmetry
from the left if we want to
get the left side view
yeah if we if we want to get the left
side let's talk about this pre-order
yeah no
left to right okay no the left right
would be one two three okay one two
three one two three okay
one two three
the depth search
we visit the definite search but for
each when we visit the node we we pass
the level
yeah we pass the level so we put we use
the level as a key
to store the values for each level
in a dictionary in that in a hash map
so if we visit all the tree in one two
three right
yeah if we visit the three in one two
three and we update the the hash map
first layer second layer
the
data one
will be three that's the right side view
right
or
if we want to
update the hashman the first time we
don't update it the second time so theta
one would be two then that's the left
side view alternatively we can do this
note
right r will be reversed in order
if we do this in reverse you know there
will be one three two so there'll be one
three two so if we update these
then that would be
the opposite it'll be opposite right
yeah
yeah yeah
so that's the test search and the
previous one is the preferences one two
three is easier
follow for the breakfast search every
time we just take everything out because
the notes in the queue belongs to the
same level so once we know is the notes
on the third level we can append the
left most which is located at q0
or we append the
the last note which is q minus one
depending on if you are looking from the
left or from right okay
yeah that would be for today bye-bye
yeah the tangent let's see it source uh
o and if the n is the number of nodes in
the binary tree okay and we're using
additional
space which is the queue or stack okay
bye