yo hello mr mr ryan i'm right okay so
today we'll talk about something very
fundamental very basic
path by variance reference or object
reference so what does it mean so let's
say if i define the function f
and i put a value x here right yeah and
i want to say x equals one right come on
yeah
yeah so look at this i have a defined
function we take a parameter but inside
if i say x equals 1 what happened here
everybody look so if i have these x
defined outside the scalable function i
say x equals 2
and then i call this function x x and i
put in the x can you tell me what what's
the value of x come on look
so
i define the red
variable x equals 2
and i call this function
which change the value x equals 1 and
then i put in the x what's the value
what's the
what's the result x
ryan
what's the result right uh what's what's
the result guess
two
your case is two what's your guess look
i haven't defined the value
but i change i call it f x
inside your change x equals one i print
x so what happened
u two x
three
the y is the switch x one
x equals one
one or two yeah i know it's one of two
guess
or your chain i mean i haven't talked
about this before yes don't worry just
learn them again
it's not one okay two yeah two two is
the right one why is that that means
let me
explain this okay i have two sets of
data here so what one is immutable
what's immutable
immutable multiple and the other one is
mutable the uh the data type immediately
quiet what is immutable
what is it beautiful can't keep quiet
no no what's immutable what's new about
come on
mutable is
change mutable is changeable by the way
it's changeable yes chen this is change
but
by this one kang chang right kang
so we have immutable like the integer
the integer the float
okay some sometimes the strings yes
strings are immutable
the sets uh the the set goes to the
multiple yeah and the list here
string and what else topper yeah pepper
yeah and then dictionary transition
these are changeable yeah this year and
set the other the other one is frozen
set you have frozen set frozen means
that
this set is
is uh spidey array yeah it's unbeatable
yeah
right and this here will be bites away
okay
and then i'll be complex here okay
okay so if this is
immutable
so as immutable means you can't change
right basically so everything you change
here
can't affect anything outside so because
it's immutable so at least you can think
of this x is a individual copy yeah it's
not the same copy as this
it's not the same x
so
no matter what you change inside doesn't
affect anything else so that's two okay
how about if i have this define
f
let's say i choose something from here
which is changeable let's say a list x
and then x dot append
it's a list i append the
number five okay
and then at the beginning x equals one
two three four
and then if we call this f x what i'm
doing the x
what do you think x will be
okay so this is com this x is one three
four five exactly yeah because this x
list is
changeable mutable so i pass the x to
this function whatever
changes in this x it means the same
right x apparently said i mean at 5
that's a very good job yeah okay so okay
so
look if so
to sum up the price and use the option
reference if it's immutable right you
pass a another individual copy if it's a
mute button pass the same copy so when
you pass the
immutable when you pass the separate
copy yeah it's actually passed by values
values means that a clone a value of it
but reference is like
the same copy yeah same copy so for
example if i call you
ryan yeah ryan lie
or i call you holzer like
means the same people right
yeah ryan lie yeah can you go brush your
teeth
how's it like can you brush your teeth
yeah i'm going to buy ryan like a toy
today i'm going to buy ryan like a house
like a toy today same thing so that's
reference right reference look
you this is you this is you
this is you i can call you by writing
why do you have a fat head
okay man that's okay that's okay i call
you my name
ryan
means you
oh hold up
means you okay
you got a sword
oh sorry
okay
yeah
okay so this
is my hair is not that long
okay
uh another thing another thing another
thing i want to talk about is this if i
want to change this let's say look i
have another thing okay another thing
define
f without function without anything if i
said x equals one
i i haven't part i haven't
given it a parameter so if i have x
equals two here i call this f
and point x
so what's the result
what's the result come on
look now
this x comes from nowhere
okay
so i haven't passed this x to it so
obviously this x and this x
it's not the same thing so you'll be
2 right so if i want to say because this
x leaves inside the locus goal of the
function this x is different than x x if
i want to say this x is the same i have
to
declare say global
global x so when i put this global x
what does it mean
it means this x
is the x outside so when i print when i
do this x will be equal to one okay
yeah okay so we talked about this the
frozen set is the the immutable version
of a set
uh the complex yeah we don't want to
talk about these because this mathematic
this is
a bit complex they're complex numbers
when you get older yeah when you let you
get you will learn the complex numbers
okay so we're not talking about that
today the bytes
buys and buys away okay buys a buyer
basically each byte is 255
feet okay a bite is 259 bits so we can
declare as bite
yeah buys
i mean i don't know
97 98.99
so now this corresponds to a b c okay
when you declare spikes it's not
changeable you can't say okay this is x
equals 5 don't say x 1 equals something
it doesn't work
but by its array we can declare it by
the way so it's it's
it's uh it's actually a list yeah this
array so we can change it right so this
is by the way
okay
yeah so what have you learned today
right about
[Music]
let's say
s
is
x okay then
we have x equals
uh
5 6 7 and then x equals
one two three so print x is it one two
three or five two five six seven oh
x equals couple one two three and a pass
to f uh x equals five six seven so
what's x
what
uh yes why why is that because you can't
change because you can't change
we can't yeah because this is tupperware
how do you pronounce this one
is immutable we can't change it when we
can't change it
everything inside the function is a
separate copy because we can't change
the thing outside right but if it's a
changeable like uh at least
look look eric you missed this bit look
if it's x the x is the least yeah this
is changeable so x dot appends five when
we pass one two three four x is
changeable it will be zero five got it
so it's passed by object reference when
it's mutable it will be changed you only
do this it will be changeable
when it's immutable so everything inside
this function is a separate copy right
yeah part path by value
pass by value is like uh uh
the pass by value yeah it's like uh
what's this okay so this is uh
this is a cube yeah present value it
will be separate copy
the same separate copy right yeah but
pass by reference is not that's what i'm
saying ryan this is ryan
although houston is ryan
i've asked ryan
to go to bust his teeth
that's not an excuse okay okay so uh
that will be for today so yeah that's it
bye-bye
bye