hello hello every hello ryan
happy new year okay so what we have
learned yesterday
okay if i'm priority kill what's
priority
smallest number first in priority out
yes
yeah okay so today what's about priority
queue yeah priority queue so uh so
you're given each
each number each each element in the
queue has been given a priority
and then when we kill we call it the q
the q
respectively the q is to get the
proper element from the q right so it
would take
the highest priority right okay so now
this is very useful for example that
we if we have a if we if we
have a problem like this if we have a
few sticks yeah
with different lens two four
three and then each time i ask you to
merge
two of them for example much to put it
together for
to connect for example if i take a three
and four i
three and four yeah you become seven
yeah
so now the the stick will be seven and
two
but the cost let the cost to the two lab
is seven okay yeah
and then now i have a two and seven and
i connected it will be nine right
the cost will be nine right so
when there's only one we end the game
and the cost will be nine plus 7 which
is
16 yeah all right so can you think of a
way
to do this with the minimum cost
do you get it for example if this you
move
you add the put the add and
three and four together that would be
seven yeah the cost would be seven yeah
and then seven plus two equals nine the
cost will be nine so
all together cost will be 16. okay and
another way of doing it if i do these
two and three together
two plus three will become five right
first would be five yeah sorry and then
four
plus four f five plus four equals nine
and the cost will be 9 so the cost is
14.
get it so this is better than this do
you get it
yeah so every time we pick 2
we merge it connected to each other and
the cost will be the total length of
this
the new new stick after merge
and when there's only one when there's
only one when every
stakes are merged into one and then we
end the game and the cost will be the
total
the tokens caught after uh at each match
do you understand this problem yeah yeah
i mean
so any idea any idea how can we do it
do we have a strategy how can we do it
with the minimum cost
so obviously this is 16 this is 14.
i think you just add the two smallest
whoa where's that why yeah it's true
you've always picked the smallest
yeah yeah i can show i can
i can tell you why this is a good
strategy greedy
greedy yeah greedy how cool makes me
hungry yeah greedy so pick the smoke
two smallest two smallest every time
two smallest yeah two smallest okay so
for example if we have a four
four for example four a one let's call
it a b c d
okay just two lengths left if there are
two
there are four lengths and let's merge
it from the left to the right
let's budget from the left to right so
first of all
a plus b yeah the cost is a plus
b right this is the cost we want to add
and then
now yeah it's just symbol
we don't know the value but it's a plus
and then a plus b
plus c the cost will be a plus b
plus c right yeah and then another match
another magic a plus b plus c plus b
the cost will be a plus b plus c plus b
so how many a how many b how many c's
there are
three a three
[Music]
two one okay so these are four numbers
and these a and b needs two times three
times and this c is
times two times and d times one time so
if these are the smallest the chords
will be smaller is that
if the is the biggest if a and b are the
biggest the chords will be biggest yeah
so the a and b must be the smallest all
right
yes do you get it if look look
if if we even really put it one
two three four so this a will be
one three no no no a
a would be i'll be choosing one right
because if i choose two
or just a and b will be one and two if i
choose four
the cost will be maximized right because
it comes three times
right three times a times plus three
times b so a and b must be one or two
and then two two c will be two look if
two times three
plus four and then two times four plus
three which one is bigger
this is 10 this is 11. of course i need
to because this
times 2 so c is to be smaller right got
it
because 2 times c plus d
if c is 3 and d is 4. i obviously i want
to see
smallest because it's times two right if
you pick the four that would be two
times four
bigger than three am i right yeah
bigger than that i'm picking the three
together yes
so the strategy i just proved like it's
always
optimum to pick the two smallest in the
selection
in the extraction first okay so how can
we do this
how can we do this how can we implement
this
using a heap yes
using the heap how do we do this define
define let's call it cost okay mean cost
green cost let's call it sticks okay
sticks let's just call it s
okay right
so this is an array how about we make it
a hip
and every priority kill every time i
pick a two and you'll be always smallest
am right and then i add it i merge it
and i put it back to the stick am i
right
hold on how can we do this remember hip
hip five right ep five hq
doggie pie import remember every import
hit hit q as
hq okay why are you doing line three
then line three then
line one uh yeah just like yeah hit p5
and then s then s will become a hit
and why why we still have more than one
sticks yes yes more than one stick yes
then we need to get two from the we need
to get
two from the first first
look so from a stick look a
b equals
hq top hip hip
what hit forward
we're you do pay attention to the class
right
did you hit pop
hip-hop s right
and then another one hq this is the same
right just
one this is the same as this so he
popped
likely twice so i have two numbers from
the two smallies from the sticks
and the cost look at the cost that is
here right cos equals yeah and then cos
it will be
equal as what cos will be equal
cos plus equals a e plus
b b okay then now i need to add the a
plus b this is the new
stick i need to put it back to the
keeper right
yeah because it becomes a new stick so
now what hq
hit what push
push push release s
[Music]
return cost when we are in calculation
or cost cost
okay so
so what's the complexity i went no
no are you logan now you're just
guessing
look there are an element in a stick
yeah yeah
so it's in this end but every time we
are push
popping and push it takes log n remember
so this is
m this is log n so all together and log
n
yeah and log n got it it takes remember
we talked about yesterday
it takes unlocking to fear to push and
pop
because it takes time to unlock in time
to
reveal the hip right yeah reveal the
heat the final hit remember
if you did it if you did it this note
yeah it takes lock and time to pop up to
repeal this the tree right
yeah the heat the root of the heat is
minimal the smallest let's call the mean
hip now if
the root of the spinal heat is the
maximum
it's called what max head
got it okay let's do the coding
keep time
[Music]
okay wait wait wait wait
okay
[Applause]
[Music]
okay so this is my channel
okay so good did you do it can you not
stay there because it's
uh you're broking the views okay so
let's let's
let's do this quickly so we i am let's
create a caller sticks for pi right
okay so now we have a stick two two four
three remember
two four three yeah so the answer will
be
fourteen remember we just show you is
fourteen right
yes okay so
9th of january is it korea it is
clear yeah it's korea let me see
it's clear yeah it's clear let me see
okay so now
defined yeah in part let's import
hip hip q as hq
define mean cost mean cost as
and we cross equal zero right like we
need to hippie file the
hq dot 55 make it of uh uh
and then when the less more than
one one hit right one stake
what do we do a b we pop it hq though
execute the hip one
pop right and another one right
hq the hip pop and then cross the one
cost one
and then we need to put h q dot hit push
as what x
comma a and b okay and then
return ghost okay let's let's do this
print
queen main cost as
to display the file content okay so if
you look this
thing vian is to edit it so this is the
program about today the complexities
yeah n is the number of the stick in the
original way
right so how about you let's try this
let's try maybe just put some numbers
i don't know but this is yeah yeah
because it's take a look
basically put it pick the two and three
first but let's do a one more small one
let's like uh uh one two
three four okay yes so what's the answer
it's 19. why is that
one and two that will be three because
will be three
three and three cost will be
six yeah six plus three yeah and then
six plus four will be ten we're not
gonna be
ten plus nine will be nineteen we're
done okay
good job today good job today good job
today
bye
say if you bye you shake i can't see it
okay
okay say bye