[Music]
for each one you can there are only two
kinds
of either win or you lose
right so you either win or lose
you win or lose
so what how many how many ways that in
which that you can have this consecutive
k wins or less okay wins
or less
but it has to be consecutive what's
consecutive order
okay
one two three consecutive
uh it continues right so you win like
you win the first game second game third
game that's consecutive but if you win
first game you lose the second game you
win the third game this is nothing
consecutive
so we are looking forward
we're looking for a number of ways that
you can have you can win k times
consecutive or less right so for example
last week one can n equal three and then
k equals two
so we play three games
and then look we can win
if we have look
if we play three games what's how many
how many kind of different situation
would that be i mean what's the
permutation total number of permutation
you should be able to answer this
question quickly
we play three games each one has two
possibilities how many possibilities all
together
the a yeah exactly two to the power of n
equals
eight okay at this time okay so
look if i write this a
in so you can you should be able to
write lr
what's r okay so actually it's win okay
win
okay and
okay so these
oh i read the argument why don't
keep writing on this r again
okay
how many how many one two three four
five six seven eight okay
uh
yeah yeah
so lose three times in a row
k equals two yeah yeah i know so which
one which
these are all possibilities eight a of
possibilities how many of them have
these k
less than k less than two consecutive
that one doesn't this one doesn't this
one
yes
yes yes yes yes yes all right
yeah
so that's seven okay so you just give me
the seven right
yeah
so what's the sauce i mean what are we
doing here what are we doing what's this
what's this approach if we eat uh
internet uh if we
list all the possibilities
what what what's this method called
um
yeah yeah yeah and and we have to do
this two to the power of n times this is
just to iterate to list all the
possibilities of all of all the games
and we have to find out how many of them
are consecutive yeah so this point this
is
the time complexity if we are given a
game outcome and it takes on time to
check if they are less than k
if it meets the requirements so the time
from next to is time complexities o n
times two to the power n right this is
total total complexity okay do you get
it
yeah so certainly we don't we don't want
this so at least it's too complicated
right too complicated
yeah okay so how about if we i can tell
you like if like let's say we define the
function f f i comma j what does it mean
okay listen carefully okay it means that
we are playing
we are playing at ice game
and we have now
j win consecutive wins
consecutive win okay consecutive wind
bowling game okay consecutively wins
okay so look so let's say look i have uh
place the icon okay so i have
root loose
i know but this is example but as an
input okay so let's see look
okay so they are i yeah
this their eye here so this is i
they're eyes okay eyes
and then we have
j wins very consecutive okay
yeah
so okay so i'm playing the i plus one
game here okay this is i plus one game
here
how many possibilities for this game
times
how many possibilities
i'm playing i plus one game
what's the outcome of this game
um
how many come on
ryan how many what if i'm playing this
game i scan how many possibilities
um for this game i mean two yeah we know
lose exactly
yeah we not lose lose or win
right
so if i lose if i lose
if i lose
so i'm playing i plus one again but if i
lose what happens to this consecutive
week
okay but if i win j plus one
yeah i plus one j plus n exactly yeah
that's very good yeah so so the outcome
will be so this look f i
j will be equal to these two angles here
exactly right and one i when will the i
play the
one way i reach the end means that we
have finished all again
right
yeah
then
then we should check if j is less than
or equal than k right yeah okay
okay so about one k
the one k when when the j is bigger than
k we return
zero right because we want the we want
we don't want the consecutive wins more
than k right this is the requirement
right yeah so but we so we with this we
can
we should be able to implement this
using recursion right easy
okay let's try this in recursion
wow
f i
j
if
if j is bigger than k
return
what within zero one come on
is
[Music]
plus f i plus one j yeah this is the
recursive recursion the current formula
right the i plus one j plus
what's the time complexity for this one
um what's the temperature
actually what are we doing here what's
the thumbs up let's say it's the same as
proof of that something like that right
because each one each one you have two
possibilities each one you have two so
two to the power of n right but how do
we make it faster what's the missing
thing here
cash cash yeah so
what do you mean what does
what happened if we put a cash what
happened
what happened if we put a test uh with
is an explanation
yeah why is that because we're
remembering we're memorizing it right so
so look i
i
has n right i is from 0 to n and
to n minus 1 so there are n states of i
and they are k stay for the j
so the time complexes o
how many states of these
um
how many states right
how many look at that
no no how many states there are n n
possibilities here and f k possibility
how many total states
n times k okay
and the time conducts the space
complexity is also uh and o n times k
why is that because they are and most o
and uh n times k states we need to
memorize minimize yeah minimalism
okay so what does this mean look at oh
and okay so we can do a tree here we can
do a tree
we can do a tree okay
okay so for example
at the beginning we put f00 and then
we need to go from f1
f1 0
and then leads to f1
1 right look
f1 0 again you go to f2
cll and then plus what f2 right you see
so f1 will go to f to zlo and
f2
f22 again right is it two no no f2 one
look f2 zero f21 here so what's the
problem here if i i'm just iterating at
least a few iterations the problem is
what look look at here
this one
two zero
and here f two zero as well right
so
once twice so i the first time i
calculate it i i i minimize it i
memorize it right so when i calculate
this one i don't have to explain the
tree here right
for example you take one day you spend
one day in this tree right you spend one
day finding out the f21 value but here
you want to calculate f to one
f to zero here
do you need to spend another one data
why is that because i remember this yeah
yeah exactly so i put it down i put it
down on the notebook hash table
right it's the same thing
you work out a very complex complicated
mathematic problem
right
you put it down on your notebook
the next day you find out okay it's the
same question do you still have to go
through this right you just look it up
right you just tell teddy okay i know it
click a one constant right so that's how
we speed up
using this cache okay this is this is
quite similar to fibonacci number
remember what's fibonacci number
what's fibonacci number one one
two what's the next fibonacci number
three
five
eight
thirteen etcetera yeah exactly f i
equals twenty one
yeah plus plus f i plus look so the
first two numbers equals the added
together will be the next number yeah so
this number is
f n equals f n minus one plus f n minus
two that is quite similar to this yeah
so you expand this uh fibonacci you'll
find lots of these
f values are repeated so we have to
cache it right that's the magic of
caching
here okay so here is the same yeah for
each game
this is top-down top-down dynamic
programming using recursion instead
using the keywords minimization so at
this game
we we know we have already played i game
ice game yeah and then we have j
consecutive win and so if we play the
next game we have two possibilities
either win
continuous straight yes straight what
this means check
straight yeah
we continue we win we keep the stretch
oh we lose we reset it to zero right
easy right yeah and then we finish the
game uh when i equals n we return one
yeah because at this point j why we can
return one here because at this point j
is smaller or equal k why is that
because if j is bigger than k we already
be ten zero okay
yeah
that'll be it for today good job
bye bye bye