hello
uh iphones yeah we have talked about ip
address when your internet when your
computer is connected to internet yeah
you're being given this
ib address yeah most of cases okay the
iphone is four numbers phone number like
a dot b dot c dot d we talked about this
before yeah eight of these therefore not
four integer each one
yeah each one
is between
255 and integer between 25 55 and 0 okay
c
so i'm writing that b c c okay
yeah okay so let me write a number here
265 8.32.5
is this our ip address which these are
beautiful now why is that because it has
over you know
this one yes and half at least 1.2.3 is
this iphone
[Music]
no no yeah why because it has
yes yes okay exactly okay so
welcome at least
okay so we we have removed the dots so
can you restore ip address here
255 255 1133 so what's the valid idea it
could be money
yeah it could be money ryan
you want to get this one i have removed
a dot from the original ip address so
what could the original ipos be
255.255.111.33
okay and this is one i know is there any
others
and what could that be two five dot five
two dots five five
one
huh
um
dot two five five
[Music]
exactly
so there too okay very well done so
what's your thoughts about doing this
how how do you find out there too
how do you do it i mean what's your
original approach
oh you're trying to do that here
so
what i was doing is
so i just count how many numbers are
they yeah and
they are
um
11 yeah
so
yeah exactly yeah yeah
okay so you count 11. now okay
i know what why why why you said two
five five and then two five right and
then it could be how how did you find
these actually i just wanted to know how
because i don't actually wanna wait for
two five five
because
because i mean two five five is
less
than two by six so it it could be you
know yeah it could be the umbrella
answer and then you jump you jump yeah
you can jump yeah until you find it yeah
all right okay so let's
i mean
i obviously need the two five five two
five five even though i could do like
two
i can do
five yeah i can't do five to five but
you can do five two yeah but
yeah and then you do five five but look
it's more than three then that's
definitely not possible okay so you
doing now a very important point is that
we have to use all the digit
but we can't use too many digits right
so we have to use all the digits right
you can say two five five two five fifty
five one hand one 111 but we have uh
you know this 33 we can't it can't fit
into the last digit because it's too big
right so each one has only three at most
three digits right you can't have more
than three digits because this two five
five is the three db you can't have four
digits etc okay and then obviously in
the meter in the middle we have to check
if it has leading zero right if it's
leaving zero zero one this is not a
valid digit right zero
you can only have a one
it can only have one
uh leading zero and unless it's a zero
if it's zero that's fine otherwise you
can't have a living hero
okay so our approach yeah so we can do
this look at we can track uh we can do
this type of search backtracking yeah so
we we can try the first stitch current
the next digit right we can try next
digit
and then
jump next digit next digit and here we
use all the digits right yeah we can use
we can go for this approach
there's only one one thing we need to
remember is that when checking that when
jumping over the digit we have to check
uh
check if it's a value
if it's valid uh
if the
is between 0 to
255 and if it's zero it can only be
represented as finger zero okay it can't
have this
zero zero thing okay for example i can
give you an example
zero
uh
okay so 2 200
to
to 23. okay so can you restore this
yeah it could be many yes but yeah it
could be many so for example if you want
to have a zero you can only have two
twenty
zero twenty zero
two five five one two three that could
be one example yes but you can't have uh
twenty
zero two
five five and one two three yeah
this is not right right yeah this is not
right because this two has the leading
zero which is not valid okay
that's very good so we yeah so basically
we are asking computer to do this uh
uh
do research for us so let's say bye
that's what search
so
by this default search so we can pass a
parameter current which is a a list and
which is the list
so so which is which is the list yeah
it's this so this this contains the the
number of these the digit the most it
could be four right there before so we
can just
first of all we need to check check the
length with the lengths of all the
features together so n equals the sum
length
x for
x in
current okay so this is a very useful
thing to do so what does it mean so for
example if this
current is
one two three
three four
five okay for example like there are
only three numbers here so the length is
three digits plus two digits plus one
digit that would be six statistics so n
equal equals to b equals to six okay and
then now now after this we need to check
look if the length of the current yeah
if then the current equals four what
does it mean so we have already four
digits and then we have to check if n
if n equals okay so
here the original one will be a
restore
restore ip address which we have we have
a string f string so if n equals the
length of s
then we put it in the answer so let's
put it the answer here answer
equals the list
because there's a list of ideas then we
have to append
answer append
now we want to convert okay we want to
convert these one
to
we want to convert at least to to string
how do you still remember array of this
we want to make this one two three four
two one top two dot three dot four
do you know how how can we convert it
from this is the list to here
what
was that okay so we can depend
dot dot join
carbon
yeah right
yeah
okay so now uh if if not if not then we
just return here because it's not
satisfying the requirement that we just
can we can just uh skip okay and then
now we just have to
for
go uh look for the next digit so the
next 60 will be for i
in
range
yeah
now we are at we have n stitches
so we have n stitch from the string so
the string could be one two three four
five six yeah so for example if we have
one one top two top three
uh one two three so there are only three
digits so we can try on the fourth digit
here
yeah we'll try on the fourth digit right
so n is b3 we can try on the first piece
so that would be n from n
up to what to the end right so we can do
this to the end
but the thing is that
how many digits we can only we can try a
mouth do we have to try to the end
why is that how many digits so now i'm
at index i so which how many digits i
can try for the next next number
what's the maximum number of lengths
what was the maximum
what's the maximum of the digit
so what i mean is that look i i am look
i'm here right i'm here
i want to try the next digit so i try 3
or 3 4 five or three four five six do i
have to try three four five six
um
no right no why is that because it's
more than three digits we can only try
three teachers
yes three four five three digits because
if it's four digits it's definitely more
than 255 that's what i mean okay so we
can do this mean
we have this n plus three and all the
lengths as
if if it only has two digits left now we
we just have to try up to the end okay
try to after the end and then
the next stage will be what next digit
um
so x equals s
we start from the index n up to i plus
one
i plus 1 up to i right okay then we have
to check x if x is the requirement so
if
this is a string and we convert it to
integer x if in x is bigger than 0 and
smaller than 255
n okay
so
if it is zero okay if it's yellow then
we have to exclude the cases which is as
the you know this
multiple zeros okay so
if this is between this range also if if
what
if if length uh if n length
x
if it's uh bigger than 1
if it's bigger than 1
or
x
x equal equal 0 okay
so we have to check if it's zero okay if
it's zero
uh okay so i have to write this one here
and if this is zero
or
if it's bigger than one digit
and the first digit is not zero okay
then okay so okay so look at this
if we if we convert this x string this
is a pidgey
substring
to integer if it's between the
yellow and 250 times that's great but we
have to check one more thing if it's
zero if it's a single digit yellow or if
it's more than one digit but
if it's more than one digit then the
first stage can't be zero right all
right
yeah
so this this means that if it's a single
digit if it's a single zero that's fine
otherwise if it's more than it has more
than one digit then the first digit
can't be zero right make sense yeah and
then in this case then we can
we have this is a valid point so we can
current append
a plan x
and then we can do this different search
current
and then at the end we need to restore
the state which is pop
right so look
we we want to do the travel search right
we want to do the definition to pass
this current this isn't
remember
yesterday or the day before yesterday we
talked about uh
path by reference object reference if if
the array is mutable then then what does
it mean it means that anything change in
the function will be
impacting the value right yeah it will
change the whole value that's right so
look we're changing this the append
we're changing this uh
list yeah we're changing the list we
pass to the recursion we pass it
pass it to search
and before after that we need to restore
the state right so this is very
important current the prop state
okay calendar append and calendar apart
and then
in between
we pass the new
new state into the function okay
and then now we just return uh deficit
we give it a empty list and then return
answer yeah
okay
we can answer
yeah
everyone uh any questions i mean what
are you what have you learned so far
today what happened
so
so what what are we doing here what are
we doing here
we're doing stuff you're doing that way
great yeah okay so do do get it okay
let me
let me write the
okay so the original original one yeah
two five five
okay whereas two noise two five five two
five five
one one one three five okay this is the
original one
this is the original string okay so how
can we do this definitely empty this
underneath
let's empty this n equal that would be
zero right
then if not if not equal to four because
the current equals one zero element okay
now for i it was from zero to length as
a mean three so the first stitch would
go from two
to
255 right yeah
okay so let's say if we go to row two
and the next digit will be
from five it can go to the five okay so
it needs to take the one and the third
there will be
five
and then four stitches will be two right
and let's see because by this length the
length is only fourteen it's not equal
but how many digits one two three four
five eleven digits right
eleven digits so it's not adding it
right so the only two possibilities two
five two five one one one thirty five oh
two five five two four five eleven one
thirty five yeah as we talk about okay
so look if if we may we may uh
here we may check the length if the
length
if the length of s is bigger than 12
so what does it mean if it if the given
string is more than 12 digit do we need
to do this backtracking
yes or no
if this string is given like it's more
than 12 digit no right because it's not
possible if you divide it into four
parts then at least one of them
is more than three digits and that means
that
that means that it's not possible so we
can just directly return to this why is
that this is called pitching hole you're
not pitching for principal
yeah
okay i have a 10 box
i have a uh maybe okay five bucks
five uh
what what's the thing what's the
container that you put the pigeon in
what's the cage yeah what does it count
i think
okay okay we have five pages okay right
so we have uh
six pigeons
six pigeons five pages
so can i say that
at least can i say at least one
page will contain more than two
more than one kitchen all right
what does it mean do you get it
right
five page
if we want to put six pigeons in
there must be
at least
one
cage
has more than one pigeon all right
how can you prove it
that's the perfect explanation you can
sit you can teach mommy yeah this is
pitching the same thing here if we have
13 digit
yeah
certain digit we want to divide it into
four four parts
okay yeah
a b c d yeah so what does it mean
okay look for 13 digit
four parts what does it tell us
one of them
at least wonderland contains more than
three digits right
yeah 13 digits
yeah
makes sense
so if if one of them contains more than
three digits it's not a very iphone
right because it's more than 255
obviously so we can return
written empty this here okay
so
here okay so this part um
any questions about
right
okay okay that's it for today bye bye
bye bye