go hello guys
okay so we have two arrays of integers
here one two three two four six
so
one three and four six okay so one three
are the numbers in first array but do
not appear on the second array 4 6 is
the number from the second array which
do not appear in the first array okay so
how do we find it how do we return these
two
arrays yeah
how to how to return this data yeah so
anything
this is supposed to be an easy question
so what what what data structure can we
use to do that
okay
so one two three we convert it to a set
so
and then two four six okay so one two
three i put one three
two four six right
yeah so from this set we can say easy
see one and three
yeah it's outside of this set yep four
and six outside of these okay so
so we can just do this yeah so look
uh
so we can do this difference okay so for
example like c uh
let's say let's convert it to set okay
set
we converted that
now we can just return what a 1 3 is
actually a minus b right
and 4 6 is actually b minus a right so
all we need to do is just return
return
uh list of we converted the set into a
list at least a minus b
and this
b minus a okay
so look at a minus b
yeah when we're talking about set a
minus b is actually the same as a dot
different okay because we are going to
check the difference different it's the
same thing yeah different
a dot difference b this is the same
thing okay
and actually we can use if we're not
using set we can we can
we can directly check which numbers up
on the first array but to not appear on
the second array so how do we do this we
can just say we can
yeah uh
uh
eric right cool
so we can say
x
for
x in a right in a
if
x not in b yeah look
like who knows right right look we can
just do this x for x in a if not if x
not in b
and then to make it faster we convert
this uh to the set set a and set b yeah
exactly and the opposite
x for x in b
yeah
if x not in a right doesn't make sense
yes okay so
so which way do you think it's better
[Music]
converting to set or we just directly
using this one return
return we can just return this thing
yeah pretend these things i think that
yes
set is more straightforward right
that's not in
okay so for this is easy too look we can
just read it look we want to return x
for x what's x x is in p right
right
and we add one more condition if x not
in there right
yeah if we write it in python it's quite
easy to understand all right yeah do you
understand
it okay and then convert into set it's
easy a what's a dot difference b what
else does it mean angle difference b
what's it
what's it it means the difference i got
different speed is what here the
difference between a
and b okay so look this is a this is b
ain't no difference b
once you eat with 10
8 different three yeah one three
and b top difference a what's in
about difference b is actually the seven
a minus b okay
b dot difference a is what
what beta difference a
is this same as b minus a okay yeah when
b and a are set okay
contains the unique integer unique
element yeah this is what a set is okay
yeah make sense
any questions so far
okay that's it for today bye