let me say mr right now right yeah
so let's say we have these
numbers of unique integers yeah one two
three
yeah and we want to find out the subset
the subset is a like like this emptiness
is a subset
one
two
three
one two
two three
eight one two three
eight eight one is missing eight
one two three four five six seven one is
missing can you find find out what is
this one three one three exactly so
that's eight yeah
there's three numbers so the total
number of subset is two to the power of
three eight why is it two to the power 3
we have n numbers for each number we
have two choices yeah
we take it or we don't pick it
so for the first number we have two
choice for the second number we have
another two choice third number and
another choice so it's two times two
times two which is nine
yeah
two and then end of it yeah and this
leads to two to the power of n
two to the power of another set of
problems which is kind of permutation
permutation what is permutation like one
two three
one three two
two one three
two three one three one two three two
one okay
these are full permutations they are n
numbers
so the total number of permutation is
how many can you tell me anybody
total number permutation anybody
yes six which is if there are n numbers
what's the total number
and one
and the first number we how many choice
we have
three
three number three choice
the second number how many choice we
have
three
no we already use one number so how many
numbers we we can pick from
two yeah and that's a number one
bacteria okay another another set of
problem is called computation com
combination combination three apples how
many ways to pick two apples
three helpers how many ways to pick two
apples
three yeah
it's the same as three apples picking
one apple right
if you look at this way three apples
picking one diaper is very easy yeah
there's three apples how many ways to
pick one at first
three yeah every time you pick one up
it's the same as you pick two weapons
because they are they correspond to each
other okay so c
and k equals c
and n minus k this is the same because
every time you pick k numbers
out of n is the same as picking n minus
k out of n right because look n
n minus k plus k equals n this is same
okay so this is the formula c nk equals
n factorial divided by k factorial
divided by n minus k factorial and we
talked about this long time ago right
permutation is p and k equals
equals 1 equals
c n k
times
k
factorial right because
when we pick k numbers
and then we can do a full commutation on
these k numbers okay so these would be
one
so so these will be c and k is this one
so times k factorial will be a and
factorial divided by n minus k factorial
yeah you can think of this way what's
for permutation
you pick a k apples out of n epoch and
after you get k approach we can do a
full permutation of cake apples so that
gives dnk okay
okay so for going back to this question
so
going back to this question we can do
this step research or
actually we call it a backtracking or
whatever i mean
so we can come up with a
recursive uh recursion so for each
number let's say
we define let's say subset subset and we
have this number which is the list of
integer
and then we want to return
a list of this yeah instead of this
okay
list of this
so n equals the length of numbers so
this is the numbers of numbers the
the numbers of numbers right the numbers
are the lengths of the numbers
and then we can say answer
equals empty list and we have this step
first search okay i define it as dfs but
nonetheless the way it's called the
preferences define
efs
what current is the length of uh is the
current choice from the set of the
subset and then we are picking the ice
number
so when we finish picking the when we
reach the last number then we can
obviously we can answer the append
current right and then we depend because
we are running out of numbers
and then we can return
okay so now for the ice number how many
choice do we have
you know we are picking this we are now
look at this one
this is original numbers one two three
okay then one i
is zero i is yellow here
yeah for the first number
so how many choice do we have when
considering the subset
how many we how many choice do we have
when put considering the number one in a
subset
okay
am i clear how many choices do we have
when conserving the numbers in the
subset what number is one we were
talking about these numbers only we are
now looking at these numbers i
numbs at index i okay so
now i'm going to do something here
i'm going to do something here
with list numbers i regarding into the
current subset so
i want to please number how many choice
do we have with this number with the
current now with the current set it's
one two three and one two three
there are eight how do you get the
number eight here
ryan
how do we get the number eight here i
mean t times two times two exactly
what's two
two is how many choices you have okay
how many choices do we have for this
number
we want to put it in how many choices
are
they are n numbers yeah you are right
two to the power and for each number we
have two choices here for each number
how many choices
how many choices do we have
yeah exactly two two choice okay two
choice to pick it okay so let's talk
about not pick it at first
we not pick it
so if we don't pick it what happened to
the current
what happened to the color if we don't
pick it
it's still the same right
but
the next one we're looking we're going
to pick i plus one right yeah
okay so if we pick it what happened
if we pick it what happened what should
i do with the current if i pick it i
should add it to the current right so
carbon plus
num i
okay
and then
we do this step research at the
beginning we start with the empty v and
i go first number what's the second
parameter here
the first one which is
yeah and now we can just return
answer okay
yeah
okay so this is the
core of our learning today so for each
number we can pick or we can skip when
we pick it we do nothing with the
current and we're picking next number i
plus one index when we pick it
we need to append this current
num nums i to the current set and then
move to the next
number right
and when we reach the end this is the
termination of the recursion when we
reach the end we just put the current
into the answer into the answer okay
a little bit okay no b yeah the time
complexity for this one obviously
two to the power and because they have
the number of
the total number of the
subset is 2 to the power okay
okay so this is one way of doing it
tomorrow we're going to talk about using
another one which is called b masking
and the day after tomorrow we're going
to talk about another agreement to solve
this is called cascading okay cascading
so lastly and then daddy then that'll be
okay that's it for today bye-bye
bye-bye