okay so yesterday we talked about the uh
the subset one two three and one
how many subsets of that
eight yeah eight because there are n
numbers 10 unique numbers so we have
total
2 to the power of n
for why is that that's very easy to
think of here yeah but for each number
we have two choice we include we will
pick this number in a subset or we don't
pick it so now we can choice and then n
of it so it's 2 times 2 times 2 here 2
to the power 2 times negative 2 that
will be n 2 so that's 2 to the power of
n ok
so we use this backtracking so for each
one
uh define
[Music]
the fs we have this current set
conversation and then we are looking at
ice numbers so if we literally n
n is the numbers of the
original unique numbers and then we want
to put all the subsets into this list
and the list and if i equals m we reach
the end and we answer the append
a pen we append a copy of the current
set so
yeah these symbol means the copy so we
all we can also do this copy copy here
right and then we can
otherwise we have two choice which is
if we don't pick it we move to the next
number or if we pick it we include it in
the current subset which is nums i yeah
and then we move to the next number and
then dfs start with entities the first
number return
answer yeah easy okay
okay so today we're going to solve this
problem slightly different okay so by
looking look this is a very good good
thing is that we know the number of uh
subset total is 2 to the power of n okay
so let's find let's look at this number
yeah look zero to the three numbers from
zero to seven
so zero in binary is let's just look at
three digits okay because that's three
numbers zero zero zero
one is zero zero one
two is zero one zero three is zero one
one okay can you tell me four what's
four
five six seven okay so can you tell me
the binary for this number four is i
give i start first one zero zero okay
five
what's five
uh
[Music]
yeah you see always it's like uh
you know this is the the significant bit
at least it's the most significant bit
so look from the right hand side we call
it asb from the left hand side we call
it msb
yeah most significant bit okay
so each bit this is 2 to the power of 0
2 to the power of 1 2 to the power 2.
okay so that's the most interesting part
here okay if it is 0 0
the the subset is
empty this if it's 1 1 1 is one two
three okay
okay and then zero zero one
zero zero one let's it's one
okay zero one zero is two
okay
zero one one is one two
and then this is three
this is one three
okay so can you tell me one one zero
what's this what does that correspond to
i give you the most look
one one zero
anybody right
one one zero what does it give us
two three totally wired
okay so can you tell me why oh yeah can
you tell me
[Music]
and this is one and
there are three digits so that's a good
thing three digits in the number three
right so if it is yellow we don't pick
it if it's one we pick it easy right so
look look at this
one one zero zero we pick the three we
don't pick the seals
first uh and one and two so no desire
easy
so we can just we can just iterate over
this number and then by checking each
bit
okay by checking each people just
we just need to check if each bit is set
if it's set then we pick it in a subset
if not then we skip it okay
and that will be
okay i'm going to keep this but i'm
going to rewrite this bit okay so this
is called kind called uh
big masking
quick masking fit
masking
each bit zero or one
masking what mask
you put a mask yeah masking so every
time i look at one number and one bit to
see if it's zero or one okay so
define
the subset
these numbers i'm going to write it okay
it could be shorter right so the answer
and this is
n equals the length of numbers yeah
we assume all the numbers in the subset
are unique okay
four
i
in range n right so we're good no not
range and range two to the power of n
right two to the power and we can say
power to n of
60 and position okay so okay so here is
the thing
power
2 to the power of n this is 2 to the
power n
one shift is shifting n this is the same
thing is two to the power and why is
that look
two to the power of
three
is eight yeah
this is power
two to the power three and then one
shift is fifty three what does it mean
look i have one here
i sift in one position to the left i put
a zero in binary i shifted another
position to the left i put another zero
i shifted another one
okay
three zero and yeah what's this in
binary
what's this in binary come on
yeah it's there okay hey exactly because
this is one
two
four eight okay
so this is the same thing okay so this
is the same thing as
s power two to the power and four
power using the mass power two n okay
this is the same thing now we go through
this i now we need to go through these
this numbers yeah so for
j
in range we want to go through we want
to check each element to see if it's one
or zero so in range
n
right so then we need to check if
i okay so this is the binary this is the
one i want to check check these this
number so j
and
okay this is finally
one
shifty shifty j
then i put this current
dot append
nums j okay
i'm going to tell you why okay these
carbons equal
each neuron
the current current is empty list and if
this speed is set we include that
that number
in the current set and an answer for
each one we have a new subset
a pen
current okay
and then we can answer here that will be
written answer
okay so
so this is the most difficult part to
understand what's this mean okay this i
and
i
i is this number yeah i
i is this number this binary so j for
example the second one the second one
the bit is represent is one shifty 50
one which is
which is one zero in binary zero one
zero the the third bit
third bit is
zero one zero zero okay so basically one
shift j j is the index so for third for
the third number is 1 50
j which is two zero one two okay two so
this is two to the power of
what 2 to the power of
2 to the power of
how many 2 to the power of 0 2 to the
power 1 2 to the power 2
2 to the power of 2 equals 4 so the
bit the big masking for the third digit
is 1 0 0 right so if any of these
numbers
end to the n operation
and operation by this number if we give
it smaller than 0 then we need to
include this number this is the same
thing what's
n and
and then we talk about this n in in if
statement yeah if eric is a good boy and
ryan is a good boy
i give you
both
uh ultraviolet pens uh
yeah
or if eric is a good boy or ryan is a
good boy
and i will give you
both
uh a pop right so all is that at least
one of it and is that both needs to be
true right so in binary it's the same
thing one
and one is one one and zero is what
cl n
zero zero and one is zero
zero and one is zero one and zero is
zero zero and zero
is zero okay so this is the same thing
as the if right so
it will be one only if both sides are
one if one of them is one it's not
enough okay so this is the same thing
okay and and
then the n
okay so look at this term complexity
this is o to 2 to the power of n
and for each one we need to iterate
anytime so some complexity is
o
n times
2 to the power of n okay right because
look
this iterate the inner loop literally
and time the outer loop it raised
two to the n times right
antenna
and
and iterate uh success okay
yeah okay that's it for today good job
bye bye