okay so we've been talking about a
subset for like two days yeah but today
this is the last uh
of doing this subject okay so let's just
review a little bit
three numbers you need one two three
and then we want to
have this uh
success there are eight yeah
a subset yeah
empty list one
two
three one three
two three
one two three yeah
am i missing anything
one two three four five six seven
there's one thing missing let's see boy
one two three one three two three
one two three okay there's one thing one
two yeah one two missing one i'm so
small yeah yeah i know you are yeah okay
okay so let me there there are n numbers
so
the total number of subset is 2 to the
power and why is that because each
number we can pick or skip so we have
two choices for the first number we have
two choice for the second number and so
on there
they are in in times of them and numbers
so that's two to the power and
for the backtracking yes for the
backtracking we define this uh deficit
define that first search current list
and then we are looking at ice number
so when the i reaches the end we just
put this answer
current list apart append a copy to the
current list
this means the
deep copy clone okay or you can use the
copy.d copy
or and then we can do this default
search if we not pick this number we
just move to the next number or we pick
it but we have to update we have to pass
the current uh we have to update the
current cell with this number so we see
plus
nouns
i
and then we move to the next number as
well so let's at the beginning we do
this data search empty list and then
start with the first number then we can
return this answer
easy peasy easy peasy
this is backtracking and yesterday we
talked about
the
what we talked about the big masking
yeah we're asking what what i'm asking
so because
yeah yeah finally exactly because
they're 2 and 2 to the power n so if we
look at the numbers between 0 to 2 to
the power and -1
yeah for example like that
yeah 000.0001.010.011.100.101.11011
okay so this is this actually each
binary number corresponds to a mapping
so
0 means the empty list and then 1 1 1
means that we pick up all three numbers
one two three okay so let's uh to lisa
what's what's one on one what's a one or
one three
and how about how about zero one zero
um that's two we're done okay so we got
it yeah so we
so how we interpret this that would be
uh what's to know so how do we implement
this
let's review a little bit so
answer and this for
i
in range we go through this number up to
2 to the power of n the 1 shift 50 n
this is also okay power 2 to the power n
and now we go through this index for
j in
range
n okay so i have at least currently
which is empty so if i and one shifty
shifty j bigger than zero then
carbon.append
open uh
nums
yeah because we are checking this j
number if it's uh uh if that bit is
particular set okay and then return and
answer the append command
okay
okay we can answer
okay so oh uh we have this uh iteration
for two to the power enter and for each
iteration we have to iterate over the
index so these time contracts is all n
times two to the power of n okay
okay so today let's talk let's look at
other
method which is called cast taking
what's this one mean by the way
cash
cascading how can i
c a s c a d
[Music]
c a d cascading
cascade it probably means
you know you put it
yeah it means that it put these pieces
uh one by one yeah i don't know it's
just
i'm just guessing okay
okay so let's see okay look at the
beginning
i have empty this yeah this is one of
the subset for any input right so okay
all right right look at me this is the
important thing here answer here right
so every time i take everything inside
the inside the answer
i i take this off right
and then i put this number that one two
three okay
okay so i take this number oh yeah empty
this i can take this number
type this number
i do i i'm looking at this first number
okay
so i'm looking at this first number
i take it off okay look i take it out
i take it off
and i append to whatever in the answer
so now the current the current list is
empty and plus this one number that
would be one right so i now i have this
two right this answer will become here
okay
now what's the next number to look at
two right
okay so i take these two out okay
so now whatever we have two
here so what i want to do is i put these
two
here and make a copy so i will have
these i i the new subset will be two
and then
one two
okay make sense okay what's the next
number
three three okay so now i have four in
the subset right so what do we do now
now we just pull the three in the subset
[Music]
so that will be
and another one will be three
one three
two three
one two three okay you got it yes so how
many of them at all one two three four
five six seven eight yeah okay so you
might not be
clear
let me repeat it okay right let me
repeat this
let me do this okay
let me do this again
now look we have numbers one two three
one two three
and then i have this answer this is we
only found one
sublist
subset which is empty this okay
now okay let's take the first number out
yeah
let's take the first number out
okay so what i want to do with this
first number is i will take whatever
here the answer
yeah
i have this answer
so now i just copy this answer here yeah
and then i want to
i want to put this one
append to it so that will become
one right so we have now two
okay so now that next number is two
right
yeah
so i put that two
so first of all i copied these i copied
two things here yeah
completely uh
whatever we have here
now i put a two here
i put a put a two at the end
okay
yeah
the third number
that's the number how do we do it
the cell number
anybody
um three
first of all we copy everything well we
have here
yeah
and now we put a three
to the end
yeah
make sense
do you want me to repeat it again
okay it's quite easy yeah so that
becomes a subset right look we have this
we have this unique number one two three
so now look
at the beginning
empty set yeah obviously until this is a
sunset right look at look at this is the
essence
yeah
now
every time i take a number first of all
i will copy everything
of the subset which is here yeah
now i i copy one right i copy one
i copy one this is the reason why i copy
one
yeah
so i put a one
at it
yeah
right
now i want to look at the number two
so we have two so let's copy
so i will put a two at the end of each
disk okay
okay now three
first of all i have these i copied
everything
and i put a three at the end of each
disk
okay it's this surface
empty one two three one two one two
one two one two one three
two three
three one two three yeah
make sense okay let's say we have
another one four one two three four
okay so how do we do it we copy
everything
we copy everything yeah
i'm gonna copy everything here
this is the copy one yeah this is the
copy of the existing one and i put a
three at the end i'll put the four on
the end four four
four
four four
four okay so look this is the process of
cascading
i take it whatever
and i open the new element make sense so
every time the subset doubles
yeah at the beginning is one
yeah and the second one
the second iteration two
and then i make two copies
four
eight sixteen
yeah it corresponds to this okay
yeah
okay let's implement this this should be
very very easy to implement
cascading
define
subset
numbers
these are unique numbers yes answer
at the beginning it's an empty list yeah
right
so i i just have to go to each number
for i in
nums
so we can do this right
so what do we do answer
plus equal we want plus equal
uh
what
c
plus
for c
in answer yeah okay
okay so look i take whatever in the
color answer i append numbers back to it
and i append to this answer and that's
what exactly what i demonstrate before
right then return answer
yeah make sense look here here this is a
bit tricky okay c
let's c
see here this is
uh this is
okay look this is c
c is defined here for c in answers for c
and then i take i take everything in the
answer current answer
i append
the current numbers i to it and then
this is a set this is a list and i'll
turn this list back to the answer okay
so every time the size of the answer
doubles
right every time the size of the answer
does at the beginning is empty this okay
that's it for today good job bye bye