okay
okay so today we are going to talk about
a very interesting problem called the
visible blocks okay so let's say we have
n blocks yeah we have really interesting
and
blocks come on come on
we have n blocks
and the size is one to n okay so look
this is one point
you you
uh you know the number of blocks yeah
one
okay let's say
we have four blocks n equals four
and then
the blocks type is one two three four
okay so if if okay eric or ryan you know
yeah
sunny on the left look
how many blocks can you see
ryan eric how many dots can you see all
of them all of them four right yeah
exactly how about this
probably
so if you hear
to the right how many blocks can you see
i could see one two three
four
one one yeah exactly yeah okay so the
question is that i have unblocked right
and i'm standing on the left
i'm standing on the left
right
and i want to see
exactly k blocks right so how many ways
how many ways can we arrange the blocks
do you get it for example if n
if n
if k equals 1
okay if k
let's say if k equals n n equals k so
for example
i have m blocks i want to see exactly k
blocks how many ways can we arrange in a
box
uh always the tallest one and
then
i didn't really get it okay so look
you you're getting there right so i have
uh i have uh four blocks and i want to
see exactly four blocks how many ways i
can put it
right so look at one two three
only one right exactly because you can't
that's the only order if you if you if
you if you don't if we don't have this
order some blocks will be invisible
we'll be we'll be blocking others right
yeah there's only one right okay that's
very good so when n equally equals k
then we should return one because
there's only one right from the smallest
to the biggest all right
okay how about k equals one
so i want to see exactly one block so
there's always a tool
in the front where that very well done
so always the tallest but how about
these it doesn't matter right
okay so how many blocks are there
uh three yeah there are n blocks overall
and i have one block the tallest in the
front so how many blocks here n minus
one and minus one okay so far four it
doesn't matter you say it doesn't matter
so n minus one blocks doesn't matter how
many permutations
we want to talk about how many orders i
mean what
times yeah you kind of do it look at
three three three blocks how many
permutations how many ways
exactly how the first block we have
three choice the second block we have
two choice the third one we have one
choice what's this
what's this
six yeah i know what's these five
we're done so n minus one factorial yeah
exactly okay so when k equals one we
return
n minus one factorial
right
exactly okay now tricky part is here
yeah
this is the difficult part if you don't
get that's fine right but that's very
good if you can if you you can already
get these two parts that's very nice
okay yeah
okay so now
this is these two are base cases very
easy yeah okay so now
how about
how about n is not equal k and k all is
not equal one so look
yeah so how about that uh i have uh m
blocks right
and then how about if i put the smallest
one in the front okay let's say i want
to put the smallest one in the front
right
yeah so
i can always see it right because it's
smallest in the front right yeah
yeah i can see it so let's say f and fnk
is the number of ways that i i need to
place in blocks and with i want to see
the k visible blocks right yeah right
actually
so now i
put the one block at the beginning the
smallest
right and how many blocks left
how many blocks left
i put one block in the front how many
blocks left minus one and minus one
where down
right
and i can see one blocks how many more
blocks i need to see i need to make it c
also minus one right
so that's k minus one right yeah when we
put the smallest what why can we do this
k minus one because this is the smallest
right
if this is smallest what happened i i
can see all the blocks on the right hand
side right
so let's f let's f n minus one k myself
okay that's one path if i don't pull the
smallest on the left
okay this is the tricky part if i don't
put the smallest in on the
on the left on the left
i can put it
in n minus one position right i can put
it any minus one position right yeah but
i still need to to see k blocks right
because this block is invisible right
because it's the smallest so in my east
smallest it means that it's it's
invisible
the left most block
blocks it right
so it's
f n minus one k
okay
yeah
so how many ways we can do this i i was
just saying i have i can place the block
in minus one position so we can just
times it right
yeah
so how many ways
for these two we we do it add it
together
okay cool so
so
you get it right let me repeat it okay
let me repeat it this is a bit tricky
part okay
okay let me repeat it
can you stand here for a while
okay listen one more time this is very
interesting okay
ryan you got it
n minus n equals k there's only one way
right from the smallest to biggest k
equals one
what does it mean the tallest on the
left
right and what what's on the right
doesn't matter and there are n minus one
blocks here so it doesn't matter what
does it mean it doesn't matter we can do
this full permutation on n minus one
block that gives us n minus one
factorial okay so now
for the end and blocks we want to see k
blocks yeah oh total and block so we
want to see k blocks
are we right
why are you doing what you're doing
yeah and blocks i want to see k block
what happened if i put the smallest on
the left
i can see it right
so if i put the smallest on the left i
can see so the these how many ways i can
do it
that's n
f n minus one k minus one why because i
put i i already put one blocks here
so i have n minus one blocks left and i
have k minus one blocks left to seen
right
but if i don't put it on the left
if i don't put it on the left
i put it somewhere from the right on the
right hand side because it's the
smallest block
it's invisible
all right
if it is input if it's invisible so what
does it mean if it's invisible then we
still
have k blocks left to sing and we have n
minus one block but how many ways can we
do this
n minus one times it why is that because
we can place this smallest plot from n
minus one position okay
so now we can implement this
we have this uh equation so how can we
implement it anybody
if we have we i already have this
defined f n n k
equals okay let's say
n minus 1 factorial
when
k is 1
over 1
when
k is n
and otherwise
otherwise what f n minus 1 k minus 1
plus
n minus 1 times
s n minus 1.
okay all right so alois
so we have defined this how can we
implement this look what's this f of n k
f n minus 1 f1 minus 1 k minus 1 what
what do we do with
this to implement this
if you look at this
f let's f what how do you implement this
what what do we call it
[Music]
where with cushion wow you're on fire
today recursion yeah
i know that's a
metaphor
that's a metaphor saying okay you're so
good today okay wait why burning good
okay f and k right okay and that
we have to i also give if it is zero
when n is smaller than
k right it makes sense
when n is smaller than k what happened
what value should we get if we have n
plus we want to see k plus k is bigger
than n how many ways can we do it zero
exactly that's common sense yeah we have
three blocks we want to see four blocks
how is it possible
yeah yeah
so if n smaller than k
we tend zero
okay
so if
k is one
we tend
n minus one structure we talked about
factorial yeah we can use the math dot
bacterial thing
yeah factorial
okay n minus one
if
n equals equals k we return
one exactly otherwise will return
f n minus one k minus one plus
n minus one
times f n minus one k okay so that's the
recursion look look one f and k
right n is always decrementing by one
right but k
sometimes equilibrium sometimes not
so what does it mean look if n is always
decrementing one right and n is
smaller is bigger than n
n is bigger than k right so what does it
mean either k reaches one first or n
reaches k first so in that case we
define these two
terminal condition now
that could be
sufficient less sufficient yeah because
n is always decrementing one
look okay so n is bigger than k right
n is always decrementing one but k
sometimes not equipment so it means that
k
will reach one first or n will reach k
first right
yeah so we have these two so
ryan do you understand this do you
understand this do you understand this
and do you understand this
anyway do you understand these 12 bits
list this this
the first three you understand
obviously yeah how about this one
yeah okay let me repeat this okay this
is a little bit difficult to understand
okay but don't worry okay it's hard yeah
i know that's why i'm repeating one more
time okay
okay all right for the last time come on
for the last time
yeah
so
f and k
means that i have
n blocks and i want to see k blocks
right
and let's place let's try to place
the smallest block on the left yeah so
what does it mean if i place the
smallest block on the left can i see it
can i see it yeah yeah yeah obviously i
put a smallie from the left
i put anything on the left i can see it
right
so if i put a smallest on the left i
have
n minus one block right because i
already use one block and how many
blocks left to sing
k minus one right because i i look f and
k i want to place m blocks
i see k blocks i put a smallies on the
left i have n minus one block and i
i have k minus one blocks to sim okay
let's see this part how about this one
if i don't play on this left most i can
put it on
n y and minus one position right because
they're total and plus if i put the
smallest block on the right what does
this mean can i see it
no
no obviously because look this small is
blocked i can put it on the right
i can put it in m minus one position but
it's the smallest what does it mean
it can't be seen right
you will be definitely blocked by the
leftmost block right
so i have
still n minus one profit to use and i i
still need to see k blocks but how many
pro as i said i have n minus n minus 1
positions to put a smaller spell so i
need to times this by n minus one
correct that's where we come from right
this is mathematics actually this is not
coding
this is mathematics
yeah mathematic equation
the most important thing today is this
mathematic equation how we getting how
we solving this
we're using computer this is just
implementation of this mathematics look
you can figure out
from this python code it's easy right
yeah the python code no skills
yeah
we can put a cache yeah we can put a
cache to remember the values we have
seen yeah but i doubt that this would be
useful because the
n would be based on n minus 1
k minus 1
k
yeah maybe yeah so
it's not reusing it right it's not
uh do we we use the intermediate results
that's a good question let's try okay
f let's say f
n minus 1 k minus 1
that would be based on
that will be based on what
no f and k f and k will be based on m
minus 1 k minus 1 and n minus 1
k right
okay and then here m minus 1 k minus 1
will be based on n minus 2
k minus 2
and n minus 2
k minus
k minus 1
yeah
and minus 1
k will be based on n minus two
k minus one
and minus two
k right so do we see any repeated value
here look we see this repeating
we've seen this repeated n minus two k
minus one right and minus n minus two k
minus zero on this is like the binary
tree on the right
the final tree the last three
k doesn't uh k change by one decrement
by one on the right tree
k not changing so look n minus one k
minus one this will be n minus two
uh n minus two k minus one okay so look
we are we have this
overlapping sub problems
so it means that we can put a cache here
to save to speed up right so in that
case with the maximum stage we are
calculating is n times k right because
their n n will be from one
to n minus one
k
will be from zero to uh yeah yeah from
one to k minus one so n times k okay so
that's the very important thing today
okay it looks it looks like
similar to fibonacci number right yeah
okay that's it
all right
[Applause]
[Music]
you