hello miss eric misali all right
okay so let's talk about the largest
unique number today very easy simple
questions last is unique number what's
unique
uh the different tibialis
that's right unique okay
okay two two one
four
minus one what's the largest unique
number four okay how about if i put
another four here what's the largest
unique number one
okay
one okay if i put another one what's
that this is one
okay let's change it to minus seven
minus seven yeah
what if both of them are what if they're
like four four four now we don't have
unique numbers right two two one one
minus seven minus seven four four in
this case we return minus one okay
easy okay
okay
any idea are you ryan all you have to do
is use counter
counter where that exactly counter is
basically like a hash table to
to store the frequencies for each
element so if we do this counter thing
define okay so largest unique number l u
n okay numbers
easy so we just c equals counter
so once we do these numbers counters
here so what does it give us it give us
a key additionally key value so for
example 2 2 1 1
3 okay if we do if these numbers is here
it's this one
okay
then if we do this counter counter c
equals counter numbers
what do we have what do we have the c is
actually a dictionary so two appears two
times one appears two times three appear
one time okay yeah
so these are the keys
these are the values and values are the
frequency
okay c dot
c dot keys
which has two one three see the values
return two to one see the items between
an array of tuples couple of tuples
tuple yeah
is basically a way of list
two two
uh one two
and three one okay so we call it
we use the c dot equal well in this case
the c stores the frequency and
the frequency for each unique numbers
now we have just have to check the if
it's unique and then we get a maximum
okay let's do this answer
answer equals and the beginning with 75
minus one if we can find it okay then we
go through these keys therefore
key right to my key value in c the items
yeah we talk about see the item here
okay so the key k is the number v is
that how many times they appear now we
can say if we equal equal one if we
equal equal what happened what does it
mean if the frequency appear only one
time what does it mean
what's it what does it mean
then it's uh
if it appears only one time what
happened
exactly if it's you if it's uh
one because they appear only one times
and also the key the this number is
bigger than the answer yeah then we can
say answer equals
t okay and then return answer
easy okay yeah so the time to next state
hash table or when going through these
items away please we can change this
four lines one two three four lines into
one line okay
return
maximum
maximum was
uh maximum
okay okay
okay we we pretend uh this is list or
tuple internet k
we want to determine the maximum key
for k
v
in
c dot items
if v equal equal one okay
now we use this or we can use the list
alternate doesn't matter know you have
to give us d4
fine before equals minus one so the
second parameter look d4 equals minus
one follow up
okay that's very funny okay for the
maximum
maximum function
second parameter we can supply of a
parameter d4 equals minus one what does
mean it means that even this is empty if
at least is empty we can't find the
maximum and then we should keep the
minus one so it's basically this the
same as this your answer equals one look
if we can't find anything
uh
equals one right so that would be ten
okay so
yeah look if we can't find the unique
number these answers will never be
updated right so it will return to minus
one here okay
so that's default default means that if
if okay so let's go back to this okay if
the list is empty max i want to get the
maximum value of this of a number right
you can always get the maximum there is
always a maximum value for for a list am
right
unless unless this is empty
yeah
if you haven't okay so put it this way
if i haven't given you
numbers what's the maximum value
nothing nothing yeah d4
before equals minus one is minor that's
what it comes from in okay
okay uh the second
second way is like if how about if we
can solve this number
if we solve the number what happens look
if it is two two one one three if we saw
the number
what do we have
if we saw the number what do we have
so we we sort it yeah we can sort it so
we can say the numbers
stop solved
if we sort it that will become the
numbers will become one
one two two three okay
yeah different numbers we if we sort it
what's the time complexity if we sort of
uh a list
what's the time complexity
sorry
okay
what's the time complexity to sort a
list of the numbers
okay so now if we sort it then we can
use the group by okay so if we use the
group and then we'll be the adjacent let
the similar the same values will be
grouped together and then we can check
we will introduce ourselves the same
okay so number thought okay let's sort
and then we can do this return is quite
similar max
max uh
k
for
k v
in grew by
goodbye goodbye what do you go by numbs
yeah
okay we should we can sort it
in the balance or we can put if we don't
sort it here we can do this sorted nouns
here the iterator sorted is the same
salty nums okay
certain nouns grew by
if
if length the v this is the iterator to
the list then we can length list v
equal equal one okay
and then
p4 equals d4
equals minus one okay this is the same
thing okay so it's quite similar max i
want to get the key key is the numbers
and for v
uh
uh v is the
the grooves of this
of of the the similar values the same
values okay and then you say iterator we
have to convert it to the list and we
check the last thing with one if it's
one it means that it's a unique number
right between the one
the d4 the same
if we don't specify the default and if
we can't find what happens if we don't
specify the difference is that
if they are not unique numbers so this
the the first parameter the list will be
empty and we're trying to get this
maximum value of the empty value whether
your the computer will screen
because it doesn't know
it doesn't find it can't find a maximum
value if you don't give it anything
right and your screen
that's why i would put that before
equals manufacturing okay
yeah okay
okay so the third method the last one
okay so if we say in these numbers are
between zero to a thousand and one okay
so if this value these values are
between zero to a thousand what happened
what can we do
if these values are between zero to a
thousand
okay by the way when we are where we
talk about the second method yeah which
is using the group group yeah group we
saw the numbers oh and again
and then if you like numbers similar
values the same values are together we
can group them right yeah we can groom
them right yeah google man i know we can
count it look this is quite the same get
started
but
the third method is if okay let's say if
these numbers are between zero to a
thousand now we can count in a bucket
what does it mean we have a thousand and
one bucket
and now we can count each bucket
right okay so look
the river these numbers are between zero
to a thousand okay and how do we do it
look
easy
easy if these numbers are between zeros
uh
a thousand the second method using group
by the time complexity is always not
them because the sorting yes sorting
takes place it's valid it's small and
it's dominating the aggregate okay so
now let's talk about this look we can
say this bucket
bucket b equals at the beginning is zero
times a thousand and one
we have a thousand one and one bucket
and then we can do this for
i in numbers
and then we can say b i plus equals one
right so we count we update the bucket
yeah
right right
okay now we update the bucket not easy
because we only have a thousand and one
buckets so we go from
for i
in range
we start from a thousand up to the minus
one minus one
we start from a thousand we decremented
minus one we up to zero okay
beyond one
minus one is one beyond zero okay so we
this is basically the same as i is from
decrementing from
from one uh is from a thousand
decrementing to zero okay now we can say
if vi if it is bucket equal equal one
that is unique number we can just return
i yeah you see and then our eyes return
minus one
okay
look at this
what's the time frame let's see
oh and we're done these p o n and n
numbers yeah but these speed the time
domains for this one is a one for this b
why is that because
this iteration this these four look
executed a thousand and one turns at
most so it's fixed when it's fixed then
it's constant
okay that's it
that's it for today any questions how
many messes we have talked about
first one second one
i forgot starting yeah salting and grew
back second one that's another one
bucket we put it in if these numbers are
look the third method is not very
genetic yeah general yeah generalized
it's not general because we have to
restrict the numbers to be
between a range here to a thousand okay
now we count it we have a thousand a
thousand and one bucket yeah for each
bucket we we count how many how many
numbers for our lying
are placed under each bucket and then go
through
because we're looking for the largest so
we go we can start from a thousand and a
thousand buckets a thousand the last
bucket and then counting backwards and
we check if that bucket is contains only
one number then that means that
it's this is the largest unique number
that we determine okay the time the
message is okay
okay that's it for today bye-bye
[Music]
you