go hey
hello mr harry mr ryan are you all right
okay so today let's talk about the
binary tree again okay fine number three
one
two
three
four
five nine binary
the leaves do not have any kids right
yeah how many how many notes are besides
their parents
um
three and the one we love the parents
okay so if we remove the leaves now what
what do we get
we don't need
okay so now how many leaves are there
all right
how many leaves are there
um one
which is two right see we keep removing
it that would be one okay and then that
would be the only note left that would
be moving because the single note is
also a leaf okay so then we will move it
so look the first term
the first time we remove which is three
four
the second time we remove which is the
two
the third time
is one okay
[Music]
do i make myself clear yeah
okay so okay let me repeat it
basically we are removing the leaf nose
and here we cannot okay so look first
time we remove the three four which is
under this note
and then it become one two and we keep
removing the two which is the leaf now
and they become one which uh
but we remove okay okay
okay that's right right okay so
how do we do it i mean how do we do it
with
with this kind of problem yeah remember
uh we talked about remove remove the
leaves
yeah of the final tree yeah remove the
even leaves yeah we talked about these
before right but now this is the
slightly a little bit different right
because we need to keep removing the
leaves until we cannot right so the best
way to do it is to uh
definitely search right remember
so
look at this how do we apply the
different search here the key point here
right is that look three and four this
is the
three and four we need to remove it
first and then two and then one
so if we can
can
so if we can remove if we can store the
num
the leaves yeah by their levels so let's
keep a dictionary which is called data
which the keys would be the level okay
what are the depth okay steps
next steps yeah remember the depths and
then little points to the lead to the
nose okay
to the notes
so look here one two three so let's
let's look at these
these four okay these four look if it's
an empty note the the number is zero
okay so look if we're looking if we do
this different search bottom arm yeah
so the note
the empty note has the depth still
the single leaf now has the text one
here this is next one right
here here is this one
why i want to do it
yeah that's one
yeah this here
step two
right here
definitely
why is that look because this each note
the depth will be determined by the left
the depth of the left tree and the depth
of right tree
plus one right right
yeah so look
what what's the no what's the depth on
this one
what's the depth of this one
[Music]
what's the terms of this one two why is
it 2 no look
why is 2
that's not never level is 2. i'm saying
the test that's what steps that is the
maximum of the 8 of the left 3 and the
right 3 plus 1
right so what i'm saying if the t equals
zero if the note is empty
all right so these notes are one always
one right look so this one is one right
yeah
this one is one look this is two and one
so i'm standing at that note one yeah
rooted one right
so it's the left tree
this has the depth too this has the
that's one the maximum will be the two
and now we get the maximum plus one that
would be a three okay
that makes sense yeah
okay
so let's do this uh let's find this uh
test okay so
find the test and then we can put it in
the dictionary
put it in the dictionary okay so let's
define
that for that
no
okay so let's define this function
return the maximum test come on if not
dude what should we return not do if the
loser is empty what should we pretend
the depth is what if not what should we
return
zero yeah obviously yeah okay then what
let me call the left one we call it the
first search recursion yeah blue dot
left right
and then right can you can you copy can
you can you do this y equals what come
on left equals definitely y equals one
i'm here
yeah
yeah obviously yeah
and then look now the current level
current level current depth current
depth
equals the maximum
right
maximum what the left
and the right
uh what should we do plus one here right
yeah and then we need to return this
steps here return
okay so now we need to put we need to
store
the note this note
by the desk this would be a dictionary
which is the key will be the level
will it will be the depth okay
okay confusion death
death is not equal to level okay
yeah when we talk about level let's
level by level pressure search right
now the dictionary let's call it data
data default dictionary yeah we can do
it before dictionary
the default dictionary which is the list
type
yeah and then we can do this data
data
depth
dot apparent
apparently the value okay do the value
why can we do this
because list is deposition or at least
right if we don't do this definition if
we declare the dictionary like this a
simple dictionary yeah this is
sympathetic
we can't do this because these steps
might not be the key may not be existent
and we have to do this theta
that's
equals
theta we can use the get function get
the level
get the depth level
and then if this key is not existing we
return a simple
empty and then plus
plus a
plus root of value okay this is uh
this is this is the way to go if we if
we are using the simple dictionary right
the same partition right using this way
compared to the default dictionary the
main the main difference is that look if
we declare additionally using this way
if a key is not existent
the computer will screen
okay
but for the default decision before
before yeah
what's default we'll talk about this the
you know the preset value if the key is
not existing it means that okay if the
key is not existing then you will
you will give us a default value
of the type list which is
entities okay right
yeah
okay so now look
now this data depth so the data for
points for this one yeah let's write one
two
three four
right come on
yeah okay
look at this look at this final three
again so after this step search what do
we have this data
data this is additional area okay so
never
this is level one
level one will be three and four okay
level two will be only these two right
level three will be one okay
and then what should we return we want
to return these this value which is what
we which is what come on
this is the keys d what's this
the values where done so we written data
value just that
return
first of all we do the step research to
do the obviously we call it and return
data dot values
okay
data value will be this one look do you
see this one
one
this is the depth of the nose three
three and four this is that one
left two number two or that's two
two step three one okay why is that look
the left and right
the depth the current depth is the
maximum of left or right platform
make sense
the time complexity definite search
[Music]
n it's the number of notes in the binary
tree okay because each note gets visited
one space complexity is the same again
okay
yeah
okay so what have you learned today the
last question about tweet about let's
leave what
[Music]
yeah so okay so okay let me give you a
quick question okay
five
six
seven okay so what should we return
what's your opinion
this one two four three five six seven
okay what should we return three five
six seven three five six seven okay and
then
two four
two four and then one exactly this is
easy how about if i don't have this
right three six five three six five
yeah three five six i mean uh yeah and
then two four and then one okay so this
is probably easy okay how about this if
i give you another one so seven
seven
uh-huh and then one three five six
three seven six yeah
five
two
five four five four yeah two two yeah
exactly okay got it okay that's it for
today good job bye