okay
so let's say you know we you have
yeah well flight flight airplane yeah
the fire item the tickets
so basically if i say a piece of you
eric yeah yeah you have a bunch of
tickets uh first phone so you want to go
to somewhere australia right yeah
city yeah australia so you go to london
london heathrow airport yeah
london history expo
and then you go to
uh beijing yeah china
and then from beijing you probably go to
australia senior sydney is the capital
okay
so look you have you need two tickets
one ticket london to basin and then that
that's the connecting flight so from
beijing you can take another airplane to
friday
what are we where i am like just going
to capital cities
i mean i'm just giving an example okay
so london here for example like so you
need two tickets right so if they are
from sydney
where else can you go from sydney new
zealand for example i don't know what's
the capital of new zealand okay
new zealand is part of australia
no
it's not
it's a different country
[Music]
to
to beijing
and i have sydney
sydney to new zealand okay new zealand
four two one two three three five
okay so if i
okay look this is a three flies three
tickets three tickets okay so i'm going
to erase this speed so can you tell me
which which is the first city you visit
i mean which is the
for start place
tickets because look the tickets may be
shuffled
so what's the what how do we find out
how does this computer find out so the
thing is
so
so you find the
all you need to do you find the
the there are six uh uh places yeah yeah
some duplicates you find for one
the two that that are only are unique
from the others so
and
and this one is from the left so that
means you should start first and this
one is from the right side exactly
that's very good point yeah yeah you
know what i'm talking about yeah
there are three tickets let's shuffle so
we want to find out the first place
right let's start the the strong start
yeah
and then we want to find out you know a
bunch of flies and unless we go go to
the destination at destination so you're
saying that all these in the middle of
cities in the middle will be duplicated
right yeah yeah and then only the start
and destination and from the left-hand
side is london
this is the destination
very good point very good australian
yeah
okay
okay so look yeah yeah so what
come on listen to me yeah
yeah you're right so this is kind of a
simple graph which means that no let's
let's assume that no cities
will be visited twice
what does it mean it implies that
there's there will be no cycle in the in
in the graph right okay so look a to the
b
uh c to the a
uh okay another one okay a to the c
no no no not a b okay a to the b c to
the a b to the c
okay and
uh c to the a c to the
d to the c
uh b c a
okay so there might be a cycle
okay uh that'll probably take about 30
hours yeah yeah good look leave this
there is a cycle here look yeah
look at me look
a to the b
b to the c
c to the a this is a cycle yeah and how
about look if i'm not saying b to c i'm
saying that uh b to the d
okay
and c e to the c okay can you find out
which one is the star place
which one is the destination here a to
the b c to the a b to the d e to the c
which place which we are visiting first
come on
uh we need you to see
which place is the star which place this
is the star yeah which place is the
destination
to the a a to the b
okay so that's like what you said okay
we if we have a duplicate
that's that's something in the middle
right so that's a graph okay so e on the
left hand side is the sound d is on the
right hand side is the destination
this is a simple bar actually this is
just a part yeah and we love
the cycle so if we find the first one
then we can just follow it right we can
just follow it follow the photo until we
get to the end all right yeah okay so
that would be that a little bit of task
today okay so we remember the graph if
we have an edge pointing up pointing in
the the in degree
the indegree of the node c b
plus one right so if the edge coming in
that will be the in degree and that will
be if the edge going out that will be
our degree right you get it so this
finding the start of the
graph is basically the same as
the integral of a star is what
the integral of the star
the in degree of the star is
how many edges coming to the star
going to the star zero oh certain
degrees zero exactly like that okay so
we can do this and
okay i'm going to write this okay so it
should be very easy so we are given this
that of uh the structure the fry tickets
and we want to find out that the
the route okay so which ticket we take
first we're connecting fries and then we
find out the destination ryan
defy okay let's say the
flight
and that will be the ticket okay let's
say flights okay right
yeah
right okay it's not right yeah if
we check these special cases if the
given input is a empty list then we just
return empty yeah because we can't let's
not take it we just we cannot empty this
okay now we put this answer here answer
at the beginning we have uh empty this
this is the this is the uh
the answer yeah we're going to return
written here yeah written somewhere and
we can answer okay
now we want to put down the flight
flight will be given as you know the
string like a to the b
a eight
a uh
a b
so you'll be given as a
an array of uh
an array of tickets yeah it would be
something like that yeah b to the c
this will be a rate of the flight ap
okay so let's put it in the graph yeah
graph
graph is the edges and remember what's
graph graph the collection data
structure with the collection of uh
vertex and edges yeah vertex vertices
here
vertex is the node it's like the the
cities the edges are the connecting
flight okay
so now g will be equal to let's say we
can use this stationary additionally
a to a comma b
for
a b in flight okay we can do this one
single line
right all right
right
look at it ap
so this is the dictionary yeah look
decently a b a to the b what's a what's
b defined here a and b is in the place
so basically this is saying that uh we
are transforming the these
data structure a list of the tickets
into a graph which is a to the b so that
will be
the keys will be from city the values
will be two city okay so it's a flight
okay and now we want to find out
let's say we want to find out the star
city as you said we want to find the in
degree okay that's one easy way let's
please
first of all let's please state
the dictionary decision we can we can
take these flights we can take these and
put it into a dictionary we can convert
the list into a dictionary so the data
of keys
will be a b
data values will be bc okay
so this is the steps uh a way of doing
that look let's let's put another one c
to d
here
yeah yeah at least that's three tickets
a to the b b to the c c to d this is
easy okay yeah
okay so if we convert it to data that
data will converge theta to be a
to b
b
to c
c to d so this is the keys
these values so now look if we we we
creating a set of these abc right so
look set of keys will be a
b
c
set of values so b b c d right so b c
d okay look
to set set of keys will be abc
set of the values will be bcd yeah look
with
data
is a dictionary
we're taking this flight of tickets a b
c abc will be q
and bcd will be the values so the keys
will be abc here
values will be bcd i put it in the set
yeah so if i doing this
difference
set a minus set b will be the elements
like in first set
not existing in the second set okay so
what's what's that look if i'm saying
this this this first circle is a right
okay that's a smaller a
these will be a equals
a b c
and b equals
b c d okay
so can you tell me what's a minus b
a minus b equals
a minus c
equals
a
equals a what does it mean it means that
the elements that exists in a not
existing b okay how about b minus a
the opposite it's in here but not in
here which one
a minus b
a minus b will be a
actually this is a okay
okay and then b minus a will be what
which element is b
okay yeah that's the difference a minus
b is the same as a dot difference b yeah
this is the same a minus b if we set is
equal to a dot difference
difference b meaning that the elements
it is in set a but do not exist in set b
okay so now if we do this
if we do this a minus b
then that would be let's start right
that'll be the star which is the a right
so
so we can just do this uh the set let's
say
uh s equals
set
data
set data is the same as the data of keys
okay set data keys
minus set data values
and now let's should give us
a set with only one element and we can
convert them a set of one on element to
a star we can do this next function yeah
remember what's next function next one
it takes an iterator so let's convert
this set into iterator which which
first of all we convert the set to the
iterator and then we can use the next
function to retrieve the first one the
next one which is the star because it
only has one element right another way
we can do this the empty join we can
join s this is uh also okay right
because look s is a set then we can join
it and you also give us a
let's start okay both are okay
and then we we have this star then we
can do this
answer first of all answer the opinion
so probably we can
instead of putting here we can just say
answer put it because we can directly
put a star at the beginning
and then wire
where a
star in the in in the ticket then we do
this what we can do this answer
answer actually we need to go for next
so star equals
star equals g
[Music]
star okay we find the next ticket fg
this is the graph yeah we find the next
one
and then we can answer the append
apparent star okay
all right
return answer
g
what's g
graph class
what does it contain what does this
contain
uh it contains
a b a b b g c c d yeah it would be
traditionally a to the b so u b
because it's a single line yeah a to the
p u so uh we just uh
the the values will be just a single
value yeah normally
normally if we use this kind of
dictionary to represent the graph the
keys will be the note the value will be
a list of notes but in this case we only
have one note right because it's a
single way
we're traveling just one way yeah and
there's no cycle we we are not traveling
there's no such cases if you go a to the
b and a to the c okay this doesn't exist
yeah
so a from one node there will be only
one node
connect so in this case there will be
only one all degree
right from a there will be only one out
degree
there's no such cases the article will
be more than one okay because if we in
more modern y doesn't make sense you
will come from a
which way you're going
right
there's no right
no you can't go both so you go a or you
go go b then there's no c or you go c
there's no b so so we only we only have
one value here which is the
the destination of latitude okay a to
the b and then that's b to the c
and then here will be c to the b okay
additionally g
this is a nice way to construct a
dictionary a graph dictionary
from a list of tickets right
data dictionary as we talked uh
we're converting
the flies into the data
into the data so actually obviously we
don't need this right because let's look
at this data this is the same right here
right all right
so probably we don't need it right
this is the same thing these two are the
same thing okay i just small area
right g
so we just don't we we we just do this g
equals left
right yeah it's the same thing is it
should be the same thing okay
so g dot keys
g the values and
and then
yeah it should be all right okay
then the time complexity that end ticket
will be lan because each each city will
be visited only once okay
the space complexity o o n we're using
that dictionary to store a graph
right
to store a graph
okay that's it that's it for today bye
you