go hello hello hello
yeah okay so we have given a few
integers yes like five seven six
four can you tell me that if it's a
consecutive yeah four five six seven
how about
seven
six
three
two no no why is that we've got two
three six seven one where's one
missing where's five
your butt okay seven
five six five
yes or no four by six seven
hey
okay so how can we achieve this how can
we do it first thing to do is do one
and then we check if the neighbors are
one different right
define
is consequences
how do you spread the sensitivity
consecute
yeah i'm right okay so
first of all nouns
and we just have to check
okay comma if the nums i
if it is not equal to nums
i minus 1 1
look
this number
if it's not equal to the previous number
plus what what number that will return
for
if this number is not equal to the
previous number
the previous number
was if after we saw that if this number
is not the same as the previous number
plus what plus one which number here one
one exactly that would be ten fourths
yeah
after all the check will return true
here
okay so look releasing
can be turned into one line because we
are checking look what what are we what
are we doing here we are checking
if for any violation yeah
okay everybody listen to me
we're checking for the violation
so it's the same thing as we return all
of it all conditions are satisfied or q1
remember
everybody
okay one how do we say
nums i o
if equals num
i minus one plus one
for
i
in range
one
can you explain to me
this one
return oh what's it all
uh oh
i mean everything everything needs to be
true here right so everything look numbs
i
this this is
if this is nums i and what's this numbs
i minus one what does it mean what's a
num time minus one
right
uh i minus one is like the one before
yeah so the numbers are should be the
nums
before it plus one for i in when you
start from one right yeah why start from
one
one two three four why we start from
here
this number should be the previous
number plus one this number should be
previous to normal plus one this number
should be previous number two okay all
right right
okay time convexity this one is o and
again this one is a one
so what's the overall time complexity
this one
this one is o and again
this one is oven so what's the timer
velocity
yeah this one is dominating this one is
complex now this one yeah takes more
time yeah so we ignore this one huh yeah
space complexity a one we are not using
any
linears uh we are we're only using the
constant base right
now
okay
okay so what have you learned so far
today
can you tell me one sentence what have
you done today we have learned how to
you're turn first we learn how to
um
generate is consecutive
how about you right
i learned how to uh
check if
[Music]
and how do we do it what's the most
important thing salty and checking and
then this is keyword okay so apart from
this all keyword
there's another one can you guess what's
this meaning any
any of them so at least one of them
all means everything yeah exactly yeah
your english is better than mine
okay that's it for today bye bye
bye