go
hello mr miss ryan are you right
we talked about the largest uh sublisten
yeah largest
sadly
service
sometimes we call it sub-array okay
what's so funny nothing
what's the difference between service
sub-array or and subject
what
it's continuous what do you try is
continuous
these two are continuous okay for
example like let's let's do this one two
three this is an array so can you give
me a example of a service
three two one no
two one
three three what is it
one two three okay two three one so
these have to be three
two three one is not two three one this
one
so let's continue
yeah continuous one two three one two
one two three four five
and twelve fourteen fifteen sixty seven
one
eighteen twenty twenty one zero
[Music]
can you give me an example of
subsequence uh one
uh
one six nine eight two one three four
three seven one three one three okay
not continuous yeah not continuous one
two three four eight nine six
and all of the others only alice what do
you mean because
sex don't have to be uh
you know
subsequent don't have to be continuous
yeah that's right so lee all these
are subsequent right
am i right yeah service
yeah okay so stop this
service
is part of a subsequent yeah this is
kind of in
that means in okay
subsequent
so if we draw a set
here
that will be sublist
and then here will be subsequent okay
because subsequence includes the sunless
okay
okay let's see that's it no more
yeah
so for for problems like sublist we can
always do
we can do what uh we can b false false
and that's going to take roughly oh
what's the time complex
o n squared
why is that look we because we we can
pick
we can pick one
uh the particular style of the sub list
and then we can pick the end of the
sunday right so that would be like a
nasty for
loop and that's going to take owen
square time okay
if it's a subsequence right because if
it's a subsequent the time context if we
prove us it you'll be out to the power
of n yeah because for each element we
can pick or not pick right
yeah yeah so 2 times 2 times 2 times 2
that's 2 to the power okay so so usually
subsequence is uh is the problem is more
uh complicated than the
sub array okay
so for this kind of problem proof us we
can do this uh we can do it in
performance okay let's quickly improve
okay i think i'm running out of ink
you can use my pen
defined last is the sadly some okay
okay
so we just have to proof of the left and
right index right the left and right
index
first of all first of all the answer
is minus
the mass infinity
and then n will be the length of the
numbers
four
i
in range
and right
for
j
e
range we start from the i the next
boundary is the left boundary j is the
right boundary
and then the current sum will be
sum
numbers
[Music]
start from i to j plus one yeah because
up to j plus one
and then answer plus one answer equals
what maximum of answer uh and the sum x
310 answer
what's the time complexity this one
[Music]
because this is one time right but we
can easily optimize this this is o n
square o and q b sorry
but we can optimize it because this is
every time for each sub array we we
don't need to calculate the sum right we
don't need to calculate the sum okay
so how do we do that we just have to
how do we optimize this into our own
square
we make it quicker look we just put the
sum here s equals zero
right
so instead of summing because this takes
time let's take some right let's take
some but we we just do this s plus equal
nums
j
and i know b right look
here in this case this is
o n square right
do you see how we do it yeah this is
slow why is that because every time we
have to calculate
the subtly sum again and again
actually why is that look one two three
four we know this summary sum is six
right yeah yeah
yeah
okay what's the subtle sum this way
this is i told you here this is six
if i include one more number what's the
third sum
so this one is ten exactly how do you
get the ten uh six plus four is ten
exactly here right but previously this
one it does not do it the previously you
will just do it very stupid one plus two
plus three plus two that's stupid that's
how it's very slow okay but we are now
changing it because we already know this
okay okay we are now knowing this is
streets
plus another one
accumulated it's just well done
okay so
katan
yeah we also know the katan right what's
kaidan is
[Music]
so look one two three minus four minus
five something like that okay so let's
say
the kazan is like the iterated dynamic
programming and we talk about it so if
we're saying dp
dpi this is the maximum surface sum that
ends at index i right so it's actually
equal to
maximum of come on come on can you can
you calm down all right people not
seeing it
dp i minus 1
or zero plus
nums i okay so this is the basically a
dynamic problem what does it mean is
that dpi oh listen to me
it's the largest subject sum that ends
the index i right so it equals to
the previous one
right if we pick the previous one oh we
don't pick it we start is the least
number okay ryan come on
so look
look you are here i am cp vp we are here
dpi so we are considering this number so
this is
we are considering this number so there
are basically two choice all right so if
we include this number in the pre in the
it is uh previous previous sub
right so you will have one more right oh
we don't include the previous number so
we started as a new list so let's let's
sub this star is here basically there
are two choice that's what it means
right that's what it means
so
we can do this
let me just write it right
define
largest sublet sum lss
numbers okay
okay so if not numbers we can just put
it if not numbers we just return zero
okay
and that is we got one number so answer
equals the curve equals num zero so we
start with putting single number then we
start from the second number for i in
nums
start from one one to the end
so current equals the maximum of current
plus i or
i okay so this is basically saying that
okay let's try two possibilities one is
to include this number in the in the
largest submission or
we start this
start a new list with a single number
current number okay and then answer
equals
maximum
answer
sum okay
count
we can return one
also yeah
what's the tank on backstage if you look
at this
okay answer because maximum okay
make sense
yeah
okay so now come on today's problem
today's problem yeah today's problem is
look one slightly different
is we want to find out this continuous
continuous sub array which is the
absolute value abs
so nums
i
plus
num i plus one etcetera okay so we can
we want to find out a sub this
continuous surface which has the
absolute which is this what is this
absolute value why is this absolute
value
what is this absolute value
what's this
what does it mean
abs minus 10 what's what is it equal
it means
oh is it a 10 10 the distance to the
deal right basically so the minus will
be
the
negative
the negative value will be at least
taken out
so this is the only difference we want
to find out the absolute value so
so obviously we can
use the first two approach yeah the
proof was o and cubic or in cubic
exactly o n square yeah i'm gonna i'm
not going to write it's basically
similar we just have to write put one
more absolute value right but how can we
apply this kadam
or dynamic programming approach to to
this kind of problem right with this
absolute v1 with this as a blue killer
what's this absolute key word actually
so you will make the you you'll be
you'll be actually the distance to the
zero right right
so the only two possibilities either you
go very very far to the right or you go
very very far to the left right
so in this case we can use two values
one is to store the maximum
maximum sum
of the
of the subways we have seen so far and
the other one we see is what we find the
minimum
sum of the subjects we have seen so far
right yeah so how can we apply this this
is quite interesting look so we just
have to do this right current we just
have to put this color into the laser
low
and then equals and then also equals the
max and the height
okay
yeah
then this is the same we do this the
high
equals maximum curve high plus
i and we add one more low equals the
minimum
low plus i i
then answer equals maximum answer
okay so there are two more values high
or minus low right okay and then return
answer this is only changes right come
on this is the takeaway of today
this is the new thing today
do you get this problem
we are adding this absolutely absolute
value is basically the distance to zero
right and we are finding this absolute
value so it could be only two choice
either you go very very far to the right
which is to the to the east yeah
yeah or you go very very far to the left
which is to the
west
yeah
all right east
west
north
south south okay so we basically
two choice
we can get
we can track the
largest value that going east or we can
check the largest value going west right
so instead of checking the one single
value we have this low and maybe we just
change it to
to
east and west okay east and west
so
east with maximum easter plus i
the west will be minimum right because
what going west going left will be the
minimum so we're going to minimum plus i
and then
going east or minus going west so this
is the same thing as taking the absolute
value yeah because we know the west will
be the negative number so we just do
this minus w so so
this is basically the same as like we
are applying we are applying the kadan
uh agreement twice on this program okay
yes what's the time complexity for this
one come on
oh n right yeah because we just
we iterating ones of the array and we
are taking tracking the maximum minimum
value okay yeah
yeah what have you learned today so far
come on one sentence
[Music]
yeah absolutely the largest surplus
largest
services okay so today we we we are just
adding a keyword abs here absolute
service sound okay and then how do we do
it we're just applying the kadan
twice kadai is basically like iterated
dynamic programming yeah so let me talk
to me so it's uh let me just write it
again one more time okay right here so
dpi
is let's let's
what's dpi
[Music]
numbers i okay
let me explain this one more time so
this is the key key takeaway of the
dynamic programming dpi is the largest
surface on the ends the index side
so we are looking at this number so
the largest sub is sum we can include we
can try to include this number in the
previous of the sum right
and plus it or we don't pick the
previous one then we start with kinds of
numbers so look one two
minus four five okay so if we are
looking at this number so
there are two choice
we can increase minus four
in the previous subtly sum yeah
previously sum is bpi minus one here
so i don't know
i don't know uh
which one is
maximum right which one is higher so
basically dpi minus one dbi minus one
come on it's the service sum of the
previous here yeah
i can include this number
right so you the previous sub list will
include one more minus one
or i decide i can drop it so i start a
new list from here right
yeah do you get it
do you get it right this is basically it
okay and then plug yellow means that we
we are dropping the previous sum right
and then we we start with a new one
right
okay that's it for today bye bye bye
bye bye