yo
hello hello guys hello mister with mr
ryan all right okay so let's talk look
at this mess a to the power of a equals
2 to the power of 2048
a is an integer obviously okay
a is is integer it's integer
is integer
okay integer bigger than zero okay
obviously obviously bigger than zero
okay bigger than zero
a is bigger than zero
okay so have a guess what's a
is it is it 100 is it one
no
two
three
obviously because it's too small yeah
how about eight
definitely
not okay
how about a hundred we don't know yeah
we don't know right
okay so yeah
this this is a very huge number it means
that we multiply two
2048 times yes two times two times two
times two how many times of two two
thousand and thirty eight times which
equals 496.
4096 that's 2 times 2048 that's right
but no because that means that they are
these means
2 times 2 times 2
how many of 2
okay that's the power two to the power
of left okay so let me show you
uh
a to the power of b times c
right what does it equal
this is base it's actually equals a to
the power of b
then to the power of c okay how can i
interpret this
3 to the power of
2 times
three okay this is equal to three to the
power of
six right
yeah
it's actually equals to three to the
power of two
to the three so this equals nine to the
power of three
is it the same like
six three together
times together now that's six of three
one two three four five six how many
nines
three nine yeah
yeah so these two here
these two yeah
these two here yeah got it you get it so
a to the power a to the power of b times
c equals to we can do these two together
and then
to the power of c
okay so how does that help us
how does that help us look
2 to the power of
2048 is equals to 2 times
look at this yeah
yeah
so if i do this together
that equals 4 to the power of
10 24 right
so this thing is equal to this thing
okay so keep going
this equals to what
1024 equals 2 times
515 right
512 right so if i do this together
that will be 16 to the power of
512 right
yeah
okay so can you get the next one
next one so this is equals to 16 to the
power of 2 times
256 right
yeah so we can do these two together
16 times 16
oh it's there it's almost 2048. 16 times
60. 256. yeah okay so it's 256 times
to the power of 256 okay what's a
256 exactly okay that's how we get it
yeah let's mathematics but
one of the important thing today is this
a to the power of b times c equals a to
the power b we can do this together and
to the power of c okay yeah
yeah
very beautifully
we get it yeah
so we know b
a is
256 to the point
these two numbers are equal it's very
huge numbers we don't know yeah
okay so the other way
this is mathematic we we can ask
computer to to find this value right we
can ask computer to prove us this right
yeah about blue force you know
156 times 256 200
250 okay so look
a to the power of a equals b so a must
be
smaller or equal than 200 for uh
2048 right obviously yeah if this is
2048 2048 is obviously bigger than 2 to
the power of 248 right so the upper
bound is 220 48 so we can just
ask computer to search the a from 1 to
20 for there right yeah
or we can find the research
yeah you don't know what's final
research
guess the number one to a hundred
guess the number you always find the
middle one fifty fifty if it's if i tell
you the number
in my mind is bigger than 50.
so
[Music]
yeah yeah you always find that yeah you
got it you're searching
upper pump if i i'm saying okay the
number in my mind is
smaller than 50. you search in a lower
half right always cut enough okay so
25 yeah exactly always find find one in
the middle so
for follow one in
four one uh in linear so for a in range
and that's range 1 to 249
248 20 48 then if a times a
okay eight times time a okay let's do
the power and we talk about that
a
time multiply multiply b is the same is
the same as a to the power b and then
you can write math the power a b this is
the same thing here
okay if a
multiply multiply a equals two
multiply multiply
to twenty forty eight and then we return
a right easy this is the linear search
meaning
linear okay but we can do a binary
research
final research
so the lower bound is one right low
about is low about is one upper bound is
20 48
final research why the left and right do
not meet
yeah
why the left and right the window look
left and right do not meet
air smaller equivalent right
length meter equals
l plus r divided by two right divided by
two okay
find that in the left or you can do this
r plus a plus r shift is fifty one this
is
same thing okay m n
equals m
multiply
let's do the problem
power m to the power of n okay
then if mm equal equal
2 to the power of
2 to the power of 2 multiplied to the
power of 20 2048 then we find this
number return mn right
okay okay now you tell me
if this number mm is bigger than
this number okay bigger than 2 to the
power of 2048
right so look
if if this number is bigger than that so
what what does it mean
look here
this is the middle yeah yeah this is
middle
all right if this number
to about if m n
if m m
if the
we are guessing this m now but if this
m to the power of m is actually bigger
than 2 2 to the power of 20 48 so which
half
which half is this
then it has to be
left
which one left or right
come on if this number m to the power of
m
is bigger than
2 to the power of 20 48
so
this number is bigger
than this
left so we should look for the left
right so for leveling b
r will be equals to n minus one as let
us look if it's smaller than
if it's smaller than that so which
way should we look for
which half is this number
right right so a is what
s1 or else look this is l this is r so
[Music]
where that exactly i wanted to meet
okay
final research what's a tandem
breastfeed
usually a organ oh logan yeah oh logan
okay
but here look because we already know
the outlaw about upper bound so in this
case the term convexity is one okay
you're right yeah
but do you understand the reason behind
it
yeah you sure okay why is it the one
because look the lower bar and upper
body is already we already know
we already know with the the maximum
that the search space is between the one
to two and twenty forty eight right but
you are also right
what i meant is that when this
you know when they are end generally end
you do this smoking okay
yeah
log
log 2
2 20 48 what's this number
2 to the power of x equals 20 48 how
many how many
what's
x 2 to the power of 10 equals 10 24.
what's x
how many more 10 24 times 1 equals 20 48
okay so how many more twos i need to
multiply
how many more
twos one yeah so two to the power of one
equals twenty ten forty eight eleven
exactly
okay
for today
bye bye
bye okay that's it