good
hello mr mr ryan are you right
okay let's talk about very simple
problems yeah cupcake frequent elements
so we call these numbers one one one two
two three so i want you to find out give
me an answer like
the top two
top two frequent elements one two
exactly look
one appears three times two appears two
times right
so
what data structure is very useful to
count how many
numbers appear how many how many times
we
if we want to count the numbers the
elements and the frequencies
counter counter exactly okay so let's do
this okay so if we do this counter
c
equals counter
number
okay so what does it give us this should
be easier you give us a c is a
dictionary
with a key one appear three times
two
appear two times
three appear one time right
three
one two three three two one exactly the
keys are the elements
the values are the frequency they appear
right one appears three times two appear
two times three appear one time
right so we want the counter equals
dictionary
yes uh kind of yes counter is like the
record for the dictionary so you give us
the dictionary which have the keys are
the values the
values will be the frequency so
basically we want to count we want to
find we want to sort these items this
item
by the values three to one right so the
top two
are three two so we want to return this
one and two
yeah the order does not matter okay so
the counter the very interesting thing
about counter is that we it provides the
method called most common
yeah what does it mean what does the
most common mean
so let's say look see the most common
if we give it a 2
then it will give us these
right because these are the most common
if we don't give you any parameters you
will return
the orders right so you return these
these this
right okay so we give the most common
two so then you return this then we but
we need to return these values yeah
usually okay
so now
that will be very useful okay so then we
can just do this
okay
we can just return
within one
okay so because we don't return one and
two uh at least yeah so we want to
return i
for
i
j
in c the most common
okay
okay so see the most common k returns
the the item see the items in the order
of the values which is the frequency and
then i
the first i items the i will be the
value the number the key right will be
these numbers the j will be the
frequency class
okay
yeah make sense yeah if we don't give
this value k then it will return
everything by the order of the frequency
okay okay so funny enough is that this
counter does not have provide the least
common yeah yeah
it does not provide the least common so
so look if i uh
this number c c will be let's say c will
be one three times two appear two times
three up here one time okay
see the most common yeah most common k
will be this if we don't provide this k
then we turn the frequency in
in all the in the items in order will be
one three two two
and three one okay
so
if we want to get the least comment
which side okay so look
see the most common
salted items in order of frequency so
which one is the seed or which one is
the least common everybody come up which
one is the least common
one yeah exactly so we sorted right so
see the most common it's we can do this
c is the mouse command
and we don't give it any parameters
there remember we don't give that
permission we change everything and then
minus one
yeah that would be let's see uh
least comment okay
okay
this is using the most common if we
don't use the most common we can sort it
we can sort it the see the items yeah so
so we can just saw the seed of items so
we can just say
let's say a equals sorted
see the items
right see the ice and we want to sort of
see the item see the item is 1 3
is an array of items two two
three one we only solely see the items
but
by which key by which number
which number
we want to solve the c the item by which
number this is the number this is the
frequency almost we want to solve the
items by the frequency right so
here we will pass the key equals
p1
p1 means the second number right yeah p
is the item
and then obviously we want to sort by
default sorted is from the smallest to
the biggest but now we want to sort it
from the largest smallest so we pass
another key called
reverse equals two okay and then we can
just return
return
i for
i
j
in
a up to k right because it's in reverse
order and each one is the item so i want
to return this method
yeah okay this is this is the second
method we started okay by sorting the
old logan right obviously the infinite n
items right all right here with me fine
it was me okay okay so what's he but you
mentioned about him what's deep remember
what's he
fasting priority out
uh yes yeah that's one kind of the
it's not exactly the same thing yeah but
you mentioned a very good point the
first thing priority or let's let's call
the priority queue okay priority q are
based on uh heat by uh you know usually
based on binary heat heap is the binary
to tree
the loot
will be the smallest or the biggest
right by default the heap in in python
he p q heap q is the smallest the root
is the smallest so it could be one two
three but this loop is smaller than a
than a kit two is smaller than five six
three smaller than seven eight right
something like that and the
opportunities would be the max heap okay
but the python
heat q is the smallest key is meaning
that loot
is the
uh is the is the smallest okay so then
we can use the we can push these items
into the heap right so we can push the
item into the heap
uh let's put it in
a so we want to push these items into
the into the heap
so for
t v
v
in c dot
items yeah
see the item and
hit
keep q he push
he push a i want to push one
push the
key and value there
we can push the key on value now let's
push the value because it's the
frequency it matters we want to we want
the hip to
to maintain its order by the order of
the frequencies so let's
do the v but but the thing is that we
wanted to find out the
top k frequent uh element right the
frequency should be from the largest to
smallest but the python the heat q as i
said is from the smallest to the biggest
can you think about walking around right
so can you think of walking around that
that could
need
to work for the hip cube
to get it look hip q
is from the smallest to the piggies
right but i wanted to maintain the order
from the largest the smallest one good
way would be to
to neglect negate the sign okay so let's
put minus v
and minus vk
okay
now i have the key key and i want to do
it
i want to i want to pop k elements out
of the heap then that would be the last
top largest
top k frequent elements right am right
okay so now i want to push push it up
okay so let's say this answer
and i want to do this for underscore in
range k
yeah range k
and i want to push
push in the
underscore because i don't want to use
this value i just want to use the
numbers
okay
in
heap pop
a right
and then answer that append
append k
return
uh actually i don't i don't uh we can't
use the k this
the case already used that's called
value okay
and then return
answer
so look
c dot counter yeah and now i go through
the items and i push the i push the
value
a pair a topper a purple jupiter
pepper
cup of soy
the key first element of pepper is the
inverse of a frequency the second value
is the it's actually value right why we
don't why we push the negative v
right
why is that because the hip q by default
is from the smallest to the biggest
right it's the small we call it mean hip
right mean hip
in order to change the mean hip to max
heat
now we the the best way the quicker way
would be just put a negative sound right
because look one two three if i put a
negative sun to it what will become
minus one minus two minus three
yeah look one is bigger smaller than two
three if i put the minus what happened
minus one is the biggest right
do you get it
i want to check i want to reverse the
order the the quickest way to put the
negative sign because the frequency is
not always a positive number right
it's a positive number i put a negative
sign and i reverse the order that's what
what we do is minus v here
and then we just go through 10 times it
put
top
the smallest element from the hip and
then push the value yeah push it ready
okay so look at this thing leaving can
be used
can be can be can be replaced by by
one of the heat function which is for
heat
and larges or end small leaks yeah we
want to enlarge this
yeah so
enlarges so we don't need to put a
negative v here so we can just return
heap
keep the n largest
the first number is how many you want n
okay i want that k
all right so which which is the heat the
second parameter is the heap which is a
the third parameter is i key
key
equals which key you want the item
getter okay
this is similar to the sort function
item data let's
which which one we want to basic uh
which which key is in the first one or
second one so because we only learned
based on the first one so let's put in a
zero
right so we want to basically this is
saying that i want to extract the n
k largest
from the heap based on the first first
item
which is the v
and it retrieves the item right because
in a heap it stores the cover
so we just need to return
i uh we want to return the
the second value here so j
for
i j in
hito enlarges okay
keep enlarging
is to get
n the first parameter is n which we want
the cave top uh
k largest the second parameter is the
heap the third parameter is the key like
a sorting function right which we need
to provide it as a item getter zero
means that the topper we want to the
heap based on the first element instead
of second element second anime is the
number the first element is the
frequency right yeah so if we put the
minus v here then you will reverse the
order then we we can change this to
smallest right and smallest right yeah
make sense
does it make sense everywhere so what
have you learned today so far
so
how many methods are do we talk about
which one you think you you can remember
or you can understand better which one
you think
is easier counter
counter then we can solve the item the
first one is obviously very easy most
common right yeah it gives you the most
common most common right
see the most common is sorting the items
by
by the frequency by the value
the second answer we sorted by ourselves
we sorted the c dot items right by the
key equals the
the
p lambda p p
p square 1 the first which is the
frequency the third method pushing it
all to the uh
pushing everything to the hip right
putting everything to the hip and then
we get
we get it
we extract k times that which will be
the top k frequent elements right yeah
okay the fourth uh method which is the
enlarges or n smallest yeah these are
easy to very convenient to use okay but
the key thing today is
key thing today is that counter
yeah counter now we want to solve the
item which is key value pair by the
value value which is the frequency okay
okay that's it for today bye bye bye
[Music]