yo hello mr mr rhino you're right
yeah good okay so let's say we have a
map
we have a map and if each number is
different color right let's let's just
look at this three times three map okay
two three
three
four
one
one okay so there are four colors one
two three four and in one operation okay
in one operation we can change any piece
of card connected like this brilliantly
connected horizontally vertically
connected we can change any pieces of
color to one color
right i would call it as one operation
okay so the question is that
what's the minimum number operations
that we need to convert all the colors
all the numbers into one single color
anybody everybody
so in this case which color
let's see so which color would you like
to convert it to three
which color we want to keep okay so we
want one one why is that because it has
a mouse
yeah three pieces right
so we want to keep the maximum uh the
the number of the
we want to keep the
the colors that have the most pieces
right yeah okay
okay
i see i see yeah yeah why is that look
two two three four okay
okay let's see that's it
i'm not an
example okay
[Laughter]
okay
[Music]
okay so which color we want to keep
which color we want to keep come on yeah
okay we will keep
one
one one one one
because i have the maximum huh
which column one one you say one what
will be you
because you have the most mickey
come on
we can count how many one one how many
pieces five
no no no this is one piece so
remember we can change any
one operation we can change everything
connected to another color okay so that
only two
two okay so
would you like to change your answer
yeah okay two how many piece how many
how many connected
okay that's another one yeah
three how many
three
one two three
four how many one
okay so which color we want to keep
which color we want to keep
come on easy
so you see so we can change any piece in
one operation we can change the
connected pieces to to any color we want
right so here
so which one has the largest pieces
so okay so
what's the answer
yeah we want to keep the three right
yeah so how many operations do we need
how many operations do we need come on
we only keep the number three yeah yeah
so how many operations we need to
do we need
how many operations come on it's there
how many operations we need to change
all the colors to three how many how
many colors which are different than
three
why is it three come on here is two
right look these two one this is
separate we need two operations
yeah
okay so yeah you're quite like this one
but
different they are two different pieces
right that's why we need two operations
so two plus one plus one
four operation
yeah
okay so what's the how do we do it look
we can
i think he
fish
yeah
you cannot drink this problem now yeah
you switch these to two
and then you switch this to three and
then you see all of this two three and
then that oh okay
that's very good but
that's different problem okay we are not
talking about that complex but you are
quite creative i i know what you mean
once the color is changed it's changed
it cannot be changed again
so you're saying that change leads to
two and then do this whole thing to
three right
yeah but we are not doing that okay
yeah now i see why you get a number yeah
that's very clear okay so i have to
point out that
a color can only be changed at most once
so we just change any colors to to
another color so
so yeah in this case we just find out
the maximum not pieces and we want to
keep it right and the rest the sum of
the rest
some of the rest will be the number of
operations we need yeah do you get it
yeah yeah okay so look how do we do this
remember we talked about the island yeah
we counted our number of islands right
so we just go through these
and then we just mark
using mercury neighbor neighbor which is
vertical
vertical come on come on listen to me
vertical lens vertical or horizontal
connected pieces we let's look how do we
do it do we have elephants other colors
yeah can i have it do you have red
okay okay
how how do we do this look at this map
so it goes to two
yeah
so two
mix colors up two okay so what do we do
two we just change the connected pieces
to minus one okay minus one minus one
minus one minus one so two
let's
put it a one right because we have put
we have counted one piece of length
colors which is one right okay three
look three connect it
make it minus one three one four
connect it
minus one minus one minus one minus one
four
one okay this is minus one i skip one
one okay minus one okay skip my three
three here look three here one man
um
i put in minus one yeah i have to
increment one so that would be two yeah
one
minus one minus one minus one minus one
yeah
two okay three
minus one
i i increment three okay
okay so which one is the largest three
we keep this all the rest one plus one
plus two is the number operation we need
because look there are four colors you
need to change to
let let's just just i don't want to go
here okay yeah
okay
okay look it says the peppa pig
oh that's a big man
yeah
okay
that first search
rc color color let's say color okay
color
so if
okay r smaller than zero or c smaller
than zero or ah bigger or equal than
rows
the number of rows on the map or c
bigger or equal than columns
along with 10 okay
okay then we check if the map
even a map map rc
it's not equal a color then we
this is not a connected pieces or it has
been visited then we do 10 okay
and then we just we have to mark it as
visiting let's mark it as -1 okay so we
visited it remember yeah yeah
and then we just have to go for four
directions which are the four directions
no i'm a current rc so which are the
four positions
here here here here right cfs r minus
one c
color
r plus one c color right go for four
direction all right can you can you tell
me what's the
next two
huh this is yours
okay r minus one is here alpha last one
is here so what what's here
ah c one
rc plus one where that and then what's
the here
where's that
okay so in this case we use surfaces to
visit the map okay
and then we from
the front
so this is separate
i just need a little fuel space okay
so let's take put a color in
additionally before
decisionary which has the internet this
this data structure dictionary is to use
to count the number the colors the key
will be the colors the value will be the
number of pieces right the number of
connected lens for r in
range
rows
for c in range columns yeah
and then if
map rc not equal minus one because if
it's minus one then it's being visited
then we have to
uh the color color will be
the x x will be mac
r c okay and then we have to define
search r c x
and then theta
theta x plus equals one right yeah
now first of all we mark the connected
pieces to minus one right
you know
and then we do like that for such uh
mark and then we
we increment the counter for the color x
right
so we can what do we pretend if we do
this through this step search yeah we go
to the map
pixel by pixel if it's not marked by -1
what does it mean it's it's a color we
have to trade we have to do a definition
and we match the color to one right
okay now we need to return
return sum of the data values so this is
the
data the value minus sum
minus max yeah we want to max these yeah
there is a value okay what does it mean
okay
okay so
remember before
before yeah before that yeah
one two two
two i don't know three four okay four no
one okay
so we also keep
look we want to keep the count of three
right yeah yeah
so how many operations do we need
from this decision right how many
operations we want to keep the current
three how many operations do we need
four
two plus two plus
five how how do we get five
we can do this sum 2 plus 2 plus 4 plus
1 let's sum of values yeah that would be
9 right
minus 4 right that's the maximum right
minus 4 that would be 5. do you get it
yeah some of these that's the number
total number of connected pieces of
thing all the colors
minus
the biggest one
color three is the number of
the maximum number of the colors that we
want to keep and then all the rest needs
to be
converted right
so we this one we are using the texture
search right
can we use the process
yeah yeah you can also use the
preferences
[Music]
in a map that's because because
because
because each look here each pixel
is only visited once yeah because when
we
mark the connected color
we mark it as minus one so it can only
be vegetated once so that time conductor
is always space for maxi
we're using this data right
suppose the data the mac has
has uh unique colors right each each
pixel will be different color then data
will be on right do you get it
okay nobody
will be say bye bye to people bye
bye bye
bye all right
bye