up hello he's very miserable all right
okay so remember we talked about this uh
thing yeah
so we use the different search the
problem was uh what was the problem
is that we have a
okay so let's review this a little bit
we have this kind of map like one two
one two three three one one four in one
operation we can change any
connected
piece look this is connected connected
from one color to another and we want to
find out that what's the minimum number
operation in order to make all colors
into one single chart for example in
this case we change 2
to 2
into 1 so that's going to take 2
operations
three
into one that's going to take uh two
operations and one operation because
this is connected and four into one that
would be another operation so one
two
uh one
one two three four four operations okay
so
how do we do it we we
the excellent would be just to count the
number of say
uh
to count from the number of the islands
yeah remember to talk about the iron the
connected pieces number of pieces for
each color and now we want to keep the
the color which has the most pieces
right so in because if we have we keep
the color with the most pieces then the
number operation will be the minimum
we change this to one okay
we change this to one
right or change this to one so this
would be another connected pieces right
so we just need uh one two three three
operations to make everything into uh
into color one so to in order to count
the number of pieces uh for each color
then we have to store it into a data
before dictionary well the keys are the
colors yeah well the keys are colors and
the values will be the number of the the
number of the pieces so the key thing
here is that we increment this as long
as we do the step research we mark the
connected pieces into minus one or
whatever and then we increment this
color kind of with one piece it means
that we have found another piece of a
connected color
x right so we can do this with step
research or we can do this with special
search so let's do it then with the
question what's what how do we usually
implement the breakfast search any idea
come on anything any different q q
q yeah dq yeah exactly so leave so you
so we can do this there so let's remove
this
yeah we can mark it as minus one yeah
so
so this function means that let's start
perform a process
rc
mean
what's the e mean
double ndq means the kill can be
approached uh we can have these
operations in two
this is a q double entry we can have at
least
a pen
pop
a pen left pop left yeah we can have
this push and pop operation on both
sides the advantage of using this dq is
that we have
these four operations will be the
constant operation right right
will be constant time okay
so
so if we're using the list yeah if we
are using a simple list we this can be
used as a queue a simple queue but the
operations of doing of using this list
on the on the left hand side would be o
i'm constant right it's not uh o n not
constant okay so that's why we use the
we prefer this double ndq
so dq let's put the initial one which is
rc
in the array okay so we're using this
okay and then while
y q is not empty now we have to
get a pixel so
carbon uh let's let's let's write the
lrcc equals q dot problem
okay cube the problem
okay can i use this piece
okay
q the problem okay
so now we have the kyoto problem we get
it from the queue and then what do we
need to do we need to
we need to append its neighbors which
has four directions for that so for
dr dc this is offset in four direction
will be one zero
zero one
minus one zero
zero minus one yeah these are the four
operations okay
uh four directions one zero one zero
means the one up uh
under it zero one
zero what does it mean zero means on the
left minus one zero on the left uh this
is on the right on the left zero kilo
one zero one on the right
minus one zero above it zero minus one
on the left
yeah
so now
this is the offset so the new r will be
the r r plus d r
and c new c would be c c plus d c and we
have to check this coordinate if it's in
range so we have
we can just do it if zero smaller than n
r
smaller than rows
and
right
cl smaller nc smaller than columns so if
this is in range also the new pixel is
not being
it's the color we want so it's the it's
a color so metric uh so we can only make
map
and r
and c equals color right if it's equals
color then
okay so we ryan let me stop doing that
so look if we are at rcc this pixel uh
rcc pixel and we want to find the four
directions
so what do in what cases
we can
append this picture back into the queue
okay anybody
anybody
yeah so
so this is the pixel we take it from the
queue and then
in what conditions we can we need to
push this neighbor back into the queue
if if what if the
color this this picture the color is
what we want okay and then we push in
the kill then we have to change it to
mac
rcc
equals minus one so we mark it so
suppose this is color x and this is also
color x right so i just push this into a
q and i might make these minus ones just
to to avoid these being pushed back to
the queue again
all right and then
q dot append yeah the most important
thing kill the append rcc okay uh us uh
n r and c and i and c
okay and then we can just
and that'll be yeah because this
function will not
we uh we don't need to return anything
with the
function of the processor function these
functions would be just to
to say okay we want to
mark all the connected pieces to these
rc right with the color with color x
yeah
okay
uh
so that would be the perfect search
right that will be preferred so so we
can just plug in replace this with the
preferences and on all to continue to
work
okay
okay so
so any questions so far i mean
guys
this is the breakfast search uh the
color so let's let's
let's give an example okay
so just
to
you a little bit okay 1
1 1
2 2
one
okay
three
one two
two
one okay so which color we want to keep
obviously
one two now okay
let's just just go through the activity
to see
if which color we want
no no no you're not connected as uh
okay
so this is not connected okay i'm going
to
i'm going to let let's let's go through
the
editor okay so we have a dictionary data
yeah we have a dictionary data
data come on
oh
okay i'm starting at one okay and then i
want to mark all the connected pieces
using different social preferences here
right so that would be
one one one here i will change it to all
minus one minus one minus one so now
ones have three
uh one has one okay
one connected and now we skip the minus
one
two
the connected pieces here one
two and then one pieces and i i need to
meet we need to make it as minus one
minus one master just to avoid being
physical again three
three
only one pixel minus one
one
one here minus one
so we increment this one to two right
three
three minus one minus one
that would be an added another one so
two
right and one
make it minus one
three two three okay two
make it minus one minus one increment
one two
one make minus one
increment one four okay so now eric look
color one we have four piece of
connected number two we have two
connected three number three we have two
connected so which which color we should
keep which color is the cape from here
the keys that kind of the values would
be the number of one exactly so we keep
this one so the number operation will be
two plus two right so actually we sum up
the value will be four plus two plus two
and we get a maximum four so four plus
four four plus two plus two minus four
equals one
four plus two plus two this is the sum
minus the maximum four with this which
is the answer so what's the four exactly
let's look at the answer okay
yeah
okay so that will be
okay that will be for today yeah thank
you
bye bye