hello mr miss narayan okay so today we
want to talk about how to check if a
graph this is given uh this kind of data
structure to represent the
graph likes and we want to find out if
this is actually tree detection
algorithm okay this index means zero
one
two
three okay so we have
we have four notes neighbors zero one
two three
so look zero the left over zero is one
okay
one the left the right of zero is two
okay the left of one is when is minus
one it means that it's
it doesn't have a the kid the kid is
known okay so we skip
one doesn't have the left three
right right uh one of the ones right is
none right
two
the left of the two is three
the right of the two is nothing okay and
then four
here the left of three is nothing the
right and right of three is nothing so
it's at least a tree
given this okay
yeah
yeah look the left of zero
is one
the right of zero is two the left of one
is minus one which means nothing the
right or minus one is not minus one is
nothing
uh the of one okay is not minus one the
left of the
the left of two
is three the right of two is nothing
minus one okay and a three the left of
three is nothing but right of three is
nothing so this is this
trick is this a tree
very obviously is it
this is not a trick question is this
about a tree
yeah
maybe what do you mean maybe
[Music]
you're quite picky okay so tell about
this
because one of them looks very circle
okay so don't worry about the notation
it's just you don't want to there's
three four notes connected by this way
this is the final trick it's a it's a
tree it's a binary look left or right
okay
so
in order to
to be a tree what kind of thing we are
looking for
in order to be a tree everywhere anybody
[Music]
in one piece yeah you can't have like
another one here that's not a tree okay
these are
cycles foreign down so so we can't have
any energy we can't do this right this
is not a three this is one okay anything
is
one root
one root okay so it's kind of like if
you have two roots it means that
and you know
if it means not connected so it's kind
of here okay if i put it here right it's
one thing whether anymore no
[Music]
i think okay so we're talking about this
undirected graph yeah under the ground
uh
it needs to be
clean
and actually actually it has directions
from parents to the kids
so yeah so how do we do this yeah so
first of all you mentioned about the
root so the idea is that we need to find
the rule first right so if we find the
root
if we find the root then we can do this
breakfast starts your diagnosis right
what's the perfect search of these these
three anyone this is easy question
what's the difference zero one two three
okay what's the
what do i say
zero one two three zero one two three
okay uh
the preference search level by level
therefore search you go down
as deep as you can and if not no
breakfast
do you use food okay we are given this
formula how do we find the root
possibly
so we need to count the one one thing
what is this
the number of what kind of egg is coming
what what is it called
in degree where down in degree in degree
so this is the number of this is the
edges that going in so if we go through
these then we find that in degree first
of all we go final in degree equals one
equals zero then that's a number yeah if
we find that uh if we find
there are two roots or zero roots
what does it mean it means that we can
just return right because it in order to
be a graph to be a tree it needs to be
exactly having one one it needs to be
exactly one node that doesn't have any
in degree uh it doesn't have any uh edge
coming in okay and now we can do this
break for such stafford search and we
can can find out the number of nodes the
number of nodes visited is exactly
i know okay
we find
three different detections
[Music]
we have this left and right okay
so we are given this difference right
first of all we need to get this n n is
the number of nodes right lens left on
that right
it should be the same yeah the both
arrays will have the same size okay and
then
we have we can count the number of
in-degree edges so let's do it in uh
in the data okay in the data data
before this is the integrator before
dictionary
default dictionary in
okay and then we go through for i
in range
and right
so look if
if the left eye
not equal minus one right there's no
point to count the integral of nothing
right if left i not equals one then
theta alright right
left
i
plus equal one okay
okay third one
is right you're man
what am i writing here if right i not
equals minus one your writing if right
eye
okay and right
i mind eric can you tell me what i'm
doing here from this line here to here
guess what does it mean plus equal one
we are counting what
i know theta is addition so we are we
are iterating over the
nodes and then
because left i is the lesson trial of
the node i and now we we increment this
by one what does it mean the number of
in degree yes we are look we are we are
updating the in degree weather okay in
degree here so now we want to find out
the rule there's a root
root that would be equal i for
i
in range and
if is what so we are going we we have
this note from 0 to n minus 1 but we
want to check if
if the data
data i
in degree equals 0 right look here right
this is the loop right at least
maybe empty
or you may have more we may have more
than one root right look this is the
least yeah for i in range i if theta i
theta i is the indegree of i equals zero
right
right yeah what does this equal zero
mean
delta i equals zero anybody
come on i will just say beta i equals
zero
[Music]
the in degree is nothing it's nothing so
there's no edge going in so that's a
loop okay so look if if the length of
the root
is not equal one then we need to return
what
if the root if if we find more than one
root or if we find no root
right if we find no root what does it
mean there's a cycle right 0 1 2
something like that
there's no note each node has
has some in degree right yeah so
if it's zero it means this kind of
situation if it's more than one it means
what something like that right
right even more than one so
so these two are not trees so what
should we return
nothing false okay
okay yeah so now we know to find the
rule
that zero will be the root yeah then we
do this breakfast search here or another
way we can do this we can turn this
we can turn the root they say this
[Music]
iterator boot
and then we do this next then you give
us the loop this is basically the same
thing okay
we turning this the list into iterator
and we put it to the next this is the
syntax of
you know sensing syntax
but as long as we know it's only one
element here so then we can do this
loser okay then we do this preference
search okay question search what kind of
data social can we use to implement
buffer sensors right
i i think you know this question
question search
what kind of data structure can we use
to
kill yes and in python
wow good job okay q equals d e q u e
first of all we put the load in okay the
zero okay put a little zero
or you can do this again the same thing
and then we need to have this thing
equal step headshot
okay
now y q easy
current equals q dot problem
okay and then
[Music]
if okay if current in sin right we have
seen this before then we need to return
first right why is that because look if
we've seen we have seen this now before
that means lesser cycle and right so
that's why we seen it so we didn't talk
otherwise we need to put it in the same
table let's see in the headset it's a
notebook okay
a sim dot add carbon
okay then if
it was if left
left current not equals minus one and we
push this q dot append
up and
left parallel right then if right curve
and not equals one then q dot apparently
i don't have enough space but you know
what i'm talking about right
i okay that's just the question here
here is the breakfast search
bfs
here this is counting the in degree
updating the integration updating the in
degree
in degree
of the notes okay and then after if all
all are released then we need to return
return length of the scene we want to
find out the the note we have visited is
equals to the n right this is the
number of nodes we've given in the graph
right
everywhere come on
yes
any any questions so far any questions
no okay
okay so uh can you okay one last
question can you tell me how do we
how do we check uh
how do we check that no the node has
been visited or not how do we check
which line is the data structure we use
to
to check to put the nodes that we have
visited
come on it's very obvious here okay let
me see
and this is the set
stop
okay here look set set okay set
okay if it's exactly now
okay and if not we put it in a
in a headset
okay that's it for today bye bye
bye bye
okay that's it