go
hello mr mr rhino are you right here
so
yesterday we talked about this tree
detection agreement so we are given two
arrays left and right and representing
the left right and right side of the
node
from zero to n minus one okay they are
given the both arrays
have n elements representing the
the triad the triad okay the note it
connects to
if it's from the left direction or right
direction okay so we want to find out if
this data structure presenting here
presented by this kind of
lesson right
is a
tree okay so it's a graph but we want to
find out if it's a tree so
in order to find out if it's a tree
there are a few things we need to check
anybody are we right so how do we find
out if it's a trick you need to find
if it's connected connected we're done
okay so if
no cycle okay because connecting means
one single component so uh and no cycle
obviously we don't want to something
like this yes and that's all i remember
yeah that's pretty good okay so connect
it
so if it's connected there must be okay
one node which has zero
in degree okay zero in degree means that
there's no edge coming in okay there's
no edge coming in then that must be the
root so because the tree has the root
there three is the dag what's the ag
anybody
dig
directive a cyclic graph okay it means
it has direction from parents for kids
it doesn't have cycle it's a graph okay
it's a graph
and
to find out to find out is we we need to
find out the loot first the root is the
one only the only node which does not
have any in degree so
so we use this data degeneracy to store
to store the integrity for each node
right so then we updated the indegree
here after in degree after integration
from the left and right okay if right is
not the right the right node or the left
node of the node i is not empty it's not
empty right so then we update the node
this is the so so look this is the node
i yeah look i and here that will be the
right right eye yeah that will be left
eye
so
left eye has one more in degree from i
right right i for x one more individual
i
okay and then the root
this one so we want to find out how many
notes have this in degree zero so if
it's not equal to one then it must be a
tree right because for the tree we can
only have one in degree is zero
every nodes have in degree more than
zero okay this one we have two nodes
two nodes
in degree
zero
and we only want to make sure that that
there's only one node which has in
degrees here okay
once we have this root root zero
blue zero
then we do this uh questions we start
with the root right we start with rule
and we do this preference search left
level by level and we want to find out
that all the notes have been should be
visited exactly once
it has no cycles right because if you
have cycles it will be something like
this then that would be not uh
that would be not a trick right
so we use that preference we use the
double indications
number two they have no numbers okay
yeah
okay so this is the preferred structure
okay so then we're using this uh let's
do use the type of search here
how do we use your name
how do we usually implement that
yeah that was yesterday
using double nbq removal and the cube
processor and then this
which part of code here is is
to check if you have a cycle here the
preferences which part i'm calling it
checking the second
come on come on
you know this
with the scene you've seen if the note
has been seen it before yeah so it has
cycles so this one yeah because if we if
we have seen this no before then it must
appear before name it means that we have
cyprus okay for the test massage you
will use the recursion right remember
recursion yes so let's do this define
preference search with the root here
okay so now if
we still need a sin okay if the loop
in sin that would return force yeah
if we've seen this note before yeah so
now what do we do
now we have to check it a lot less they
have left to loose
left to root do not equals minus one
right
if let's not know not equals one and
then we need to check if
we're calling that itself if not
therefore search uh let's
[Music]
do it
now we do ten fours okay
okay and then if also we travel
right tree yeah right loot if we have
the right route
and then
if we have a right or then we travel in
there if not therefore such but if
if it has cycles or in the left tree
right on the right tree
right
root
ryan
and then we return four right then
fourth
otherwise will return true right
okay so then at the end we can call this
return
this is outside and return that first
search
lose yellow because we have only one
root and we also need to check if all
the visited uh all the nodes visited all
right so length of the scene
is equal or equal and okay that will be
the differences
what you doing
yeah okay let me let me explain this
again okay
this
is
taking a parameter which is the root if
a loop has been visited it means we have
side of return force right yeah
okay listen this is the keyboard okay
if the left root not equal minus
meaning the loot that that we have the
left tree right i have that note and
then we need to travel therefore search
here here because you know we need to
travel but if this function return false
somehow then it means we have cycles now
we determine false and the same trapping
the
right route return first otherwise if we
can travel successfully travel the left
tree and right three then we depend too
okay and at the end we call it
differences blue zero right we of blue
zero because new zealand
a single single node and we need to
check if the length of the scene is the
same is same as n because there are n
nodes and nodes and we want to find out
if we we have seen a node exactly right
why is that if we don't see the endnote
what happened
if we don't see that notes
if we if we don't see a nose it could be
somewhere uh something like that right
so you'll be not dis connected right so
from here this is the loop here
right i know whichever here
yeah okay
make sense when it says
actually it's not connected it could be
something like this one pointing to left
right instead of pointing this so
because because loot
because why why is that because we have
already checked if it's disconnected
here right so it must be connected it
must be connected if it's disconnected
it will be returning force here so it
could be some graph like this this is
not a tree why is that because this is
the directive so this node could be
pointing to here yeah coming to here so
you travel here you travel this is the
root you travel here but from here you
can do like this the direction is
not the same right so it means that it
means that this part of note has not
been visited so this is uh not a tree
that makes sense
yeah
okay in one sentence what have you
learned today
yeah what did we do
yesterday what's the difference between
this search and breakfast search
they have different names different yes
and what
come on if this is the thing
chooses one i use cube okay one two
three four okay so can you tell me
uh
one two three four five six seven okay
what's the test search order
if it's uh
if we go to the left first
what's the what's the preference search
for this one
come on anybody
one two three four five six seven and
what's the tesla search if we go to the
left first
one
six seven okay
okay exactly okay that's it for today
bye
bye bye
you