you go hello mr harry mr ryan are you
right
yeah okay okay so we have talked about
the tree detection
that left for three days okay
for two days actually we talked about uh
different structure we talked about uh
search so basically we're given this a
graph and left and right uh representing
the left child and right side of the
note i right no i i from zero to n minus
one and we want to find out if this
given graph is a it's a tree right it's
a tree it's basically financing because
there's only left and right left right
away okay
so
in order for god to be a tree so what
makes a
what makes it a tree
it's not true so what makes is a tree so
what are we looking for connecting yes
no cycles no cycle connected yeah so we
want to find out the root the root is
that no acceptable yeah
is the only node that has a
zero in degree okay has a zero in degree
okay so if we have more than
do one node that has uh zero in degree
then that is not connected right so it
could be something like these right this
is we have two notes look at my mini
phone okay okay we have two notes
look at this one is the three it's a
piece of three
no yeah why is that it's not connected
is this uh
no
numbers and it has a cycle okay you have
cycles okay don't worry about the
numbers okay
okay and how about this this is a tricky
one how about this one how about this
one how about this one is this a note i
one two three nine why is that yes
because it has two groups
uh well done yes two roots it
yes
yeah it's connected but it has two roots
but this one is a special it's a case
that it shows that one pair one note has
two pairs but in a tree in a tree what
do we have how many how many parent
maximum parents can send a note have in
the final three two
the parent the parent no kids one yes
what is that
okay
okay come on come on come on
okay so now
[Applause]
okay um that's it okay so we talked
about the default third yeah i'm
question
area
here this is constantly in degree right
right with counting the integra
integration
even it has more than one degree so what
happened if you have no one has more
than one name degree
then it's not a root right obviously and
now we are not we are finding the root
and then we do this by factoring we want
to make sure that each node from each
node can be visited exactly one from the
root okay and then at the end we check
that the node visited is the executive
end node right now okay
so
so today we talked about uh we want to
talk about the same uh
some problem
we want to find out we want to use
another algorithm which is called the
strong set yeah
[Music]
too much
oh my god this is
okay
so
how do we apply this to join set and
unify remember this joins that we have
these uh at the beginning we have
angular n groups and then we can have a
function to operation to union so we can
union two into one group or union
another three into one and then at the
end at the end if we if it's a tree how
many groups do we have if we look at the
beginning we have notes about you know a
tree for three if you say it's connected
how
[Music]
to solve this problem but okay so let's
let's do this union fire again okay this
screw is set okay let's see let's say
too much too much errors right too much
too much so destroy that i just need a
better
pen okay
okay so first of all this shows that
let's say class disjoins that these s
okay ds object
so define
in it
graph
oh it means that we have n
at the beginning we initialize as angle
okay so let's say
angle so how to do that
dot plr sends your parent their parent
equals at the beginning you'll be angry
will be so at the beginning you'll be
initialized to uh from zero minus one so
we can turn these and these
kind of range range and range n
is that range range n is a iterator that
will give us that from zero to a minus
one converted to a list that fits
perfectly with this uh purpose okay and
then select parent okay so
we want to have a find
find
find one find x we want to find the
parent of x okay we find we know the
kind of parentheses remember if
it's not apparent x so look uh
if
the pair
x not equal x yeah if it's equal to x
and it's in the group and then we what
what do we do then we can reset
the pair
x equals 75
self defined because you'll be calling
it yourself to find the center pair x
okay i'm going to put it
here okay
and then
so what does it mean okay so look this
is to compress the compressor
compress the
uh the path okay compress the task step
the parent if the second pair uh parent
x is not equal x if this is not a
problem we need to keep finding its
parent okay keep fighting is current
okay this is the fight and then how
about uh
define union
yeah union union union will put merge
two groups together
so this is a little bit more work to do
here okay i'm gonna write it here
come on guys sit down please
so first of all the parent group is of x
equals cell
so
the 5 yeah we use this 5 function
x and then py equals 7.5
okay so look
we want to merge x and y but if they
belong to the same group we don't need
to do anything right right if they
already belong to the same rule like if
px equals ti right
if vx equals p1 return okay
okay for now i'm just going to merge
from uh for uh
for uh for x to y or for y to x it
doesn't matter okay so then let's do
this third top
pair
p x
equal p y okay
so once we have merged it so we have one
more less component right and the
beginning okay
at the beginning we have angle
and if we merge two groups how many
groups left
how many good left
come on very easy question i have n
group and then i have merged two two
notes how many groups are there
okay so
so
at the beginning we can put another one
set of size
equals and angle right and then we are
merging one so
dot size minus equals one right yeah
right so the thing here is that
remember the the disjoint set
there are two group okay here
so you tell me which group must do it's
better here look
[Music]
okay everyone look
guess we'll talk about it i have a group
bigger group i have a smaller group so
is it better to move to attach the
bigger gluteus molecule of from the
smaller to bigger two which one you
think is better bigger grip teaspoon
smaller go to bigger book right that's
better why is that because you have
you only because they are
yeah if you attach small to
here and then the total part will be
more but if you attach less to
the total path will be less
right so something like that right so so
in order to do that we're going to do
this self dot side sizes okay
at the beginning one times n right
and learned
i realized
too much noise okay
union indian union so in here
i'm going to check right if
i'm going to check i'm going to check
what i'm going to check here if if the
size is if the size is several sizes p x
d x if it's smaller than p y along with
i i swap p x and p y so
the thing is i want to append the group
with less to the right to the bigger one
so if if the site if after swap the px
is bigger right if it's bigger then i
can say i want to move the py attach ui
to px then i can say save the size is
so size is p x
plus
equal
seven the size p y right and then i can
and i can
set the parent p y equal to p x
right okay so this is one other thing
okay so we see this is the disjoint set
we have talked about a long time ago
right this is the one of the data
structure that is useful
to
to do this kind of thing
we what kind of thing so you can merge
it's a graph data structure you can
merge different components and then at
least and us we can check how many
components how many how many groups left
okay so we can have at least another
property
at property properties define count
and allow cells we can save the
cells uh
which which parameter is itself the
sizes okay set the size return sample
sizes
[Music]
okay so now i'm going to i'm going to
write the
main thing okay which is to
i'm going to write the main thing
this is the white for the babies it's
not very good for
wiping the white board
easier white gold water
okay so so the thing is the thing is how
do we apply this disjoint set unified
into into solving this program to find
out if a
graph is a tree so so uh basically it's
it's actually
a lot easier
so normally we don't have to implement
the disturbance letter you can just uh
import it or maybe i mean we don't have
to really have to reinvent the wheel
every time
so define
this is tree detection okay this comes
the magic it's actually very simple with
that disturbance
the left
the right right
so like okay ts equals
n equals length of the left
this is
also length of the right
is the number of notes
of the graph or binary tree okay ds
equals df
n
okay
then right oh
i i'm going to iterate
i'm going to iterate i the note i in
range
and right so let's say if left eye
not equals minus one right if it's if it
so if that
if the node i
has the left node right look this is i
alright
look this is i if i have a decimal which
is left eye right
here
then what do we do if we have a h coming
from i to left eye what do we need to do
we need to do is the distance set to
merge it
yeah so look if there's an a
what does it mean
these two belongs to the same group
right
so what do we do look d s dot new union
okay now we have to do this t e f c s
union
not u
not union
i left i
then we return force right we can first
okay so i think we forgot about how when
in what cases we need to return unions
uh union remember the ds unions if it's
the same group then we return first
right if it is if if t x
equal equal py that will be turned forth
right return false
otherwise do the margin return true
right so if you if this know if these
two notes already belongs to the same
group then we'll return first
everyone makes sense why is that look
there might be another edge coming
later coming back then this will return
first right so that's what i mean and
the same thing here
uh
if right
if right i
not equal minus one and if not
d s dot union
i right i yeah we want to merge them
the note with the left tree and right
three return fourth
okay so like look there's a there's a
right eye okay i'm running out of this
ink this one
right so here
okay so this is all
okay for most okay but it's a special
case this does not attack
three points to two if
uh it does not violate this uh
uh this condition look we just merge it
we just merge it right so it's the
central it doesn't matter how do we
check this
how do we check this is not allowed
right because look these two have two
parents
so we can use the individual if
number two parent yeah my mommy and my
daddy okay okay
but in binary in in data science in data
structure
no can only have one parent okay
so this is the band this is a tree
this is a tree
okay so
this is a tree a nose can only have one
parent right
yeah the nose can only have one parent
if an i don't know comes in
another comes in this is invalid this is
not a tree right it's a graph actually
uh so we want to find we want to find
out this this kind of thing so we use
the in degree
yeah in degree in degree let's say in i
and d
equals default dictionary int right so
we just do this here
so left okay so if left i know equals
one and theta the in degree
in degree left i plus equal one
then we have to check if this is bigger
than one will return false
and at the end if all these test paths
now will return true okay
yeah
so to sum up to sum up how do we check
if this is uh uh how do we check if this
is a tree okay let's just forget about
coding let's just walk through the
example a few examples okay and then we
find out
uh
okay not return true actually it needs
to return the size needs to be one yeah
because
only one component right yeah look
okay
uh
one
two
three four okay this is not true yeah
look it's disconnected
yeah how do we use this the ts
at the beginning
one to two yes so one and two merge to
one one
three and four
merge to one
how many
how many how many uh size when the ds
dot the size they will return two
because there are two groups right
everywhere look
it's not equal one they return four how
about this one
one
two
three
four okay essentially there's a cycle
look one two three yeah so one to two
so i have one two three here there we go
one to two
so these two
same group
two and three
okay i include one more one yeah look
three and one look three and one already
in one group so we do ten four right
here
and how about this these cases one
two
three
okay look
here this one yeah the last example yeah
this is one this one
this one
one two three
one two two
three two it's okay but but it violates
the
in degree because in degree two has more
than one right it means he has two point
parents that's not right
okay so the second one yeah so basically
this disjoint set
can this join set has to
find out if laser cycle is very good
helps to find out if it's disjoint
if it is connected because with at the
end we will find out if t is the size if
it equals one
but for the least cases
we need to use the in degree right a
parent a
note a no in a tree cannot have more
than one parent okay
a note in a tree
there's a no in a tree that does not
have any parent why is it
where are you listening where them to
jump how many kids i mean the kids the
the note the witch does not have organic
kids what do we call them
exactly okay yeah
for today bye
bye bye
[Music]