up hello hello mr mr rhino all right i
go quick okay so anybody can tell me
what is a binary search tree
finally finally starts gp partnership
it's a pirate tree right yeah but buying
the research tree what is the final is
that's true eric wine
okay so
i'm going to write the two trees two
financially and you tell me which one is
behind the search tree okay
one wow look at this
orange and quick
um one three
okay anybody which one is the final
research tree
on the right on the right why is that
because binary tree
left is smaller than three and right and
bigger okay yeah exactly finally search
string both are binary trees but binary
search tree the last note should be
strictly smaller than the root the right
note should be strictly bigger than the
loose note and i have no duplicates in
uh
also if you do that through one three
three and in order it will be in order
we're done okay um that's what i'm
talking about yeah okay so this
and if is
do that in order
if we do this in order you become one
two three which is in order right that's
very well done okay come on
so today's task very easy we want to
convert a fine research tree two
to something like that
two to these one
two three so there's no left kid
the final three only like it
and the leftmost leftmost note
one which is the root yeah so basically
we want to convert these to these look
this at least looks like a linklist but
it's actually a binary tree it looks
like a banana binary tree which doesn't
have any left hit okay so any idea do
you do that
do you know how to do this come on
anybody
so we want to convert these to this eric
eric ryan come on we're
that's one way okay so we just yeah
basically we just do this in order
all right we do this in order yeah we
can save it in the list yeah or we can
use the iterator yeah yeah the keyword
yeah what's here what's this one i
forgot you forgot what's here
uh
it's the last word
yeah for example mommy give you both
five pounds each month but she's not
going to give you
five pound you know 60 pounds all
together in one go right right yeah she
will just give you
every month every month
so one
at the beginning of each month
every month yeah
will be going to eat at five pounds and
you're going to get it okay so this is
kind of yet okay so if we're not using
the iterator we're not using iterator
then everything is raised
apparently
okay
yes
praise repent ask so okay so let's do
this in order thing yeah define
in all the
um
annoying little boy
if not root we just return empty return
our empty list
yeah there are many ways of doing this
in order but let's pick a way which is
more straightforward another way is that
you have lisa lister here you have this
answer here and then you do this instead
of returning you you just return
and then you push
every time
we visit and now we push the to these
to this answer instead of returning a
new one so we can just return here
return
in order in order
to let yeah we are visiting the
tree first and then we want to visit the
current law which is know the value
yeah
concatenate the list this is the list
and this is the list yeah they do the
value is an integer we concatenate it
and then plus
in order that we visit the right tree
yeah rule right
okay
right so
if i if we put the answer the
empty this then we would
what do we need to change we just ignore
the root of that and answer the
appendage value and in order to write
that basically look recursion this is
recursion what's your recussion in one
one sentence
what is that it's calling it itself well
done it's calling itself yes and let's
determine the condition when the loop is
empty then we return nothing right yeah
calling itself okay okay let's
now we have this in order now we can do
this yeah we can do this answer equals
current equal we create a node which is
the dummy node yeah tell me which what
is
it's not really
useful we just have a placeholder for it
we have created the price of it then we
can say four
uh pie dummy
four okay so for c
in in order yeah we could we do this in
all the rooms
right now we can say what tyrant dot
next
current on right okay
current.right equals c right and i see
current equals current dot next
and then we can just do this uh return
answer
dot
right okay so basically this is what
error you propose we do this in order
and then we just go to we just do this
yeah one two three because once we have
we know that we have this one two three
yeah so we just iterate over the list
yeah and then we do this current
current.net white you know left right y
equals c yeah currently equals current
on right
okay so current equals counter double y
what what does it mean
current was current on the right
then current would be equal to z right
so which is here
and then the next iteration c will be
two right so x current will be two and
currently you could count the right
camera will be moving to two okay
yeah yeah
okay the thing the
exactly once the space complexity also
on yeah we're using this uh additional
list to and uh calling stack for
education to install this uh
uh to store in order okay so like yeah
if you want to do this here yeah i think
so in fact
we want to do this thing how can we do
it
i'm gonna do right here this this this
part will be the same yeah this part
will be set but we change this
so
we can just say if not loot return okay
we're not returning anything come on be
quiet
then we can we can we can do what we can
do
yet
from
in order
to left yeah we want to
right yeah
okay so basically it's quite similar to
this syntax yeah yeah from
yeah
right
it's returning the same thing this is
concrete
no no no returning this this is actually
written something concrete but what i'm
saying yes wrong earphones means that
okay i promise you
that i'm going to return something but
it's not time yet when you actually when
you're the when you actually need it
when c actually need it when we actually
iterate c
yeah then we
the year we actually return something
right so you get it so
okay so the generator the time
complexity and complexity so 01 okay so
uh what have you learned today so far
come on everyone anybody
bst yeah we were converting a binary
search tree into
a a final treat which only whoa
what what what do we call it it's a
banana tree which has only the right
triad
right left final reset yeah so so
basically the key thing today is that if
we are performing an inorder what's the
password if we are
performing like another traversal on a
binary search tree the least we get will
be in order right yeah let's see that's
it for today bye-bye bye bye