hello everybody hello ryan and today
i'm cleaning okay okay
oh i forgot get a chair please
bye bye folks forget all right
okay so today
so remember what is a calendar
with a spellback
[Music]
okay like the race car so today we
talked about
uh interesting problem which is
paddington permutation
permutation permutation
exactly different ways of
to organize the for example like uh
one two three different the permutation
will be
one three two right
and two one three two three one two
and three one two three two one so
basically different
possible sequence of using these three
one two three right one two three one
two left six right
remember how many how many permutations
if there are three
three characters that will be three
bacteria because the first
first place you can play three times
three possible yeah and then the second
you have two choice at the third you
have one choice three times two times
one
got it permutation yeah so
so given a string like
given i'm giving a string like a
a c c e r
okay this one can you tell me if you can
make a pairing drum using this camera
yeah you can yeah
yeah so how do you know it's possible
[Music]
so how can we know that if given a list
of the
uh given a list of the a string
using the characters only the characters
in the string
how can we know we can make a parameter
by any
sequence subsequent unfamiliar
permutation of these because
you can't do one of the beginning one at
the end without the odd number so this
one needs to go in the midwest
apparently yeah very close yeah
apparently
like look this one rey
ska you have one only one character
which is
in the middle right yeah or you can have
something like
a abba right
this there are two types of parents one
is this you have this
odd number or even or even the
odd number of characters which means the
middle middle one
is only the one which is unique right
not
you have even numbers but it's not
middle numbers yeah
this is two two possibilities so in both
cases
every characters every character needs
to appear
of even number of times except you can
have only one
one yeah only one which is odd number
right if i i do this for another one
okay
like palindrome and
o and o
b a can you make a parent using these
characters
no why why is that
because yeah
so how about one can you make it
uh yeah yeah because you can do this and
you can put it at least in the middle
right
yeah okay so okay so that's that's good
you get this okay so what's the a uh
let me let me just try this problem okay
look
defy hey
equals counter counter
and then we turn this s into a list
string
s right now y after this we have the
dictionary which you have different
numbers
different account right like that yeah
different account
different accounts okay then i just need
to do these four
um i i need another number
count or count okay odd count
equals zero right what we are interested
in
is in account if it's more than one it's
definitely
not possible so look for i
in d dot
keys remember d dot keys is the
e is least the characters yeah
characters in the string column
if d i
is this the pure number of times yes
yeah if it's odd we can do this modulus
too right
yes or modulus two equals one right we
can do this yes
remember an integer or remember the
binary yeah binary like three
three the binary is one zero
one one right this is three in binary
right
remember two in binary is one zero yeah
four in binaries is one zero zero right
one in binary is zero
one yeah so in finally
if the last digit is one then it's odd
number
right if it's zero it's even number
right
yeah so we can use this binary end the
same as this
so if t i modular two equals one is the
same as
if d i n one
and one means like to the end on the
last bit if it's one
then it's the old number then i want to
list odd
count plus equals one right
yes
bigger than one one what do we do here
return
two of us if it's more than if there's
more than one odd number what
four yes the next one must be true
yes and then what's your happen here
after this
all right what's the space complexity
yes because we're using this counter
yeah this is basically
uh if we are not using this counter
object
even how can we do this we can use
we can use what if we
if we are not using this counter we can
do this
we can do this
default dictionary yeah which is called
and the type is integer then we can do
this
for i in s right
i n x now i can just put b
string d i plus equals one right
yeah okay then after this
do this counting and then we do this the
same okay okay
when you check this this entire screen
will shake okay and people will not see
it
do you get it whoa yes
i was just telling you come on sit down
please
a bit tilted that's okay but but you
still can see
yeah is it clear it's a little bit
easier it's very clear yeah let me see
you see clear i think it's clear not
really
yeah it's clear yeah i guess so let me
see
let me see yeah it's clear okay
blurry okay
a little bit okay tier tip it's
beautiful let's do it yeah
that's better yeah it's not better yeah
it's better okay
so now let's do this corporation we have
pairing
drums now
we have a defined check function
what important
phone collections we import
counter we need a counter object d
equals counter object as this
as too close people will see it
for all curve equals zero for
i for what i in
b
and we have a key if if
d i i
n one equals one right
put a bracket maybe
and outcome plus equals one and if
account is if we find any any time if we
found anyone
any odd number of the character more
than one time
then it must not be uh uh
possible to construct a pending job from
this okay otherwise become true
let's let's check this queen
check like uh what's this
ncc
[Music]
yeah so if it goes where what was your
previous video
box choo choo first yes we're done wow
exactly yes once again okay you need
that
yeah okay so please
complexity time complexity
oh and time and
by the way this has the comments yes
yeah when you start with a hashtag it's
a comment it means that it's only do it
it's only for human yeah you can put
anything
in the after the first line okay it's
only for me
yeah so um
yeah this is the this is it any
questions
and if you actually we can we can
i was talking about um let's do it
without a
counter object check two okay
let's do this check two thing
check two things and then we have a
dictionary right
yeah and we have additional this is two
additional but we now we have to
in s right and every time if i
in d then we do this as uh
d i plus equals one as if it's not
in then we set it to one right and then
after this
you can copy from the uh form i in
d this is d dot keys this is the same
right if d i and one you can also do
this modular two
equals one it means that it's even on
bottom
and all the time
which one looks a bit weird
looks a bit weird it's a bit blurry
oh you need no people yeah wait wait
wait let me try let me check this if
it's uh
if it's all right oh come on
yeah let's try if it's all right
yeah it's the same look it's the same
yeah it's the same
so both both are fine if you're using
the dictionary you can do this in the
beginning but
in the line line six in a line
six is basically the same as from nine
sixteen to
twenty one okay line six this line
is basically the same as from 9 16 to 21
which is the you see numbers so this
version is much
simpler much easier to use we are just
importing this
counter object from the collection uh
package right
okay any questions
no okay good job today good job today
good job today yep yeah bye
bye bye bye bye bye both
okay bye bye let me