go hello mister and mr ryan all right
okay so we talked about the binary
search tree okay so final research tree
what's fine research tree in one
sentence please anybody finally said
tree
is funny tree we and but it also a
binary search tree is a binary
tree
finally search tree is a binary but it
also has to satisfy that the notes on
the left side should be strictly smaller
than the
flute okay and the node on the right
side should be strictly bigger than that
so this is the final search tree look
the loop
left smaller than the loop the line
bigger than the root
eric yeah
so
one thing about vanessa's trees it does
not contain duplicates so we cannot have
at least double two here you know
that that is not a brand new trick and
then also
also if i have at least minus one and
then this this note yeah
eight is this minus thirteen why is that
because eight is not smaller than two
exactly that's a p four yeah so every
note on the left should be smaller than
that right so this is bigger than that
but that has to be smaller than two okay
so i can put zero so why do we have
these because if we perform what kind of
order then you become in order
yeah don't you get it
so we want to do this binaries uh we
want to perform this in all the
traversal yeah in order if we perform
this in order to traverse huh
in order to have answer and then the
lead then we'll get the assorted list
yeah for example in order to have a lot
so it's visit the left tree first
we visit the left that tree therefore
search left i know which is the loot and
then we visit the
white tree right this is the student
code from that
in order traversal so look if we visit
the left tree
yeah first yeah and now we visit the
node
so we what do we get here is minus one
zero to three okay so it's in order
right ready okay so today's task we want
to find we will given this by psc we
want to find the k
smallest k smallest
number in the
bst
yeah we want to find out the case for
example this this given this another k
is in one index if
if it's uh
k equals one then the first one then is
which uh the
the smallest and the first smallest
number is minus one and when k equals
two
then you
we should get the zero right because
zero is the second smallest right okay
any idea any idea
another what do we what did we learn
yesterday we learned about turning this
into a greater tree yeah yeah zero
minus one
two three yeah
yeah
that's what we talked about yesterday
but today we want to find the katie's k
smallest
number in a binary search tree anybody
what's your thoughts
[Music]
the same thing yeah same thing yeah
exactly same thing perform this in order
right and then we we talked about the
year thing yeah what's the year i think
right
what's the year the iteration
yeah promise yeah exactly it's like that
i promise you i will return this but
that's not the time yet yeah when we get
it so why why do we need a iterator for
the year for in this case because the
three might be this big
the the total number of notes might be
armenian right but if you're asking me
like what's the 10th
smallest number do i have to traverse
all the tree
right do you get it
so look if if there are lots of notes
here if the total note is a minion
and all we want to know is the
the third smallest
third smallest
number in the final search tree so
if this is the case i don't need to
travel i i don't need to visit a minion
right because this final research street
give us the thought that we have
all we have to do is visit the third one
and that's it right so we we can use the
uh the year so so it it you'll be better
to use the iterator instead of
converting obviously if
if
um
if the note is more right the number of
notes is more like maybe a 100 right but
we can it's okay we probably can convert
everything convert this binary into a
list yeah into this into a list and now
we do this k thing okay i'm going to
write this okay
so i need the eraser
so i'm going to write uh
um
a few methods yeah so you and you tell
me which one is the best okay the most
naive way of doing this right so let's
say
define default search loot
okay
if not loot
if the root will return empty list yeah
empty this and then we can do this
return
dfs rule the left
this is from yesterday plus this is the
least concatenation rule the value
plus
dfs
rule.right
so this is the in order traversal
that returns a list then we can do this
ar equals that's what search
root and now we want to return the case
one so we just return
a r k k one the first one will be there
will be k minus one right k minus
something let's say sound is one the
first one is the index
you see
that's that's the most simple one right
so the disadvantages the pulse is very
simple to implement everything
right
the cons the disadvantage okay i'm going
to talk about this well the disadvantage
is what i was just saying that if the
number of nodes is to be a million nodes
and this method needs to visit all the
armenian nodes and come put it in the
list and then do this yeah return okay
yeah so this is not very convenient but
we can do we can improve it we can
improve it
with this one so how do we do this so
so instead we we are not written in the
list we are not returning this
therefore such root and now we have this
k here and we have this answer at the
beginning we set it to 9
right so if if the k is smaller than
zero we just written here
because we don't want to continue
visiting it now we want to visit the
left
left path down left
okay and then we here we k minus equals
one right we have visited one more note
if k equal equal to zero then answer we
set it answer answer equals two dot
value
and
return okay we written here
and now we can do this definitely don't
write uh loot alright okay
and then we do the stafford search root
and then we return the answer yeah you
see
this is a small improvement yeah all
right come on
i'm going to explain this one more time
yeah we won't we decrement this k when
we visit one note we decrement it and if
it's zero then it means that's the node
we are looking for
and we set the answer answer here right
okay so i'm going to write here a noun
loader just to use the variable
non-local answer
okay okay
and then look look we visited the left
tree
we visited the current node we visited
the right tree
do this type of such one sun yeah
so this is simple improvement yeah
because that allows us to skip
the rest if we if okay so pst with a
minion nodes and now
i just want you to find out the
first movie the smallest note yeah yeah
so you just find it right
and you don't need to find find the rest
a mini minus one note right once you
find the target do you need to continue
because you already have the answer why
would you visit all the rest yeah simple
as that
that's this part if k is smaller than
zero then we just return
yeah here
k minus equals one okay okay
okay so now i'm going to write this much
better one which is called the yield
yeah function yeah yeah iterator yeah if
we're using the yield to iterator to
write it then you'll be much simpler
okay define therefore search
root
look here
yet
okay so i'm going to still if not look
uh
ah okay probably here one one thing
missing is that uh if not loser we
should return okay if k smaller and zero
are not root not root we should return
okay
yeah here
if if not root
return
and then yeah
from
year from
dfs to the left okay
and then yield
load of value
what's the money and here what's next
can you can't tell me what okay
here from the left here
is value and here from
what right right exactly yeah
and now we can just do this if we have
this dfs dfs rule that returns the
iterator yeah it returns a iterator
so what do we do now so we just do this
we just do this here
return
we're using the next next function
next
i
for
next c okay for c i c in ic in
innumerable what's enumerate anybody uh
like
keys
i was i
is that index c is the value
d fs loser we want to return this is the
iterator i is the index if
i is equal k minus 1 right so we want to
find out k1
so obviously you can rewrite this using
the traditional if statement yeah for
see in enumerate dfs root yeah if i
equals k minus one then we tend c okay
but we are using a fancy syntax called
the next function right next function so
what's next function anybody remember
okay the next function is the
you know the returns the next
next value in the iterator yeah next
okay so look
range function is a generator okay so we
look a equals branch yeah we know the
range yeah when is 10
yeah
range 10 from 0 to
9 if we put an iterator here we convert
it to iterator yeah then that's the
iterator okay so next
next a what does it return
next a
uh
what's the first first value in the
range ten
one zero it starts from zero right okay
it's yellow okay and then like two is
another one next a what does it mean
one
two next
seven eight nine nine
okay okay
next a suppose next a now is nine okay
so next a what happened
no no no come on
you already it's only eight
look i'm the best come on yeah look at
this range function between zero to nine
but now we're writing out the number so
you would you throw the error you'll
have a mistake yeah you have an
exception however if i do this next
next a the second parameter is the
default value if two things go wrong if
i say minus one and it will tell me
minus one right do you get it do you get
it next
range 10 range is a generator i convert
it to iterator yeah convert the iterator
and then every time you ask for it
you'll give me the next one next one
next one
in in the iterator it's like a year
promise right the iterator range 10
means that okay i promise you i will
give you ten numbers from zero to nine
correct
okay last movie zero you asked me one
ask mommy okay you ask me nine and then
you ask me one more time but i'm running
out of numbers i promise already 10
numbers you asked me 10 times already
and you asked me one more time what what
do i do
i was screwing yeah i don't have more
numbers for you next there's promise
yeah
and then but if i give a second
parameter minus one yeah i can give up
everything i told eric to you
do you get it
do you understand
yeah
all right yeah the range from the start
with
[Music]
sss star stop
or
range stop okay there are three kinds of
you can call this range function in
three format star stop step stop does
not include a stop like 10 you give a 10
it does not reach the 10 right get it
sss yeah star stop if the star
is missing then it's default to zero if
the step missing is default to one right
step is one right okay make sense start
stop step f okay in one sentence what
have you learned so far today
one sentence what have you learned so
far yes
final sentence what are we doing i am
the best
what are you what are we doing with the
finances too what do we do
okay smallest
yeah we're using that different search
in order yeah why do we need to perform
it in order of the final search what do
we get if we perform in order uh
smallest to largest assorted okay yeah
that will be for today bye bye
bye