hello mr mr ryan all right
yeah okay so yesterday we talked about
the k smallest binary search tree okay
so finally search three the note yeah
that is finally tree where the left
notes are smaller than the root and the
right notes are bigger for example like
four five six okay
how do we traverse the final research
tree in order to get the saltiness eight
four five six yeah what what what all
that
you know that okay so
yesterday was small yeah so yesterday we
talked about these case models
three yeah so we're using this in order
of traversal in order to get
certificates and then we use we have we
talked about uh
year yeah we talked about the iterator
yeah thing yeah because look
the k could be very small the total
number could be very big and
in order to get the k smallest node we
don't need to actually visit all the
nodes here if just imagine that t could
be a meaning more than a minute it could
be very large right so yeah so we talked
about as uh
recursive in order i think
okay so today we're going to solve this
problem
yeah using another approach using
another approach so let's say okay so
just just
imagine yeah imagine this is a battle
research tree
yeah i have a note if that's the luther
no lord enough
and i have a left tree yeah obviously
ever left but i don't know what how many
are there yeah i don't know how many of
like i have the right tree here
and again i don't know how many of them
okay
look listen
if i'm telling you that okay if i'm
telling you that k
k minus one no here
so which no is the case one is not come
on if that k minus one note on the left
top load exactly why why is that because
because these the notes on the left
three are smaller than the root right
yeah so if i'm saying k minus knows on
the left tree so it means it makes the
loot and a case notice right makes sense
okay so now if i'm telling you there are
more than k minus one nodes on the left
what happened so look this is uh let's
say there are n nodes okay if n equal or
equal k minus 1 then the root is the
case smallest one right
look this is the case smallest one all
right but if i'm saying that they are
bigger or more than k notes what happens
if there are many many know more than k
notes on the left so where is the case
not going to be
where is the case not going to be if
there are more if n is more than k if
there are more than k notes on the left
street where is the case not going to be
come on
exactly you'll be on the loot on length
yeah somewhere
somewhere on the root of left but we
have to we find it out right okay
how about n smaller than k this is the
tricky part
right look this is a tricky part if
there are n nodes which if they are less
than k notes on the left
on the right yeah but
we
exactly it's on the right but
if we keep fighting on the right so
look all right
look
this is the tricky part okay so look
loose on right it's not on the right so
look at that one note this one note the
root n note on the left right so so k
minus k is bigger k is bigger than n so
k minus 1 minus n there will be a note
on the right right so what does it mean
look
look if k is bigger than n right and we
are finding the k smallest no right but
it's only on the right tree right yeah
am i right on the right tree so look
i have to minus one note because i know
there's one note smaller than
something okay and there are n notes
here right there unknowns here so
so the note should be k minus one minus
n regarding root or right do you make
does it make sense all right
okay now let me repeat this again okay
come on
this is interesting
i'm get i'm finding n notes i'm going to
do the left
little left that do the left has a note
okay
if
n equals k minus 1
great that makes the rule the case
smallest
do to understand this part
okay if n is more than k or equal to
if there are more than k or equal than k
notes on the root of that tree
so where is it where is the node going
to be where is the case knowledge is not
going to be
yeah it will be somewhere here and then
we can because it covers it
because
yeah but the second parameter is which
no you if you will be still on case no
yeah the case number will be still on
the left right yeah
okay now the tricky part is on the right
right
so if they are
if the k no if k is bigger than n if k n
is smaller than k k is bigger than n
right so
obviously it's on the right tree but
which no i mean where is what's this
case now going to be
which no on the right tree we have to
substitute a substrate one node here and
unknown right make sense
it doesn't make sense
okay
look if if there are five notes here one
knows here and then if we want to find a
tenth note right if i'm gonna if we are
to find the 10 k k was
k equals 10 and there are finals here
one note here
right so that rule the right three
the note would be ten minus one minus uh
ten minus one minus five right yeah
because we already found five plus one
nodes which are smaller
which which are smaller which is longer
which is not the node we are looking for
right
all right so using this we can just do
this recursion we can just do this
recursion
and then first of all we need to
have this code function to count the
number of nodes in the subtree so well
we can do it many ways can you give me
an example how do we how do we find the
number of nodes in the given binary
we talk about this yeah we can use
what kind of search
step search preferences exactly okay
let's do it each step or something yeah
define that search root
if not loose
otherwise will return the first third
root of left
plus one plus definitions google wire
can even using the lambda function and
lambda pfs equals lambda
lambda
uh
root
and dfs lu dot left plus df plus one
plus dfs root or y if root
and
air okay this is the differences and how
about the question reference search is
also very easy to implement we just what
kind of data structure we need to use in
order to do the processes
if not loot
returns zero
otherwise we have a qdq
root of left
and then y i q
uh i have to put it in n n equals zero n
plus one we have one more load yeah a
equals q to the power of left
if a is the left we push it back to the
q q that append
q a left
if a dot right
q dot appearance alright yeah and then
we return the i'm right we can and this
is the
breakfast search okay and then coming
back to these coming back to the
location function to find the case model
okay
uh define case okay good
n equals let's use the different search
rule dotnet we're counting the root left
tree okay now look
uh here okay the second parameter
if n equal equal k minus one we can what
in turn one
if n equals k minus 1 only someone
there's no answer
if n equals root yeah
okay okay if n is bigger than or equal k
return what is only that tree right
so k according to the cursing
blue dot left
and then the second pin was still k okay
and otherwise return
case what should i do with the list
if it's uh nowhere is that where is the
case not going to be k is bigger than k
you know on the left tree otherwise it's
on uh right right all right
and which you know is it
that value we talked about
what you always know is that k minus one
minus n right yeah i know the question
yeah
yeah what have you learned today what's
the time complexity for this one
the
uh the in order that the method time
conductor is all n right if you go if
we're going to visit all the nodes but
if we're using the iterator yeah we stop
searching if we stop searching after
finding the case now then the time
connection is okay
sometimes you pass the height edge okay
because that that's going to be
the height here the height of the tree
for this method yeah the the worst case
scenario okay if you don't understand if
you don't understand the time complexity
of this one let's look at these some
very extreme cases look one
two look at this three
four
two two here okay okay i'm going to find
out the case mode it's not which one now
is it which you know is it
that's the first one is though which is
the k
which one is the case smallest yeah so
for each one i'm going to call this the
question
yeah but look at each chord there will
be a differences chord so the time
convexity will be o
n times n this is o n right and then o n
times k okay k smallest okay can case
noise
makes sense
yeah so the time number is
and in the worst cases right right
because k is smaller
because k is smaller or equal than n so
[Music]
okay that's it for today bye bye bye
bye bye
bye
you