yo
hello mr mr ryan are you right
okay so let's talk about this the
longest increasing path okay we're given
this map of integer matrix and
we want to find out the longest strictly
strictly increasing strictly increasing
pass in metric so a path we can follow
the numbers horizontally or vertically
yeah there are two directions actually
there are four directions we can go up
down left right so
can you tell me that which
which one is the longest pass in in this
case everyone zero one three five six
nine okay
zero one three five six nine okay
anymore
yeah
zero
[Music]
okay so both the those are the longest
equally longest strictly increasing type
has six numbers yet okay
so this is the problem uh when we are
solving this today so any idea any idea
i mean you can say profess if you won't
yeah
how do we do first okay so my next
question how do we perform ryan
we check every single one
we check every single one we check every
single picture okay
so let's define it might take a long
time yeah let's define frc
is the representing the longest
longest path starting
starting at pixar rc the coordinate okay
so this actually returns an integer
telling the length the length of the the
length the length of the longest yeah
that's the longest
so then
then we can go through these possible
starting position and we
and calculate the maximum of it right
answer at the beginning so what's the
minimum what's the minimum length of the
longest path what's the minimum
[Music]
one exactly yeah yeah exactly each
number is each you can start with any
position and that gives us the longest
path
you know at least one right so answer
equals one and then four
r in rows with rows is the number of
rows in the metric
four c in current
the columns how many columns right so
answer equals maximum of answer does it
have to be three by three
no rows and columns then this is just a
very simple example okay
very good question okay by the way i
thought it was next answer
frc and then return answer yeah so the
the key thing here is
this an f something right something f
function so we start with this pixel and
we want to find out the num the long the
length of the longest path starting at
this position right
so
so this is it uh
so how we implement this rc function so
if we can
if we need to find out that we need to
find out if the neighboring pixel full
direction if it is strictly bigger than
the current pixel
right
then we can work right so so for example
look
okay so here look if frc is here look
it's f4 right and i'm realizing that 6
is bigger than 4
so f
this is what 0 1 0 1 f 1 1
will be equal to what mac 1 plus
1 plus f
if this is what coordinate will be there
that would be one two right right you
see
that
i'm right
because if i starting at this position i
can add one more pixel and the maxi one
plus you get it yeah
yeah yeah okay so do you
so so we we can just walk check four
direction and to to implement this to
increment this one
yeah if less restricted
if the next neighboring the four
direction the pixel number four
direction is bigger
it's bigger one of them is bigger than
we can just extend it one more bit okay
and then
obviously we need to
do one more thing one more magical
keyword to make it
efficient cash if exactly why is that if
we don't don't do that cash what will
happen everywhere
exponential how look if we starting from
this point yeah yeah
i know we somehow
somehow we need to calculate that
function from this point after the
function from this point f function from
this one
yeah and then we come back to these
functions and this pixel again and we
need to call this function again so but
we are obviously we have calculated this
pixel before
then we don't need to calculate again so
that that's the beauty of bringing in
the cash right yeah
i answer equals one right
so for the four directions yeah dr
minus one zero zero minus one yeah
that's the
that's the offset in the fourth
direction all right then what uh the
current
let's
define this f function uh c right and
then we put a cache here okay i'm going
to
i'm going to
mark it as
red so this is very important because if
we don't put this cash
this solution will be invisible it means
that impractical to to uh to solve in a
few
in a short amount of time right
okay so cash answer and then look
new new row equals r plus dr
news this column equals c plus dc then
we need to check if the is still in the
metric it's zero
bigger smaller than nr smaller than rows
rows is the number of columns number of
zeros yes and then
zero smaller equal nc is more than
columns if it's in with responsory
and also the metric
look matrix rc
is strictly smaller than metric
n r and c right this is the new
neighboring pixel and i see then one
plus
f
and r
and c return answer so what about this
cache yeah frc is the
last is the representing the length of
the longest path longest increasing
strictly increasing power starting with
this position rc
yeah the minimum is one if if the
neighbors if the neighbors are all
smaller or easier than the current pixel
then you'll be one right
drdc can you explain to me what it is
what's this for four vectors four
coordinates look what's this one zero
zero one minus one zero zero minus one
what's this representing
the four directions
this is one is
one zero one zero means down
zero one means right
minus one zero means left and what's
zero minus one
yeah zero minus one is up okay at least
it's the new coordinate and now you have
to check if it's in the boundary yeah
because it doesn't make sense if the the
new coordinate is beyond the boundary
right and then we have to check this
what's this what does this mean
yeah if metric rc is smaller than metric
n r and c
when do you understand this metric rc if
it's smaller than metric and not in c i
metric rc what's a 9 and c
what are we doing with these the four
directions
and r and c was
yeah and nic is the next cell okay so
metric rc is smaller than metric ni and
see what does it mean can you tell me
what's this represent me
uh so so if
so if
um
[Music]
yeah we can go to it we're done look we
can go to it how can we do it we can go
to it we one more yeah because if we put
one more which is the current pixel
right it makes the longest
pass one more number right and that's
the
that's the f and rnc is the longest part
starting with the next one next one
right
yeah and then if we put the current
pixel that will become one more right
you get it
yeah
so if we put the cash
then that means if if we put a cash then
it means what if it means that we the
maximum stay number of state we're
calculating is r times c
okay this is the number of states we
these are calculating then we iterate
over each pixel and we try to calculate
the length length of longest path
starting with legs what's the tango next
so
maybe not for r in
row yeah
for c in columns
and answer and the outside answer equals
one answer equals max
answer
f r c y and rc
here right so this is o r times c but
for each one we we can we calculate only
once
right so
so if the time connection is oh i see
okay oh i see
let's call talk down that let me program
here
yeah we need if we don't put a cache
that'll be exponential because for each
know maybe
maybe duplicate the
you know values we need to calculate
again again okay that's it for today bye