yeah yeah okay so let's say we have a
container container
like a container water container yeah
a vertical lines once again we have a
few vertical parts what color yes so
vertical lines
like that
so our task is to pick two
and with these two
chosen vertical bars
and we want to find out we want to
maximize the water like the container
can hold okay so for example if i pick
this one and this one
right so look let's just look at these
two lines yeah so if i pour you know pop
p-o-u-i how do you pronounce this one
par-4 yeah it means you don't have much
money no no no not poor p-o-u-i means
that you pour it in yeah pour the water
in yeah
yeah pour the water in and then
you would be determined by the lower bar
right because the
the more
you put the water in moving it and then
you will always get it towards the other
the other one will make it worse yep
yeah it makes sense yeah and you are not
allowed to slang the slang slang the
the container yes
so you put the water in and the volume
is determined by the lower back it
doesn't make sense yeah okay so
so okay another thing is these what
these wording paths are separate equally
so we can think of it as system one okay
so we have given this h away
actually which is the represent the
height
represent the height of each bar and we
want to maximize we also maximize the
water by choosing two any two
i need two vertical paths okay
yeah so how do we solve this problem you
know one easy way would be to do what
if look there are n bars and we want to
find out two bars so what we can what
actually can we use
yes that's a very uh obvious thing right
i'm saying that empath and pass and i'm
going to find out which two right so so
basically i'm saying is that there are
anything i want to pick two
so the how many ways is c
n two
means picking two out of n
okay so
three apples picking two apples out of
three how many ways
how many ways
uh
okay three efforts picking one up how
many ways three yeah exactly so
basically it's the same right picking
picking
x out of n is equal picking
picking x items out of n is the same is
picking n minus x out of n right because
because what is mean because look there
are n items yeah if i pick x items and
this is the same thing as
picking a minus x items right when we
pick one apple
we also get the way of picking two
vectors and vice versa okay
okay okay come on cn2
cn2 equals n times n minus 1 divided by
two yeah we learned about that in a
combination right so look obviously look
this is n square
i'm right
yeah yeah okay so now we can prove us
let's prove us yeah blue first is very
useful yeah
but you know what's the time complexity
yeah yeah i'm just writing here
look at all in square n times n here
yeah one square so let's do first
answer at the beginning we hold no water
which is zero and equals length height
h is the height for each vertical bar
and then four
the left right the left the bar
the index of the left one
in range and
okay four
right back in range okay so can you give
me the parameters for the right bar
the way that come on anybody
right bar start with one
the air bar is from zero to n and y bar
is
is what from the
what's the first parameter
what look if i have a determinant
we want to maximize the answer of what
come on can you tell me this
this is very easy yeah okay
okay bye anybody so if i have an air and
r okay so if this is air
this is air
this is r okay
so what's what's the volume what's the
volume of if this is air this is the
height here is h air the height of this
one is hr so what's that what's the
volume of this what's the volume you
know the volume is the rectangle yeah
what's this bit how much is this
yeah but you don't know which one is
bigger yeah so we picked that one
yeah i know i'm just giving you an
example of a computer this is the value
sr so you are basically saying this is
mean
of h air
h r right
yeah okay so this is this times what
what's this bar
this is the we know this and then what's
this a one
now a and r is not necessarily separate
by one so what's the distance between a
and f r
well done exactly okay
yeah
okay yeah so look
this is the come on come on ryan what
you doing so
what i'm saying here is that this is
help this is the volume of the
of the rectangle yeah for this this uh
water if we we chose an iron okay
so this
so you have uh
so
so yeah the
min or
because
the smaller one is vitamin b
right yeah so
this is the minimum
of these two yeah yeah
and times
times the length of this which is r
minus five we're done
right you get it
okay pull first oh n square okay oh n
squared
it's a bit slow okay but we can do it
better we can use the two pointers see
but how can we do these two points i
think look okay so let's look at this
example yeah if we are air at the
beginning we set it to zero r set it to
n minus one which is the uh you know
left most and the right mouse if we say
air the height
if we say air is smaller than r right
so how do we move the point we are
supposed to move one right so
is it
is better we move the lower bar or move
the higher bar so now we are we know
that air bar is smaller than the
ah right
so we want to move the
the answer is we want to move the
shorter part towards the
towards the center right
let's say if we move the bigger one
towards the smaller one what would
happen let's say it might be so tiny
that it might be
that
that it might be only like this
yeah yeah no no look here this is r here
right
this is longer than air and if we move
here towards the left what will happen
will come like
the lens will be shorter okay so let's
try so let's say
let's see if we
okay so if this is air right so let's
say
currently the volume is mean
air r
times t okay so look this is t okay
let's say this the distance here is t
right if we move the r towards the left
the longer one so let's say if we move
it somewhere here and then the distance
is t1 which is shorter right e1 here t1
and
and the height height is what is mean
l and r1 okay we know we are not sure
how big how tall is r1 right it could be
very tall it could be very small okay so
let's look at this t1 is smaller than t
right smaller or smaller than t right
yeah because it moves towards towards
each other is smaller than the original
places but look at this one mean a r
mean a r okay so mean a r and min air
are one okay so look if this is very
tall
r1 is very tall and the min air r1 will
be a right if it's very short
min air r1 is r1 which is smaller than l
so in
in so what does this mean it means that
means
l r1 is always smaller or equal than
mean a r am i right because it's always
determined by the small smaller
by the smaller vertical bar right so
originally
originally the smaller bar is air a and
r right because it's smaller and if we
keep moving to the left right so
so if this r is very tall then
the mean of l and r one is f if this is
very short the mean of air and r1 is r1
r1 is smaller than air yeah so in both
cases the first case is
is equal to air the second case is is
smaller than air right so so that the
volume yeah if we keep moving left we
don't get a better volume am i right
yeah okay so what does it mean look
if i move a taller bar to towards the
left
we don't get a better choice
right so what does it mean in other
words it means means that we have
we don't need to try
these r right because we know we don't
get better
ah so we don't move it so in that case
we just move the air to the towards to
the right
right because because look if
this thing will get
squishy
in both yeah
at the beginning is on the right on the
right you see they will be
squeezed anyway right they'll be
squeezed they're moving towards each
other i said what did i say if i moved
out towards longer one towards the
shorter one we don't find any choice we
just pull that well on any better one we
saw we just pulled it right so if we
find out if we know already there is no
point there is no better gain if we move
longer towards the center then we just
don't move it right
yeah what's proof of him so we with each
air
we try each other right
but now i'm playing with this is with
this air we don't find any better choice
than these are the longer one
right because the distance is shorter
right so we we are actually blue forcing
already but we don't and we don't try it
it will be like blue force with some
optimization right
by moving the left to the right what
will happen
we could get something like that right
look
what did there just look
yeah what did they say come on if i move
the left to the right i could find
something here
and then which
which is longer and what is that how
does that matter the volume will be
potentially bigger do you get it
yeah
this is not a strictly true of the
solution the two-pointer thing okay but
if we want to actually prove it we need
to use the mathematic the contradiction
to do it but this is a little bit out of
scope of this uh
today's talk okay so um
i'm not going to talk about it so let's
talk about this uh the two pointer thing
okay so air at equals zero
r equals n minus one and equals the
length of the h right the answer at the
beginning would be zero like why look
these two points i think yeah
we talk about the two-pointer thing
do we still remember we have a look we
have a thoughty number
one three five six nine 11.
once this is the salted numbers yeah
can we find the two numbers added up to
uh to 10
um
[Music]
how do you find the nine one i need my
number ones eric
how do you find nine and one added to
ten
and a on here
and ah here you use two pointers yeah
one one plus eleven twelve come on one
plus 11 12 which is bigger than 10 so
which point which which side should i
move
smaller
right right yeah because it's bigger and
i have to move it to the left yeah okay
so yeah
exactly okay you get it okay this is
probably not a good example let's say do
you find any any
two numbers that add it up to eight
okay so can you simulate this again add
it up to eight
so look one eleven twelve what's your
eyeball
[Music]
never had no right hand so i move
right okay i'm here ten
right right
then
left
yeah because seven is more than an a
right so
wrong nine
right
yeah and then you've got it yes you get
it this is the two point thing right
yeah so now here
why why
left is smaller than r right
answer this is the same we are trying to
maximize our answer
and then there will be mean
of h error
the
the volume that the determined by the
lower part
times r minus a right and then look
if h air is smaller or equal to h r
what should we do else what should we do
come on we're talking about if the lower
bar look away
from the air the height is smaller than
one which where we should move hr h is
smaller than r so which one we should we
should move
left left yeah because i was just
talking about that for 10 minutes why
moving the right does not give us a
better choice do we get it
so exactly so that would be air plus
equals one and then s ah minus equal one
okay and then we can answer okay what's
the tango next thing come on um
yeah yes
that's what i was about to say well okay
all right yeah because look y is
allowing we can prove we have two
pointers at one step
one pointer moves towards
the the other one you know you pick this
one or this one so when they meet how
many iterations
how many steps both yeah and exactly
yeah yeah it's like arrogant ryan you
you stand 10 meters apart
right and one
one step
yeah either eric or ryan what the words
one meter towards each other yeah
and then when you meet in the middle
somewhere in the middle the total step
would be 10 right
yeah you get it okay so that's the time
time capacity i'll win okay stay
complexity with one constant space okay
uh
and yeah that will be for today good job
you