yo hello
hello mr ernesto and i right here
do you still remember what's turning
john yeah yeah what paranormal when you
reverse it it's still the same can you
give me an example
okay a b c d egg no b a a b c b a okay
any animal race car blaze car exactly
okay
okay so yeah exactly okay so let's i
give let's see i have a few letters yeah
c c c d
d e
okay can you can use all the letters for
me or some letters sorry can you can you
give me the longest
peninsula um
by using all the letters
constructing letters each one can use
ones uh most one
okay about that
what if there's
there are three c's can you use three
c's
up to you you know so yeah anymore come
on the longest one okay
no no no you can use you can rearrange
the letter it doesn't have to be in
order
sorry i don't think you should use an a
b or e
[Music]
ccd
separate
cz and dd no not together
okay okay okay
c c d d yeah
that's that's shorter than this one yeah
that is nothing okay
yeah uh so you're saying this one is the
longest
yeah probably you're right this is the
longest yeah
so i knew that a b or e since there okay
no they're not two of them we're done
you bring a very good point okay so so
first of all
you know there are many of these yeah
that's not very good and there's some
others which is
like
for example
dc atd
dc a c d
yeah
well we're done b c a c d d c a c d yes
exactly that's another length of five
okay so the five is the longest right so
how do we find we want
you know there are many many examples
but
the task is to find out the length you
know it doesn't have to require you to
return the longest which one you just
need to tell me five okay okay okay let
me give you a negative example
what's this what's the longest
what's that
is
[Music]
yeah okay so okay so
that's right that's the correct strategy
okay
you know but obviously you can have
money yeah you can swap these you know
as long as eight meters you can have
this uh e right or c
and b yeah so there are many many
variants of this yes yes of course yes
okay so so what's your source if i have
a few numbers like m e i c ryan
okay so look how what's the longest so
how do we get this how do we compute the
longest one so why one of them is
find what we want to do what
that's the thing let's thing in person
that allow us to
to to count the number of the frequency
for each character what do we what what
is it called
you know we want to count the number of
frequency for each each letter a string
a list or whatever what what is the car
look me
all right come on
a
a b b c okay for example this if we want
to get these the count a two times b two
times c one times what what does that
call what kind of data structure what
kind of thing allow us to
uh dictionary yes traditionally
counter exactly okay area use me powder
yeah so if we have this counter we have
the numbers we have a frequency for each
we have a
m so we can get the frequency for each
letter right so what do we do with the
letter with the numbers
what do we do with the numbers
if it's an even number can we can we use
the all of the letter if it's even
number yeah because we can put one on
the left one or right right okay
because if it's like just one but if
there's like one
this
is one
yeah but it is like like a d
one it would be one
but i can use one at most one okay and
how about c three three times how many
times i can use
uh you can use it um
really yeah
the thing is okay c3 d1 and then a2 so
what's the longest
what's the
c c longest
a c
c a
yeah okay okay you mentioned that's a
very good point so so if it's a odd
number right look if it's an odd number
yeah we can use the minus one right
because look it's three characters three
c's we can use two c obviously right
yeah
we can use two two c but what's next
but
but we can also use almost one odd
number in the middle right am i right so
the point is to greet it to to use as
many characters as long as they are in
pairs
and then we can put one more in a meter
if there's an extra one but but that's
it no more right let's that's it no more
do you see it
yeah
yeah okay so we can use this counter
thing and then that'll be yeah
[Music]
let's quickly write this implementation
and then you'll see
probably you can um you know you know
how to do it right
right when
you're not standing in front of the
camera because you used to see your head
yeah
sorry
okay
okay so define the longest
longest parenthesis
[Music]
s okay for example is x so we need to go
to this d e d equals the counter right
yeah we count it
counter s
now answer
answer equals zero right
this is the longest parameter and okay
so then i want to have a counter which
is all equal to which means that if we
have
one more extra letter in the middle like
oh at the beginning is zero okay so
let's go through this dictionary for
i
in d right
now if
if d i
is uh
and one or modulus two equal
if it's an odd number
if it's an odd number what if if the
different frequency is an odd number so
we can use all of it right
all right yeah so answer
plus equal d i right
okay now you tell me
as
s it's a
term of the story what do i say it's an
even number right yeah if it's an even
number then we can use all the numbers
right
and how about its odd number
if there's more one or number
if it's odd number we can use a minus
one right answer plus equals d i
minus one i'm right look if if it's five
we can use four of it all right yeah
put one in the middle so we we put this
we have a counter here or equals
three to one so means we have extra more
at the end right
now
so we just need return answer
plus on at the end right look this is
quite beautiful right look everybody
come on
come
on look beautiful
let's uh
let's give a give it a go with some
example if s is empty right if s is
something the loop will not be executed
so the answer is zero right obviously if
s is one one character a
right so the d will become
a one right yeah so we go through this
uh what a one if it's an even number
look
it's all number obviously so the answer
plus equals bi which is one one minus
one equals zero
one minus one equals zero and odd equals
one so return zero plus one one right
because any single number is a pending
term right
how about two letters like a
a b okay this is example so the correct
answer will be
a or b
one one character okay so look if the b
counter thing you tell me a equals one b
equals one right yeah
because of the t
well
so this is the
even number this is all number okay so
answer plus equals zero all equals one
and the second iteration with the b
and return answer plus or which is the
which is one okay and how about another
example like look
a
b
maybe let's try b b c
a a b b c okay so least this the with
c a a the d will be a equals 2 times b
equals 3 times c equals 1 okay
yeah
so
a which is even number answer plus
equals 2 so we have 2
and then b which is the odd number
answer plus three plus three minus one
right
and then oh i set it to one okay come on
yeah
and c equals the whole number
all number answer plus the plus one
minus one and all equals one so the
result would be answer
two plus two four yeah plus zero
four plus one is five so let's we can
use the five characters am i right
so we can either use the two a's
two b's
one c or two a's and three b so that
answer is playing do you get it
all right what have you learned today
about palindrome pandering
we want to construct the longest parent
drum using the letters you have okay
yeah this is one okay one one example
know b okay
okay what's the longest parameter
you can get
d
but that's not the only one yeah i know
because if you if you have a t in the
middle you can swap the abc here you can
have a c b and d okay
okay okay
okay so you get it yeah okay to sum up
okay one more sentence to sum up
if we tell
if it's
even frequency okay that if that that
character appears even number one can
you solve it by appending one on the
left one on the right right if the odd
number
we can
we can use
its frequency minus one right yeah you
get it yeah
and then we need to set it x to one one
character because we can use the k x
okay one character
in the middle why
yeah because we just have one loop going
through the characters at once yes let's
face contact c
o n we are using the counter right you
get it okay for today bye