hello hello mister visa right now right
that's good okay so we are going to talk
about the long case
period what's paddington
what's paraguay can you give me an
example
[Music]
x w okay i see what you do you put it a
to z and then backwards again right so
basically the string it's reversed it's
the same then it's uh
it's parallel okay so in python how do
we check a string s is a pentagram any
idea look the easiest way can you tell
me the easiest way come on okay i think
you know this one if you want to find
out you know there's a quick syntax in
python that allows
yeah so s equals
s
column kernel management right so
basically look what's this look here
this is
wrong
the second is two the third is step okay
so we are we we're not giving any
parameters from the front so it starts
from a zero not giving anything to the
two parameters so it goes to the end end
of it so which is n and my n right and
even the n characters and step minus one
means reverse so so we can define you
know each pairing drum
print of s then we can just return
return s equals as common color minus
one so also you can do this e is telling
a lambda function a short function
without a short function we will not
define it
uh its parent drum equal e equals lambda
s and then we can say s
column column minus one equal equal s
okay so this is the quick syntax
otherwise we can use the two pointer
thing and we have pointer from the left
on the right we check if that both
characters at the at the index if it's
the same if it's the same then we keep
moving until they meet in the middle
otherwise it's not apparent all right
yeah so we talk about that the time
complexity is o n right obviously okay
so now i'm given a string right look
a
b b a
b
what's the longest
substring
palindrome what's the longest string
that is also kind of another substring
continuous yeah obviously okay so
substring continues subsequent which is
not continued yeah substring continue b
i i b okay another example
a b c d b c
okay
come on what's that what's the longest
substring what's the longest subject
what's the longest option a b c d d c b
a
a b c
okay how many of these one two three
four five six how many of these one two
three four five six seven seven eight
okay so this is clearly longer
one question if the whole string is a
parenthesis then the longest
substring
which is also which is also the longest
substring right
yeah a b b b a
c c what is what's the longest current
substring the whole thing exactly so now
okay so you understand so substring
continues usually when we solve this
kind of problem we need uh one square
right if the string even the n
characters yeah and there are cn2
tn1 right so why is that look if the
substring contains more than one
character than this cn2 if that contains
only one one character because one
character is also the substring so it's
cn1 so if we add these together cn2 is n
times n minus one divided by two c n one
is n obviously so if we add it up these
two together will be n n plus one
divided by two if if my math is correct
okay
so they are total these number of
substring and and plus one divided by
two so if we want to prove what's in
here so it needs the one square right
you get it
so how do we if we don't proof of these
uh
n square
practices so what's the overall time
complexity of this argument
look we are we use o n square to prove
us all the substrings right but for each
substring we want to check if it's a
paragraph that's going to take over n
time right so what's the temperature
next week
anybody
[Music]
where downloading yes because o n
squared
[Music]
this is the total number of the
substring cn2 means that pic if the
substring contains more than one
characters cn1 means that if the subject
contains one characters okay
okay so
we we can do this okay but we can
optimize this a little bit it's all n
cubic yeah it's one cube and think how
do we make it o n square one easy way
would be to make the
pentagon check a one yeah but how do we
make o and uh preliminar one we can we
can compute we can calculate it in
advance and put it in the table right so
we can just look it up right all right
then that will make the check a one
right okay so now let's do this process
for example yes uh long case
ryan
what
so the easiest way right this way
so we want to store the left left and
right would be the
left and right index of the longest
current which is to minus one maybe okay
maybe better for
i
in
range and
come home this is the
blue force for j
in range
i to the end right
we have seen this before a long time
right all right
this is the classic way to go for
a
you know a substring right so we start
with i which is the left index j is the
right index and then the current string
will be one the substring current string
will be as
i up to j right up to j
and then we just have to check if
the c
minus minus my uh current minus 1 equals
c then
also we have to check if
the j minus i is bigger the length is
bigger than r minus f then
we recall that the r equals i
r equals j right and then we turn
x number one
r plus one right so this is the proof
from complexity
and then
okay so we need to check this this is o
n all right so o n times o n times one
so the thing is that this is so we don't
need to
every time we do this very don't check
it it takes time right it takes time so
we need to find out a way
to
to store these results so we can get it
in o and or one container
okay one one optimization is that look
that even this is o and cubic okay even
this is one cubic we can still optimize
this a little bit
so how can we optimize we can
we can reverse the order of the j index
right so instead from i to n look
here this is i
the index the the characters
goes this direction from zero to n minus
one
j will be j at the beginning of this
from the j will be from i to n if we
reverse this
if we reverse the j from this this side
from n minus 1 to this psi okay so what
happens if we reverse this bit
if we reverse this
n minus 1 up to i
we
reverse j from n minus one to i right
and minus one which is a step backwards
then if we follow the paren jump then we
can just break right because there's no
point to
no point to
keep finding it right he find it
okay what i'm saying is that look if we
found if we found a parent
if i we determine this i and we j we
determine we go
reverse direction if we found this is a
parent jump
then we don't need to keep from keep
moving the j towards the eye
right because if
we already found this is a parent if we
keep doing that the the palindrome the
substring will be shorter
you get it
so there is no point to iterate the j
right so we can break what's break in
the for loop what's the break what
happened what happened with the break up
here
it breaks it breaks it so four you will
break whatever j here your breaks and
then your tears and i will be increment
here next one right so that's it so we
can optimize this by
caching
catching the punishment check right so
we don't want to calculate if this
substring is apparent in real time so we
can use the
you know we can pre-calculate this this
table let's say we have this f function
f i j
so that would tell us if the string s
substring i to j
i to j include including the j index if
it's a parenthesis right so then we can
replace
you know we can replace this check yeah
we can replace this check
uh
we can replace this check here this is
expensive right we want to replace this
chair
yeah first of all we can use define this
function and define f i j
f i j it means that if s i to
s i to j j the index if it's a paren
drum right so if it's equal so let the
two-page
two-based cases fi if a single character
this is also a
parallel and this is a pendulum
how about f i
and i plus one right yeah f i and i plus
1 equals s i
equal equals i plus 1 right
so basically what it means is that what
if there's only one single character one
single character is a pentagon right
yeah
two single character that needs to be
the sum this is two base cases right and
otherwise f i j
equals f i plus one j minus one
and
s i equal equal as j right
so we might want to we put this in the
front yeah
yeah so as f i j equals s i j equals s i
equals three if these two characters so
basically look a
something something something something
a okay so let's f i here is i here's j
f i j
if it's equal look at a equals a then
it equals f i
f i plus 1 this is j plus j minus 1
right what kind of equivalent is this
not quite i mean look if i tell you that
there's something missing here
cash yeah cash yes what what's this what
argument do you put the cash
top down programming minimization
exactly yeah exactly so look so if we
want
we want to know f i j if it's uh the the
substring from i index i to j if it's a
pentagon
then we have to check the index the
characters index s i and sj they are
equal then also f i plus 1 j minus 1 it
needs to be apparent right needs to be
true right
easy by putting a cache here so so look
f i define f i j if
i equal equal j return
2 right
if i
plus 1 equal equal j then we need to
return
s i equal equal s j
otherwise we need to return
s i
equal equal as j
and
and f i plus 1 j minus 1 right so
sometimes we put another check if i is
bigger than j then we also return i i
don't know return true or false index i
should not be bigger than j right so it
should be smaller than three okay so we
put this s i equals j in the front
that's right why is that because if this
is false we don't need to continue
evaluating it right
do you get it yeah
why is that look if i'm saying
there's a thing a and b
what's a and b what's the a and b if
if pulling a and b you know true and
true right
two and two is true true and fourth is
false right two means n means then both
needs to be true all right yeah
okay if i am telling you this a is false
do i need to evaluate b
because it's false right okay how about
b how about a or b
o what's o
any
one is true is true right yeah
so if i'm telling you that a is true do
i need to evaluate b
because it doesn't matter no matter what
b value is this whole thing is true
right do you get it
yeah okay so that's why we put this in
the front okay then we can replace this
okay
replace this
and we don't need this line okay so we
can say if i f i j
then we can do this okay but let's see
look this is this is actually a
recursion and then function calls and we
want to save it so we can we can put
this in an array in a in a to this array
okay please array okay and we we don't
need to worry about the function call
there
so then we can again let me erase this
bit okay
so
f equals
at the beginning true
we set it to true for underscore in
range and we basically create
for underscore in range so this is the
two dimensional wave
n times an array so it's n times an
array and that begins the values is true
for all cases
four cases then we have to
for
i in
range
in order to compute this uh f value
we need to iterate the left index from n
minus two up to
up to zero okay
and then for j
in
range
i
plus one a single character is always
the paranormal and up to n one
one okay
then look f i j
equals s i equal equals j
and
f i plus 1
j minus 1 right look
yeah so this is the same thing but using
the iterative so we are feeding we are
computing the x values using the
necessity for loop right so look this
bit is o n square obviously yeah but we
only do it in front of these so look
this is our n square this is our n
square two o n square is zero n
o n square right so because look we are
optimizing it
optimizing it look
the key point today is what this
this check
takes a long time and then while we are
pre-computing it
we computing it use and put it in the f
array for lookup
and so so the time complexity overall
time frame this is one square and the
space complexity is solving square we're
using that and there are many other ways
of doing this yes we're going to talk
about in the next few lessons but this
is one of the i mean most
straightforward way right what have you
learned so far today
about
how
how do we optimize this from o and cubic
to one squared
[Music]
yeah so which power this one cubic
which power we can optimize
the
red circle yeah what what is these two
um
yeah but this is chicken in a real time
it takes all the time right
yeah i know what are we doing here
[Music]
yeah we are calculating we store this uh
we basically store f i j right look what
f i j is the substring we want to know
if uh the substring from index i to j if
it's a parameter right so that will be
calculating it in
and put it in a cache uh put it in the
table right so why can we do this in one
square because we're using the dynamic
programming look fij
is based on fi plus one j minus one
right so we are reusing it look at this
part right
right so what why we can do this in one
square look
we want to find out the index from the
substring from index i to index j if
it's apparent
right we we are not calculating it every
time instead we just check one more
thing which is index i equal index j
yeah and then yeah based on this yes
look at it yes
look at this one we want to check this
whole thing with the tension right right
this is our thing now we first of all in
chicago this a equal needs to be equal
to this a right
if it's equal then we compare we we want
to
check this is a pendulum but this has
been calculated before so we don't need
to over calculate it again right yeah
okay that's it for today bye-bye
[Music]