hello hello
hello mr riviera here remember we talked
about the longest furniture substring
yesterday yeah so let's review this a
little bit here so
this is o o n o n square
the key thing of yesterday is what these
this paragon check is our end time right
so if we put all these together like
which which is a very basic you know
naive blue first
and then we'll take o and cubic because
this is very expensive to check
you know this is look it's
it happens
every time we want to find out if a
substring is a paragraph and that that
takes a long time that's very expensive
so how do we improve it we we can use
the dynamic programming dynamic
programming which this is dynamic
programming
equation
yeah to
to find out to compute to compute any
substring to see if it's a paragraph
right so we are reusing those f i j
representing
if the substring from i index j index
included is the parent term and then
for for each each substring we are not
calculating every time we are
calculating you know like the whole
stream
instead we use the fi plus one and j
minus nine so this is kind of we use in
the previous result which is bring down
the complexity from o and q because
right so and we can also implement this
using top down dynamic which is a
recursion with minimization with cash t1
yeah yeah so that's o and cubic that's
the
that's a way for us to find out the
longest tension substitute in o and
cubic o and square time right so this is
o n squared this is all n squared 2 o n
squared is 2 times of n squared
which is
o n squared because when we talk about
the time complexity
on all space complexity we drop the
constant right look at it
okay so now
today actually we have uh
another egg when yeah we have another
rhythm how many uh pending drums can you
categorize
i mean
how many cat uh peninsula what's the
pattern's about it by the way
uh when you reverse it it's still the
same can you give me an example
aba race car and then everybody yeah
yeah yeah poo p-o-p right
no two okay
if this is s in python we use this
syntax s
minus one equal equal s y count oh we
use the two points i think yeah two
points the counter
what counter no no the counter doesn't
have this case but like the two pointer
thing so look i and j
it's the same
i oh i know it's the same okay when i
meat it's a parent all right and if this
is not a person like
uh
like
uh let's say uh d okay
the same
okay the same
but if i change this to okay not the
same no apparently okay two-pointed
thing easy
okay so so how let's come coming back to
the question how many kinds of
transgender how many kinds of vendors
how many how many kinds of pairs yeah
what are they old and
yeah
odd number
on what characters or even characters so
for example all characters a b a
okay even number
a a
uh
abba yeah you see
so you see the difference
yeah with the odd number or characters
the one in the middle right the one in
the middle
yeah it's just you know could be any
right it's a it's a single single one
right
for the even and everyone every
character has to be has to match another
one on the other side right okay
so so let's look at this a b b
b a
maybe
c's
okay what's the longest paradigm here
a b b b a yeah exactly so
c a b yeah okay let's look at this
example yeah
so if we can treat it we can go through
this a yeah we can use it as a center to
expand right
okay it doesn't go any b
i can explain no
b
look the thing is that if i use two
pointer i can expand this i i can use
these
as a center which doesn't give any more
uh any parent drum other than this b
right if i can use these two
right and that's two right the same b
so if i use this as a center then i can
explain look if i try to use this b
okay and then i can go both ways b okay
yeah okay so the longest turning joint
is character is
yeah five okay got it the same as look
the similar thing yeah uh a a b b c c
okay another one so look if i'm if i
have two two uh
pointer i and j here right
another time i can go i can let the
pointer go both ways uh go two ways yes
so b
c
right yeah you get my point
yeah so let's say we have explained
function it's uh expand to expand
it's back expand yeah it's fine
expand and then take two parameters i
and j so i and j means the center the
center of the paragraph we're looking to
expand okay so it could be
i and i means that
it's an odd number paragraph or
i
i plus one
which is okay so even okay so i i which
why this is the odd number
and why this is even number anybody
because i
the center if it's ii the index the
center is the one character it should be
even it will be all right the center is
two character and then so it will be odd
but then you plus one to make it even
which one you're talking about the
bottom the bottom one the center will be
two characters neighbor
that always will be even right okay
you're talking about the first one
so the center if it's a one finger
character and then you expand you go
back you let the pointer go the uh the
opposite direction right go over to the
right and then i'll be uh
odd number right so
so we can use this experiment and then
to remember the longest distance that
both pointers can travel
right if we remember the longest
distance they can travel then we find
the longest challenger make sense
does it make sense am i right
these two pointer and
yeah so
every time i start checking i i have two
choice i start checking the
the palindrome by expanding around the
center so it could be two right it could
be even or it could be odd
when it's when it's odd
the center is one single character when
it's even it's two characters and then
like that two pointers go
you know they separate the opposite
direction and then let's see how far it
can go how far you can travel right and
then you stop
and you stop and then we can we can see
how far the distance is that's the
length of the longest
that's the long length of the longest
pendulum okay basically that's how we
use these expensive around center things
so we just quickly write this okay let's
see
so
n equals length s okay let us define
this expand define
expand
the center
is bigger or equal than zero and
r is smaller than n right so look these
two pointers cannot that cannot go
beyond the boundary i'm right yeah
and
s i
s l equal equal s j s r okay
so
look alright ryan come on this center
when they when they're the characters at
these two points and match the air goes
to which way ah
sorry
look this is air this is ah
okay there suppose this is center okay
and the point that the characters are
the same like a a and then which
category l what's your air move what's
your one
yeah s move this way actually move this
way right
exactly and if it's a single character a
and
it goes this way and this way right
exactly so air minus equals one and ah
one
hour
easy
plus equals one plus equals one okay and
then return we want to return we can
because when it when the break
when the loop terminates right it point
the l and r points to an embedded
position so we need to return its
previous state which is a plus one
and an r minus one right you see
everybody okay let me repeat this
when the
y
terminates
the air and r pointer points to the
invalid state which is could be smaller
than zero of outer boundary or s air not
equal hr right this is basically
embedded or embedded
for alternative so that's why we
returned it previously which is air plus
one and normalized okay with that in
mind so with air at the beginning l
equals
maybe
you know
minus one
m l equals zero r means minus one okay
we just said that
look at the beginning air
is
l is zero
i is minus one okay so this is opposite
why we we need that because in this case
we the
the length will be r minus l which is
minus one right right so the minimum the
minimum parameter length would be one
one character right yeah so we said we
need to choose this uh initial
uh states carefully okay then we can go
through these four
i in range
range n right so now
uh a b equals expand
it expand i i x
right and i will check if
b minus a bigger than r
minus a then we remember
air r equals a b okay and then another
choice okay look this is for the odd
number of characters
and what's the second choice what's the
other possibilities
even so i i should push i and what
what's the second parameters
if it's even a b equals expand
i what's the second meter anybody and
then this is the same i copy again
here
i i sing character and if it's two
characters
what parameter should i use
i what's its next characters
exactly so this is i plus one okay and
then we copy this we need to check it
look because this function returns the
longest
the parent drum yeah the parentheses of
the left boundary and right boundary and
then b minus a means that
the length and roughly the length
actually plus one but in this case you
have uh we can pass one in both cases so
we don't need to plus one here
b minus a bigger than uh this is the
correct this is the existing
existing the longest pairing drum
substring right if we find a better one
then we remember the left and right
boundary right you get it and then we
return one and then at the end we do ten
return s
air
to r plus one right
yeah
it's easy to implement yeah yesterday we
talked about the brute force and we
optimize it by dynamic programming right
and then the code you have to write lots
of code right but for this one and not
not much code to write right
yeah okay let me repeat this one more
time okay so how does that work look
uh let's try another example okay
e r i c a a
c b
e x okay what's the longest parameter
c
a a okay
yeah so i try i i
okay and i also try i i and i plus one
okay so if i try to i and i plus one and
here i go both ways go both way
okay so that character is four four
characters apparently you get it
yeah
okay then if i have another one this is
uh b a
so then in this case like we try the
middle one i and i
we explain around the center b
a
c
yeah this this is basically what expand
function too yeah b a c
and then we turn the left boundary which
is here this is left this is right
right and the lens will be r minus l
plus one to get it
yeah and that's what it's doing here
look at this okay one more question last
question what's this
what's big why this is this i i and why
they sign i plus one come on because i
must be the same because if you have
someone a b a the center is if you want
so oh yeah yeah yeah
[Laughter]
middle is about
yeah yeah okay and what's this x-men
function doing
uh it's just open in the car
okay so look it influences look at the
uh
okay i want this one
c
b
d
a c p
a
x y okay so if i look if i is here
i i okay
so expand
so what's the
so look it points them to the meter
abcba yeah
so after the expand what does it return
what does it return where is the air
with r
you know if the s is y a b c b x
and an air r points to c
where's the air
is
we're done that's it for today bye bye
bye bye bye oh one more thing the time
come next t
we go look this is n character we go
through this
that's n
and for each one we need to
expand that takes n so what's the time
complexity look
this is n
o n square this is o s o n square yes or
n square okay that's it for today bye
bye
bye good job bye bye