hello mr erami all right we are given
this multiple arrays yeah each array
contains the distinct number this thing
is another way of saying unique numbers
right yeah if this thing unique
i want to find out which elements
appear in most of them are in all of
them so that's what intersection is okay
can you give me the answer for this uh
which point
okay
yeah animal
four yeah three and four three
okay so basically you need to tell me
the answer is three four it needs to the
numbers need to be in increasing order
okay ascending order okay so easy yeah
okay
yeah so to repeat we are given multiple
arrays we want to find out which
elements which numbers appear in order
in sorting order in sorting order let's
call the intersection intersection or
multiple arrays
please know that that these all this uh
array contains distinct unique numbers
meaning look
it's all unique
distinct distinct unique numbers yeah so
when we talk about this unique thing
yeah
this unique thing so if i draw this
diagram what kind of data structure can
you
that set exactly we're using set so we
can just use a set
yeah we can construct a set from what
first array
and then we can do the inside section
yeah by each of it right
define
intersection of multiple array
arrays
okay we're given these nums which is the
list of this
now look if we are given an empty array
then we just return and empty this right
return and then finish
otherwise let's say a is the first uh
set set from the first least lungs here
then we just have to do four
i
in nums we start from the second
yeah for the second list
a
a equals a dot intercept there's a
function there's a method for the
for the set in the set i right
but i this is a list so we have to
convert it to a set set i
so this is the same thing as a equals
eight and
set the i okay this is the same thing
okay and then return
return sorted we want to convert it the
converted to a sorted list so a right
but easy
yeah so to
to sum up we are converting we are
converting at least to a set so look if
we have the first list is what
if first this is one two three four five
yeah one two three four five and the
second is one two three four so one two
three four
right so if we do the intersection the
second this will be this one
right another the third one three four
five six three four five
the third is three four five
yeah and then six here
yeah so look look at these three circles
what are the comments about it
[Music]
do you get it
no
okay so look
one two
three four
five
six
okay
uh
i'm already correct yeah so which which
part is the uh the comment part
which part is the common part of all
this yeah exactly
three four this part appears in all the
three arrays
that's all we got
make sense
okay so now this is the set we can also
use the counter you have to remember
what counter
additionally exactly so we count so we
can count how many numbers each number
yeah and we go through each number in a
dictionary and then we count how many
times they appear because each array is
uh
you know only contains the unique
numbers if we do this counting if it
appears n times then it appears in all
the arrays right then we can do this
define okay so these
nums
so at the beginning we have a c don't
equal counter
[Music]
we don't need to give anything so it's
empty dictionary okay so then now week
four i in nums
then we can use the counter to update
you know which update which is the
incremental
changes which takes the changes from
another set so c dot update
yeah see the update
counter
i
okay yeah
now
c contains the frequency of all the
numbers combined for all arrays then we
have to count each number if it appears
that n times right so that n equals the
length of the nums which is the
number of the list yes so then we have
this answer answer equals that
for
i
in
in c
in c if c i
equal equal n if it appears n times then
it appears in all the arrays then we
answer the obtained
append i
right but this is could be out of order
then we have to return sorted
sorted
circuit answer
right this is one way and we can
make this shorter we can make this
shorter right make sure
so we can just return
salt it
and i
for i j
in
in c the items
see the items if j equal equal n
right look all these one two
no one two three four five side lines
can can be converted to one line all
right let's return sorted i for i j i is
the number j is the frequency how how
many times this i appears see the items
if j equals n
all right what does it mean if j equals
n
it appears in time what does it mean if
your number appears in time what does it
mean
[Music]
exactly if it appears anytime it appears
in all of them right that's why it is
some complexity
and how do we find out the terms of next
if there are anything if if let's say
each of these is
these m numbers and they are only the
time complexity of below and all right
the space conditions were using either
the counter or using the set
right
yeah
so what have you learned so far today
come on
[Music]
in one sentence just to summarize the
section of multiple right black set
how many ways did they talk about
set and
set
okay
now okay what area
what have you learned today and what are
we trying to solve
and how many ways can we solve okay just
two questions
multiple arrays yeah so it means that
which find out which numbers
appear in all races
two what are those
uh count and
uh
counter is the second method what's the
first method
yes yeah set what set is the data
structure that contains only unique
numbers okay so this problem is quite
simple and
the the the diff i mean the one thing we
have to keep in mind is that these
arrays contains distinct or unique
numbers so there are no duplicate
numbers in each array right so
if they are duplicate in each array then
we cannot use the
set because we don't know how many times
they appear for the set you only
remember once right right they get it
look
one two three three and one two
two three three okay if we can construct
the set
from these two
look these two arrays are different one
two three three that duplicate threes
that duplicate two and duplicate three
if we convert it
if we can
construct a set from each array
they both will be a set of set
set what one two three right
so basically we said it's just the data
structure contains only unique numbers
right so it doesn't tell me how many
times up here but that counter will be
okay right counter you can but but the
thing is that the counter
for the counter to work we have to check
it appears in time if it has the more
than one
if we have the if each array contains
more than one duplicate number so then
this way this method is not also not
working okay
make sense
okay that's it for today bye