hello mister hello mr ryan all right
okay so let's say we have a string
pattern yeah tiger
and then suppose this this string
repeats itself infinitive time what's
infinity
white tiger i know it doesn't matter oh
you can say eric yeah
okay okay let's change it to arie
i like it
which is the best oh yeah okay
environment as well yeah okay so eric
yeah
and it repeats itself yeah
why infinitive time
so if i say i equals rice
i equals three right j equals 10. so can
you tell me the substring the you know
the index from
three zero one two three here this is i
equals three
and then ten
ten you know so it's i up to j not
including j so it should the last index
to be included is nine right so that
three four five six seven eight nine
nine yeah
this is nine
and
ryan right so that would be this is jake
yeah so you need to tell me this dream
yeah character
make sense
yeah
yeah okay
this is an easy question so
what's your thoughts about solving this
i mean i mean this is what you did
obviously
that could be a solution that allowed to
be very you know
but the thing is that uh
we want to
how how do we find out because this
stream never it's not existing you can't
put these three in memory it's infinity
yeah
it's in infinity so we we don't have
this string and memory this is infinity
yeah we can't put this string in the
memory
so we need to do some math right so we
need to do some math so we can go
through this index but how do we like
the key thing today is that how do we
map the index to the original index all
we have is e-r-i-c this index right so
if i'm saying e-i-c-c
needs to map to this one
e needs to map to this character ah yeah
you see what we're doing
yeah
so we only have a copy
and we want to go to the range here for
i
in let's say for x in
range
we start with i up to j right so now we
have this index x but how do we map this
x to the original index
any idea that's the backspace
what but
oh well my question is this index x from
i to j how do we map this x to the
original guys because that's all we have
one copy so how do we make this x to
resist to here so so for example like
this is three four okay so here is four
five six seven eight how do we make this
seven two
two three
you just count um
yeah under the count how do we count i
mean this is c
i equals seven how do we make it zero
one two three
that's my question how do you remember
this okay another example e
when i equals a how do we map it to zero
do i need to give you more example of
this it's very obvious yeah we can't we
go around the table so what kind of
operator is this i'm trying to get this
thing out of your mouth
we go look dear one two three and then
back to yellow one two three a tl one
two three
so what operator is this come on
modulus
yes wow
i'm getting this yeah i'm almost giving
it up
okay
yeah modules so we can just do this
answer equals at the beginning we put in
the list then answer
a pen
a pen uh the original copy let's say s
s okay x modulus
modulus the length yeah the length of
s
okay and then now we can return this is
at least we need to convert it to a
string dot join
all right join answer
yeah
and that would be like easy question the
most important thing is this
module yeah easy
so we can even use the one line return
um
going on you're not explaining it just
repeating my question so my what's john
here what's john doing
it together can you give me an example
yeah
it's common sense yeah okay can you
explain to me like i'm a five-year-old
boy
what's going on
where does split okay ryan you're
listening yeah right okay so what's join
uh
[Music]
okay so
oh what's split
like
cut in here
yeah okay so look
hey
a
space a plus b plus c if this is a
string if i split it start split
split by a plus then you'll give me a
list array of
a
b
c yeah
this is called delimiter separator yeah
easy and then join look
i can say
uh
well i can say x
dot join
every
ryan so yeah tell me what what do we get
here eric doctor no no no this is x dot
join everything right so what do we get
eric x ryan
exactly yeah you'll understand it yeah
so you need to better
you know explanation i know you you
understand but
one skill right
one skill is to explain it to other
people who don't know it right this is a
very important skill do you understand
yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
okay so another way of doing it yeah
another way of doing this
this eye because this eye could be very
big right so if we modulus this length
length s
then this is the starting position how
many characters we need to return is j j
minus i right
so if
this is the number of character we need
to return not that come on this is the
number of characters we need to return
my fluffy
what's j minor
uh so it's basically
what's j minor sign
what does it mean
it means
that you kind of search
so what's this number k minus i come on
it's very obvious what you're looking
for
three minus i what's the same what is it
what is a equal equals that green bar
the number of what characters of the
return string right yeah yeah yeah okay
so
if this is n
and then the time conditions are when
the space complexities are when
obviously yeah so what we're saying is
that i model that's the star and then we
can do this i okay i equals
i modulus equals modulus equal length s
right
then k this is the number of character
we need to return j minus i
and then we have a
we need to construct a string that's uh
you know let's just string that one not
infinity right so p equals
how many times k times then we can do
this s times k plus one time right now
we can just do this return
p
i
i plus k because there are k strings
there are k characters we need to return
f k is the number of characters and we
need to return from index i i has been
down this modulus
to i plus k
okay
okay that's one way of doing it okay
yeah enough for that will be for today
bye bye bye