hi hello mr and mr man
so look we are given a list of uh sorted
numbers so these numbers are sorted in
long descending order ascending yeah
ascending right yeah
so we also return a copy of the squares
of this at least for example the square
of each number all right so look this
one is squares of it which is what 25 25
and this one four this one
one
49 we're done okay but we want to return
square and sorted as well yeah one for
25 49. zero
we're done okay so how can we do it
simple we're going to square each number
to the power of two
to the power thinking of something
solving yeah we're done sorting yeah so
we basically we go through each number
we square it yeah we square it and we
just sort it yeah
that's a very obvious way that's very
obvious look how do we do it
so we can look at um
we could
go
go on the shops and look for timetables
and then look at each timetable
sound on it and then just
do and sort it
further okay so you're saying that but
this timetable could be very big right
yeah because these numbers are arbitrary
so
how can you find it that numbers in the
time table so
so we are we're talking we are not
talking about a few numbers like in the
range right
yeah
yeah exactly so and then done
wow that's an easy question yeah so okay
so i'm doing a good job square
so do the math that's why you say mess
and then thought yeah
okay so two step square and soft okay
let's just quickly write it okay so it
should be very easy i'm definitely not
done okay okay
so how let's do this look define
square of list and then we given these
numbers
so
so answer don't attempt
how do we calculate the square how do we
calculate a to the power
in paisan how do we do this in person a
times a
we're down n a to the power of a or
power
a b
power a two f or a star star two yeah
remember this index yeah
okay so i times i okay let's do it and
then we just pretend
sorted
sorted answer yeah we can do this sort
of answer or we we can do this answer
the thought in the front and then we can
answer those are okay okay so the thing
is that we can we can change this to a
better syntax yeah better how to do this
return we can just retain one line yeah
return salty
sorted x times x for
x in numbers right look this is one line
yeah or we can do this another one using
the map function return sorted
map
but the first function is the map the
first parameter
of the map function is the
the function so we can pass a lambda
lambda is a short function x x to the
power of two
and then the second parenthesis
this is okay right
yes what's the time complexity
and logan we're done because we have n
numbers yes we have numbers yeah sure
okay so
so we can do in o and term so you owen
time so how can we do this or when then
the thing is then we
so what's the thing what what the thing
is that the original is it's already
sorted yeah it's already sorted so we
want to make use of that look minus five
what minus two zero one seven right
so we will this is already
yeah so
can we tell the thing is that the miners
you're not sure which one is bigger
right
look i am
that one's bigger because i have brains
no no
so because the largest one we can go
through the largest one to the we can
feel the array this is the answer yeah
this is the answer which is the the the
salty of the from the smallest squares
to the largest square right so this one
should be the the largest one it could
be only two cases either you take this
one or take this one but where here this
is bigger right seven to the power of
two is forty nine two to the power is
twenty five so this is bigger right
yeah so i put it take this i put it here
forty nine i i and and now
minus five and one which one is bigger
come on minus one and five which one is
bigger
to the power of two
[Music]
minus five okay so i take this one and
put it here 25 okay and then here which
one is bigger minus two one minus three
okay
okay so what's the time complexity if
you look at this way i mean what's the
term complexity each one
where they're always linear
yeah so which one is bigger the previous
one the saltine oh and again
which one is bigger which one which one
is better
owen or logan which one is better
oh and obviously i have a brain okay
okay let's implement this two-point
thing okay and a little bit okay come on
and you're definitely gonna give us
another
[Music]
okay now
it was the lens numbs
the left pointer equals zero the right
pointer equals n minus one and we also
need a
a pointer
to
to point to the
to the location where where we store the
answer right the numbers in answer let's
call it i don't know i
equals
r right okay so wire
air is smaller
l is smaller than no no
so we are not actually we can do this i
y i is bigger or equal than zero right
yeah this is the index then we will
check if how do we check which one is
bigger we can do this absolute value
yeah so
look
x to x square
x to the power 2 equals this this to the
power 2 right what's this this absolute
value which is ibs the distance yeah
yeah correct so if abs
nums
air
bigger than abs
bigger equal numbs
ah right so we take the left one right
because the square will be bigger so we
take the left one then we can do what uh
so the answer let's okay so we need to
have our answer answer equals let's
allocate it uh and
okay
okay this needs to go to the front
we we
have an answer right which original is
all zero okay it doesn't matter which
value we save as long as we we're going
to overwrite updated later okay so
answer
i
equals num
air
times times 2i to the power of 2 and
then l plus equal 1
s answer
i equal then we take the number on the
right num
r
time time 2
and then r minus equal one and then
return answer yeah no b yeah
okay
yeah yeah that time the next thing we
talked about the time that let's say
something
okay
look uh okay so there's one thing
missing is i we need to i i minus equal
one because every time we we
choose a number we need to move the
pointer i to the to the left right so
so
at the last we we are going to have
these n numbers because i originally
equal to n minus one
and then when it reaches two yellow that
will be exactly
and numbers okay
yeah
do you see
do you see how this works yeah
yeah okay okay
so what have we learned today so what so
the last solution would be just do the
math like you said to the mass
and sort it
no not a big deal you're not a fancy
thing everybody could think it yeah
every everybody can think of it
yeah but let's go to take the o and
again because the slotting right that's
all sorting but this one is a better
approach why is that because we're
making use of the fat like the original
array is already started so if it's
sorted every time we take a number we
want to find the
largest we want to find the largest uh
square
yeah it can only be in two numbers on
the left
with the smallest or the right the
biggest right so we have two pointer we
pick one which is going to give us the
largest square and then we'll move the
pointer right okay
yeah so we always feel that
the square largest as the square numbers
number squared from largest to the
smallest right this is what the i is for
and the time time let's say someone
because each number is divisible exactly
once two point nothing and we are not
sorting
yeah let's let's give us this a better
performance for this echo okay
yeah well that will be it for today
bye-bye
bye