[Music]
yes good job
remember we talk about binary search
right yeah
what what is what what's that
binary is two yeah so every time you cut
the search space into half
for example i give you a number i i i'm
i'm thinking of a lumber yeah in my head
i tell you it's between 0 to 100 okay
tell me what it is just pay again 50.
it's bigger than i what i saw
okay so you guys keep guessing
keep guessing ryan says 50. i said it's
smaller it's bigger than
the number i in my mind so what's that 6
22 you guessed 22 yeah it's smaller than
what i think three
small this number is smaller so it is in
this range
36 36 is smaller
uh 27
it's smaller so you need to it's in this
right
49 five nine it's bigger
46 46 is bigger
48 46 is bigger so
4.85 it's still bigger
uh 39 yes whether yeah that's the number
i guess
so basically you cut into half so when i
say 50
is bigger than you you know it's in this
way right yeah
then it's it's and every time you cut
into high so the next number is 25
yeah and it says it's smaller so you
know it's between
24 25 and 50 right and then you search
in the middle which is
i don't know it's it's 38 maybe
yeah yeah 38 roughly yeah in the middle
i say it's smaller
then you even know it's between 38 and
50 and then you do this
every time you you pick a remainder and
you ask me
yeah if i say bigger then you know it's
in a smaller half
if i say smaller you know it's in a
bigger half right
so the complexity is usually what
[Music]
log n right because if the n i every
time i kind of half yeah
all right so this is log
remember log a b
equals x
so what does it mean it means a x to the
power x equals b
right normally yeah yes yeah okay
so this log function it's like that
this is x this is y
yeah so look uh
y equals log if i say
log 2 base 2 okay log base 2x
so what does it mean what does it mean
do you know how hard the function goes
how the function goes
if x is x if y
is 0 so x is 2
2 what power equals
no it's the other way so if x
is 1 uh
how can i do it actually actually this
is not x right
log two x equals y
so y is zero when y is zero
okay for using no actually actually this
is
listen to the opposite okay this is
alright so x
equals not y okay so when y
is zero and well when y is zero
uh wait wait wait y can't be
zero right two to the power of anything
can't be
zero right yeah so yes i was right at
the beginning
okay so 2 to the power of
0 is
1 2 power 0
equals what's this it's one yeah
yeah yeah so x this is x this is one
two to the power of zero is one so
if i put the zero here this is one yeah
y is one
and x is zero okay yes so
2 to the power of 1 equals 2 right
right 2 to the power of 1 equals 2
so 1 y is 1
the x should be 2 right yeah
1y is 1 so x should be 2 2x should be 2
here
so basically it's a function like that
yeah this is log x okay this is the
function of like so you can this is a
curve
so what is mean is that the y
can be from negative infinity to
log to positive infinity yeah
but x cannot be negative it's always
strictly bigger than zero
so you can't find any value 2 to the
power of something
equals minus something yeah there's no
such number like 2 to the power of
something equals minus something
yeah so that was this means x is
straight so how can
look this function is we we call it
montana
more monotone function
monotone increasing function what's
monoton
what's this what mean monotone
monotone this molar what does it mean
yeah single sound singular
so it means that when x increase y is
always
increased so when x is more
decrease the y is decreased do you get
it
so look what does it mean look
if like somebody's uh how old they are
so if i if you don't know this value if
i give you this
log to a hundred and log to
500 which one is bigger this function
these two value
uh the bottom one yeah this is
maternally increasing because
you you don't need to calculate the
value right because i tell you 500 is
here yeah yeah somewhere here 100 is
somewhere here yeah
so you compare like you know it's bigger
right
it's somewhere here this is 500
so 500 is somewhere here and then 100 is
somewhere here
so you look which one is higher this one
this one is 500 yeah
yeah all right log 500 this is log 100
this is called the maternal
increasing yeah is x
square maternal increasing y equals x
squared
x to the power 2
no because its function is like that
look when x is 0
0 when x is 1 is 2 is 4 but when x
is minus 2 is also 4 okay
minus two square equals
what minus one square times
two squared okay minus one square is one
connect because negative double negative
makes positive okay so this is
non-molecular
molecules increasing look because look
this is monitor decreasing here but this
is monitor increasing yeah it's mirror
yeah
okay so if it's monitor increasing
then we can use the binary search don't
touch it
to solve this problem okay okay
so
so we don't know the value but we guess
right
remember we get this value yeah
we let's get given this uh uh
y equals log to x
we we want we are given this x but we
don't know the y
right so we can guess that we uh
guess let's check this this part first
if x is bigger than one okay
yeah this part so
what's the left about left bound is the
lowest power which is
y equals zero right yeah yeah yes
yes yeah one other bar what's the upper
bar
what's the upper bound upper bound you
can pick a very large
value or you pick up x why why we can
pick
x because when x is y y bigger than one
two x to the power of x is always bigger
than
x y 2 to the power 3
equals 8 which is bigger than 3 right
yes all right so you can pick a value
of the
so you can pick a value of x right okay
yes so look we can pick a value and then
we every time we
find the numerator and then we compare
the compel of a
compeller compare if it's actually power
if
it's actually 2 to the power of this
middle value
if it's actually if it's bigger than
if it's bigger 2 to the power of meat if
it
is bigger than the y uh no
if it's it bigger than x x is the given
input it means it means
that it's in the lower half right
otherwise it's in
it's in the bigger half correct
okay so let's do this coding okay maybe
coding
will make it more clear
turn on that thingy no no no define
log 2 x
okay log2x column
if let's first check if x is smaller
than
or equal 0 there is no such thing right
what should we return will be 10 no
we're done depending now we can't find
this this value okay
okay another thing i forgot is there's a
formula look remember
we talked about this we talked about
this one yeah
when it's here you you can't find the
lower bound because it's negative
infinity so we can turn it into the
positive
so so so there's a formula
it's log a
b uh
wait log
2 sorry so a
divided by b equals log 2
a minus log 2 b okay there's a formula
of least
and then log 2 a times b
equals log 2 a plus
log 2 p okay okay this is the formula
yeah and now
if we it's x is smaller than minus one
so we can
do it this way log a look to
x yeah not to x equals log two
and let uh also there's a formula
log 2 a to the power of b
equals b times log to a okay we're going
to use this one
log 2 a to the power of b equals and we
can move this b
to the front okay so now you you don't
need to
remember you just need to know we can
ten
we can turn when we continue when x is
smaller than one
we can turn this case into the positive
case so look
this is equals to 1
divided by 1 divided by x right
yeah x x equals 1 divided by 1 divided
by x all right
divided by 1 yeah so this thing
is x divided by x 1 divided by x
minus 1. look 2 to the power of -1
what does it mean it equals 2 to the
power of 1 divide
1 over 2 to the power 1 right
okay let me let me tell you 2 to the
power of 2 what's what's this value
power minus two yeah minus two
uh
equals two to the power of two yeah
you got it yeah yeah so it's a quarter
yeah
another one two to the power three minus
three
t to the power three what
minus three equals one two to the power
three
one over because it's minus you need to
make it one over right
yeah so this this one one over this is
this minus one yeah
i minus one look right and this thing
you can move it to the before so it
equals
minus log 2 1 divided by x
you see when x is negative
when x is smaller than 1
when x is smaller one bigger than zero
we can turn it into
one minus log of and one divided by x so
when x is smaller than one
one divided over by x this value is what
is larger than one right if x is smaller
than one
like 0.5 one divided by 0.5 equals what
two right okay yeah
yeah okay so now okay
i i just write too much thing here but
here
so if x is smaller than one
yeah yeah yeah return
the formula we just said minus log2
1 divided by x right
yeah now we just need to focus the case
when x is bigger than one right so let's
say lower bound
upper bound lower high equals lower
bound is what
lower bar is zero right because what
look look at this
when x one x is here y is
bigger than zero right yeah when x is in
this range the y
is b bigger than zero the lower bound is
zero higher bound is what
we can give a very big number or we can
just put the x right
uh yes because 2 to the power x 2 to the
power x is
always is bigger than x right
yeah so so we can use this now look
why and we can get some initial value
current value is zero okay let's just
guess the value we don't know yet yeah
but we need to say why the
abs do we still remember abs yeah
abs absolute value yeah yeah when the
absolute value
c u r minus one
c one minus one p u
r minus the power of t
this is the current value we are uh
uh the answer we are looking for
right so we need to we need to
answer no no actually x x
power plus one
c u r is the value we are looking for
log
2 x right so if 2 to the power
of current
minus x if it's big if it's bigger than
an
error when we we error a bigger error
okay
this error we can define it as
0.0001 or we can do this
one 1e minus 5
one two three four five one e minus five
okay
one e column yeah e
what what's e
e is this it's a good question it's a
scientific notification yeah
just remember we can one e minus five
equals
zero one e minus one zero point one
y minus two is zero point zero one okay
[Music]
okay so it's basically means that uh
where is the thought
so we finished no you know you're quite
quite close
quite close okay so this is yours
yeah so wherever we uh so the value is
that then we need to turn
uh
oh actually actually no if current
we we if current minus
x is bigger than one then we we need to
calculate meter meter equals
low plus high divided by two
okay and then current equals power
2 to the power of k meat
okay then if current
if current is bigger than x
if carbon is bigger than x we mean
it means that it's in the lower lower
half right it's in the lower half lower
half so
high equals mid as
low low equals meat
right and then i only this finish will
be 10
meter yeah we return the meat
done i think so
but here we need because we return the
mid we need to put it
low plus high divided by two
in case okay
so let's do the coding let's go ahead to
see maybe coding is more clear this this
this lesson is a bit difficult okay but
don't worry let's do it
together thank you
thank you yes
wait is it what please
so let's let's do uh it's clear yeah
it's very clear okay don't shake okay
it's very clear
look at that screen look and swing hey
can you see it clear okay yeah yeah
why okay let's do this
define log2 x
so look if x is smaller than zero
or equal to zero we know now we know
there's no such thing
if x then is equal smaller than one
we return uh minus
log2 look this is recursively calling
yeah when it's
smaller than that we recursively calling
uh
oh wait wait wait wait
is it clear is it clear can you see it
here yeah yeah
yeah i'll be cute
yeah yeah yeah i think this is fine okay
so look look two one one point zero
divided by x
right okay so now low
high equals zero
and x current equals low
low plus height divided by two
y why the
um
because the current value is the
wait power 2 to the power of this
we're guessing we're guessing this this
value
y current abs current minus
x is big still bigger than 1 e
minus 5 okay this is what i mean look
all right one e minus five is zero point
zero zero zero zero one okay
and then we need the meter equals low
plus high divided by two high
carbon we update the current two plus i
mean high if
the high high
if if now we need to check if this
current value
is bigger than x
right it's bigger than x it means that
the
uh the the value is in the lower half
so the lower uh the lower power so we
change this to the middle as we change
this to the
middle to the lower bar we can please
equal
and then return
return current with no return
meter we are we are we are calculating
the middle yeah
middle value let's try putting log 2
1.0 which is
return try and then 2.0
100 1000 yeah
yeah let's return 10 right and then 32
let's try if it works okay i'm not sure
[Music]
ah okay meat must be referenced okay
there's a value
yeah because we look we're using the
meat but we haven't
we haven't declared yet right we haven't
declared yet
what does declare
[Music]
you need to declare it before you can
use it
declare it means you need to use it why
because if you're not declaring the
computer don't know okay
for example you want to use the arabic
value and then
the computer don't know what's the area
why
so you need to define it define it
before you use it good job
why
the first value is very small so you can
pretend
because it's close to zero so the
computer the floating
numbers can be displayed something very
strange but it's very close to zero
so the second value one point zero ten
point zero five point zero okay let's
see
if it's yeah two to the power log two
two is one point zero log two
uh so log two this is this if you
put the uh let's you put in one yeah
this should bring this you put in the
ten
unless you bring five right
[Music]
okay so uh let's try some numbers
try the neg the number between
between zero and one so what is log two
zero point one
return you should return something
negative right yeah
yes exactly it returns something
negative you see
so we use the binary search and let's
just do it
what about zero 0.2
what would that do so it should be okay
good question
so what's the number is it it should be
bigger than
and blocked to 0.1 or no
what's the value is it bigger than look
look to 0.1 yeah
yeah yeah
yeah minus 2.3 is bigger than minus 3.3
i'm alright
yes yeah
so let's let's let's review this code a
little bit more okay
so if x is smaller than zero uh we can't
find such value okay
let's let's let's oh i forgot
[Music]
don't worry
no what i want is that i want to put
this
uh graph so you can have a look better
this is x this is y and then log 2 x is
this yeah
log 2 y equals not to x
this is one this is one and it's
from the value of y is from negative to
positive yeah you see
yeah negative two positive
okay so look if x is smaller than zero
you can find such
value in the graph in the mathematical
yeah if x is smaller than one and bigger
than zero we turn it into
the bigger case which is bigger than one
otherwise we find the meter
we define the range upper power and
lower bound
the upper bound at lower every array
please
and then we calculate the value two to
the mean power of mean
yeah when the current e and then x
if current is the same as x we we know
the value is mid
right yes yes meter and then
current and if it's bigger than x we
find it
because when x look
if this is the final result if we find
this value
if if we find this value is bigger we
have a lower bound
we have a lower bound here for example
and upper bound here and we find this
value
down yeah if this value x if we're given
this value x here
is here it will give you x here but this
value is bigger than this value so we
know
it's in the lower half right so we
continue
search in this half otherwise we search
in this half
okay so this is what i mean even bigger
than the value then we search in the
lower half otherwise in the middle half
when this value when is the difference
is smaller than
smaller than these then we find a value
which is very close to the
what value we want okay put it yes
okay okay okay so good job today okay
this is a bit tricky okay
any questions
[Music]
go sleep don't shake please don't shake
okay