hello mister mister right now you're
right
okay so look you know the backscape uh
key on the keyboard right what does it
do it deletes the
last character the
latest character
it deletes the character before the you
know before the blinking
cursor yeah
so let's say we are given this string a
b c
and then there's a lower
smaller and minus okay so that's smaller
and minus these two characters together
means uh we are pressing that backscape
so what do we get what do we get as the
final string ryan array come on anybody
ryan
we get a b a b okay
that's very good let me get another one
which is more challenging okay
i bet it's not
okay so what's this what do we have
a b best game a b basket
nothing nothing how do we even count how
do you even yeah that's
nothing step by step
yes
and then there are three boxes and
they're three letters so
look one two three four and then one two
three four so we have four keys and
we're here that's very good
so so you have any questions flat toilet
yeah
yes i need that toilet okay
what is the back spaces at the front
well that's a very good question what if
we have a backscape in the front and
then
there's nothing that's a very special
case okay so like that if not
so
what kind of data structure can we use
to do this i mean
yes yeah exactly how do we do this look
for example we're taking this one a
stack a b c
so what's that first thing first and
last step yeah no like like this okay so
a
b for the b plus c okay then we have a
best game so what do we do we take the
one out of our stack yeah so that's what
we have a b
okay then we join this
we join the journal stack right so
that's what we got
okay
so eric when we have uh when we have a
back scale in the front we just do
nothing okay okay so let's quickly write
this okay
okay
so we start using the stack we can we
can do this using the step easily
define let's say that we have this text
editor
and we have this string so
we have a stack answer equals empty
stack
then we have we need to know the length
okay
so now what do we do so we just go
through
so for
eric went for i
in
he was in range
n right
so if if i is bigger than if it's on the
second character then we can check n
as i
equal equal
minus
and
s i minus 1 the previous character is is
more small yeah
well how do you call this what do you
call it what what do you call this
uh
great
greater than
less than less than less than
then what do we do so we
uh pegman
[Music]
i see i see so look
what what is this chicken if it's uh if
this character is a minor and the
previous one is the less than that like
makes a
that makes a
backstage then we need to do this answer
dot pop
but we also have to check if answer
i need a toilet okay answer the pop
right next to that i'm going to explain
this later okay ass
and
a pen
[Music]
and then we do ten
empty the joint let's join by the way
we're joining stuff oh we join the
answer okay not during the
answer is a stack okay
so
look at that let's emulate this okay
a b c
this one yeah
so answer at the beginning okay it's not
coming in
we put the a let's answer the append a
all right answer dot append b answer dot
open c
is not a pen
smaller sign
now
when you will get to this point yeah
it's pretty it's current symbol
character is minus its previous one its
previous one is the less than equal so
what do we do so we just take it out and
also take one character okay
yeah
so
why do we need to have this let's let's
avoid that
there's nothing before the
escape for example like this one so if
this is a symbol yeah so what we do
coming there coming here so let's stack
we have less than equal time
let's
let's not equal and then we'll go here
what do we do we pop it
then there's nothing left in the stack
so we don't talk okay
so that that's one way okay the other
way is it's quite similar it's quite
similar
it's just yellow uh look we're checking
this current character and the previous
one to come to make a backscape yeah
that's good back backspace
not landscape
no backspace best space okay sorry best
base yeah backspace okay sorry all right
so it's bestscape
okay backspace okay bs
bs
okay so another way
another way we we have at least this is
quite similar so answer then we have
wire
is smaller than n
then we check if
i
before i plus 1 smaller than n
and
s i
equal
this one
and s i plus 1
equal
minus okay
so this character and the next character
makes a better on the school
okay
and then what do we do so we have a long
school no no need to be in the middle no
no no we do work if answer if answer
answer the pop right
but for this one we need to jump to
character i plus equals two
else i plus equals one
and then return
the joy
very right
so what does it mean look
this means that every time we go through
this character one by one and we're
checking if this current if the current
character yeah if current character is
okay so i i i probably need here answer
the append okay we have a
missing answer a pen si
so if this character is if this uh
character is and the next character
together is the best game then we need
to pop one
first base so then we need to pop one
character out of the stack it's not bad
and i plus equals two
otherwise we can append this one put it
in a stack and i plus this one right
because every time we we have a best
backspace
we need to ignore it and jump two
characters ahead right
make sense
yeah
this is this is one and this one is with
checking this current character and the
previous character if it's a bad space
then we need to pop one
but at the same time we have to pop
another one because because the first
time we met eric ryan tonight the first
time we have we meet the
fast space we already put push it
to the stack so we have to push we have
to pop these again
so we have to put the properties again
and this is just
in both cases just to avoid that
there's nothing
in a stack right when there's nothing in
the stack when you press the
backspace nothing will happen so okay
because because if i don't produce a
check what happen if you try to pop from
an empty stack what happened
if we if nothing no no no the computer
will scream because you're trying to pop
something from the empty stack
the computer will say
okay something is wrong so that's why we
have to check if the step is empty or
not right okay
another way okay which is quite
fancy okay so look
a b backspace
b c backspace d okay
look if we can use the split function
remember look eric this is quite
interesting if we use the split from c a
b d yeah yeah yeah look look then what
you become you'll become
a
right look
yeah that's the three groups so what
happened so we just have to
remove the last bit
of each one
right
if it's two unless uh
yeah if it's not the last one right
don't get it
so look a b
because we have a best verse we can do
this bc
we have backspace here so we did it here
so that without be abd exactly yeah did
you get it
so
so let me just remove this bit okay so
how that will be quite interesting as
well look so what um
array
equals s dot split
we split by this backspace okay and an
answer
okay so answer equals what i say equals
equals the okay so let's check if not as
if s is empty then we just return okay
our answer equals we have the first one
first so which is a uh zlo
then we go through for i
in
range
probably we don't need a range i in
a r we start from the second one
so
first time so we get we need to get rid
of the last character
this is a string yeah answer so answer
equals answer
minus one okay for the string we use
this way to get rid of the last
character here up to minus one means to
get to get rid of last character and
then answer
plus equals i right so we need to plus
the current character yeah
current group okay and then return
answer
okay make sense
the time time actually for all of it is
one right we are going to each uh one
time right right
so we're going through the characters
the string character by character just
one in one go let's open time
space convexity for the first two
we're using the stack
o-m right
for this one we also need to use some uh
additional array uh
yeah so that's all then as
all right so okay so to sum up what have
you learned today about backspace
factory
what about backscape
backspace backspace
so we are given the string then we want
to emulate the process of the keys
typing using and then we want to that's
the key thing today is what what kind of
data structure are we using
yeah because every time we push the
characters character by character to the
stack and then we have when we meet uh
press the backscape
backspace sorry we just take one
character out of the
outer space yeah so the thing is that
the corner case is that
that's very good ryan you raise this
question and area as well but when
there's nothing when how about
the cases when we have uh the backspace
and then the front
nothing happens right
because when we need to check
if answer if the stack is not empty if
it's empty then we do nothing okay okay
that's it for today bye
bye bye