hello hello mr mr ryan i like yeah okay
so finally search trees let's say we
have two finalists here
11 and then
five
eight
okay and then we have another here four
six
right okay let me put another one is
this a by research tree
um no why is that beach has where is
that 16 is not smaller than seven where
the let's have a good spot
the on the left on that left tree the
nose has two piece
the nose have to be strictly smaller
than the parents the the loop yeah
so on the left side put in other words
on the left side the null test
this might be the same as that well
that's another question no
because there's no duplicate yeah
there's no difference all the notes
needs to be unique right if it's a
duplicate it's not strictly so what we
say in the final century is the notes
have to be strictly what's strictly
smaller right it means and then they're
on the right hand side of this chicken
figure okay so that's good so if we want
to perform the what kind of tree travels
that gives these a sorted log a list i
mean if it's a what order then you'll be
in order what order will be left anybody
in order
in order so what in order in order is
what we visit the left tree
and we visited camera now and then we
visit the right tree right why is it
called in order because the node we are
visiting is in in the middle let's go in
all right yeah
so at least the left beat and ripen are
recursion we can do this because yeah so
we recursively visit the left tree and
then we visit the node
i know we do visit the right trigger so
this would be easier how do you how do
you implement another defined in order
easy
and then lose and line yeah so if it's
not empty we just return
we just return empty this
otherwise we return
in order
bluetooth left
plus do the value
plus
in order
blue
right right
yeah this is very trivial right come on
right yeah
ugly
it's not
it's not difficult right it's not
difficult
okay yeah
okay so we probably talk about this this
is recursion because we call it in order
twice now to visit the left tree and to
the visit the right thing okay
to the visit the left tree and the y
chip but we can do this iteratively yeah
iterative okay
okay so we can do this iteratively as
well
so we can do this iteration the thing is
that we keep visiting the left tree
because that's the smallest that give us
smallest and then we push it into a
stack we push this left in a stack and
then we travel every time we take one
out
and we visit the right tree right
because of the right look so look seven
we push this
we push this in uh stack yeah
so
seven
five
four
right and then we take the four out this
is four yeah take the four off
and then it doesn't have the right okay
then we take the fire out
take the fire out
yeah and then we go to the right
six right and i will take it seven out
and we go to the right
which is a right yeah
define in order
let's do that
okay so i i'll write the question here
just to do the comparison with the
root
that will be very easy if not root let
me write it again not loot
if it's empty we return
to this yeah
and then we turn
in order you know what whatever you know
the one
plus
one
plus in order
so what should i put here
i roll this five minutes ago
here is what
left yeah left yeah
and then what's here
right
here these two are because you're not
doing this
this is the iterative answer
and d1 yeah
so wire we have a stack
empty
wire root
or stack now we want to go to the left
as as much as we can wire
root
stack dot append
blue step of the pendulum and then low
equals to the left
right and then we take one out root
equals stack the pop
the last one and then
answer the append
root
the value okay
and lu equals to the right okay
this is it's iterative
and we can answer
[Music]
the tank and let's see both are the same
but practically speaking the iterative
one is
faster right because it doesn't have
this
calling stack overhead at least one
recursion recursion can be sometimes
very costly
yeah okay so that's coming back to
today's question so we have to find
another tree
let's just put another
a easy one
so
if we want to
if we want to return all the elements
from both
binary search tree but in order so what
what do we have look this find the
search tree
cl one two this final third string three
four five
exactly easy so how do we do this any
idea come on
this is ignore the left and right and
then merge them
and then how to yeah
where the wow that's excellent yeah so
so this is five times more obviously so
basically this question we have we have
talked about separate two steps separate
before right so first step is in order
we are that's very obvious we know that
and once we got this in order we have
these two sorted this right
and the next step is to merge them right
yeah so if we don't use this if this is
a two arbitrage financing not not a
binary research tree then the only way
we can do it is to uh to to to travel
both um trees
and then we just merge them and then
starting we need to sort it afterwards
right if we put them in order so we can
do any arbitrary trans tree services
definite search pre-ordering order uh
post order
or all the level by level
order right the number by the
preference search order
and then we got a tool list which is not
sorted and now we can merge them and
then we will do sorting so what's the
time time next if we want to sort it do
the stocking
[Music]
so for example the first planetary if it
is n nodes and the second one is m nodes
if we use the
naive one we if you're not making use of
the fact that they are both uh
binary search tree and we can do this in
other things to make it a salty beast if
we're just doing these you know blue
falls just just run the medium
just do some random travel so to make
sure all the notes are visited and then
then we combine two
notes and then we just can do this
sorting so the time conduction will be
om plus m that's the total number of
nodes and log
n plus m yeah
yeah this is uh but we but the thing is
that it's a five uh binary system so we
can do this in order i know we can merge
it yeah so so okay we can have these two
in other things so
a equals in order
to
one right and b equals in order
rule two right and now we can merge this
because a and b this is already sorted
right so
so the time conductor okay let me
uh
let me write this merge first okay so
this uh this one is easy i'm
erase this bit
and this is for the iteration iterated
in order thing which we're going to use
later okay so let's say a equals in
order
blue one blue one the first three yeah b
was in order
blue two
blue two okay and then we have a length
l a l b equals length a
lens b
and then we have this answer
equal empty list and then i equals j
equals zero we don't how do we merge two
sort to this any idea if there are two
sorting like
zero one you see which one is bigger
yeah yellow two four
yeah look there's two salty days here
look yes co two four six a and one three
five seven nine so we have two pointer
zero is smaller than one we put a zero
we move the pointer the first one to two
and two one is smaller than two
yeah and then go this way but ten
conductors om plus mb yeah
look if there are not in the first three
and the end node in the second tree so
time conducts it to merge two sorted
lists two two threes would be o n plus n
right or em plus them and to the time to
trevor today in order is o n for the
first three o and four first three for
the second tree so the time convexity
will be o n plus m plus m plus m
o 2 n plus 2 o 2 m
which is o m plus m right because we
drop the constant when we talk about the
time complexity and specific complexity
and then let's go back to this one i'm
not going to cook it very much y is i
smaller than a a
and j smaller than lb
now we check if a i is smaller or equal
than bj
then we merge the we take the smaller
one answer the append
a i
and then move this pointer i plus equal
one as
we take the
smaller one i'll take this pick a
smaller one for which is bj right in
this case
bj
and j plus equal one
okay and
when we are outside though
one on the outside the while loop so
there might be adding remaining elements
because the the length of the two arrays
two sorted array might not be the same
so we need to append the rest right so
if
i is smaller than a a then we answer dot
extend with using the extent functions
to take whatever
is remaining which is a i to the n
and then the same if j smaller than l b
answer the
extent
it's 10 right what's extreme in english
b j to the end
make it longer make it longer exactly
okay so return answer
okay yeah look we have this in order
iterated in order right so another way
is that we can do this iterate in order
on both three
in parallel there okay this is a little
bit advanced topic it's a
it's a it's more complex yeah but it's
not easy to think of but this one yeah
we have talked about doing in order
recursion they are iterative
and then once we have this in order we
have to sort this then we can merge yeah
we talked about these two topics before
right yeah so today nothing new it's
just to combine these two two steps
okay so now the thing is that look we
have this you know that we can do this
iterated in order with two binary final
search tree in parallel layer so how do
we do this in pair so we can do this st1
yeah then we have the st2 equals
okay and then while root or st1 yeah
root one yeah there are two trees yeah
actually that's two three blue one rule
two
blue one or st1 or ru2
or st2 yeah
and then we we do this we need to copy
these two yeah why l1 uh blue one blue
one the left and now we need to copy
these to rule two okay there's another
one for row two
okay
and then now we we have to take we have
to take the smaller one so we how do we
take a small one if
if not st
or
st 1 dot value
if not st 1 or st 1 dot value
st 1 the
one stack of value is smaller than st1
st2 minus one dot value
yeah okay so the thing is network
if we if the stack
if st1 yeah if st1 is smaller than st2
value then we took we take the smaller
one right if not st2 rst1 and c1 and
st1 the value values and we take the sty
we talk take the note from the first
tree which is the loot one or st1 dot
pop and apparently
i s
as we take the rule two okay i'm going
to write this here it's too squishy here
okay
so we are combining two iterative in
order in one single function
so we're checking every time we
push
the
left node to
each stack st1 st1 st1 as d2 okay
st1
and then we have the another one for sd2
which is the bluetooth and now we need
to check if the st is the value in the
first stack the first step is for the
first three it's smaller than the second
one we take the first the node from the
first one otherwise we take a note from
the second one right
do i make myself clear
okay so it's too squishy here but
basically that's what it is so every
time you see this you need to duplicate
it for the another tree
yeah and
taking this is taking a note from a step
but we we need to check which stack
has the smaller number right so if the
second step is empty
if the second step is empty then we take
the first node or if the second stack
the note of the
if the first if the second stack
is empty if we take the first step
or
if the second stack is not empty but
the first stack is the value the top of
the stack is the smaller than the top of
the second stack then we also take this
first the node from the first step
otherwise we take the node from the
second step so this time condensing it's
a it's a it's the same but it's one part
the advantage of this is one part for
the previous one is two parts why would
you save two parts because they're in
order
in order one pass right that's one pass
and then we merge it
second pass yeah this one is one task
okay what have you learned today
about
what's the problem what's the problem uh
there are two binary trees finally
search trees yeah and then we thought
um
we
we want to return all elements from both
trees combined right yeah so
what's the way what's the egg room you
do in order for both of them and then
yeah and the time to next year will be o
and plus n right yeah i know what's the
second one do you understand this one or
is it too difficult for you
it's fine if it's too difficult because
this one is out of scope
it's medium it's medium so we do this
one is iterative
iterated in order so we are take we are
doing so basically this one is what we
are doing the inorder
for both trees in parallel yeah but
dealing
in order we just take whatever is
smaller
right and this one is not uh
it's not recursion it's the
it's it's rated using the step right
okay that's it for today bye-bye bye-bye
bye bye