yeah you're given a positive integer
within the inner format of string and
then we also give a
single digit like one so can you tell me
you can remove any one
in here and the result should be the
maximum
so if we can
even talking so how many ones in this
position obviously okay so which one
remove by removing the second one
by removing the second one what we got
is one two three four why by removing
the first one what we got a two three
one four
things two three one four is bigger than
one two three four so you need to tell
me it's two three five four got it
get it it's exactly the same
why is it exactly the same this number
22 000 is bigger than one thousand what
do you mean exactly the same
okay what is that
there's not the number in there good
question that's a very good question to
us that you just returned nothing
except
return one two three one four that's
right if at least i even use this like
nine for them
okay simple okay another example
five five six
five
two three
one if we want to remove the five so
which five remove gives the the next
second one the third one
the third one
yeah if you remove this one
that will be five five six two three one
yeah if we don't move the first one or
the second one it's all the same five
six five two
yeah it doesn't matter so
you just
so you just
the thing is that you need to tell me
this number
yeah it doesn't you don't need to tell
me which number which side we did it
okay
okay simple
any sauce
uh you look at the number that's right
first of all look at numbers it has one
one of them and then easily just that
one okay okay that's that's a very good
point yeah
that's a very clever solution we go
through each digit if this digit is the
thing that we can delete right
then we try to do it to see what number
we can get
for things
and we maintain it back okay so look
this number okay so this is the one two
three four five okay so if we want to
remove this uh digit so this is i
this is the index i so we want to remove
the digit
sorry
so
s equals one two three four five if we
want to remove the index i i which is
here right so what we can do is look is
s
up to i not including right not
including this digit plus s
i plus 1 to the n right i plus 1 is here
to the end so basically what we are
saying by removing the
the index the character index 3
we are using the string
concatenation
up to i is 1 2 right look
s up to i is 1 2 x i plus 1 to the n is
4 5
so s up to i this big plus s i plus 1 to
the n this bit
1 2 plus 4 5.
it's the same thing as mu nu 3. okay
yeah got it that's so simple so we can
just do this
yeah today basically this is a simple
question
this is the question to test your python
the list the string
concatenation defined
as a max
remove
okay let's say we have given these
numbers
num
and we given this the k
okay so at the beginning answer you know
because these are
we are only given this the positive
individual right so we can just can
compare
two numbers by using compare
by comparing the layer string format so
what what i'm saying is that 1 2 3 is
bigger than
one
zero one right
this is the same thing as one two three
the integer bigger than one or one is
the same
yeah so we can either compare because
we're given this the string
we can compare directly the string or we
can convert it to integer
so if this one two three if we can
convert it to ind
this will give out one two three this is
the numerical format this is a string
vice versa
so we use the str functions
one two three this will give us
one two three okay so this is the basic
look
one two three this is a string we use
the int and they'll give us the
numerator if you want to think
in the opposite way one two three this
is the number we put str stands for
string we got the
quote one two three
when i said a code is a string it's not
a number but we can compare the number
the string yeah all the numerical values
that's what i'm saying so answer equals
at the beginning we put nothing there
okay
but okay so the thing is that previously
ryan you asked a very good question
what happened if k is not in numbers
yeah
yeah so we have to make a special
case for that to check okay so i'll talk
about that yeah
so look answer equal that then if we o4
i j
in enumerate okay what's enumerate i
talked about it i use this function a
lot in numerator what's that mean
uh index and values yeah
index value basically this is the very
helpful useful function so we don't have
to use it but by using that
yeah we can get the index and the value
at the same time if we don't use the
enumerate we have to do this for i in
range
lens number
then j would be
num i okay but by using this we make our
curve much cleaner for i j this is the
yeah top
topper is basically like a
immutable
list what's immutable
what's immutable anybody
can't change it yeah what's the opposite
of it
[Music]
means the opposite okay so for i j i is
the index j is the value okay so now we
check if j equal equal k okay okay
suppose this is the string
a character
if j character if current j character is
the character we can remove
right then we can do this answer equals
next answer we want to get a maximum
answer answer
what do we do
remember we talk about these yeah to get
uh
s equal as a string a string any string
ryan
and this is the index i we want to
remove so how do we move it
s
up to i
plus s i plus 1 to the n okay
yeah everyone right to get this point we
want to remove the string
we move the index i character from the
string s what we what we did is what we
use the string concatenation so
basically we are saying that okay we are
using the characters up to i
and we skip this character i and we use
the character
from i plus one to the n right so this
is this is the way to remove these ites
characters from the string
then
find the max answer
num
after i
plus
num
i plus one yeah
and then return
answer okay so look if if k is not here
that would return now right so
we probably can check we can answer if
answer
s yeah yes num right
okay
we can change these
into one line yeah so we can just say
return
maximum
maximum one
maximum of num
up to i plus num
i plus 1 to the n
for
i
j
in enumerate
num
if j equal equal k okay
okay
any question so far so so does this
handle the case that when the k
is not in
nouns
so if it's not in nouns okay look so
look if j is in not enough so look when
we call this max something
we're not going to get the maximum
element from a list yeah on from a list
if the list is empty then there will be
a problem
when the list is empty we try to get a
maximum
and then there will be a problem right
because the list is empty let's work
what when the j
when the k is not in the list so in this
case we have to put a second parameter
which is before we can say default
equals now okay
so what does it mean it means that when
the k is not in the list
then
these this the first parameter will be
empty then in the in the case when
when the list is empty now we return the
number so this is the basically
the
return answer is answer because if it is
there is no k
that equals to j then these will not
never be executed and an answer would be
always empty
and then if answer
if the answer is empty then we return
the number okay so we're changing one
two three four five five lines into one
ninth okay the time come back see
if there are n characters in the string
in the numbers what what what's the time
frame next um
space complexity are one constant right
so that if we consider
if we can see the these doesn't use
additional space okay
so a one okay but if this is needs
another space then
away okay so what have you learned today
about
that what what in one sentence can you
tell everybody like what have you
learned today just one sentence
um
[Music]
and then you find the biggest
exactly another way
yeah and then what's the solution
what's our solution
how do we do this
yeah how do we
yeah
every possibility of removing each digit
yeah if we go through this digit one by
one
and if this digit we can delete it we
try to do it and we a
number yeah we compare
okay that's it for today bye bye
[Music]