hello mister miss all right
yeah
okay so let's say we have uh given uh we
are given a list of words yes hey
b
[Music]
a b
a b c
d
[Music]
this is a word it was a list of strings
and
we are given a s which is abc we want to
find out
how many words how many strings in this
case
it's a prefix of s okay it's a previous
x so what's prefix
a prefix is a
word up there playing the beginning of a
word it's the substring application
[Music]
subscribe
continuous okay so how many can you give
me some substrings that is uh
of that's the substring of eric
[Music]
e
e obviously one single character e r i c
if two character has to be continued e r
i i c f
e r
r i i c three characters e i i c f
yeah and
and sometimes empty string is also
considered as a substring okay so how
many places
one plus one plus four plus three plus
two plus one
how many of
these 11 okay
how can we do this look how how can we
get the 11 so for example like if we
pick
nothing
yeah it would be nothing out of 4
characters c
c four zero
that's one if we pick one characters
that's c four one yeah
that's four waves if the substring
contains more than one character so it's
actually c four two how can we interpret
this
so we are picking we are picking one
index from the left we are picking
another one from the right we just go
through each word and we check if it's a
if it is a
prefix of the s and so this is actually
quite trivial we just use this that star
with yes stars
with function of the string
so define
f
words and we're given this as string so
answer equal and the beginning zero so
we go through this word w in words
now we say if s dot starts
with
w and then we just increment the counter
very easy yeah return answers
okay
yeah all right
so actually these these lines can be
converted using what one liner we can
just return
return one we can use this method sum
and map function some
map
s dot stars
and then the second parameter would be
the words
the first parameter of the map is a
function
yeah okay and now we basically were
saying that let's
let's
apply this function to the words to to
release the list or iterator yeah
and then
with that sum let's count how many of
them are returned to this return to so
this is the
same thing okay
sometimes you can you also write it seem
uh slightly different for example like
you can say return
we can stop
starts
with
w for
w in word
this is a list with pulling true or
false now we can count how many of them
are true right slightly different okay
so we also talked about the try trie
remember what's what's this
pi
tri is a data structure remember we
talked about this try
yeah let's root
and we want to insert the eic so we we
insert e
yeah
r
i
c okay so this is three and we also
insert right in this way so we insert
another one ah
y
a
and okay so for example let's say we
want to insert another one called
rick ryik so
r y
i
k okay so basically this is the tree of
the letters exactly so what why do we
need this kind of tree try
all three i'm gonna try so basically
this is
because they're prefixed yeah if it
begins something like if you wanna find
a ride yeah
and then
and then you find go to art because
yeah yeah
and then you
yeah i find ryan that's it yeah so yeah
very good that's basically the data
structure that help us to find the
prefix or search
any words right such a number we can
just follow the root of the you know
follow the path of the tree so so we can
construct you know we can construct a
tree and insert that s
so for example this s is abc so inside
this abc
and with this tree
then we can go through each word we can
go through each word to ch to use the
try to find if this word is a prefix if
it's in it's a prefix by following that
right so basically you know i'm not
going to implement this try again
perfect so suppose we have at least try
t equals try and then t dot insert
insert s right and then this is the same
thing so
t dot enter s now we can do this sum
okay i'm going to use another
color sum
sum what some t
dot
such we find a search search
uh
some uh actually map some map as he does
search and then words
okay
and that will be return some of it okay
within some of it so what have you
learned today
yeah perfect what are we trying to solve
here
uh
you find the
number prefix
is
and then
in the you know as here so we want to
find we want to count how many words how
many string in the words is is a prefix
of s and prefix is basically like a
substring that occurs at the beginning
right
so look if we are using this we already
have these in tyson right look s dot
starts with this is string the star ways
we don't have to implement these right
because they are already given so we can
just use this sum map so
uh you know basically this is like uh we
go through each word and we check if s
is
if w is a prefix of x and we implement
that and that can be
also implemented using the one lambda
yeah because we don't use implement it
starts with right so it's already
provided as it is then we just use it if
we want to implement this we can use the
try right we can build a try actually
by
uh try tree and insert the prefix insert
s right and then flow through each word
and delete so return
return sum
map t dot search words okay
so basically we're replacing this uh
starts with with the try okay
yeah okay let that be it for today okay
that'll be bye
you