hello mr mr ryan i right yeah and mrs
chesley okay okay so yeah what's
underground
an anagram is two words that use the
same letters
n a n h
g r a m s underground okay so can you
give me an example of the endocrine two
elegance
rice rice
listen and silent listen eat tea
and
eight
e t
okay that's a very good example eight
eighty yeah okay so basically a and a
yeah yeah that's enough
basically these these words are elegant
because they use send a number
of characters and
yeah each character is the same number
okay
yeah so look for example kt e1 a1s t1 ea
e1 a1
c1
ones e1
ones okay and listen right as well just
different order if you so
in if we sort those anagrams
what happens
if we solve the energy what do we get
we
get of anagrams so what let's put it in
our way so if we solve these emigrants
what do we get for this one if we
started you know a e t
if we saw this
a e t if we saw this
a you see do you see one again
so if we saw this
c
or
e i r okay
so so basically we're saying that if the
n ones we sorted and we're gonna send
num some words same string okay
yeah so today's question would be
we are given a list of words
and we have to grieve that unique yeah
we want to grow back
how do we do that i mean dictionary we
use dictionary yeah so we use the
dictionary before dictionary the keys
keys
we can do it with the sorted salty yeah
because we said if we saw the endergon
we got the same thing yeah yeah so you
the keys will be sorted and the value
will be the least of the
the end ones belong to the same group
okay
yeah make sense yeah
so before this generally the default
type will be the list
so define
group
anagram
underground okay
and i'm given this word so first of all
we have this data
equals d4 additionally before
additionally
we'll talk about that lots of time this
is a
class from the collections yeah from
collections into deposition and our
default type will be the list list of
words
now we go through this word w in what
because it is worse and then look
this is where okay and we
what do we do we salt it so that's a
salty version
salty w then we can you change it to
tupper yeah
to make it flexible yeah
because the keys needs to be hashable
but a pen
right a pen doubly and now we just need
to return
return data value yeah because that's
the thing we are going to return return
the list so basically we're going to
return this
data values
what's data value so it'll be something
like e a t
ate okay and then it will be
a list of the energon so different the
subways will be a group for the energon
so they'll be listen
and sign
the keys the keys will be the salty
version salty version of the energy yeah
what's the time complexity for this one
yeah no why is it going look at it
again
okay so you're part of this look we are
going through like if there are n words
so n word yeah and let's say the maximum
length will be k okay
not quite because we have assorted so if
we're saying the length will be k for
the
follow words so this part
come on don't guess this part takes okay
log k
if the k is the length of the w is k
but we have w we have n times so we
times n
okay so o n times k locate okay
yeah because we have something here yes
so
the other approach the other approach is
slightly
different right
the thing
come on the thing this is uh slow
because we have the salting here so we
need to stop each word right
so we can count
the the other way to check if two
strings are underground we just need to
count right we will use the counter
counter
counter we basically if we want to check
string a and b if they are underground
we just say retain counter a equals
equal count b right yeah we'll talk
about that but the thing is this counter
is an object
right so how do we put it
uh put in it as a key so we can just do
this we can just really see we can have
this if it's a
if these words are low order case and we
have 26
yeah we have we have 26 characters and
we want to talk let's create an array
and then we can do this
for c in w
d
o r d c
minus 97 plus equals one and then this
thing
theta
that's
tata we convert this to tata topper d
dot append this is the same
okay so let me explain this d
this is an array of 26
this is the
this is an array of 26 elements
representing the counter the number of
times that
for each alphabetic lowercase character
used okay and we go through each word
and then we update what's our d
this
yeah we talked about asking
what's the asking of the
uppercase a
um i forgot
65 what's the lowercase a 97.
okay so that ort is converting a
character to is to the number to asking
code minus 97 right because the
lowercase a is 97 minus 97 yellow so it
corresponds to the first
element okay
yeah so look so instead of sorting we
count we do the counting and then we
convert this counting this is a real
converted to the chapter then we can do
use it as a key
through dictionary right so the time
context is that if they are
n words and each word is k
so this time complexity is all n times k
okay
the space complexity for both cases all
n times k right because m was k yeah
just dictionary okay
you guys what have you learned today so
what come on right
now
what am i
doing with this energy
yeah and how do we do it what we talk
about very important data structure here
we use what
dictionary yeah key value pairs the keys
will be important to group the endograms
right because each the each enneagram
group has the unique keys so we can sort
it yeah we can sort of any ones in the
same group and then they all produce the
same
same key right or we can count it right
we can count we can do the counting for
the characters yeah
so we which one do you think is better
okay so look these two come time
complexity this one is o n times k the
first one we are you using sourcing it
will be o n times k
log k which one is better
okay that's it for today bye bye
bye bye good job
you