hello mr mr rhino right yeah we talked
about the binary before yeah look this
is the binary this is the maximum okay
we we know how to convert the numbers
from the decimal to the binary and vice
versa okay so how do we convert the
binary from from the you know from
numbers from parentheses for example
like one one one zero in binary what how
much is this investment
what's
what's this is
50 this is 15 and what's this
14 well done wow clever yeah exactly
yeah so how do we put this 16 easy look
you just have to
you just have to look this this the
right mouse bit is
one right this is one
this is two
this is four
this is eight yeah yeah if it's one you
just add it together yeah eight plus
four plus two plus one at least if this
is zero then we just stomach it so it's
a plus four plus two
and that's fourteen because this is zero
okay yeah one more example 101 1011
what's this what's this
eleven one
two
this is zero yeah and this is eight a
plus two plus you know
exactly whatever good job
how how about 33 in decimal we want to
convert it to
binary how do we how we do it
but the easiest way will be what 32 plus
one okay what's 32
2 to the power of
whatever 32
power of
5 yeah 2 to the power 5 plus 2 to the
power of 0 so 2 to the power 5 2 to the
power of 0 is one
one two three
four yeah two to the power five uh okay
one more digit two to the power five two
to the power one
uh
one two three four five so this is the
thirty-two okay thirty-two thirty-three
yeah make sense
okay
so
how can we do this in you know the
normal approach normal 33
divided by two is 16 remained 1 right
divided by 2
is a remains 0 divided by 2 is 4 remain
0 divided by 2 equals 2 remains 0
divided by 2 equals one remain
zero
divided by two equals zero remains one
and when we got zero we stopped so the
binary is this way
one zero zero zero two one okay four
zero yeah yeah we talked about like in
the very early days yeah
okay another example like uh 19 okay 19
converted to finally divided by two nine
remain one
divided by 2 4 remain 1 divided by 2 2
remain 0 divided by 2 1 remain 0 divided
by 2 0 remain 1 so what that was is 1 0
zero one one
okay let's verify
what's this it's two to the power of one
two three four
plus
plus two to the power of one plus two to
the power of zero so that's three
yeah and what's this 16 plus 3 equals
19. got it
yeah sorry coming back to binary the
problem with this is that right look
from three to four
there are three digits changed right one
change to zero one changes to zero zero
to change one right yeah so look uh if
we want to change from five to six we
need to change this
to
one digit two digit right
yeah
so we talk about hamming distance right
hamming distance is state of between two
numbers it's basically the number of
bits needs to change so the hamming
distance between four and five is
one digit one one digit right so we also
come up with a coding a great coding
which is called record you know that
could minimize the number of bit change
between a successive consecutive number
which is one digit you know we just have
two ways right
one digit could be
zero one right one digit yeah how about
two digits how about two digits
uh two bits yeah two bits
look at the normal way the normal way
would be one the normal binary will be
zero zero zero one one zero
one one why this is binary does it
does this satisfy this
okay from here to here only one bit
needs to be changed from here to here
now look
here
this is a binary
from one to two how many digits needs to
be changed how many fits needs to be
changed
this is zero one two three from one to
two
how many what's the humming distance
between two yeah because look glitches
here can you rearrange these four
numbers so that any two numbers only one
bit needs to be changed zero zero how do
we put it how do we rearrange these
numbers so that the only two even the
first one and the last one right look
the first one and last one two bits
needs to change
if we swap these two
so look how about we swap these two
so zero zero one zero zero one one one
doesn't make it better no because zero
zero and one one so how can we do it how
can we do it
do you see the problem right sit down
please
okay so if we solve this two
zero zero
zero one
one one
one zero
perfect let's look one digit change one
digit ten one digit change and even this
one on this one one this chain
yeah great job yeah yeah that's what i'm
saying this is great coding okay
great
great code
okay the guy whose name is greg designed
this so
the time the purpose of this is to
minimize the digit the bit change
between any two numbers even the first
one and the last one it's for the
electronic circuit yeah design yeah
so the humming distance the harming
distance between any kung
consecutive yeah consecutive or
successive what does this mean
successive
yeah is it the same thing as concept
security
meaning the two
seconds numbers even the first one the
last one is that
yeah and how about three digits it'll be
harder right but there's one way we're
going to talk about how to do this but
yeah it's slightly different right
different to the binary so look
one bit this is easy yeah only one big
yeah does it have to have four
no no no this this is one piece bits
only one bit okay how about two bits two
bit easy yeah zero one
two bit is this one
zero zero
zero one one
one one zero so how do we do this how
can we get it from one bit to two bits
easy look
so first of all
first of all
this is the magic
line
magic okay so how do you do this look
first of all we just copy these yeah but
reverse these things so here put it here
zero put it here one okay
yeah and then
i know what do we do
and then we just put a
zero zero here and then one one here
okay so let's become zero zero zero one
one zero one one okay
how about okay another third three
first of all we take this here yeah copy
here
and now we copy this bit put it here but
in the reverse order so it's one one
one zero zero one zero zero
okay
and then what do we do
this is the copy period this is a new
bit so we put zero zero zero zero and
then one one one one can you can we
double check
only one digit change
everyone did the chat
yeah one digit
okay okay sorry so
so that's a mistake here all right okay
change here to one zero okay
all right yeah so let's redo this okay
there was a mistake
that's a mistake
zero zero zero one one one one zero okay
then we copy this in the reverse order
so one zero one one zero one zero zero
and then we put
the first bill is the other one
oh yeah yeah that's why we got a mistake
okay ldl one one one one okay let's
double check
one one digit
one digit
and here
one digit this digit and here this digit
and this one this digit
and then this one this digit and even
this dip and then this one
one digit yeah
makes sense
so this one zero zero uh okay so this
one should be
one
and then this one zero okay
yeah
so look how do we solve this problem
look what did i just do
so
so you yes i do this in like mirror yeah
and then just do
my old ones zeros and then
okay so
this is the this is the base cases base
cases if we have one n equal equal one
then we know we need to return zero and
one right this is the base case
for a greater n
for the greater end we just do the n
minus k cases yeah f n we want to solve
the f now we just need to take
first of all take a
f a
a equals f n minus one cases
f
f equals a equals f and minus k 6 is
this one and then we need to reverse
this bit
reverse this bit okay
and then we need to put the first uh put
the one this one
is equals to two to the power of
how many digits
it's actually one shift n minus one
places yeah 50 and minus one
so this bit and i will put this number
in front of all the numbers
of a
i know we get it yeah
makes sense yeah
there are actually many ways to do this
grey coding but i i think this this is
one of the most easy to understand uh
straightforward way right so so i mean
you can also do using this backtracking
to do it
let's do this look define
and that's great gray coating gray
and
if
n equal one okay and this is the number
of bits yeah if n equals one we just
return the base case is zero and one
right
this is the face cases now what do we do
okay let me just write this at zero one
okay and then we what do we do we just
take this zero one and then we reverse
it put it here and put it here one zero
yeah so this bit yeah
this bit and then we put a zero zero at
the beginning one one okay yeah you
missed something what wasn't it you
missed cash
not yet no yeah we've talked about that
probably we don't need a cash but good
good point yeah if you if we are going
to use this function a lot many many
times then that's a good idea to put a
cash to remember the values we have
calculated yeah okay let's do that again
so
this is this is n right this is n cases
this is m n minus one
so first of all we take we first of all
we take a previous one previous one
equals gray
n minus one right so this previous one
would be zero one right
right all right but now we need to find
out what what's this value what's this
one what does it equal in binary it
equals how many digits of that that will
be n minus one digit yeah so it's
actually this k
this this k let's let's name it k k will
be equals one shifted shifty and minus
one yeah yeah so if what does it mean it
means one
followed by
how many zeros
and minus one zeros but this is in
binary okay come on this is in binary
what what does this mean k
one shift is shifted n minus one is
basically meaning that okay one here
shit one
shifty one shift is 51
means okay i shift one position to the
left so that'll be one zero i shift for
another position to the left that will
be one zero zero right it's basically
like the same as two to the power of 2
1 2.
one shift is shifted
2 is 1 0 0
in binary so basically this is the same
as 2 to the power of
2 okay
okay this is k so now we want to put the
k this is the value in front of the
reverse one right so we first we need to
return what we turn
right we turn that this bit yeah but in
indicate this is still exam we put a
zero in front of the values it doesn't
make it make a change it doesn't change
it right all right
this value look zero zero zero one is
the same as zero one right if we put a
zero in front of a number
it doesn't change this value right even
in decimal right
a hundred you put a zero in the front it
doesn't change the 100 but it's still
equals to 100 i'm right
yeah so return previous we still need
that result the previous is listed
plus but we want to pass this video
yeah we're going to plus this fix now k
we need to put a pen this k to all the
numbers in front right
plus what
k plus x
yeah for
x in
in
this previous but in previous we have to
reverse it how do we reverse it how do
we reverse the list
minus one column column minus one yeah
okay i like it look
now okay and why don't you put the
mention a very
important point cash
just to remember the values yeah
this is just to say that uh
if going to we run this many many times
better to memorize it right memorize it
what's the harming distance between any
two digits like zero zero one yeah
exactly because only one digit change
and we're going to talk about a genetic
genetic aggregator yeah genetics
what does this word mean genetic
mutated genetic pokemon genetics what
does it mean it's in biology right yeah
genetic
look
like you're not another parent yes mommy
and daddy yeah
mom and daddy
you are the offspring of mommy and daddy
offspring
yeah
yeah but you too
get some
genes for mommy and daddy but with some
mutation right
yeah so we're going to apply this kind
of biology
you know knowledge into ignorance so
basically we have a few parents parents
and then parents do this crossover
cross over
with the gin cross over
and then we we you ryan yeah you get
something
from mommy and daddy everybody you get
something from mom and daddy but
slightly you're different right let's
call the mutation
let's mutate i'll get a pokemon flashy
what's the mutation
what's immunity
i don't know
immutable mutable what's mutable can't
change yeah mutation is that your gene
is
for example you maybe you can change
yeah yeah for example you get maybe i
don't know eighty percent of genes for
mommy and daddy and with two twenty
percent slightly different that's a
mutation
yeah so that's very useful this quaker
is very useful in muta in a genetic
argument why is that because
because with the mutation it's just
slightly different right slightly
different so we can use this to apply
the mutation because look
the grey curve the next
the next number in the grey curve series
only slightly differs only one bit right
only one bit so for each bit we can
consider it as a gene so let's look at
mixed number zero zero one and zero zero
and zero two one we can consider it as a
gene right for example this one
maybe can be represented as the color of
the hair
you know the the intelligence yeah
i don't know how tall you are right so
each num each bit could be
a gene determine something and then we
this uh mutation we can with a grey
curve because when the breaker
determines that we can use the quaker to
to
to go up to to mutate the gene right
okay so this is a very interesting topic
maybe we can talk about
you know in the future
okay so to sum up this is kind of the
mirror way
we take m minus one yeah we take n minus
one greater
yeah the base case is still one right we
know how to solve the base case zero one
with the logarithm or we take it
whatever we have
and we put it
we will put it in the reverse and we'll
put it one in the front okay so
let's do the
number three again okay let's do the
number
okay okay
let's do take these one more example
okay so look zero zero zero one one one
one zero and then we take
take whatever we have and then reverse
the order so that's one zero one one
zero one zero zero and we'll put a zero
zero and one one in the front okay so
that will be one digit change
one digit change
one digit
i wanted to change
okay i wanted to change one digit
here one digit change
yeah one digit okay i'm going to
mark
these please this only one did you
change
from zlj1 to 011 is this did you change
yeah is it
yeah
okay that's it for today bye bye bye bye
bye