hello hello mr mister right now right
okay so let's say we have numbers yeah
one two three four five yeah okay
six seven eight nine go go yeah
nine numbers yeah if you want to pick
k numbers these cannot be duplicate so
for example like if i pick k equals
three numbers
and n equal n is the sum n equals seven
so basically
picking three numbers you can only use
one number once yeah you can use any
digit any number one let's pick three
numbers out of these ten numbers and
each number can only use one and then
can we get a list of the sum
to seven
do i make myself clear so basically we
have we need to pick three numbers one
two four we're done one two one so can
you tell me
if xk is bigger than nine do we have a
solution
because
and then if we pick more than nine
numbers what will happen
that's right that would be difficult you
can't use reuse the number okay so k
equals nine we need to return empty this
and how about the sum can we put a
constraint on the sum each number we
need to pick at most once so what's the
thickest sum that the list can have
so what's the biggest uh thickest
why is that 24 7
not talking about this yeah you are very
very i'm i'm talking about any k and any
n so what's the thickest n
that
a list can have given the constraint we
are using only number each number once
we are very close if we pick in three
numbers seven eight nine how about if we
keep speaking
where down how do you connect for forty
five
which numbers
how do you get this multiplied
exactly yeah because this k nine number
uh this is nine numbers one plus two
nine okay yeah if k is bigger than 9 or
n bigger than 45 then we need to write
an empties because there's no need to
search right because it's
it's not satisfying
the fact that we only
picking one number once pick one
and most ones yeah and most ones each
number so what's your thought i mean
what's yourself how can we do this we
can use the breakfast search
we can use the preference search that's
also and different search travel search
test massage in this case we can you
know do some branching so that would be
a backtracking so for example let's say
if we let's start from picking one first
number yeah okay let's say picking first
number one
at the beginning we have empty picking
first number one
yeah
is it
do we have enough k numbers
yeah if k if we have enough k numbers we
check the sum if it's equal to n
right if it's e then then we place into
the list
if not we continue the next number we
can pick is more than one right because
we cannot reduce this
can we pick a one two number two right
so
so we try to pick each
number and i will try to see if we have
enough k numbers
also if we have already
well the sum right but if it is if we
satisfy the first requirement and we put
the candidate list into the
array right yeah and in and and the case
is if we have more than k numbers we
return we just go back we just go back
for example like
you know we if we only have k equals
three one two three
then if it's more than three numbers so
we just go back we don't
don't continue to pick
right and if it's the sum look if it's a
sum it's bigger than the current sum
is bigger than the sum then we don't
need to continue right because the
currently what we have is more than n so
there's no need to keep picking i'm
right
okay so this kind of thing is definite
search and if we apply the branch you
know chord then that they'll actually
become a
backtracking what's backtracking
backtracking
is
looking back
so so basically look
one so you go you visited the tree right
you visit the tree and then you find out
there's no need to continue you go back
checking right
you continue to dig as far as you can
but at some point you realize there's no
point to keep picking the next number
why is that because that
there could be two things
one is we have picked more than k
numbers
or
the currently the numbers on our basket
the sum is more than n right so in if
one of these satisfies there's no need
to continue then we go back
right so we don't
waste the time keep putting other
numbers yeah it's like a
picking number picking the you have a
basket you have numbers you put you try
to pick each numbers yeah yeah
now you have a big basket and then if we
want to pick look k equals three numbers
n equals seven the sum
right this is the basket
this is the available numbers yeah
available numbers
okay because currently my basket have
one four
eight
do i need to continue picking the
numbers taking the numbers put it here
why is that
because if
you're gonna
get over k
yeah yeah yeah and also okay so that's
maybe here
do we need to pick another number
no because it's over n
yeah exactly okay and how about look at
one and two and three
do we need to pick another number
nine because one more number will become
more than three numbers right exactly
yeah let's kind of backtracking so one
and twenty three
oh yeah so basically this is like a
thing yeah we
at some point it's a different search
it's in a different search but we apply
some logic in it
yeah if we don't apply this logic we
keep finding the numbers look you will
pick all the combination right and then
there's no point because they're not
part of the answer
we don't waste the time doing that it's
like a tree yeah we don't waste the time
doing that that could be a massive there
could be a massive tree here but we
don't export it why is that because we
find out there's no point keep doing
that we already know
no matter what numbers
chosen from now
yeah it won't be part of our collection
okay
so let's implement this the definition
and then now b
first of all we have this answer yeah
answer
then we have to check if n is bigger
than 45 or k is bigger than
nine that would return empty this yeah
there's no point to continue
okay bear this in mind okay this is very
important optimization
i know we have this different search
okay so we have the current selection
and
we have the next number to pick next
number to pick let's say a okay
right
and then i want to read i want to do
this step first at the beginning we
started empty this an empty basket and
we start from the first number right
let's say we start from the first number
okay so now if the length
of current
is bigger than
numbers or
one
or what all the sum
of the carbon is bigger than n
then there is no point we return okay
and then we do another check if length
current is equal k and
the sum
current is equal and then we put this
current
to the answer yeah answer that append
append current okay we need to make a
copy of the selection because it's a
list we need to make a copy
deep copy okay look this is the d copy
this one this one yeah so this is an
array yeah array
one two three if i say b equals a r
this is an alias array it's a it's it's
not a copy then we need to do this
okay put this column that's a diff copy
and then we'll return otherwise we try
the next number for i in range
we start from the next number right next
number would be
a
what a plus 1 to 10
tonight tonight actually included then
that first search
current
plus
i
uh
actually this is a
we start with the a
to
the next number if we pick the current
on the i then we the next number we can
pick is greater because we can't pick
the i again so it will be i plus one
okay yeah
and then we just pretend answer
okay
yeah that's the
that's the backtracking effort
backtracking okay
okay so the thing is that look every
time we need to do this sum
we can we can accumulate a sum when we
do this different
uh different search right look current
currently every time every iteration at
every recursion call we need to do this
and this is very time consuming and we
can do some optimization is by putting
this some at the beginning we haven't
picked anything so let's let's let's put
the thumb yellow here
okay and then i'll have i change here to
current sound
calendar instead of some current and i
we can do this current sum
yeah and this is the same current sum
and then
we pick the number i so the current sum
needs to be updated current sum plus i
okay
yeah so the time conductor is quite
tricky we love this you know it's this
yeah because look with this n is bigger
than 45 or k is bigger than nine
then we just written empty this there's
no point to search so we say in mind the
the problem is actually you know bounded
by the constant so the time complexity
will be a one
do you give me
yeah do you get me because we we have
this problem the upper bound is bounded
by a constant yeah because when the size
is bigger then there will be
we don't continue right so that's
limited
but if we don't consider this big if we
don't cancel this big this is the thing
is that there's
nine numbers we're picking k numbers
yeah what we talk about the c
c
nine numbers picking k numbers
equals one c not c is the combination
picking
four apples speaking to apple how many
ways
there are four apples
picking two apples
it's hot
okay let's see this is equals to
four
factorial divided by
two factorial divided by four minus two
factorial
equals what equals four times three
divided by two times one is six yes
you're right six
c combination yeah the permutation is
with orders yeah so permutation is
actually without p 4 2 is actually
without these two terms yes
2 4 0 divided by 4 minus 2
4 minus 2 factorial okay
and then let's write it p
p and m
n items picking m items
with orders yes
n factorial divided by m factorial
divided by n minus n
factorial oh no without these okay
this is the permutation permutation yeah
permutation
one two three
three numbers four permutation one three
two two one three
two three one three one two three two
one there's six yeah three factorial
equals six okay
first of all we we perform the
permutation and then we divide it by m
we okay but this is n for permutation
right so that not be a combination right
yeah because all these one two three one
three two two one three two three one
three one two three two one this is one
combination right one combination so we
divided by three factorial this is what
it is here one factor right here okay
think about this way okay
so so the time connection without
looking at this one is c
c
c nine k okay and then at the end we
need to make a copy of the combination
so it's time k
right yeah there's a iterator from
italy
import
combination yeah then actually this is
already
provided and we have also permutation as
well so what does this mean combination
so we can do this combination
combination and then we can have this
range the first one parameter is the
iterator we want to perform a
combination of the one to nine numbers
and we want to pick k numbers yeah so
this gives the
combination and then we just have to
check if any combination of these so
return
x for x in
at least one
and this is the iterator so we have to
convert it to a list
if
sum
x equal equal n simple as that look
combination
the same thing goes with combination the
first parameter is that the thing we
want to pick the apples right so we want
to pick k
numbers out of 10
numbers and we want to check if any of
them
sum up to n
wow look
simple
yeah yeah
for example like com com combination a
combination let's say
one two three and then if we want to
pick two
if you want to pick two so what does it
give us it'll give us one two
one three
two three and that's it look
very powerful and then for the
permutation if you change this to
permutation
what is what does it give us you will
give us one two
one three
two three
and then the reverse yeah
two one
three one
three two okay yeah look permutation
different order is kind of counted as a
different permutation but combination is
the same okay
yeah
okay what have you learned today so far
today
okay so what's the problem what's the
problem there's there is
what's the problem so we have n
[Music]
we have ten numbers one to nine and we
can pick
k numbers so it sum up to n right
so we can do this backtracking yeah
backtracking is basically the default
search with some branch optimization
right so we cut up some branch when we
realized it there's no point to continue
right this is the back charting okay and
we also can use the preferences
yeah
given time we're not implementing it
today and we also talked about this
from italy
combination permutation we can use this
one return x
for x in this combination range 110
this is the nine ten numbers we want to
pick k numbers do the combination i want
to check each combination which
combination sum up to end okay that's it
for today bye