hello mr miss narendra right yes okay so
last lesson we talk about uh combination
sum so there are nine numbers we want to
take
k numbers let's sum up to n yeah we want
to return such a you know a list of
these summaries so for example when k
equals three we want to find the three
numbers
you can pick the three numbers from one
to nine we have to pick three each
number can only be used once and can we
find such this that sums up to nine it
could be many yeah for example like six
one two three one three one five two one
four uh okay last lesson we talked about
the backtracking which is kind of like
uh definite search yeah we try to go as
deep as we can and we realize that at
some point there's no point continue
there's no point continuing not this
three yeah there's no point continue
based on the current state there's no
point to continue then we just backtrack
to the previous state okay so there's no
point wasting time searching
a subtree
when we realize that there's no point
doing so so for example if for each node
we can store the the current choice of
numbers and if we find out that we have
more than k numbers there's no point to
keep adding it right there's no point to
keep adding it and also if we find out
that the the sum
the sum of the current choice is smaller
than n and there's no point to keep
adding it why is that because if we keep
bringing more numbers then that would be
obviously more than n right which is
normal uh the thing we are looking for
okay
so
we also talked about it to us from
literature input combination so and also
we can use the permutation so
return x for x in combinations you know
the first parameter will be the
the choice and the iterator so we are
giving it range 110 meaning that we have
nine numbers and we also pick numbers as
a combination i know we we can use the
least comprehension return x y x in this
you know this is the
proof of thing the
provost in all the combination right and
then if sum
equals n right and we can also use the
backtracking so how do we factor so we
keep adding the numbers you know until
we find the solution so basically it's
like uh define yeah define
the default search we have this current
list and then we have the current sum
and we have these current numbers
right current numbers i
if current sum current sum is is bigger
length and
or if the length of current is bigger
than k yeah because if we have more the
sum more than n or we have take more
than k numbers than we just repent and
then the other thing we need to check if
current sum equal equal n or the length
k length the current equal equal k when
we find the one this then we need to
append it so answer the append
append current and we need to make a
copy of that right
otherwise we just check the
next number for x in range
we check from the i to 10
uh up to 10 not including 10 to 9 then
we do this definite search if we use the
local number x then what will you
current plus
the x
the custom will be updated current sum
plus x and the next number we can use is
x plus one right
okay yeah yeah
yeah right just at the beginning we try
with the empty list and the current sum
is zero and we start with the first
number easy okay let's definitely search
backtracking okay so coming back to this
combination we can actually replace this
combination yeah
if we define this combination of a c o
and b combination so coming if we want
to replace this current i we want to
have this cover a combination which is
the first parameter would be the current
these current choice i will be the next
number
okay so then we need to if length
current equals k
then we can year yeah what's the year
year current and return
otherwise we can just try
for i in for x in range
i to the 10 up to 10 not including 10
then we can yeah from
yeah from
here from what current
plus x and then x plus one okay so
basically this function is just to to
generate the iterator yeah yeah yeah
meaningless promise yeah i promise you i
want to generate these for you when you
need it
so
in this current list and up that's the
number let's we can pick
right for example if this is 2 that
means that we can pick the numbers
greater or equal than two
okay
and then for each number we can just try
to the earth from okay yeah from and
then this is the location here from
combination
uh column plus x x plus one okay
this is the combination and how about
the preferences what kind of data
structure we need to use to implement a
purpose yes eq and impression
specifically is dq double and liquid
so so
it's just that because we have this
three right we have these three we can
visualize the search
by the tree so at the beginning we start
with the empty bs right empty this and
then the tree the first note would be if
left side try to put the number one okay
if we the number one let's that's still
okay to add more numbers then we start
with that number uh we add another
number two and keep going number number
three
so you know for the backtracking deficit
is going down as deep as we can and if
not we go back but for the breakfast
search
we're doing level by level so now we try
the first number we try the second
number with uh the number two number
three etcetera okay so level by level
we're using the dq okay so let's
implement this defined
preference search
at the beginning with the q q equals dq
and then we given this uh
couple the first one
is disk and the sum
the sum will be zero the next number we
want to try we can try from is one
okay and then wire q yeah right why
there are elements in the queue so we
need to find out how many of them let's
say size sc
equals the length of cube so
if we get this sd so it means that there
are sc numbers of nodes in the current
key which belongs to the same level and
then let's pop in then let's pop it out
each by it okay
in range fc
so now we have this current
current sum
and the x the note we want we can try
equals q's of top left
we're taking from the left first thing
first oh yeah so we need to dq from the
left of the queue okay
now so then we can try if the sum equal
equals n
and
the length of the current equal equal k
then we can just answer the append
append uh
append a copy of the current okay copy
okay
as as what as if
as if
carbon we want to find out
we want to find out as if the length of
the current is smaller than k
yeah we still have
we still have numbers to pick
and
the sum
the length of the sum
the sum is smaller than n yeah we the
numbers we pick do not exist the sum
okay then we actually we need to go
through the numbers for i in range we
start from the x up to 10 not including
10 q append
attend
dot plus
plus one
column plus the i
s plus i the sum needs to be incremented
by i and then the number needs to pick
is the
i plus 1 x if we pick the number i the
next number we can pick is i plus one
and now b
yeah okay
let's press the search
okay
so what have we learned today
[Music]
so what are we doing today what are we
doing
we're adding numbers
yeah so come on it's meant to be what
what what do we learn
what's the new what's some what's new
today
the problem is there are
only numbers one to nine yeah
and
you can use each one number one yes
and you have to make the target whatever
it's called yeah
yeah we talked about that yesterday and
the day before yesterday so what's new
today
what's the queue
yeah what's the anchor then come on
yeah
yeah uh last lesson we talked about the
deficit backtracking okay
so today it's just reference search for
the process you will use the dq but with
the dq we need to store all the nodes on
the same level but with the default
search we don't need to store all the
nodes in the same level right we just
kill
just follow the path as deep as we can
and if not we just go back okay
yeah okay that'll be for today bye bye
bye