hello mistery mr runner all right
okay so let's say we have a finally tree
yeah finally what's finally what's to
find and what's three is it basically
three obviously
okay so what's
what's the difference between a by a
tree
and a graph
three is a girl that's
excellent three is a graph the graph is
not necessarily a trick right so three
for three you know it doesn't have
cycles right and then what else
it's
it's also
what
directly a cyclical
be connected well if it's different than
what we call it like forest okay if we
both of these
if each of these is a tree then we call
it a forest okay forest lots of trees
yeah
okay so no cycles a cyclic locker no
cycles and each node has only one parent
directive okay each each node has only
one parent and the one which does not
have parent we call it
what's this we call it one and one have
more than one route
yeah yeah yeah excellent yes and we the
ones we love the kids we call it
what do we call it what are these nuts
four five six seven leaves leaves yeah
it's actually like upside down too yeah
if you're looking from the upside down
that's the rule that's the branch
always uh koi trunk trunk
and the
leaf
and finally the three is basically like
uh each note can have at most two kids
okay left and right okay so today is the
question very easy
so we have uh
a balance tree and you know the biology
usually you have this node and then the
node that will have this value
[Music]
and we have this left and we have this
right pointer so now we're going to add
one more field which called next
so initially the next pointer will be
all initialized to noun and then
we want you to
populate the binary so that each node
points to the next the next
point to the one on the third level yeah
so basically i
we want you to
add one more link yeah
that's it
you get my point
yes do you get my point
so we want
to point the note to the next on the
right
on the same level
yeah so basically look this is left and
right yeah left and right but we want to
add one more next which is initialized
to be nine but we want to point to the
the one on the right okay
so the root does nothing
exactly okay because it does not have
any notes on the right of the root right
yeah
so when we okay so does it remind you
something look the same thing the note
on the right on the same level okay so
what's hint is that same level
so
well done breakfast easy so probably we
can do this definitely but perfect
search is the way to go right it's very
obvious so we just reference search
and then
by taking because look the breakfast
search actually we can implement in two
ways one way is that every time yeah
look this one two three four five six
seven eight nine okay so we have a queue
dq double ndq yeah okay so how do we do
this first of all we put the note in
yeah
look one
okay
that's the initial state okay
i take one out i take everything out
from the queue because that's the all
the notes in the skew is the same level
only one note on the first level and i
push it keep
it's a kid
i take one out yeah
what's that no what's the children of a
two and three of one two three yeah okay
i'm gonna put it in yeah two and three
in q
okay so now look
all the notes in the queue
two and three there are two ways one way
one way of pressure searches i can take
it one note at a time so i take the two
out and then push the kids is full and
fine all i can take the other way is i
can take two and three oh at the same
time and push each kid because i know if
if i do it this way i know at any time
all the notes all the notes in the queue
belongs to the center look two and three
the number yeah so how about that i take
a two out two and three out you know dq
take it out
first in cersei what's the children of
two four one
four and five what's the children of
three
you see look now four five six seven
what are these notes in common
we're done okay so now i do the same i
take four five six seven out and i push
their kids which is eight and nine right
so i take these out everything go out
here like four five six and i put a and
nine look a and nine the same the same
level yeah so
if we do it this way we can make sure
all the notes in the queue belong to the
same level why do we need that because
if we know that all the nodes in the
same level then i can point
this node to the one on the on the next
we want to put the node put three screen
next
we're going to put the node next to the
one on the right okay
so we want to add one more link
from the note
and to the one on the left on the right
okay so we'll put the formula to a five
five to the six six to seven right okay
now we can do this question search how
do we implement a preference search
usually
you know this question
how do we implement a process search uh
key and in python we can use the
dq double
breath
means white yeah yeah as opposed to
death
depth okay
this is different okay breasts
that okay
okay
okay okay
okay now let's implement this square for
search okay breakfast breakfast okay
okay let's see that's it that's it
define
let's say populate right pop right okay
popular right
popular right okay and i'm given this
blue node
okay so q equals dq
the amount is of using dq as opposed to
at least you know we can in python we
can use the list to implement a queue
right first thing first off right but if
you go for this approach the amount
the disadvantage of using that is as a q
is because that but the operation when
we do this q probe zero this is linear
time okay as opposed to the q the top
left which is constant okay dq and root
so
as the normal preference such while q
and we check n is length q this is the
number of nodes in the currency belongs
to the same level and then we can do
this four
or four
and go in range
and now we do this current
q dot one if we want to take a note
from the queue
first thing first of all what method
is this q dot one
power left pop left here left
if we don't specify left right then
you'll be the right yeah
yeah yeah
a pen a pen left look q dot pop
without the left is right
q dot append with down the left is right
okay if we don't say which way it by
default on the right hand side okay
okay and then we have to do this
look at this is the number of notes in
the curve in the queue yeah in the queue
like one uh two three okay n is two two
notes okay and then we go through each
note then we pop it we take a two out
and we have to check if current the left
then we push it back we append it to
append the left kick to the to the back
to the queue so cue the
append karen does that i understand
what's next is if what can you guess if
ewa turn the right is calling the right
and then what
a pen what
and now
look we just pop it and then if look
a tiny and then the next the most
important thing now is to link it to add
this link so add this link right
how many notes we need to link we need
to add a link
four five six seven which nose needs to
be adding a link
[Music]
yeah how many links
okay so
which link which note does not need to
add a link
yeah yeah yeah yeah but but i mean the
same level which note does not have to
be as a link
let's take a look at the notes on the
side all right far right the one on the
right is no because the points do
nothing right exactly so then we have to
check
yeah
okay so okay so we have to okay so let's
we have to use this index for i yeah so
if i
not equals n minus one because if it's n
minus one it's a instant white on the
right right then we have to pop it we
have to we have to link it so
so what current dot next e chord q zlo
this is the thing today because all the
rest is processors can you explain to me
what if i
when when is the case when i is n minus
one
if i not equals n minus 1 what does it
mean
if i it means i if i doesn't
it means
if i not equal
what if i i is n minus 1 what's it what
does it mean it means if it doesn't
point to anything okay so if i is n
minus one it means the what the note is
on the far on the right right so if it's
not on the right
yeah if i write then we can point
current the next original points to q
zero what's q zero can you tell me
what's q zero what's q zero mean
q this is the q q zero is what the
okay so this is the q
one two three there's three notes in the
queue so q0 where is it
which one is q0
yeah so it's the front of the queue
right this is the q first thing first
off you go in here you take it out here
q0 is the front of q so here look if we
are here q zero because we already
taking top left we take the four out so
the q zero will be five right
for if i'm visiting a five q zero will
be six so what this means is that i'm
current i point to the next
pointer to the right okay
except the last one is at the node on
the far
far right right yeah
so this is the thing all the rest is
reference search the time complexity of
n n is the number of nodes in the binary
tree okay let's face complexity o n
because we are using the dq
got it
okay to sum up what have you learned
today come on
follow me
yeah no no what have you learned today
you need to explain to me in one
sentence not in one word or two words
okay so what we have learned today what
what's the problem
and
what are we trying to solve today and
what kind of approach are we using
taking we're using breakfast yeah we're
using
to do what software kind of program
come on
don't give me a few words i want a
sentence a whole sentence so okay we got
you
what's the problem first of all what's
the problem the problem
is i have hiccups
sorry what's that we have a tree
obviously we have a banner tree yes and
then we're supposed to
buy the next number yeah in the level
the same level okay so we try to write
we we try to add the link to the right
on the set on the note on the same level
okay and what's the approach we're
taking to solve this what's the approach
graphics search and i'm implementing
using a queue okay so two okay i'll give
you an example yeah next time i ask you
this question you can answer it right
now okay so today the problem is that we
are given a binary tree and we want to
add a link
for any node
yeah
any node or in the binary to the one
to the to its neighbor on the right in
the same level okay an approach we're
taking today
is breakfast search because the
preference search
is
used normally to do this level by level
traversal
and when doing this level by level
transfer we add a link here except the
last one that's not on the far right
right because it does not point to any
neighbor on the right there's no
neighbors on the right
and right
yeah got it yeah that's it for today
thank you bye