hello mr and mr ryan all right we have
an array to
represent a list of meetings and then we
want to find out if
a person if you can attend all the
meetings right so for example like we so
for simplicity okay so we just use the
number to represent the time of the
meeting start and end for example like
we have a meeting like
start at one and a ten
another meeting at start at 20
finish at 70.
can we attend all the meetings
yeah because i can attend i can attend
this meeting one to ten and then go in
order
okay that's a very good question it
doesn't have to be necessary you know
that's for example if i give you like
three
five and then i give you another one
four can we attend
all the meetings why is that
because so
why why we can't attend these two main
things that you know let's put this
number the meetings
in this line right this is zero okay so
one two four
one
two
three
four one two four one four so
this meeting is start the duration is
here right wonderful another another
meeting three to five
so another meeting
three to five okay so look
we have an overlap so if two meetings
have overlapped we can't attend all of
them right okay so and another thing is
that if we we we can attend the meeting
immediately right so for example like
after right so for example zero one and
then only finish the first meeting we
can have this attend the second meeting
from one to two yeah that's what i mean
it has to be in order to be
you know
okay you mentioned a very good point
order so
yeah so we can
all the we can solve this array right so
to make a solid array in by the time by
the start time okay so what's your
thoughts in this so
so um how do we check if the person can
attend all the meetings
you mentioned a very good one so how do
we check there are two ways basically
you know how do we check how how we
first yeah proof of how to improve us we
have end meetings so we want to check if
the person can attend all the meetings
so how can we prove us what are we
checking exactly so
so yeah i know then the question is how
do we check all the if the person can
attend all the meetings how do we check
it i mean we want to find out what there
are meetings so this is a way all right
this is all the meetings meeting meeting
array
and it's an array of arrays and each
each array each separate way is has
has two numbers one for the star term
the other one for the end term
um
so what is this
what are we checking i mean what are
which is
of what come on you're not you're not
answering
right
yeah you're not answering the question
directly so what i'm what are we
checking so if we find out in what kind
of if two meetings what then we can
attend all the meetings
okay
so what's what's it called so what
what's this
intersect yeah so we we want to find out
so let's we're going to find out if
there are two meetings that overlap each
other if i overlap then we can attend on
the meeting right this is overlapping
okay
make sense
so
with overlapping it's very easy right so
we if not n
n meetings when we need to prove us the
time complexity will be what
if we want to check any two what's the
potential that's even o n square where
that one square
and then we just have to say for i in
range n for j in range
for j in range i right now including i
if if meeting if overlapped meeting i
meeting j then written fourth right
otherwise written two right this is o n
square right so
how about look ryan you mentioned a very
good point to sort it in order if we saw
the meetings in order by the start time
right
so look at this meeting how do we find
out look if this is meeting in order 1 4
5 6
okay 6 7
6 8
seven nine okay can we attend all the
meetings here do we have a lower left
here yeah
six a yeah lesser media okay so listen
overlap so how do we find out look if we
saw this array by the start time one
five six seven
then how do we check we just have to
check the ending the meeting ending of
the current meeting
if it's bigger
than the starting of next meeting then
there will be overlap right look six
eight eight yeah
color meeting ends at eight right but
the next meeting starts at seven
like this is seven
yeah that's good look
six if it's
okay so we can just finish and straight
go to the next one but let's probably
get a rook a
the end of a
but the next meeting starts seven
okay so what does this mean
if the overlapping will turn fast easy
yeah what's the time complexity here
first of all we thought and the next one
again we're down good that's very good
because look we saw this array oh and
again and then
the second first of all we saw the array
the next the second one the second pass
we just go through the meetings in order
we check if the current end
time is bigger
than the start and the next meeting then
if it is then that's the overlap will
determine i don't know all retention
yeah easy okay
yeah
so which one is better come on
that one
that is first one second one
yeah this is better than that right yeah
okay so now
let's implement this should be quick
and easy yeah define
can attend okay a 10
attempt okay meeting let's use n
first of all n equals the length meeting
then m the saw so yeah oh and again this
is one of them yeah but we want to start
by default it's solved by the first
element which is the start time but if
you want to be specific you can say
thought
so by what key equals what p equals num
da
x x zero x zero x zero is the first
number which is the
which is the start okay let's
that's the sorting and now we need to go
through for i in
range
right right range to n minus one
yeah
now if
if the meeting
i
and
for the the second value will be the end
time is bigger
if it's bigger than the
next meeting start time
then we return fourth right return first
otherwise we return true right
yeah
so what are we doing here is that we try
to find the viral and overlap if we find
an overlap we return first otherwise
we'll return true right yes so this
thing this these
four lines
you can do using this o or function
remember we want to find out all return
return or oh what is mean means
everything needs to satisfy or
what m i
1 needs to be smaller or equal than
m i plus 1
for
i in
range
range n minus one okay so this is the
same thing look
the logic here if we find a violation we
return false at least one is what
means
all the conditions needs to be
true or right
yeah everything here needs to be true if
one of them
is fair it is false that is false okay
what's all that's all right
yeah
and we talk about any
right so what's any pretend
if i say any what does it mean
what does any mean
what's the difference between all and
any
any it could be one of them
has to be every single one exactly
that's perfect yeah so any if i say any
i put a not
is it the same thing or
can i write it the same english sentence
like honey it's the same thing yeah
all right
yeah
look all needs needs to be exactly that
everything needs to be true
not any so i have to
i have to
neglect the condition here i have to say
mi
if
one if it's bigger than m i plus one
zero for i this is the same okay so
basically this sign yeah look
okay smaller or equal if i use the not
any i have to make it bigger the
opposite
can can we uh understand this better so
for example if all your students in your
class needs to have a score
six at least six in this exam oh right
the opportunity
not any so it's the same thing as
any of the student in your class has the
score less than 60.
i put a knot you see the same thing
you see the same thing
yeah
yeah do you understand this
is the same thing i'm i'm asking that
everybody in your class
needs to attend the 60 or more
yeah in an exam
all i'm asking
not
any
of your
other students you know class has less
than 16. these two is the same thing
right but we neglect these
this line is different right but we put
a not
not any is equal to all right
yeah makes sense
so it's a little bit tricky here okay
but look we're using this fancy syntax
and if you
i mean if you want you can still use
this this is still good right so we are
trying to find out the violation and or
fighting of overlap if you find an
overlap that then we can not attend
these two meetings at the same time okay
and then the time complexity is
dominated by the solid because the
sorting is
uh you know it's all unlocked and this
one is linear
okay so can you tell me why the
complexity is not always knocking plus
and
oh and logan this is o and again
this is o n why don't we say okay the
time context is oh and then plus n okay
ryan do you have to understand this
why don't we say the time convex is our
knock and plus n because it sounds a bit
odd
it sounds a bit odd and
this is technically correct
but
that will be n plus
and
so this is technically clear but when we
talk about complexity we all usually we
always talk about uh what
the most dominating part because this is
bigger than that right compared to our
logan this is so small
yeah
all right so we don't talk about it it's
the same thing okay
yeah yeah
okay that will be for today bye-bye bye
bye