hello hello
[Music]
hello mr eric hello mr ryan hello
mr teacher okay so today
no no no no okay today remember what we
have talked about
the linked list learn english
what's english link list
link list what's in english with a list
israelis what kind of list
look remember we have this we have let
me note and we
connect the node yeah yeah okay
now so we're given this a head
ahead this is a head yeah this is a
different color head
pad head head so this is number one
number two number three so today our job
is to reverse it three two one
exactly but but
but it's not it's not just
changing the value you are not allowed
to change the value
right three to one you know you you are
not allowed to change
yeah yeah yeah exactly you need to
change the errors
errors error i know
you can change it this way so any idea
how we do it
no no good job yo
do you have any idea how do we do it
you don't know just
yeah yeah that's the general idea change
the arrow on the other side but how can
we ask computer to do it
i need that one we need
other computers i want to bring down
the hour the other way please
good job when i said that you're not
allowed to change
the values but if we we are allowed to
change the value a little bit easier
right
yeah we can just follow the linked list
and we push this value
one two three two to the array right y
and then we go go through this one more
time and then we just change
we just assign these values in the other
direction yeah
one so we're changing the value not why
it's the way to do it okay
do you get it yeah yeah this is one way
of doing it
okay but we are now allowed
not allowed to change the value so we we
are we we
will do this using the other way just to
re-link
the directions why
you'll be naughty again
okay so now how can we do it define
yeah we're going to define okay define
so how define
linked list define reverse okay
reverse let's given the height
so if if
if head
[Applause]
next is now
so if it's just a single no or if it's
why why does the catapult
and banana now it is a lowercase
good good catch this is when what should
we return
you can if not no if it's if it's
yeah it'll extend head because good job
yeah
because because if it's a single note
a single note the reverse version is a
single note right
yes exactly yeah
[Music]
so now we this is the base cases so
what we want to do is that we reverse we
are now here right
we want to reverse this no matter how
many notes here we want to
reverse this bit yeah when we reverse
this bit we want to
change this direction to here yes that's
two step
all right yeah don't worry there could
be
a four or five a little bit more yeah
but what in general we want to check
this is head we want to
reverse this whole bit
and then once this is done we want to
change the location and
the link from this direction to this
directory
that's it yeah so look so
so what we can do
and equals reverse
[Music]
[Applause]
dot next what's happening now head on
next is this now right
yes yeah and then the next
needs to point it to head am i right
yes yes yes
so look head down next is this one and
the top next is
pointing to this yes yes this is head
yeah and now what what's this pointing
this to pointing to none right
yeah so half
dot next equals nine
and then one return
why what should we return
[Music]
the new head the new head is somewhere
here right
it's this bit yeah yeah the new head is
somewhere here which is called the
recursive
so this is the way to reverse it got it
yes
do it okay let me let me explain it one
more time
reverse if it's a single note we just
return it
because the single note reverse it is a
single note right
then we reverse this is the head we
reverse
the this this large bit no matter how
big is that
right then head down next is this
now and we need to change the link from
this direction to this direction so we
point it to head
and then head down next previously is
pointing to here but we need to erase it
to point into noun right yeah and then
we return the new head which is not his
head
yeah with new head is somewhere here
right
but we don't know which is given
returning
n right got it complexity
okay yeah what n is the number of the
notes in the linked list because we have
to visit each
node can change it and change change the
direction yeah
good job how how can we do it
without the recursion
we can do it using uh another approach
if you you don't keep the middle
now we we we have we can do this have a
previous
previous previous node and we have a
colon node
and every time every time
right right every time previous no
previous note is coming out yeah pointed
to color now and we just need to
go back to the direction and move it
okay
yeah can you sit down please ryan
yeah okay and i'm gonna be here then
okay good good job so now
let's do this uh using
define whoa
if i reverse
are you okay yes pat what's missing here
always always yeah
always a column so previously
previous no is noun
yeah because the previous note here look
look
this is the head yeah this is the head
head head and then i have these notes
one two three
okay the previous note previous note is
is noun
it's long and here previous note it's a
domino and then
no equals yeah
i don't know his head yeah turning on
his head yes
then when we kind of know it's not visit
to the end
why
is not now yeah so what what should we
do
what should we do what should we do now
we choose next
chart
[Applause]
so again this is current now
this is coming we need to save save this
one saving this now right
so next time it was kind of current the
next and then
current the next equals previous
yeah because we need to point it to
previous note right yes
good job yeah yeah
so this this is just to change this the
current is here right
it's link is here but i need to we
change it to the previous note yeah
this is to change this direction to
change right
yes and then what's next
then what's next what's next
so now previous know that we need to
update that previous note equals current
yeah
previous no equals column and then
column will be
next current will be next step because
we're saving this current will be this
one here
next time return preview
return previous because previous note
the last premise now will be
will be the uh will be the new hat
right got it
do you understand it do you understand
it
yes yes so no no no this is not enough
okay so this this is the
uh so to sum up
to sum up okay can you be good boy okay
to sum up this previous note
previous note and previous no
and the current note okay so these are
two notes
that are moving along the linked list
right every time we move along the
linked list
we change the direction which is with
each line of is changing the direction
which one which line of it is changing
the direction
which line of it
now this is moving to the next which one
is changing the direction
which which now is pointing the
direction back to the previous one oh
i need to point it back right and then
these two
are just to move the previous and
current note one position
yeah move forward right yeah
got it okay the coating comes
you need to wait for me to turn on
otherwise it's a bit dark
keep crying okay okay
yes
can you sit down please sit down
do
[Music]
oh yeah that's better yeah connecting
more noise
oh yeah yeah that's better now okay
don't shake it because it's sick the
screen will be shaking as well
okay
hello hello this is my channel okay and
welcome
okay don't know remember we have a nice
note yeah this note is still okay
so so remember this is a cycle
thing do you still remember i left the
previous previous lesson
yeah a cycle yeah we we one in one
lesson we're checking like
if there's a cycle right we know what
the cycle is
now look at this head thing we are
creating a
link list with no from 1 to 10 to 9 okay
okay now we want to reverse it so if now
even if now i print it let's say if i
print it
if i print it now let's say look if p
equals hat
and then for uh y p
print p the value
p equals p next no so what's the answer
now
if i put this what's the answer
what's the expected output from one to
nine right
put it 20 different one tonight because
the length is from one two three four
nine now we want to reverse it yeah
when it turns into one look this is
this is uh let's say
before reverse the linked list
[Music]
okay okay now we can say print it after
reverse okay
link to this so but we need to do the
actually
uh reverse so let's let's do this uh
six that's the one p equals the
reverse reverse link
yeah reverse the head the head is not
changing and then now we need to
uh now and now we need to print it
print it so that let's actually define a
function to print print the linked list
okay
so define print print linked list
head okay so now
p equals hat y p
is not num okay o y p we can do this
y between p value
p equals p dot next no right
next now that's it and then
and we can replace this
if i replace this yeah yeah
print linkedin
hat okay and then after reverse we can
just
print it again right print again
after we burn the link please before the
okay so now we we need to do the reverse
thing okay we must reverse it yeah okay
so you still remember if head is
now all had done next is long next no
it's long right
yeah return what
retirement
[Music]
head weather now we need to reverse the
its next next period
next next now yeah and then
head to next now next now
equals one head head we're done
and heads on next note equals one head
no no because we we need to remove it
okay so now look if we reverse it uh now
we reverse it so it should bring
quinoa what's the answer
what's the answer here
uh nine eight seven six five four yeah
we're done
look yes yes you see yeah before reverse
the link is one two three four five nine
seven nine
after
let's try the other the other approach
that this
is one approach reverse yeah let's do a
second version
second version can you sit down please
remember what we talked about previous
equals
noun current equals
path y current right
white color is the same as white color
is not known
we need to save that next next uh
current
next now right and then current dot
next now will be previous no
previous now will be current now and
karen now will be next year
and return previous okay
let's let's try let's try reverse two
right okay
give us two
yeah it's the same yeah you see it's the
same yeah
yeah got it and how about the one we
talked about in
uh at the beginning which is which is
not uh
reverse function three do you get it
how about let's do it reverse
consistency just by copying the
values
[Applause]
which is reverse three
so we we need to save it in the data
yeah data is
an array yeah data is a
data
we put it into this value and then p
equals p dot next now right now the
theta
we got the data yeah theta which is one
two three four to nine right
and then now we need to go back to the
head
and then why p
what that is
what do we do now we need to assign the
value t value equals
equals theta dot
top remember yeah and then t
equals p dot next now and we turn
head yeah because we're not changing the
we are not changing the no we are we are
just changing the value right
yes yes
let's do this if it is working yes
exactly it's the working
but for the last version it's just
changing the value of no it doesn't
change the direction do you get it
yes do you understand eric
yes let's see the code one more time so
we have a three version yeah
this is twin reverse it this is the
uh recursion the cursion version yeah
recursive version
and reverse 2 is the iterative version
sorry how many lines did you write maybe
just 50 yeah
okay so get it 58 yes interesting yeah
okay uh
are you okay okay good job today say bye
bye to people
bye
[Music]
thank you good job good job