yo
hello me tell me mr runner all right
okay now let's look at this final tree
okay okay one
two what's finally trees a binary tree
is a tree with numbers
okay so upside down tree
the uptight the trunk
the leaves and the leaves don't have any
children the loot does not have any
pearls if you look outside now this is
the root here this is the root
okay upside down this is the leaves
okay
so the binary tree is is a graph
um
that does not have any cycles yeah
directly acyclic png
yeah
does that not have any cycles and
it's connected one in one piece okay if
we have a small tree what do we call it
you know if it is this is not connected
what do we call it
forest yeah exactly first
yeah so we only have one root right we
only have one root so for this one you
know multiple roots so multiple trees
and forests okay so today questions very
simple so we want to find out the sum
of the deepest leaves okay
some of these
leaves so what what how can we do this
what's the what's the sum of the
difference this thing is in this tree
come on six easy exactly okay how about
i add another one
okay what's the sum of 16 16 exactly
okay that's it the question is very
similar how can we do it
i'm going to do it easier it's easy so
how can we do it
how many ways we can traverse the binary
tree and how do we do it i mean
breakfast
which one you think is easier
in this case
better search and how about you which
one you think is easier both are okay so
which one you think is easier
to guess
why okay
yes
you're right
because
it's a wild guess well i guess okay so
buffer search you know professors will
travel a tree by a level by level and
then we updated the sun
to to do this in pepper search we have
the dictionary dictionary dictionary and
the keys will be the levels
and the value will be the sum so we
traverse the uh different search right
whichever
search and then we accumulate the sum
for each level right and once we have
this dictionary so for example
uh the sum
sub dictionary yeah some is dictionary
we go through we traverse the
binary tree and then we pass down the
levels and we accumulate the sum of for
each level and then we what we need to
do
so we just need to return the maximum
level right because it says the
difference yeah so you'll be max
s dot keys and that will be the sum okay
easy so i think i think definition is
easier to implement for the perfect
search
level by level yeah every time we take
the notes because we know all the notes
in the sentence in a queue remember we
talked about this a few days ago yeah
look if we every time we put uh the
first one we put the dude in we take it
out we put the kids
in
yeah we take it off
we put the kids four five zero we take
take all the notes i'll push their kids
six 10 so the la we always uh updated
the sum we keep a value of the sum for
the
for the current level
yeah when the weather search terminates
then the sum would be the
will be the level of the deepest leaves
okay
so let's go for the definition okay so
we can traverse the different search in
the tree in how many orders i'll give
you another example
pre-order
what do we have pre-order in order and
what poisson yeah
these are typically three orders
yeah but maybe we can have this reverse
you know yeah
uh a binary search tree if we perform an
inorder on a banister stream we get this
in order right we get a list in order
okay
and let's say d equals the dictionary uh
before dictionary okay
because and then we want to
be able to use this before key which is
initialized to zero if we given the type
value type is in okay
define definite search and then we have
this first parameter as the rule the
second parameter is the level
level okay
if not root
if non-load will just return
otherwise what look d
level
plus equal blue dot value okay
and we just traverse the left tree
and then we traverse the right tree
and
and what do we do we can
d
max
the
keys okay
okay that's it look i'm going to
explain this and then you need to tell
me later back up
dictionary default dictionary
dictionary.com the keys would be the
number the value would be the sum i know
it just travels uh traversal uh okay so
we have to call this definite root and
then let's pass the parameter the first
one is never zero so we traverse a
recursively and then when we visit this
node look we accumulate
the sum the level with this blue dot
value and then we travel the left tree
will write really closely and then some
of the deepest leaves deepest which is
the max
level right the next level max
level d dot keys is the level max dot
levels
right and we want to get the values
so the the time conducting oh and yes we
have to traverse the order nodes each
node is visited exactly once the
space complexity is o
o n or o h h is the height of the tree
right in the worst case h will be the n
right
okay in what cases in the worst cases o
h equals o n why is that can you tell me
why the in the worst cases
why the height is the number of nodes
can you give me an example like in worst
cases what does the binary tree look
like
that's the highest line
where that is looks like line yeah
like that yeah
okay
not exactly not necessarily to produce a
straight line it could be
like that yeah
let's still o h equals one all right
yeah make sense
can you explain to me what's this
that's
so um
are adding we are we are accumulating
the sum for this level here okay
okay so there's another problem level
needs to pass one okay i forgot this
most important thing
okay yeah
because we're going
down we need to
we need to implement that am right
yeah okay what have you learned today so
far
about
whatever
what are we trying to do today and what
are we what kind of equipment should we
use today
we're using different assets
okay and then what kind of how do we
implement this staff research
how do we implement this definition
and what kind of data structure we need
to use to store the
sum for each level stack
what data structure you were using we're
not using any
stationery they stole the
keys
okay that's it for today bye bye bye