hello mr mr right now right
what have we done yesterday what's this
what have you learned back
no what's the sum of the time of the
tickets the leaves yeah yesterday we
were using the deficit recursion
deficits
you know we can implement a different
search in
iterated using the stack but it's uh
easier to implement using a recursion
right and then look at this thing
dictionary
hashmap we use it to keep tracking of
the sound we accumulate the sum for each
level the keys will be the levels the
values will be the same right and then
when we go down we will traverse the
left tree and right three will pass down
the level when we reach the note in the
next in the left triad and the right
side the level will be plus one right
and i'll use this level to
accumulate the sum here
we do this different search recursion it
doesn't matter which order we visit the
left tree first or right three but it
doesn't matter as long as we traverse
the
tree in a different uh definition
manner and then all the nodes will be
visited exactly once and
in order to return the
sum of the deepest leaf
we need to compute with next d dot keys
is the maximum the deepest level i know
is the key is to retrieve the sum of the
of the dps level okay
so let's definitely search so can you
guess what are we talking about today
exactly yeah we're using the processors
to solve this problem
so what is the perfect search
how do we travel what's the what's the
pressure
i mean what order for example like if
this is the binary tree what are the
one two three four five
six
seven
eight okay one two three four five six
seven eight but if we're using the
pre-order search
in order
what's in order
left
note right okay so left four
goes down
four one two three no no no no if it's
one if that's that's pre-order pre-order
is not left right then it's wrong it's
uh when you say it's correct one two
four
five six seven eight three okay but if
it's uh
in order so we go to the left three
first then which is the note and which
the right three so that'll be
two
four
one five
uh
five one three
six
five
seven six eight no no four for the note
uh for the left no to right for this
three so what other would be left three
we visit the left tree first yeah so
this one will go first and then one to
here so one tree at the end okay and in
order to visit these three in the no uh
in order so what do we what do we have
so we did left three first
right
that's three note and the right three
all right so it's four two and this bit
is this bit yeah
so again with the customer what's what
how do we visit this tree
so five yeah five because it has nothing
on the left five
five and then this bit
what was that
that's easier seven six eight yeah
seven six eight do you get it so all
together for the inorder is four two
five seven six a one three correct
yeah
for the first search we use the q dq
double and dq right
all right so
for example this one one okay i
shouldn't have erased this okay but
let's do this
okay that's a simple final treat okay so
we have a q dq first of all the we put a
note in it once
then
we dequeue all the notes in the queue
because they belongs to the same number
what's the kit of the one
two three two three and then we incur it
one by one okay and then we take all we
dequeue everything in the key because
two and three don't stand level we take
it out what's the kit of two and three
four five six seven yeah exactly
okay
so every time look this is the standard
breakfast search every time we take
everything out
when we push the kids
we're gonna push the kids back to the
queue then we can compute the sum we can
compute the sum of all the kids right
so now in this case the
the sum the sum will be updated
to four plus five plus six plus seven
right
but we keep updating the sum well every
level we dequeue every node right so
that we set we reset the sum to zero so
basically we just use the variable
answer to keep tracking of the sum of
the next
level right and when the preference
search terminates the sum will be
the sum of the la maximum level which is
the details
defined by first search okay node
root
okay
if not root we don't need to continue
return zero okay
and then
q equals dq
we put the root in it right
and then we have this answer sum equals
zero at the beginning and y and q why
there is a node in the queue so first of
all we need to get how many nodes the
number of nodes in the queue in the left
belongs to some level and length skill
and now we just have to
decube all these end nodes in range n
now first of all answer i have to copy
here i i have to reset it to zero right
that's what i'm saying answer equals
zero we reset this answer to zero
because that represents the sum of the
next level okay
and then what here's a
current equals q dot problem
and then if current on left what do we
do q
what should we do
can you feel the blank
q dot append
and now we need to uh answer plus input
yeah this is
no no no current current on that
i know what's this
answer plus current value okay
i'm gonna return
okay
this one yeah because we need to
accumulate some for the next level but
we are not accumulating the sum for all
the notes because we are resetting the
sum to zero
yeah make make sense yeah so okay can
you can you tell me what have you
learned today by this breakfast search
what are we trying to do today we're
trying to find the some of the deepest
leaves in the binary cream
and how we doing it
what does it mean double yeah two sides
and we can do this
a pen a pen to the right pop to the left
uh popular right
a pen up and left
top left okay so if you want to push in
or take it out from the left hand side
we have to put the left
to say it's from the left otherwise it's
from the right okay and then these four
operations are constant 01 constant time
right
yeah we can use the lift
yeah if we use if we declare the q
equals this empty list we can still use
the
use it as a
queue
but we have to use this top zero but
this is expensive this is linear time
okay that's why we use the dq because
this top left
is one which is better than this one
which is one linear term okay
okay so why why do we need to reset this
to zero at the beginning answer equals
zero and the answer is one right which
is sum of the next level and i set it to
zero answer equals two plus three five
okay
and i i set it to the answer equals four
plus five okay so can you tell me why we
need to set it to 0
what would this answer be if i don't
reset the 0 for h each level so what's
the sum going to be
all of the next we're down it'll be the
sum of all the notes i said we set it to
0. every time i start with the new level
right
yeah for them
does it make sense now yeah okay that
will be it for today good job bye bye
bye