hello hello mr mission all right
okay so let's say we are given a final
treat what's the binary tree this is
tree
with
numbers it doesn't have to be necessary
numbers sometimes you can put the
strings you know the objects the
biscuits yeah basically the biscuit
objects the the sets the you know
anything
basically trees
data structures is used to
store the data right so what data
structure the kind of the
thing for computer to
you know to store the data yeah to store
the data
so this is the binary
and we have a copy of it let's say we
have a clone chrome clone
copy yeah
exactly the same same tree
it's a clone so it's a duplicate
these two trees exactly but they are not
their identity is not assembled just the
values the same yeah
if we are given a no here for example if
we are given this node yeah number five
okay your given is two three a and b
right so if we are given if we're given
this target typing
equals let's say five we need to find
the corresponding note in the
cookie tree which is this five okay so
if we are find if we given this five we
need to return this five if we given
this two we need to find it in the
copyright okay so chrome what's crown
what's the code
copy we're done a b
okay
okay so in the equal sign yeah remember
a equal equal in python we use number
equal right this is to check the values
for example
a equals one two three this is the list
b equals one two three if we say a equal
equal b
we check the values
so a
is a
b
so it should return true because look
these two the values are the same
then that will return to
another one a is b so can you guess
should return two of us
yeah we're done exactly first
is means the identity
right
so
if the value is the same if there are
different copies for example in memory
in computer ram look at this a and b
actually they are located at separate
memory so a is here one two three
b is here one two three
so even the contents is the same but
they are
they are different
okay
yeah
so the ease is identity so basically
this is is the same thing as id
that's the id function id a equal equal
idb okay so id
of a
parameter this parameter for the id it
returns a
a memory location it's a number if we
print the id a and b there will be two
different numbers which means they are
different
right they are different if it checks
the identity but if this one look if i
say b
equal a
then a is b that will return true
right because b is an alias so the
shallow copy is an alias right
it's not actually an individual copy
okay make sense okay so here look a and
b b is a separate yeah
it's a separate tree right if we are
given a note
if we are given a note in the tree a we
need to find the corresponding one in a
tree b because these two trees
share the same structure yeah
the structures the numbers and the
numbers and the values for each now okay
so
what's your song how can we solve this
problem i mean first of all
exactly yeah
given the financing given the tree given
a graph
the most popular two most popular three
traversal a graph traversal is
that's a search of breakfast okay and
for that research we can implement using
the recursion or iterative
and for graph research we travel the
tree level by level
and we're using the dq for the definite
search
we use the stack if we implement using
the application the computer maintain a
stack for us but we can implement it
using iterative and in this case we have
to
you know maintain a stack ourselves okay
so what's the difference between
devastation professors
episode jesus stack and breakfast
apart from this what's the
difference what's the major difference
of the definitive search i mean the name
the
how we traverse the tree i mean in terms
the order we choose to anybody
[Music]
on the other hand what's the deficits
doing
for example the definition for this one
for the tree what do we get
if we're using this the pre-order let's
say note
left to right okay so what's the
pre-order
that's the search pre-order of this
biometry
one
two four
five
five three six seven exactly okay and
and the preferred search is one two
three four five six seven eight seconds
okay let's uh let's implement the
definition today okay it should be quick
and easy yeah we have seen these
definitions many many times seven search
preferences professorship the most
important thing i mean i want you to
understand during these 400 more than
400 days yeah
of teaching
that's the most important takeaway
because deaf search and professors
are the two most popular important
very useful
three graph traversal agreement and it
can be used to solve many many problems
right as we can see we use the different
search processes to solve lots of lots
of the
three graph problems right
another thing to notice is that that's
the size look if this is the definition
if we want to
if you if we want to you know find the
solution to each other yeah if you don't
want to locate the node
yeah sometimes the default search are
quicker to find the solution right for
example if if the
if the solution is here yeah
if the solution is here which one which
aggregate do you think it's better to
find the solution quicker let's search
your preferences if you don't know if
the target node is here where we're
trying to find exactly because look it
goes it'll find it
and how about if i want even notice here
which method
[Music]
purposes yeah you see yeah you see so it
depends on the problem yeah it depends
on problem breakfast search if we find
it if we're doing the processor we find
it it's the shortest path if the edges
are unweighted the cost of between the
nodes is unweighted right do you
remember the graph yeah
sometimes the graph has at least weight
yeah that's one the cost of going from a
to b is one because of going from a to c
three these are the weights yeah if we
if we are using the breakfast search on
the unweighted graph right then uh
then you have always find the shortest
path right shortest path
because it travels level by level and
whenever we found it
i know you'll be the shortest to the
dude right
but for the depth search
not necessary because
for the different search it may not be
guaranteed to find a optimal solution
for example look here you may find this
first right but sometimes the optimal
solution is here right if this is also
okay but it finds these nodes first
then
this is not optimum
right
to get it yeah
if these two nodes are both okay if
using the default search you'll find
this node this node is not optimum
but for the first search is always
guarantee us to find the optimal
solution
in this case optimum means the shortest
path okay but we also talked about
iterative depending right iterative
depending search
long time ago first of all we set the
maximum depth to one then we do the
definition if we can't find it we said
that that we increment the max step to
two
and then we we use the repeat this
definition if we can find it we we
increment the path right in increment
the maximum limit
okay and for the different search we
don't need to store all the nodes
of the same level but for the first
search we need to use the queue to store
the all the nodes in the same level
right let's see one disadvantage of
using the brussels search is that it may
be
maybe memory inefficient yeah
makes sense yeah okay okay that's a lot
of
things to digest right that's using the
data search it should be very easy
you know the question easy
define that's the set we're going to
find that this is the
original tree this is the clone tree and
this is the target right if not a then
we return yeah we can't find it with
this hand
if
a
is t okay because t is a note in the
tree a so then we can use this identity
check right then we can set it to set
the answer equals b and then we do 10
and then we can definitely search
a to left
b left
t and then we also need to search the
right through excess dot
therefore search a dot right b dot right
p okay
we have given this node t which is a
node in a we want to find the
corresponding node in b right so we just
do this definition you see the order of
traverse traversal the def and right
three does not matter right
this is all that the definition
when we find it when a is t or a or you
can say a equal equal t
but that's not identity check that's the
value to check okay so it's better to
add to do this is because t is given a
note in a right if the tree contains the
duplicate number then if we put it a
equal equal t which might not work right
because it might return
incorrect
no
okay this is one way another way if we
want to return this return a note for
the differences we can do this
a b t okay
if not a
return nothing right return num okay or
written
or we just return by default is written
none
if a is t
then with return
instead of setting central answer which
is the outside scope of the function
then we return b if a is t then we can b
then we need to go in the left left tree
right so x equals definite search
a dot left
b left
t
then if x if we found it yeah if we
thought it would return x y
otherwise we return
if it's not in the left tree then let's
try it at the right tree okay
b
what's these two implementation in
common
that's similar yeah yeah obviously last
year what's the common thing can you
find a common bit
what are these two in common
abt
that's more like syntax i mean what i
mean is algorithm
search okay they both definitely and
they both implement it in
that
yeah what's what's the accuracy
recursion yeah levels recursion
yeah okay and they both traverse on the
left tree first and then the right three
right and then look at this one if we
found a note in the left tree we return
without the searching the right tree
this one is the same if we found it we
set the seventh answer equals the
corresponding note
in the
in the clone tree and we return we now
keep going right
okay
the time came next t o n if there are n
notes in the tree in the binary the
space connecting o n
yeah because we are using this recursion
and then recursion we the computer needs
to maintain the stack for us yeah there
will be a calling stack right uh
every time we uh the convention makes a
call do the do the function call it
needs to push the parameters into the
step okay okay one last question what
have you learned today about finding a
corresponding node of the binary tree in
a coin of that tree
okay so finding so we we are given a
node in the tree a
and b three b is a clone
is a copy of the tree a so basically
there are two trees they are separating
three
but these two three
look exactly the same the structures and
the values exactly the same and we are
given a note in the tree a
the task is to find the corresponding
node in the
copy in the clone tree okay the argument
we're using is definite search
the default search
we can use the recursion which
we we talked today and tomorrow we're
going to use the iterative approach to
implement the deficit and the day after
tomorrow we're going to use the
breakfast search okay
yeah that'll be for today bye