hello mr mr wine
what are we talking about yesterday
find the corresponding node of behind
between the exactly okay bless you okay
yes yes so
basically we are given two trees so for
example we are given two trees here
this a
original tree b is the clone of that one
it's a copy so copy means that the
structures then content okay right
so we are given a note in a tree a for
example if we want to find given this
node this is the like
a node in three a it's an identical node
for example this node and we want to
find out the corresponding node in the
column tree okay so we're using
application that's a search
okay and then we have these two
different slightly different
implementations but they are both that
recursive data search so finding that
node in the left tree
if we find it will return otherwise we
will search for the tree and the time
and space complexity is both o n
okay
yeah make sense
so today we're going to still talk about
the step search but we implemented using
this iterated so we're using the
recursion to implement that the deficit
we don't actually manage the stack
ourselves because the computer manager
stack
for us every time we make the call
recursion call right there will be a
step involved
today we're going to use the stack to
implement the data search
the idea is that we have a stack what
stack by the way that's attacking
what's that is something to do with
themselves
first
out because yeah yeah man fifth okay
yes if i'm going to put an item one two
three in it and then
top it out
one by one what's the what's the
sequence to take the items down if i
want to put it one two three man what's
the sequence of taking it off
three to one exactly we're done you
wanna put it one two three okay so take
three out two one
first thing now okay
look
okay so let's say we have these three
yeah one
two
three so how can we use the stack to
implement the depth search so we try to
push
the left left
and we go to the left root
and we try to push the note in it and
then we take
and what so we take so for example like
one we are here this is the current root
okay we are here we push the one in and
then we go to the left we push the two
in okay and that's it
and now if we can't do that then we take
one note out of the stack we take it out
we take it out when we take it out so
it's two here i know we go to its right
do we have the right of it too no right
go again we take the one out
yeah take the one out and we
have a right yeah we go to each right
because it's right yeah we don't change
it right and
we push it to the stack okay and we take
it out
st stack empty we can use the disk to
represent the stack or cube you know so
we have this current equals okay if
we're not changing the load variable
wire
wire stack
or current
yeah and then we do this wire
wire current
append
append current and then we'll go to the
left current equal column dot left okay
and then we take the note from the stack
so
current equal st dot pop
and now we go to the right current equal
current right okay
this is basically the the template for
how we're using the whole implementation
particularly in this case what look two
one three what's the order of two and
three what's this in order
note left
right so what's this in order in order
in order so this is the template for
implementing the
in order
right of the that's the search okay
so
let's uh try another example okay so
let's see how about this one okay so
first of all we are here right here
one i put one in i go to the left
i put the two in
yeah i go to the left four
okay yeah i can't go any left
we take one level on the stack which is
four and i'm going to to the
to the right it doesn't have any light
and then it goes
it doesn't have any right so we go back
to here
stack of current stack is not empty
current is is empty right because it has
been is a vital form okay
[Music]
when look
this is empty current is empty so we
skip this path we take another one out
to
take it out too
and then we go to the right we go to the
right the current is five right and then
go back to here again
the stack is not empty the current is
fine
y current then expect a pen current
which is fine
and we can't go any further then come
here come here then take one out of the
stack
five
yeah and go to the right it doesn't have
any right for the five okay
then come back here the stack we stack
is not empty currently is empty current
is empty so we skip this bit and we take
another one out of the stack which is
one
so one
okay
stack is empty current is one
y current
stack dot append we take it right take
it one out we need to go to we we need
to go to the right okay so let's current
is three okay currently three so stack
is empty currently three why the stack
stack dot appends left so that would be
six we are playing the sixth in right
yeah and then we take it out
we take it off take it out every time we
take it out we just put it this is the
sequence take it out
to the right which is empty
six that would be three yeah i forgot to
push this so i think one hour i i know
it's a three three and then i go to the
right okay it's testing it so it's
six three seven okay
so this is the way okay how to describe
to me how to use the stack to do this in
order thing
so first of all we do
we got as deep as possible and then we
append we push these notes to the step
right
if we can't go any further we take one
alveolar step and we go to the one on
the right and we will repeat this
process
okay so how is this useful if we're
using these then we possibly because we
have this another column tree okay st
and then we have a clone one
st2 equals empty
first of all you can just use the c a
and b y s t or
o a right
then we change this to a
append a
a equals a dot next okay
and then
a equals st pop
a equals a dot right okay so so we just
have to insert the code for uh every
time we do this operation with the three
a we need to do this term with three b
okay so y
so that will be
a equals s t dot prod then we we do this
here if
a is t
then we return b right return b okay
otherwise a dot a a equals a to y b
equals b dot right right
we need basically we need to synchronize
two trees
right every time we go every time we
three a we go to the left three b we
need to also go to the to the left all
right
every time we go go to the right tree of
a we need to go to the right tree of b
if we we found a note in the tree a now
we know where is it in a tree b all
right so it's a like you know
synchronization
synchronization and then here y a st dot
append a a
equal a left and then we have to do this
st2
dot append
t dot append b
b equals b left okay
all right
and then here there's one thing missing
which is b equals s t two dot okay
so i mean what have you learned today so
far
we learned about
the same thing
what's new today what i was saying
what's new
different kind of different different
color yeah yes they were using recursion
today we're using the iterative using
the spec right
yeah
yeah okay it makes sense here
okay that will be for today bye-bye
[Music]
bye-bye