uh hello mr mr rhino right
[Music]
what have we talked about yesterday
we are talking about the deficits the
yesterday and the day before is today
yeah on the first on the day before
yesterday we talked about these the
recursive
deficits
exactly yesterday we talked about the
iterated uh deficit
we're using a stack right we use instead
we do this in order so the idea is that
we use the stack we push
push the note and go to the left go to
the left as much as we can right and
then we take one out from the stack and
we go to the right so that will result
in the in order so the problem is that
we're given two trees yeah one is
another one's clone and we given the
note in the one tree and we want to find
the corresponding one and then for
example like
this is a 3a
and then that's the exactly the same
copy of the 3a but it's a clone right
this is 3p so if we are given these
three this node a node in three a we
want to find a corresponding one in
three b we just synchronize we have two
we have two pointers so we synchronize
well we go to the left yeah we go down
we go down for example if we have a more
note here yeah
smaller note
okay so these two three is the same yeah
so how exactly are we doing this look
different search either is not recursion
or iterative right so one
two
four look look at my couple's fingers
they have the same movement right
yeah
yeah okay so because for example this is
the node we are looking for and then we
return
with within three so yeah you got it so
the default search what's the order one
two four five six three but for the
processes
one
two three four
five six okay so for example six is the
note we are looking for
now what should we do we return the one
on the right hand okay yeah okay make
sense
let's just quickly review what's my
favorite
what's breakfast don't say it's a
breakfast okay breast first
it's when you breathe
breath what's breath
is
okay so what's this word breath
it's supposed to
read
what's breath
why
how do you spell west
this is breath yeah breathe yeah but we
are talking about the breath
so breakfast so basically look we have a
tree we want to go
horizontally right horizontally so let's
dress as opposed to death we want to go
deep as much as we can right it's just
two different ways of traversing the
tree also the grass right but
okay so
how do we implement the preferences bffs
q yeah dq yeah
look i killed q equals cq f q dq
double ndq yeah
at the beginning we can put the rules in
right
which is number one right okay so now
this is the cube at the beginning
we put a one in that's in inside okay so
what do we do
we take
like the two ways we can take everything
out or we can take one note out we both
are okay yeah so for example if we want
to take one note off we take
one note of first thing first off let's
cue
what's what's the kit of one
two one three two and three another a
pen i push it to the to the cube okay
now okay i can take everything out or i
can take one note out what's the what's
the next next note to come out from the
queue here what's the key this is the
two yes because first in first order so
it comes this way this is in q we put a
note in here oh and this one is dq means
to take it right now so we take two
hours what's the kit
okay and i push it four and then five
okay and then what's the next note to
come out from the queue three okay
what's the number what's the kilometer
six and seven you got it and then we
just take a four out it doesn't have any
kid take the fire out you guys don't
have any kid take a six out it doesn't
have a drink
yeah so that's the order of the birthday
okay yeah
i was just taking one note at a time we
can also take a and take all the notes
so what's the difference you tell me
okay so look
no one in that
yeah no one in there i take everything
out which you want and what's the kid
that's a two or three okay
i will i was taking two at the time now
i can take if i take two and three oh
what's the kiss of two and three you
know that four five six seven
okay so you see the difference do you
see the difference
if i take everything out i can be
assured that all the nodes at any time
in the queue belongs to the same level
am i right
yeah we've given this to three a and b
and how do we use the preferences to
solve this problem to solve this problem
this is 3a this is 3p so 3a
is like this
so look three should be exactly copy so
every time i we have a q we push the
copper
of a and b right
and then we push the top off
of a and b
and we just check if the note equals to
the to the uh
to the three a
then we return the second parameter uh
in the top which is the three b okay q
defined
by first search
a b pocket okay
q equals c q
at the beginning we push the dude which
we lose one a and b yeah so
so what
a
b
that's right oh yeah immutable can
change so look this title has two
elements the first first element of
pepper is the note from a tree a the
second parameter is the corresponding
node in the tree b okay and then now
look
y up q right
so we can get the dense length q
and then we take everything out of the q
queue dq in range n
okay and then look x
y equals q dot top left okay we take
these
we take a note out of a queue first
inverse or the top left okay
if
x equal
if x is t
right if x is t we talk about this is
and the double equal sign right right
yes so we so what's the difference
between if i use the e and what's the
difference if i use the a so for example
a equal equal b what's the difference a
is b
what's the difference a
which one is the value check that we
check the value which way is check the
identity
i think the value is equal equal yes and
this one is identity okay so basically
this one identity is id a equal equal
idp okay this is the equivalent okay a
equal equal b is the value check for
example like
a equals
one two
b equals one two these are two different
array but they have a same content their
values are the same so a equal equal b
is true a is b
false because if they are different
right but if a equals one two and if b
equals a then a equal to b true a is b
is it true of us yeah yes because b
equals a b is an alias it's the same as
a it's just different name okay so e
so if x was t then t is the note in a
that would be 10 y right look because x
and y are the corresponding note right x
is the note in the tree a why is the
tree not in the tree b if if x is no we
are looking for then we return the
corresponding one which is y okay and
then we just have to do this if x dot
left
then we just return oh we just push the
key yeah kill the append
up and x
tapper yeah extra left right or left and
can you tell me what's missing here
is what
look we're checking the left tree if we
lay electric which push the left tree
into the cube yeah if x to the right
q dot append extra right white or white
right
if extra white
q dot append x dot right y the right
okay that's a couple
time complexly
if there are n notes what's the tangent
let's be
[Music]
so because each node we visit once
correct
so let's open right what's the space
complexity
um
yeah why is that
we're using and
space to store the notes what have you
learned today we're learning about
breakfast
yeah we talked about two trees yeah
and
they're basically the same thing yeah
and then
the problem is
there's two trees that they're saying
number one that's in the other one yeah
yeah yeah the professor okay so okay so
to sum up we are given two binary trees
yeah
a and b b is a clone of three a
and if we are given a note in three a we
we want to find the corresponding note
in a tree b all right remember what
what's this look two hands
yeah let's just search one
two
five three four okay four is the note we
we are looking for and then we return
this one right and 10 massages where one
two three
four
five okay five is the note we are
looking for then we return the right
hand okay okay make sense
yeah that's it for today bye
you