hello mr mr rhino are you right yeah
okay so let's look at this problem
partition an array into pairs and the
sum of each pair needs to be divisible
by k so we have this array all positive
numbers a k is also a positive number so
four two a one so we want to partition
the pair a pair is two numbers yeah can
we position this array into pairs so
that each pair the sum of each pair is
divisible by three anybody
so for example like four two a one four
plus two
divided by k is zero okay three and a
plus one divided by k equal equal
we also four plus a or two plus one is
both okay okay if two numbers a and b
need
the sum of a and b needs to be divided
by k
yeah we write it as modulus equal equals
zero it also means that a plus b is the
multiple of k yeah it's k times
something yeah k times something okay
so that's the that's how we check if the
sum can be divided by k okay so in
mathematics we have these three
lines two lines equal three line is
called
congruence more dura
okay so
a congruence is congruent to b modulus n
okay so let's take an example
24 is congruent to 36
mode 2f what does it mean it means that
24 divided by 2f remaining 0.
36 divided by 2f remaining 0 is the same
thing
a
congruent
more euros two right
because they both even numbers a divided
by two remains zero ten divided by two
remains zero
if however model three divided by three
modulus remain two eleven
divided by three remain two okay so that
that's what the congruence module is
okay so coming back to this question we
want to look for a plus b modulus k
equal to zero
so we can rewrite this as a plus a
modulus k
plus b modulus k
equals k minus k okay now we can rewrite
this into
a modulus k
equals k minus b modulus k
okay so look
a and k minus b is a pair okay so for
example if this number is if this number
is 4 4 modulus 3 equals 1 right so it
has remained 1 so look
4 it has remained 1
so the other number for example a not 1
2 3 four five six seven eight okay it
has two actual right two extra what does
it mean a modulus k
a modulus three remain two it has two
extra yes so actually so this group has
two actual this group has one extra so
we have one more here and we have two
more here so put it together one plus
two is a multiple of k right so
so coming back to this question so we
can use the dictionary hash map
to store
to store one if the number is i we can
store the k i modulus okay to store the
remaining phase
right we can partition arrays only if we
have
we have a pairs in each remainder for
example like for the remainder one
for the remain one we have four
for the remainder
two we have eight
two these two numbers also remain two
this one also remain one look we have
two numbers in the remainder one we have
two numbers in the remain two so we
compare so we can pair four plus two or
we can play four plus a we can play one
plus a or we can play one plus two okay
so it has to be
an equal number of numbers in each pool
so each pool is the remainder yeah
remember four yeah got it
okay so define partition
k divisible number the number okay
so if the the number of elements in that
rate is odd number can we pair can we
plan why is that because
that's right because for example if i
give you five numbers can you can you
form them in pair no because they're
always one extra right
one
two
three
four and then
[Music]
ah okay
okay that's great so first of all first
of all n equals the length of numbers so
this has to be a even number if it's uh
if it's all number if it's a down number
will determine easy then we store the i
plus k uh i'm i modulus k in the
dictionary so we use the s for example s
equals before
this generally
the default time is in by default the
intel gives the value default value zero
when the key is not existing okay and
then we go through this number for i in
nums and then s i
modulus k plus equal one okay so we are
incrementing we are storing the
frequency remember remember these though
uh 4 a to 1 and k equals 3 so what we
are doing is that 1 s equals i modulus k
equals 1 and i'll be 4 and 1
now so s 1 is two in this case and then
the the other the remainder two
remainder two is two
a and two and then s two
is also two right two numbers here two
numbers here we have to consider the
special case when the remainder is 0
right if s 0 is a whole number we still
need to return 4 right for example for
example like if we have k equals 3
and then number is 369 right so these
numbers itself can be divisible by k so
we need even number of it right because
it can't so
these numbers have its own
three six nine right if
there are odd number of the numbers here
right so what happens so you can't find
a pair
it doesn't find it doesn't have its pair
okay it doesn't have its pair
so we need to return first otherwise we
just have to check the remainder i
needs to pair with k minus i then we
return fourth are you okay returns five
otherwise if we can't find anything here
then we can show so this whole thing
these
this number of lines can also be
rewritten as return all
s i equal equal s i k minus i
for i in range one k so the time
complexity is a when the space
complexity is always because we are
using that
we're using the deformation right the
number we go through the numbers yeah
once right
we can use that another way to uh to
write it quite okay so so the idea is
that when we find the numbers we can
just increment the counter right and we
if we don't find this number in the pair
we just decrement it right
f equals d4
dictionary in okay and then we c equals
zero c equals zero okay and then we just
go through this number for i in numbers
and then we just say a is the number i
divided by k b is the num the other
number in the pair so which is k minus a
divided by k
and then if f a
is bigger than zero then we what we do
we just decrement it f a minus equals
one c minus equals one as
fb plus equals one c plus equals one and
at the end we just have to check if
return c equal equal to zero okay so
that's why i say a and b is two numbers
in a pair if f a frequency bigger than
zero we have we have the numbers in the
pair then we decrement it we decrement
otherwise we increment it okay so at the
end
the numbers need to be needs to come in
the pairs this is one time because look
goes through these numbers and we use we
use the dictionary so that's one space
as well okay so to sum up what have you
learned today
uh the facebook okay so we have an array
of numbers the arrays
contains all positive numbers and we
want to position we want to find out if
we can partition the numbers into pairs
and each sum of the sum of each pair
needs to be divided by k right divided
by k and then we what are we doing here
is we use a dictionary to store the
storage remainder by k divide divided by
k remainder right for example k 3 if the
number divided by k remain 2 and the
number needs to be paired with the
number which divided by k remain 1
because 2 plus 1 is a multiple of k
right okay that's it for today bye