hello
hello guys hello mr mr ryan all right
okay so we have a string of integers
from zero to nine so for example
this string of numbers one one one two
two two three four
and then our task is to find the largest
substring of length three two okay
and then
okay you get it there so each the
substring contains only one unique digit
so it could be it should be one on one
two two two three three four four five
five etcetera okay
yeah
so two requirements substring
of three
the second requirement is unique one
unique digit these means there are only
10 possibilities right they only from 10
possibilities 0 000 1 1 2 2
recession to 999 okay
simple okay so what's your sauce
what's your sauce
how do we perform
every possibility how i mean there are
two ways of checking prosperity how
we check
every number
how do we check the possibility we want
to find out large is three digits in
this in a string in the numbers right
this substring of three needs to contain
only one unique digit one way is that
look because there are only ten
possibilities yeah
and let's just check
from 999 backwards
if it's 99 in the stream
yes we return it if not is aaa in the
string
yes we return it one case is that if we
don't find such string we return the
empty okay for example like
one two
three
there's no such substring that
contain only one unique digit right then
we return empty okay so that's that
could be one way yeah nine and nine
we check backwards and as long as we
find
the substring
in the original string immediately we
just return it because that's the
largest one that's one way the other way
is just continuous check this out string
right
recession is it satisfying this
requirement uh basically this one
because we're checking the three
digits at the time
when is it one unique digit yes we
remember it right
is this the
the same right no and we just keep
moving yeah that could be a a way to do
it right and then we remember the
maximum for example like
if this is the same okay
then look this is obviously not the same
right yeah but for simplicity we just
move keep moving so this is a three
digit three digit three digit
three digits three digits read it okay
so which way you think it's better
yeah that would be that would be better
okay so let's quickly divide this i'll
define
uh just the largest leaf okay
[Music]
and we given this s
so we just do this for
i
in
range we start from nine right because
it could be start from nine up to zero
after zero
so the end not including we should give
you a minus one and then the step would
be minus one this string would be a
equal str
i first of all we convert the integer
into the string yeah and we times three
okay 1 times
10 multiple 3
what does it give us
1 string multiple three what does it
give us
three ones three ones exactly one on one
how about this one count three
one times eight your turn
exactly okay so this is very basic we're
done both okay
so look at transfer right this is a
string marker okay so we can we
converted this b
a a will be 99 aaa
etc okay now we just say
if a
in
s right if it's the substring of that
then we return
we will just return a right and
otherwise if we can't find anything we
just return empty okay what's the time
complexity
even if
we're done look if the line is not easy
why is
n is the number of uh characters in a
string okay so why is it going look this
one
we iterate 10 times
so this is the constant loop
but here we check if a
string suction in if it's in the
original string right
then that's going to take on time right
there there's a famous kmp
string pattern matching so we don't want
to go into more details here but in
general in general this time complexity
is oven okay like you can think about it
there's always okay that's one way so
the other way we're talking about you
know we can just do go through for
i
in range
range any number of characters in the
original strings of n minus two we're
gonna check and here that every possible
substring of three digits
how do we check if the substring
contains only one unique number one way
would be
d equals s
i
i plus three okay so this is the
substring of three characters then we
how do we check it if the length of the
set of d
right we convert it to a
set if you only condense one unique
number now we just do this length of the
set convert it to the substring of three
and then we remember we need to remember
this answer answer at the beginning is
empty and we need to do this answer
equals the maximum of answer
and then d right and then we finally
return this answer this is the first way
of doing it okay
hello what have you learned today last
question what have you learned all right
what's the problem okay okay
yeah we want to find out we are given a
string of numbers okay okay
we are given a string of numbers yeah
positive numbers from 0 to
0 to 9 so there are 10 possible digits
in a string only right and we want to
find out the largest
substring of three that contains only
one unique digit so basically the only
ten possibilities yeah from 99 aaa
backwards to 000 how do we solve this
from what have we learned today
uh we
backwards going backwards
so how do we backwards
yeah yeah we basically prove first yeah
we check the
997 if it's in
the substring okay if it's an exception
when we talk about some complexity we
ignore this uh constant time right
because
this outer
outer loop iteration we only iterate 10
times right this is a concern okay
okay and the other way is we check we
continuous checking
every possible substring of three and we
if it's only containing one unique digit
we remember the maximum value of it okay
okay that's it for today goodbye
bye bye thank you bye