hello mr mr rhino you're right
yes okay so look we have we are given a
list of words ryan
eric and and we also give a stream
e-r-i-c-r-y-a-n-a-n-d so the question is
that
can we break this this uh string using
the words given here and each word can
you can be used multiple times
so look here
look for this one eric
is here right so we can use eric this
here and we can use the ryan here
and i'll use the n here okay make sense
okay so another example how about s
equals
e r i c e r
can we can we do can we yes yeah because
as i said what if there's r y a and e r
i c and no
good question yeah that's okay yeah
that's a very good question so
each one you can use it or you don't
need to use it and you just what if it
is e-d-h-i-r-y-n
[Music]
no no right because you can't find you
we have to complete the string let's the
string the sentence in the string using
the words and each word could be used
multiple times okay how about another
one okay egg is delicious
that cats and dog
can we no why because they know
that's right yes and how about if i put
the s here
no because i know f
yeah if i put an s why not look so
cat
scent
dog okay yeah you get a point right
how do we solve this problem if we ask
the mommy to solve this problem what
does she what do you think you will try
to do look before say i don't know
but given this look given these very
simple examples you could as a you know
normal people what would you try to do i
mean for example this average
my question is that given this right
given these
this list of words and given this as how
would you do it i mean how would you do
it you know without any programming
knowledge right
yeah but you need to be more specific
not just saying a agreement right so yes
it's proof of us yeah
search or preferences okay
these are all okay to solve this problem
but what i'm interested what i'm asking
is how would you solve this problem by
guiding me through right so given this
sentence how would you
find out if this sentence can be
broken into these words given
i'd put the word
in the dictionary and then check
if it's in the screen
yeah you'll mention very good point
dictionary sets yeah because we're
giving you the list
you'll be
more efficient if you use a set to
to store these these awards right
because there will be
oh one constant time to look up if a
word appears in the
list yeah okay okay you say that to look
look at the words in the x right by
going through this
string
and then how
so look i will check
if e in a string no if e r is in string
no if i eri in the string
in a given this e i c yes
then because e i c is in a list so what
would i do i will jump to the next word
and i repeat until i reach the end all
right
and i'm here right okay i check if e
is in a list
if it's a given no yeah
if it's given no yeah if it's given yeah
i see if it's given it's given that's
great let's check
even the next word right and i can
repeat this process as many times as i
want right using the that so you
basically lose using this definition
i would be the index
your index we are currently at so so
at the beginning i i'm standing here i
equals zero
right i can jump forward if i find a
word in here for some eric and i'm gonna
jump here eric i jump here
and i jump here right ryan ryan if i am
reaching the end then i find a solution
all right
so if not for example if this one
cat
cats and
and dog okay so cats and dogs cat
you know what i jump here s s
s a not in the world s a n no no s a and
d not in one
not in the world and then
i quit because there is no way to jump
to the end
yeah yeah that's one way
the other way is the slightly different
so every time i'm still jumping but
every time i go through this word so for
example e i'm here
so instead of checking e e r e i e i c
checking
the next possible word yeah
i will just go for the opposite i will
go through these words and then check
from the current positions to the least
length if it's y and if it's array if
it's n
yeah slightly different okay
so if i
equal equal the length of the string
then we return as i said return true
right right because look
if we are reaching the end we are able
to jump
to the end then we find the solution
right
if not then we go to the four
the end yeah for n
in range from i plus one to the end of
the
string
plus one this is to do
the one position beyond the
end okay so have we have two plus one
here right and then what do we do if
s
i
current partition up to n
if it's in a word in a word we can
convert the list of words to
w equals set of words yeah we convert it
to what what's the
what's the advantage if we do this
we convert a list to the set what's the
advantage
the advantage is we look up look up time
yeah because of one because if you are
looking a word in these that will be
linear you know yeah you have to check
each word one by one and then
the time list will be o n times n if n n
is the number of the words in the list m
is the average length for each word you
have to do this but if we convert it to
a
set it's a one constant time because the
chess table okay now look if it's in the
world and also
also that's research also therefore
search we are if it's in the world and
that we start with the end we jump to
the end right learn
return true
otherwise return false
one thing is missing here
cash
whether cash
if we're not putting the cash what
happened because each look we're jumping
at each each partition each index we can
split on a split so they are for a
length for a string given the size of n
we have two we have n plus one way to
to split so the time connection will be
exponential of o to n but for this one
if we put a cache
i is the index that could be at most n
space we have n states from zero to n
minus one right
so there will be n states for each one
we iterate so leave each one we're
iterating o n
and then look this substring
substring is o n so the time conduction
will be
o n times o n times o n right look
recursive here so the time to max it
will be o and q b
or n cubic
so what we just need to call is return
outside return dfs 0 okay
yeah
by putting a cache yeah without the
cache let's proof of status search okay
o2m by putting a cache
this is basically like top-down dynamic
programming yeah because we're
remembering the intermediate results so
so we don't repeat for each dfsi we only
calculate once right okay so that's one
way okay what what is mentioned about
the other way
slightly different is
is we are not
we are not iterating over the next
straight
point right we are not this is to
iterating the split point but we are not
iterating this people so here yes this
is the same and then from this line we
are doing this for
a
in w yeah we're going through the
efficient area now we just check
going through the list of the word we
just check
e
the next for example this is for the
length of four the next four characters
if it's the same as these if it is then
we can jump right so
the lens would be
what n a equals length a
and then a string so if s i
up to
to n a right so i plus n a if it's equal
then a right if it's equal to a and also
that's what such
that difference will jump to the end
jump to the next one will be i plus and
i
then return true otherwise looking for
slightly different which here this one
is to jump to next split point well what
i'm doing here is to
go through the list of words one by one
and then check if we can jump jump to it
right and basically we are also calling
itself the default search
so what have you learned today come on
what have you done today
about word break
or break yes what's the problem okay can
we can we uh
there's some words and a string and you
want to
find if
the words in the string are in the words
okay
so we are given a list of words
this is our these words are unique we
can use the words as many times as were
including zero times and the question is
that given another string we want to
find out if we can break the string into
words given by the list
today that our approach
blue force definitely
yeah and if we put in the cache there
will be top-down dynamic programming all
recursion with the mean momentation the
default search eye means that what we i
is the index right so it means that if
we can we can split
the sentence from the index i
at the beginning from index 0 0 is the
first first character if we be able to
split the sentence split the string
from the zero index right from zero from
i in the index side so if it reaches the
end then we find a solution otherwise
the next index the next three point this
is the split point will be from i plus
one to the n
and then this is the substring if i
from the i to the end
it was and also if releases in a word
then we can check we can jump to the
next one which is the end right then we
return through otherwise
so for this one two three four we can
use the any any keyword
because look this is basically to check
if any
any
yeah if uh if we find the solution if we
find any solution here right
we can return any s i to the n in w and
define search and for n in range i plus
one right
let's using the fantasy syntax and okay
that'll be it for today bye-bye
bye-bye