hello mr ray mister right now right make
a fury feature yeah
uh actually today is the
30th yes definitely
okay so what have we talked about
yesterday
yeah so we are given this the list of
words right so
and then we want to find out if we can
break the sentences by using the words
given okay so first of all
is a string okay so first of all we
convert it to set because by converting
the list to set we achieve a faster
a1 constant lookup time right because
using the hash table
and yesterday we talked about the data
search
without the cache is the buffer deficit
actually i is the index size we can also
pass the string as parameters to to
represent current string we have
construction right it's quicker to use
the index eye performance wise okay
by putting the cache we are remembering
the intermediate results so we don't
calculate over and over again this is
kind of like top-down dynamic
programming recursion minimizing
memorize minimization okay so
so we use these four we check the four
the index and yeah we iterate for each
recursion so we iterate over the next
split point right so for example like
every ryan
also we have another arabic ryan for
example
so
we are here we can split with the next
jump point could be here or the next
jump point could be every divided here
right right so it needs to check for
each for each index i need to check if
it's possible to jump to split you know
to the end yeah so there will be n
possibilities right so
if we put a cache here right so like
obviously there will be o and
for a string of size and there are n
plus one split points for each recursion
we are iterating over the possible jump
point till the end that's on here
and the substring is o n so like time
complexity overall is o n times o n
times o o and cubic the space complexity
is purely determined by the recursion
depth for this implementation the
recursion depth is the maximum is o n
the phase complex is our and
if we are here
dfs i i from zero to n
right so that will be the the recursion
depth is going up to n so we also talked
about slightly different yeah this one
is to iterate over the index the next
clipping we can also
iterate over the words in the dictionary
right and now we check if it's possible
if the word in the list is next possible
substring if it is then we can jump into
it it's slightly different but yeah the
time and space complexity is the same
okay at the beginning
at the beginning this is the search tree
so we can jump to eric
and then here we can next we jump to
eric uh
to write right so f y yeah that's a y
and then n right
away y
n
all right and possibly if we add another
keyword it would be
every right and then possibly you could
jump
everywhere yeah yeah
and then end you see
therefore search
going down as deep as we can buffer
search level by level see that i can in
order to implement the buffer search
what kind of data structure do we use to
implement a preference session um
yeah impression one exactly
dq
d e
so it's a
data structure which you can push and
pop
on both sides so from this side would be
push i will be a pen
and then if we want to open to the left
it will be apparent left
and top
right foot is the from to take an item
from the right hand side
and if we want to take items from the
left hand side let's call the top left
okay the first search so at the
beginning we put push the loot here take
everything out from the comment queue
with eq items
we push the kids back to the cube okay
so
every time we can take one item from the
queue
or we take everything and we append we
push the kids back to the cube let's
breakfast search
we can use the processors to solve it
okay
and also we need to use this hash set to
remember
the split points we have been
visiting right so we don't need to do it
again and again so this is the same
thing as lesson
w equals set words
convert converted to hash set to allow a
faster look after now we have a scene
equal set
q equals d q dot ndq at the beginning we
start at the index field of the first
index so wire q
now current position we just q dot top
left okay so now we need to check if the
current if current is in sin
then we continue because we these uh
position we haven't seen before we have
uh visited before so there's no need to
do it again right because we've done it
and then if it's uh not seen before then
the first thing we need to add it to the
the set so we know
next time we don't need to do it again
so scene.add
current this is to expand the kids in
the horizontal level level by level yeah
before
x in
branch right the next play point could
be from current
plus one up to the end length
s plus one
and this is the same as the definition
so we just have to check if
s starts with the current up to x
in w
the substring is in the list if x is
equal equals the length
then x
it's reaching the end we return true
otherwise we just q dot append
up and the next index would be
x right
and if we can't find any solution this
is to say we are jumping to the end if
we can't find anything then we return
first because there's no way to
jump to the end
this
converting the list to set
so we can look up faster yeah one
constant time this thing
has said
just to remember the index remember the
split point look eric
y and
n okay so we'll possibly hear right or
here
so if we can jump to eric or we can jump
to and then jump to ryan so you'll be
every here
and ryan
and and you can also do this uh
every provider if the every grinder is a
word in the given list
right so suppose we we are we are here
we visit everyone
right we visit the area right in here so
the next time we jump to everything
right we don't need to do it again
because we have this is the same path
from eric right
yeah okay so
in other words right right we want to
construct the sentence every question
there are two ways one way is every
class ryan the other way is everyone so
once we know we can construct every wire
right we don't need to
do it again right because we know we can
visit here this is the the the thing
here we are talking about uh if current
in visited and continue otherwise we add
it to that
c
and then we are iterating over next
possible jump points
yeah split point the substring is given
in the list then we check if we can jump
directly to the end
now we tend to otherwise we push this
the next jump point x the q contains the
index we can also store the substrings
right but storing the index the numbers
is more efficient than storing the
string
this is one way the other way would be
slightly different okay so it will be
the same as yesterday in the depth
session for x in w we are going through
the words
in the list
then we first of all we get the length
x
so we just check if s
current
current plus and x if is equal to x
right and then this is the same if
if nx if current
plus and x equal equal
the length of x
then we return to we can jump to the end
otherwise we just q dot append
current plus nx this method is to
iterate the next possible jump point
this method is to iterate a word in a
word in a given list right i don't know
because there if there are n words there
are impossibilities right and then we
just have to check if we can construct a
substring from the current position
to the length of the words
right and then if it is if we can jump
to the end nobody can throw otherwise we
push the next jump on this
uh yeah so slightly different but
bubbles are okay
the time convex steel is uh the same to
the depth of clutch with the
minimization so which part is the
minimization in this case you know with
the difference we'll use the cash
yeah this is minimalization
that was defined
reference search eye we remember every
eye index so but in this breakfast
search how do we minimize the index i
yes notebook but in this particular case
which we should
set we have seen we have seen it before
so we don't need to continue
yeah
okay so what have you learned today one
last question what have you learned
today breakfast search
what's the problem and then how do we
same problem as yesterday okay what's
the center from yesterday basically
yeah can you just explain to me okay i'm
sitting right here so can you explain
[Music]
yeah and we've got a big string and we
have to break it into words that we're
being given like this yeah
um
we start
okay
so you got a given word like this
yeah
yeah so
this is
this and
so you break it up exactly and each word
can be used as many times as you want we
don't have to actually need to use all
the words and for some words we can use
as many times as we want okay but what
if
what but what if there's two words in
words in the word
can you give me another one
like
eric eric and ryan and in the
okay yeah basically this is the problem
here and then in the string there is
erican varian
so the sentence what's the sentence eric
eric and ryan is word eric eric yeah
ryan
yeah and then we're given this eric ryan
yeah we can use it as i said we can use
this everything as many times
every day
it doesn't matter every area okay
what's the solution we are talking today
we're using preferences to search
the possibilities from the
from
to the end
so another another example very tricky
example is that
okay e r i c
eric
a and the ryan okay so eric can write if
we are given this word
e
r i c
c a and d
r y a and can we can we do this
no why is that because on eric here
and there's no c that's right yes
okay
exactly okay
what if we got a c somewhere else like
that no i still we have to construct the
whole sentences we can't
construct partially
it has to be a complete sentence
okay
okay so yeah so the breakfast search
breakfast search so basically we're
expanding the trees level by level
that's the difference okay never mind
ever
yesterday we are talking about a deficit
with minimization basis the deficit
we're using the dfs i
i is the index
where we are currently at the split
point for each index we can split into
we can break the sentencing by that
index i so bfs i means that if we can
break the sentence if we can break the
sentence from the index i okay and we
use the cache for the professors we are
traveling level by level so from index
zero the next prosperous
index could be maybe two three four
and then we are visiting two three four
and then again never mind i'm using the
queue for example for each for some
index we we can visit in many ways right
for example in uh index form zero to
four here maybe zero three four here so
look that the note 04
the note 4 has appeared many times so we
don't want to
calculate it over and over again so
that's why we use a zinc table to
remember to only calculate only one
okay that's it for today bye-bye