hello hello hi mr mr ryan
yeah we have been talking about this uh
wordpress problem okay what's the
question
yesterday we talked about the
preferences yeah
breakfast which preferences rent
research is
bff
yeah okay let's just quickly see how the
preferences work okay so we're gonna
collect it one two
three
four whoa five
six
seven okay so first of all we have a
queue
double ndq and double ldq and then at
the beginning we put the one in
yeah and then every time we take one
item out of the queue or we take
everything out of here
we push it if you take one out the kit
is 2 3 4 we incur it one by one
okay so now that's the difference now we
can take one
or we can take everything out right if
we take everything out then we can make
sure that
all the nouns in the queue belongs to
some number okay if we take everything
out two three four the key will be five
six eight seven
five six seven
we are given a list of words and then
also we are given a sentence a string
and the task is to check if we be able
to break the sentence we break the
string using the words given and we can
use as many times the words
as possible okay does it make sense yeah
can you leave some letters out
no oh that's a very good question we
need to complete the whole string right
so for example like
a b c d e if we have a e c b
it's not possible to complete the string
because a we have a we have b we have c
we we have c d but we don't have e so we
can't jump to the end
so how about a
b
c d
uh and then if if if we have another p
here right if a b c d b
b
e
and we have uh we have e as well so then
that's okay a b
c d d p yeah we can use the p as many
times as you want okay yesterday we
talked about breakfast search the day
before yes they will talk about deficit
who is the
minimum migration cash yeah with the
breakfast search we still need to use
the hash table to remember
the path we remember the spread points
we have visited right otherwise the time
complexity will be exponential because
there may be some intermediate uh notes
that have been explored that will be
explored many many times so we don't
want to do that
so today we're going to talk about the
bottom up
dynamic and then
now top down is that recursion with
minimization remember we use the dfsi
gfsi this is a function defined and we
put a cache
so dfsi i is the index
noting that
at which position we are currently
splitting right okay
so it means that we if we are at
index i
if we can jump from index i to the end
that's basically what it means that we
put a cache just means that
you know we were stalling we are
remembering the intermediate result but
for the bottom of dynamic programming
it's the opposite way
so let's say if we have a dpi
an array means that if we will be able
to construct a substring from zero index
to i yeah so basically if we can
construct a substring from zero up to
i not including now what place what it
means for example a b c d e if dp
what does it mean it means that 0 1 2 3
if we can
construct a string up to abc
from start to abc if dp 3 equals true if
there's a d in addition if i'm telling
you we can jump from star to abc here
right we can construct it as substring
abc and if there's a d e in the string
so can you tell me if e p
dp 0 1 2 3 4 5 if dp is true or false
what i'm telling you dp3 means that if
we can jump to c including c this
position abc okay you don't need to
worry about you know how we are getting
here but
the thing is that i'm telling you that
we can jump to c at this position also
i'm telling you d e is in uh dictionary
so can you tell me dp5
can we jump to e here dp3
means that we can
jump to
c position zero one two three not
including d abc okay true and i'm
telling you d e is in the dictionary so
can you tell me if we i'll be able to
jump to a b c b e here yeah yeah yeah
obviously look you don't have we don't
have to worry about how we're getting
here i'm i'm telling you i i know
we can get to this point here there's a
d in the dictionary so obviously we can
just connect these two pieces
yeah let's directly program it okay so
ppi means that if we'll be able to jump
to
s i right we need to set it to true if
we find what if we find dp
j
is true
and also s from j
to i in w we can update the dpi right
make sense yeah
so this is the opposite for the d f s i
it means that if we can jump
if we can construct a substring from i
to the end right at least this dpi means
if we can construct a substring from the
beginning to i not including i okay
yeah this is opposite i basically doctor
and button out a reverse direction right
remember fibonacci number
one
zero
so f n equals f n minus one plus f and
minus one two y
yeah if we using the recursion the
question with the minimization from top
to the bottom let's talk about dynamic
programming but if we calculate f0 f1
and based on the first two values we
calculate
f2 f3 right f2 s3 exactly let's put it
up right so this is the same we are
storing the dp values in an array
instead of using the cache
okay that's the main difference between
bottom up dynamic programming and
top-down and minimum programming okay
sometimes called recursion with
mobilization
so if you want to explain dynamic
programming concept to mommy what would
you like to do it needs cash
now i mean how would you explain this to
someone who has not got the programming
knowledge what is dynamic programming
dynamic programming is minimalization
thing
yeah remember the intermediary design
so for example if i give you five
chocolates and like 10 minutes later i
give you another chocolate how many
chocolate will you get i give you five
and then i'll give you one later what
how many cigarettes
six yeah easy why is that because
one exactly that's very simple so you
don't actually count how many in your
hands right
you're not counting okay i got one two
three four five six
because you already know you have five
in your hand
and one more coming so how many together
five plus one
make sense
yeah that's the spirit of dynamic
programming storing the intermediate
results so we don't need to compute over
and over again okay we are reusing the
intermediate results okay
work great okay let's come in back to
this work break
the
words
i know we're gonna string first of all
we need to convert a list of words into
a set why is it better if we're
converting a list of words into a
sentence
and n will be the length of the word
the list
and then dp equals at the beginning we
set it to force
times n plus one
yeah
v p zero at the beginning we set it to
true
when we talk about dpi the i this is the
one index beyond previous one so ep 3
means that s 1
s s 0 s 1 s 2 not including three okay
so t p 0 the at beginning we set it to
true yeah because if we're given nothing
we already make it yeah we'll already be
able to split nothing okay and then for
i in
we
we iterate the split point
yeah
and then for j
in
range i
if look if dp j okay if we if we be able
to go to dpj
right and then
also
s
j up to i
after i is in w in in the in the list
right so look a what we given this
example before abc will be able to get
to abc as
dp3 here
but now i'm telling you d is in the
dictionary right so d is in addition so
that means that dp i we can set it to
true
i know we can
once we set it to true we don't need to
continue in the current loop
this is the series of the dynamic
programming i'm telling you that
somehow
we have constructed the substring abc
right because bp3 is true and now i'm
telling you that d e is in a dictionary
b is in the position so it means that we
can construct a string substitution
abcde right
the last one we just have to check we
can dp
n or dp minus one the last one right if
we can if we can jump if we can
construct the substring as
n
right if we can construct the substring
as n
this is the same thing can we analyze
the time complexity here look one loop
one loop one four
one four o n o n n times n n square but
here substring o n so time complexity
will be o n times o n times o n is o and
cubit let's space complexity we are
allocating a space
so the space complexity is always so the
last question what have you learned
today so far come on
what have you learned so far come on can
you tell me what have you learned about
can you explain what's the problem
programming
can you just say a little bit more try a
little bit more not just uh saying a few
sense he was okay please come on
okay we learned about that
what's the problem and how we stop it
the same as yesterday
what's the problem
[Music]
yeah you can use it more than twice and
no letters can be
left out in the big string okay yeah
that's good and
each letter in the string could only be
used once
no uh
no
the string in the list we can use as
many times as you want we don't need to
use
those ones
there's no limit on how many times we
can use it
i mean like that one eric and
okay okay
so what's how are we uh implementing
these today
we're using
dynamic programming
yeah and how is that different from top
down and first search
eating cash yeah and we have to remember
the thing yeah okay so what are you
doing
[Music]
so how many ways can we solve this
problem how many ways can we solve this
problem
two
two no four
why is it for how many how many ways can
we uh what kind of argument have we
learned in the past three days can we
solve this
process
and what and what's today what's not
dynamic
okay
okay that's it for today bye-bye and
proof of yeah