okay sit down please
so today do you do you still remember
the link list
yes
[Music]
because there's so much fun talking
about these
now this is given this head yeah
we keep saying head every time
okay so if i tell you that
all the numbers in a linked list are
unique
unique you know so they're not duplicate
numbers they're just
unique yeah yeah means different
different
then they are numbers of different so so
now
now i give you a number yeah i give you
a number like a two
can you remove this from the link list
yeah okay remove this so i give you a
number
number value yeah all i want you to do
is re we
remove the value from the linked list
but but pay attention it's unique all
the numbers are
unique so if the value does not appear
in this
then that's fine just return just modify
it just don't modify the
link but if there's value like if i let
value is two
then all i want you to do is take this
out
yeah takes out and then
link this here okay one three
four yes so just to take it out
any ideas
any ideas yeah take
the second one out
yeah yeah how do you take it out
yeah don't cross it you just uh
just close it
yeah but how do you ask computer to wrap
it up
how many cases are there one
two three four
then we just need to return that
its head the next right yeah
if it's not a head
so this is current so what what do we do
now previous stop
next current the yeah because
it's not equal to current but we need to
make it equals current next yes
yes
[Music]
so let's do this okay define
remove define remove the
node okay and then we're given a head
and i'm very okay what's missing
always okay so now if your given a
header is
num yeah oh
then we just return okay we can return
now okay because
you are given nothing then there's no
point to
look for it okay i'm right yeah okay so
now
if head
value is value
okay
so what happened here what happened
if the head value is the value away yeah
return return whatever
what are you reading that chinese book
look look alright this is one and we are
removing the one this is head
so what what should we do
we can head down next right we just
abandon this
we don't want to leave yeah all right
okay so now
now if we uh so what
what should we do now we can do this in
recursive way
look we can say here that because heaven
if if at least at this point right if at
this point height
is not the value right it's not the
value we're looking for
so we should we should we should keep it
next equals current dot next
now we moved we can do this because we
remove now
bracket head or next right
okay so recursively you think think
about it
[Music]
yeah look now i'm here ahead yeah
head one so now this is this is not the
value we're looking for but
hector next is some another link list so
we need to keep this node and it's next
equals
okay this must be somewhere here remove
next no okay and then i i just need to
return
return one return
return remove return one
[Music]
head of course head because the head i
keep it yeah
yeah all right okay so this is one way
and how about we do it in
because i should have got that yeah yeah
you see do you understand
the next equation because now at this
point the note to be moved must not be
the head it must be possibly but it must
be in somewhere ahead of next
right and i use the remove note
recursively
check yeah all right all right
i'm all right yeah you're right
return head okay now we can do this
define
okay if this is i copy here i copy here
and i copy here okay so
y so now i i have a p
equals hap
[Music]
equals head dot
next all right because
currently the header is not the node we
are looking for then we we say this
y
uh we possibly need to save the this is
this is previous okay let's do it
previous
previous note and then current note and
but we need to
uh let's say we have current note okay
current note equals head dot next
previously okay
and then why current one color node is
not noun
right look if current of
the value is equals to the value we are
looking for
right now we found the value we need to
looking for now
what we do previous stop next equals
what
previous equals current.next
and then we just need to because i just
told you that it only had
all the numbers in the linkage are
different so at this point we can return
right
return head right
if not if this is not if it is this is
not found
the previous
current will be equals
current and then the current will become
current next right yeah
so please the previous note become
current note
and the current note will become calling
the next note right
yeah yes so this is another way of doing
this
look we just have uh remove one okay so
we only remove one node okay
got it yes but this one
is it removing only one node no
if not this one is only removed
in one note but this one may may be more
more than that
right because look if height is value
with
value is if there are duplicate numbers
then you will return head on next
right you had returned headphone next
head on next equals no head on next so
these two are not
exactly the same it's the same you will
remove if they
are duplicate numbers and then the
number you're looking for
is the number you want to remove right
then
then what
yeah then if there are two two variants
it will move ahead of next
yeah yeah i think this will work this
will work yes my mistake
if you want to remove all everything if
you want to remove every
every number if there are multiple
numbers yes
if there are multiple tools you want to
remove
so if you have the magnetic you want to
all remove it
so add here remove before this
return to remove uh remove node head on
next
like in this case it will remove every
every node okay and this one
if if then if you want to remove
everything
so i return i'm not looking ahead here
so if current value becomes very
previous previous not next equals
current or next
and what should we do previous equal
one and then look
okay so this is previous this is current
okay so now
i just link it okay so now
now i need to move this previous equals
current
and then current equal then and then i i
need to put here
current equals current dot next
right so because this is this is the
note okay
this is the note i'm going to remove
yeah but when i remove
really i need to move the current into
the next note
right yeah into the next step and then
after this
the previous current and then we just
need to move shift one more time
right yes yes and how about this is the
same
look if this is the this is two this is
two
so that will become a problem right will
that be a problem
because you you're here and then you
move you move it to here
and then you move it to here but this is
not removed
okay this is not removed
so in this case we have to you'll be
tricky here to write
right here so you will have to change
this if to white
why current y current now
equals the value
right and i need to do this previous the
next previous dot next equals current
the next current
equals current the next right
and after this i can relink it another
way of doing this is
is is what hey
okay so uh i think that's enough for
today uh let's do the coding too yeah
can i
[Music]
can you not jump but every time i told
you
you're on youtube and when you keep
jumping and then people are not seeing
it
the screen will be shaking
yeah remember we have leads there one
two to nine yeah i think we have the
princess
yesterday so we we kind of need a point
link list increased we don't need this
we don't need it so hey bye
so let's uh printed the index
we need this then but we don't need
anything
after right yeah
okay so now if i print it print the link
please
so what you what what does it mean
so what does it twin it put into one to
nine right
let's remove the number five okay
number five in the note in the middle
let's remove the middle okay
yes
let's add a parameter here so let's say
before before okay let's let's then we
can
add a message here message and then i
say
print message okay
so now we can do this now let's remove
it
so define remove the node
head value let's try the first one
recursive okay let's try the recursive
one so if head
is now return what
none right if half the value
is the value we're looking for return
next right yes yes
otherwise what have done next uh
actually
this is the
[Music]
uh note value
right yeah and then let's let's try if
it is work
okay you remove our head
five okay and then we need to because
are not sure if the head is removed we
do this
head equals removal head okay
and then point pulling this
head after right
does it work i'm not sure okay
yes oh no it doesn't work it doesn't
work
look after it has nothing so what what's
the problem
no head of value
why it doesn't work i don't know
it was hard if head of value
is the value we are looking for then we
return head to next note
it seems all right
does it seem all right why is it not
working can you guess
because neither after
they are ahead with me
why it doesn't print anything print the
head
you see because you're not retaining
anything right
you need to return head right you're not
returning anything so it doesn't put
anything yes look the fire is gone right
you see yeah it's a it's a featurity
right
of it
[Music]
okay so let's look how about if we have
multiple values let's see that does this
version
remove two files okay
yes so let's see let's add
let's
add another note which is five okay
does it does it remove all of it no it
doesn't remove it look before you will
be fine
in the beginning five at the end it does
not move yeah
right the second second
node is not removed right so
easy fix would be just do this
remove node head
the next note right
[Music]
sorry she's being wet
because there we move now have the next
value because we're missing the
parameters here right
we need to specify what what you want to
remove
yeah you see it's okay
do you get it i get it
the the there are two
one five the other five right
i will be more one needs to move the
move this one
so it's gone it's gone
yeah monster is right okay so this is
the recursive version so it's working
how about
we do this non-recursive version which
is let's call it remote
number two okay version two okay if i
remove row two cut value
if have this is the same
yes so now
if head is numb return now if head
so let's say previous now equals
now
why carano
is known now so we also have to check if
the
if head of value is value
if header value is valid
the next next node
value right so this is this is the way i
i could now i can make sure the first
first note is not a note we want to
remove okay
current note because head or next no
why can't a note
we move return head right
one current note
so y current
and current is not now right now
and current dot value is the very well
removing we need to
link previous the next node will become
the current dot next no
then then previous
current will become current current
on next note yes
right uh premise
next month previous next now and
yes then if current is now then previous
was current current will be covered
that current will be none right so so
now
if current is now
the current is now when i
just needs to break right
let's try let's try
oh oh oh there's a problem there's a
problem
that's a problem which is not right it's
a bit tricky let's let's let's
double check why current ah
yeah we forgot the current equals
current on x
right here
currently it was current dot next note
okay okay
so let's try remove the first one okay
let's try to move the first note
we just want to remove the first note so
you should print the two
uh two two to five yeah
the first note is one yeah
i guess wow
[Music]
oh no it's not working look there's
something wrong
what the heck
what no oh i didn't i didn't save it did
i save it document
did you did i save it oh my god a
document
yeah yeah it's working look it's working
look yeah the one is gone
this is the one version let's try the
other version
uh
let's try the other version yeah does it
work
yeah it also works okay it also works
so today to sum up to sum up
uh we have two versions there are two
versions of remove the link
note and both versions are able to
remove
the note with the value multiple times
don't
please yeah let's find it
so this is the
yeah so here when the because
the special condition is that uh to deal
with the first note if the first note is
for now we're going to remove we have to
pay stage special attention to it right
all right to get it this is this one is
a bit easy to understand right because
if you put
think about it recursively then this one
is easy let's just talk about the first
one
which one uh this one look it's easy to
understand right right
from line uh 24 to 130
okay let's
[Music]
please please please look if head is not
return now yeah if the value is the
value then this value will be removed
this now we have been removed now we
just return to you know
remove the next bit we we are appending
the current node right
abandoning the corona by the head right
because we know
this the head is the the note we are
going to remove that with appending it
when we move the no
the head or next note otherwise this
note we are going to keep
now head to next note equals remove now
okay so do you get
yeah it you get it so which one you
think is easier it's faster i love it
it's easy to understand
what's your opinion um
bye bye bye
oh look at that