we have two strings s and t we have some
lowercase letters in s and we want to
find out how many copies of t can we
make by using the letters in
s
we can rearrange the s okay
so two copies yeah because look we have
two e's to us two eyes two c's two us
okay look two ass here right this is two
are coming from here two who are okay
for us okay
and
a and ryan okay
okay so we can easily map it
yeah so two copies
okay how do we solve this problem what's
your thoughts every grind anybody
um
you can counter what do we do using the
counter for we can use the
dictionary yes indication we can use the
counter in person so what are we
counting
we're counting
the number of
of the
number of tests let's say the number of
letters exactly okay so for example if
like we have we want to construct the t
t equals area
for simplicity eic
and then if we use the counter e will be
1 times r will be 1 times i would be 1
times c will be one time and if we count
we do the same for the counter s
so if the s counter if e two times r has
three times i have two times c has three
times so how many copies can you get
three two okay
and if i is only one and how many how
many times copied one yeah why is that
because there's only one r and
it is two that
there's no another r yeah exactly so we
always aim for the minimum right so the
minimum the smallest number of uh
letters the frequency determines the
number of copies exactly so we can just
use the counter okay we can also yeah we
can also use the two force but blue
force is not very straightforward in
this case so basically how do you
propose we go through the letters in the
t
if this is e then we remove the e
in one copy of e
ah we do
r i we remove one eye
etc if we can finish the removing the
letters in s after going to the
one copy of t then we have one copy and
keep going in this way we can find out
the
number of copies we can make okay the
most efficient solution will be using
the counter we're using the counter
object right counter default dictionary
we'll go through the uh letters we think
of the letters by
uh by two string and then we update the
frequency but we we can also use the
counter right so using the content will
be easier so how do we use the counter
s equals counter bigger axis
t equals counter so we have these two
counter things
right so now we just have to find out
the minimum right so for example if e
the t
in t the e letter is has two times and
the s in s
okay listen in s but what if the
target's not in the string
the target that's a very good question
when the target is not in a string yeah
yeah that's very good point so we can't
make a copy any copy that would be zero
right so but
that's a that's a very good point so
look this if e two times here and in s
the only this is uh s yeah this is s
this is the target
eight times
so how many copies can we make
if there are eight times of e in s
anybody two times of e
in the target
so how many copies can we make
four yeah exactly okay so ryan you
mentioned about if there's no such in
the s
so if if this is zero so how many how
many copies can i make
okay so we we need to go through the t
and then we find
the corresponding counter and we divide
it by it
and i don't get the minimum right for
example this e is eight times okay
and how about r
i released two times and then here r is
one time so how many copies can we make
look
in the s we got a times of e and two
times r in the t we've got the two times
of e and one times r so how many copies
can we make
how many copies
uh
[Music]
two two times exactly because look two
divided by one two a divided by two four
we we get the minimum right yeah exactly
okay so we can just do this return
mean
s
i
divided by t i
okay so we use the double division here
double divide this is to get the integer
part which is the floor look this flow 3
divided by 2
so 1.5 look this is flowing okay look
this is for this is ceiling
we still remember
ceiling
floor ceiling
if we 1.5 we get a floor that equals to
one 1.5 ceiling that'll be two
yeah
1.5 here
look 1.5 here
floor one
ceiling two
using this notation okay so look
double divide is to
actually the same as the fraud so we
want to get a minimum of s i divided by
i
for
in
t dot key okay t dot k
so we want to go through the letters in
t and we find out the corresponding
s i divided by t and we want to get a
minimum
that should be the answer alternatively
we can do this answer
infinity then we go through and then we
get a get a copy of each one so for i in
t
and an answer equals mean answer
s i
divided by t i
this is also okay
written answer okay
so basically this line
this is the one thing if you don't want
to write this one and you can use this
answer equals master infinity and goes
to the key t
for t for i in t dot keys is actually
the same as for i and t okay
e answer equals max s i divided by t i
get the floor for par
okay the size of the
string s is n
the size of a string t is n
so basically we need to go through two
twice uh one time here one time here
okay so the time converter position oh n
plus m the space complexity would be o n
plus n because we're using the two
counters
yeah any questions so far
no
what have you learned today the last
question always about
how to rearrange characters to make
target string
yeah so we have two strings yeah
and then how do we
find out the question is that we have
two strings and we want to find out how
many copies of t can we make by using
the letters in s okay and
what's the solution how many how many
accurate can you
do yeah and
how about the profiles how do we propose
check
we go through the letters in t we remove
each letter from the s and then we can
see how many like how many copies can we
make by removing and then we rub out
yeah yeah exactly and by using the
counter we just basically counting the
letters in both strings
and the number of copy is determined by
x i divided by t i
right that's very obvious the smallest
one right
the smallest yeah
okay the time space complexities oppose
o n plus then
okay that's it for today good job bye