hello mr mr right now all right
okay give it a positive integer number
we want to find out a list of factors
right for example 12. 2 times 6
3 times 4 2 times 2 times 3 okay
so the order of the factors do not
matter so 2 times 6 is the same as 6
times 2.
3 times 4 is the same as 4 times 3.
okay and the factors i can see that
bigger than 2 or equal than 2 and
smaller than n
okay look this is close this is open is
the same thing as the factor bigger or
equal than 2 and smaller than n okay
n equals 1
return empty because we can't find such
factor bigger than 2 smaller than n n
equals 2 return empty this is a very
special case here and equals two bigger
than two smaller than two we can't we
don't find such factors n equals five is
five
a prime number yes okay what's a prime
number it's a number that i only can
divided by one on itself okay one at the
exam okay
one and itself so
does this satisfy this requirement no
okay so for any prime numbers what do we
need to return nothing nothing empty
this okay another example
n equals 13 what's your return
exactly okay what's your thoughts about
these
two if it's a prime number
and if it is
okay if it's a prime number and yeah
yeah yeah obviously point number is one
of the test cases
but for these for the long prime numbers
like 12 how do we get these answers any
ideas
you just
yes okay two
three and two two three two
two three two is the same as two two
three
so
yeah two two three two is the same as
two two three so one way to avoid
duplicate these are difficult is that we
always treat the factors increasing yes
strictly
non-decreasing okay three four two two
three okay if we solve the factors
then there will be only one right two
two three two c two after something will
be all two two three okay all three two
two this this is
yeah because we cannot find such vectors
okay
yeah
so
we we can have many ways to solve this
problem one way is to prefer search yeah
i need cube yeah using q or we can
backtracking that's using data search
backtracking how do we backtrack so
every time we check with the
we have released that bfs yeah so first
of all the current integer remaining
and then the
in order to avoid duplicate this is the
standard backtracking problem you know
in order to avoid duplicating we keep
tracking of the last factor used okay so
for example if we we are using the last
track uh factor we're using is three so
the next one we pick
should be
three or more right
yeah we don't pick two
right because three two
2 will be covered by two three okay make
sense
yeah so this s is the last factor we use
so we use this we keep tracking of this
factor to
uh to incrementally you know to
incrementally build our
list of factors so this is the currently
so
with this backtracking we use the three
parameters the current and the current
integer
remaining the s the last used factor and
then c the current list of factors okay
so remember when we check about prime
numbers yeah how do we check if it's a
prime number for example how do we check
if the 12 is the prime number if it's a
number
how do we check normally how do you
usually check i check the
last digit and see if it's an even
number but how about two
yeah yeah okay so okay so for example
like 39. the two is a prime number two
is the prime number yeah that's good
yeah i haven't even finished my sentence
okay that's fine yeah okay
so
nice
any even numbers except two are not
prime number two is the very special
case two is the only even number there
is the time number okay how about 139 is
it the prime number
um
yes no no no no what is that three
tables three and nine okay okay so how
do we check if 13 39 is a per number
usually i mean how do you check i i just
remember it you just remember how about
how do i need the calculator your
calculator
i get a calculator by using the hydrogen
how do you check if it's 39 39 divided
by any number okay so you try yeah you
try with two if it's an even number okay
i divided by two i can see it's thirty
and thirty then the
because three plus nine is twelve and
one plus two is three where then where
yeah that's the way to check if the
number can be divisible by three okay
you add all the digits right we talked
about this before right we add all the
digital prove it mathematically why why
the number if we add all the digit and
then all the teacher can be divided by
three then the number itself can be
divided but what i'm talking about is
that
let's say i give a very
complex number i don't know maybe
121 is that problem
[Music]
no what is that because i remember it
in 11 times table i thought my time
how do we check if for example if you
don't know if it's in 11 times table how
do we check
you just go okay it's not an even number
so you don't divide by two okay you
check if it's a three times table if
it's four times table if it's five times
label right so okay so
it's it's a three digit number yeah so
so uh did you visit him so i asked
google
yeah oh alexa
yeah hi alexa is 121 the prime number
okay
she come here
okay so for even numbers we can easily
rule out the even numbers except two are
no problem
for this number okay three you see in
three times seven no is it in five times
table
no
if it's in seven times table we don't
check the even numbers anymore because
we know it's it's not um right so we
don't check four and six because let's
point this am i right yeah so we skip
two three five seven nine
eleven okay okay eleven it can be
divided so it's not a prime number easy
okay but the thing is that a number we
we don't check up to how how big
how that's the number we need to check
if
in general okay this is the question we
talked about that before if a number is
n
the factors how many factors we need to
check
from 2 up to what
do you still remember from two up to one
if the number is n from two up to one
and
do you need to check up to n
half n
half n is a good guess yeah because out
of half we found
by two
yeah the half half and that's a good
guess but we still can make it
make it listen this is the make it
better
square root and why is that a hundred
we just have to check up to 10 why is
that look if we have a vector 5 a 2
so the
corresponding will be 50 right yeah
you see
yeah so if we have a 5 corresponding
will be 20.
correct
if we have 10 corresponding will be 10
right so look going on 20
you see 2 times 20 20 times 5
is the same so we just check up to 10
which is the square root let's make sure
that's 2 times 50.
okay okay
2 times 50 okay okay look at those 50
times 2 okay
does it make sense here yeah yeah so we
just have to check up to 10 which is the
square root square root of n
so this is obviously faster yeah square
root of n
is smaller or equal than n divided by 2a
when we talk about a complexity time
conduction this is linear oh and divided
by 2 is linear
okay we drop the constant
okay so let's let's see what i'm saying
here
so we just have to go through the
factors from s
here
square root of n okay and then we can
check
we can check
we can backtrack okay and then we append
this as okay i'm going to just quickly
divide this okay
you see define n s c okay and then we
have this answer somewhere answer equals
empty list
for
the factor i in range
we start from s yeah look we start from
s up to
square root of n okay square root of n
plus one so how do we implement this
square root of n in python
three ways one way
in integer buyer we get an integer bar
with n
w double star
0.5
okay
okay do you still remember this double
multiple is the exponential
x
y
x to the power of y
in person we can write it as x
times times y
x y
or
or we can write it as power x y okay
yeah this is also okay
yeah if it's zero function square root
of n we can write it also as s q r t
this is the function square root
solution one square root okay if it is
square root okay here
and what can i do
what do we do now
so we have to check if n
modulus i equal equals what does this
mean
anybody tell me percentage and modulus i
equal equals what does it mean
it means that if i is divided by n
put it in other words if i is a factor
of and right yeah so what do we get if i
is affected first of all c dot append
so this is the current list open i right
and then the answer answer that append
we
we make a copy and
n
divided by i okay so look if we have a
factor i
we have another factor n divided by i
okay and then we do that to the
backpacking okay so this is look
we have the factor i so what's the
remaining if we if n and now i'm
training we have a vector i so what's
the
remaining 12 and we know we have a two
so what's the remaining
six yeah so n divided by i all right
the next factor we are using i the next
vector should be more
should be equal or more
than i so we put i and the current list
will be c
okay and then here we need to restore
the
currently electric and if we do this
that such we start with and the smallest
vector should be is two
and then the current this will be empty
at the beginning we don't have any
seconds
this this is to put the i
it to the c so this is the same thing as
c plus equal i this is the same thing
okay this one this is the make a copy of
c so we can also do this deep copy
deep copy
copy
r c or we can convert it to a list see
this is also the same backtracking we
have a factor i so the remaining will be
n divided by i we we are using the
vector i so the next factor should be i
or more right and we're changing the
list because we're backtracking we are
changing the list here
so means after backtracking we need to
restore c dot pop what's c dot
two three the pop what happened if c
equals bad then c dot top will happen
it pops
three yeah so c will become two right
because what look three
is a pen here as
i
three is a pen to see if i is three
right and then after backtracking needs
to restore it
okay so this is backtracking
okay so what have you learned today
about factors okay what's the problem
and how are we solving this problem
the problem is well what's the problem
come on
ryan
then
yeah we're given the integer positive
integer and what are we trying to do is
we try
we factorize it yeah we're trying to
find a list of factors yeah
and you know how do we solve the problem
of the duplication
for example we solve the factor of
duplication like 2 2 3
is the same as 2 3 2. come on can
anybody tell me how do we
using this approach how do we solve the
problem multiplication you know we just
find 2 3 or not 2 3 2 because 2 3 2 is
the same as 2 3
which parameters controls the 2g3 yeah
which parameter look
controls the used last used factor
s that's where
n is the current remaining s is the last
use factor yeah
yeah c is the common list of factors
right
okay that's checking okay that's it for
today bye bye
bye