hello hello mr mr ryan how are you today
yeah i'm very good yesterday we talked
about this
factor combination so basically we're
trying to find out a list of factors
that whose product is the n right for
example 12 the list of products is we
can have is that two three two or two
two three these are considered as the
same right
okay so we the agreement we're using
yesterday is backtracking which is
basically like recursive data search
deficit with some
optimization so
so the one optimization is that we don't
want to continue with the duplication
for example like two two three is the
same as two three two the idea for this
optimization is that we keep tracking of
the last user factor okay so for the
next factor we're going to use it has to
be no less than the last user factor
okay
yeah yeah yeah yeah so look for this one
yeah level search n is the current
integer s is the last use vector c is
the current list of the factors
right and now we
start with the s up to square root of n
we talked about this square root of n
and right for example like if we want to
find out if a 100 is a prime number so
how do we do it usually you know 100 is
an even number for example like 121
if it's a point number how do you how do
you how would you usually check if it's
a kind of number
if it's
121 okay so
okay i just remember my times table
okay so but if you
for example if you're not remembering
those for example what which time table
you
start checking two times they about
three times
i'm starting the three time tables yeah
yeah yeah two times table we can easily
rule out for the
even numbers yeah if it's not even a
number so we don't need to check two
four six eight it doesn't matter right
right because it's not an even number it
certainly cannot be divided by 4 6 a all
right it's not in those
even numbers time table so we check
start with 3 3 5 7 9 11 right etcetera
so the idea is we check these factors up
to square root of l right for example
100 100 we have two and corresponding
which is 50. we have
four responding is 25 so
look we have a number which is less than
square root of n then sure if we have
another factor which is bigger than the
square root of n right to 4 times 25
equals 100 yeah
it means that we also have another pair
25 times 4 equals 100
so that we appeared in we are
incrementing building the list of the
factors c dot upon i
once we found out the i is a factor of
uh is a vector of n right so we
can bear
an answer which is the i
and n
divided by i
so then we backtrack we find the factor
i so the remaining factor would be n
divided by i and then the last use
factor would be i and at least we're
passing in so the idea of backtracking
is that afterwards we need to restore
the list okay the other way we don't
need to modify the c is that we pass a
copy so instead of c dot append i so
we just do it c
yeah and we put another one i and
divided by i and then
c
just
plus i okay
yeah so so we don't need to do this
right because we are passing a copy of
it so we don't need to restore it okay
so today we're going to talk about
breakfast search basically it's quite
similar than that but we are just
expanding our search tree level by level
in the level by level order okay so i
guess you must be very familiar with
specifics so how do usually you
implement the preferences using what
kind of data structure
dq double ndk okay answer
q dot
q
left here so we use the eq double ndq
because we want to achieve the all one
constant the most efficient way to do
this operation in both
sides of the cube pop top left a pen a
pen left if you don't specify the
directions
by default it means that to the right
okay if you want to pop from the left
hand side we have to put the left top
left append left okay if we say append
it's on the right if we say pop is from
the from the right okay
so
answer equals empty this this is the
answer we're building
so at the beginning dq
we put the you know because we look we
are we are requiring three parameters so
the n we're putting the n we start with
two because the
smallest uh factor could be two right
and the smallest factor factor is
considered as
up from 2
up to n not including okay this is the
closed
and this is
open
this is the same thing as factor bigger
than 2 and smaller than n okay
at the beginning is empty
uh this is empty we are pushing a couple
right
three three elements what's this what's
the difference between trouble and away
at least
anybody
so
why a q so this is the standard but for
search we take it from the queue we
dequeue it and we dequeue it so the
number
tomorrow i'm doing swimming oh yeah the
last factor and the coverage equal q dot
power one by using the dq as a q so we
need to queue the problem
and then these will be the same
therefore we need to check we need to
check the next
possible factor you know factor so
for
right for i in range
we start with the last we
go up to
num square root of
and num yeah square root of
n there are three ways of doing it right
integer
and mathematical multiple 0.5 we talk
about this how we can use the power
function or we use the sqrt function
those are okay
uh plus one
if num
divided by i remain zero right so it
means that if i is a factor of num
answer the append we push that we find
the one solution which is the current
plus
i
and n divided by i right once we have a
vector i we also have a corresponding n
divided by i and then we need to push
the result pushing the key q append
append
and
okay this is n
divided by i the last unit vector is i
and the list will be
current we make the copy
plus yes i
okay
so we're finishing with this with an
answer this is the numbers i okay
right now
so i is a factor of num so we push we
push the result we have a result with
current this is the current list of the
factors and plus
i and
num
divided by i okay and then the next
kit we're going to explore is
once we have
found the factor i the remaining is n
divided by i the next factor to be used
should be no less than i should be i
know more and then
the list yeah we found the eye and then
we append it right we need to make the
copy yeah we can either use this list
current or current you know this is
array slicing or we use the copy dot d
copy it's the same okay
[Music]
can anybody tell me what's deep copy
is it copy that
copy what's it what's steam copy
[Music]
yeah so what's the opposite of give copy
copy yeah so deep copy is copy
everything yeah you can tweet it and
copy everything serial copy is more like
the alias right alias so you just copy
the name right does it make sense please
okay for example like array equals one
b equals a is this yellow copy of the
copy
shallow copy b points to a so b and a is
the same pronunciation but if but if i
say this is the
b copy
yeah or we can use d copy copy dot b
copy a b equals copy this is the package
dot d copy
a
right
or b equals this a we convert into a
list
so look
this one this one and this one are all
deep copy all right but this one because
hey this is yellow
okay
okay so today what have you learned so
far what's the last what's the what's
the thing you learned today come on
okay so what's the problem and the
problem is we got we've been
we got
we got a number a positive number yes
and we have to
do all of the
we want to find out the list of factors
here the factor should be
more than 2 and less than n right so if
we're given a 2
we don't find such vectors bigger than
or equal than two and less than two
right there is no such thing and any
prime numbers we need to return empty
this is because we don't find such
valid factors in this range between two
and and not including them okay
so yesterday we talked about recursive
data search with some optimization which
is uh essentially is the backtracking
and backtracking is the best search with
optimization
level search we travel the search path
search tree
as deep as we can right and then we
backtrack if we can't find the solution
we don't keep continuing we don't
continue dig deeper if we found an
opportunity
and
in order to do this we use the q dq we
do this number by level okay okay that's
it for today bye
bye