hello mr and mr rhino all right
yeah okay so yeah we talked about the
binary tree before you find on the tree
final tree what's pine on the tree any
anybody yes
look this is the final tree
[Music]
how do we define a binary why this is
the binary
question because yes
i know you know primary but what is the
financing if you want to tell your
friend what's the binary in computer
science data structure how would you
describe it
like that's one answer yet but it
doesn't have to be numbers right i put a
number just for the simplicity it could
be
the names it could be objects it could
be anything right it could be me yeah
every subject okay so playing games oh
yeah yeah so listen yeah the binary tree
is the data structure what's the data
association data structure is easy to
instruction
it's for computer it's in computers how
do we store data yeah we use the data
structure this is binary tree why is
that because if you look upside down
it's like a tree and binary means two
means that that for any node
the maximum number of kids
is two that's binary finally two right
the binary tree is also it's a tree
three is a graph right especially the
final tree right it has the maximum two
kids and the note without
any kids we call it loot the note we
allow
any children we call it
leaves okay so you need spinach what
note are the leaves how many leaves
knows do we have here
one two
three notes
three
what's leave you said
okay so why do you say one two three
uh
okay so we are given this final tree and
each note it has this unique number okay
unique this thing number
right unique
so every now is different and we also
given the target
okay
right for example k equals three
okay so can you tell me which is the
closest leaf node to k equals 3
which no which leaf now is the closest
to 0 3
7 yeah obviously and how about if i give
you
that's a tricky one right 6.
this is a very unbecause if what
happened if we already given the note uh
you know which itself is a leaf note
should we return itself or should we
find another leaf right
i think he should return itself
but turn itself yes because
because
closest leaf node okay so we turn over
linearly this node to the target k
so what happens if the target is already
a different node
right so we just return itself yes
you're right
right it's the root
it's also a leaf
okay so we return six and how about if i
have these five if i giving you k equals
five so which note is the
closest note if not to five
eight hey if i have another leaf node
here like nine and then i give you k
equals four
so which leaf note is
the closest to four
eight
how about nine
[Music]
okay you're measuring okay okay this is
not really good
okay okay good and this is that
and
this is
i see i see okay okay very creative okay
so in this case you can return a or nine
doesn't matter we are not measuring on
the actual distance okay good yeah i'll
return it yeah
ela will be okay okay what's your source
above is
looking at all of the yeah
yeah i didn't find all of the leafs now
yeah
897 in this case and then
and then
just look just calculate the distance to
it yeah okay that is a very intuitive
way that's very good
intuitive is for human we look at this
we have a very powerful brain we can
look at it we can get the answer
straight away because it's future
depending on how big is your brain yeah
it's just there right
the computers are dumb right so we have
to tell the computer how do we solve
this problem your approach is okay for
humans you know if you ask mommy
mom look at it like that it'll be very
easy for mommy to figure out which is
the closest leaf to the cake but if we
implement this kind of idea in a
computer if you ask computer to do this
kind of thing then you you'll be complex
it'll be difficult for computers to do
it right because we have to you know
implement these algorithms
it's not trivial to implement we are
given the loot right we're given this
load according to your agreement find
the least the final leaves we need to do
the deficiency of processes right yeah
and finally
and and then if we get a collection of
the leaves then we have to calculate the
distance calculate the distance
for all the leaves to the k right
and also also we need to find out uh the
k where is the k right so
in order to do this
it's not easy how do we calculate the
distance between two nodes in a binary
tree you know for binary tree the tricky
part is that once you are given the root
you cannot visit the kids from the
parent
but you cannot go vice versa in order to
do that we we can convert it to a graph
remember we talk about this right so the
loot children yeah left and right right
it has two points pointing the left to
the right but we want to pitch the
reverse direction if we are given this
root two we want to be able to reference
the parent so in this case we convert
into a graph suppose we we have already
have this kind of graph and then we
calculate distance between any two nodes
what's the traversal agreement if we
want to traverse a graph
and find the shortest distance
[Music]
level by level when we found a node it's
a shortage distance right yeah because
look
it's preferences she never buy level
only found it it's a shortage that
search may not be the shortest distance
in this graph we have given these like
unique numbers here so first of all
convert the graph yeah so step cl
convert the tree to the graph 3 to the
graph graph we can use adjacent metric
or adjection this yeah we talk about
that how do we store the graph right
graph is more like a
g
g is a very powerful graph is a very
powerful data structure with the
collection it's a collection of vertices
and edges and vertices and edges the
vertex edges and for the graph we can
have these
uh directed right directed a cyclical
with a direction or we if we don't have
a directions we call it
undirected graph for the graph you can
have cycles in it right you can have
different components buffalo tree it
says to be one piece and one component
you can't put the two two trees that
would be called a forest right and you
cannot have cycles the tree does not
have cycles yeah but even so we it means
that we can convert the tree to a graph
but not vice versa right sometimes the
the graph is not a tree so that's why we
cannot convert it backwards but for
definitely tree is a graph so we can
convert a tree to a block for to convert
three to graph we can use the different
search references as well right so once
we convert this graph then we can do
this all right this is the improvement
to your angle you are saying that find
the leaves right find the leaves do the
perfect search each right i'm taking the
distance right
so why not start with this k and do the
pressure search until it hits one of the
leaves
you'll be quicker right because in this
case i just have to do one thing one one
process right makes sense
so i do this first search
yeah five six two and then the next one
a okay i found it a is the shortest
result but
according to your angular how do you do
it i do this breakfast search here
distance to here two
okay i i notice down two nine distance
here two
here distance one two three four four so
i have to do
three times of personal search in order
to find the shortest distance right
and if we reverse it
if we start refreshing with from the
sauce we hit the leaves and we stop
that's the closest
my approach is better right but yours is
good
that's the first try okay correct me if
you spot any mistake okay i cannot
guarantee the code i write on y bar is
100 correct which means
okay like g
g e
means that
g for example g1
is at least two three
it means that
no one connects to two and no one clicks
to three okay that's what it actually
means okay
so
so we use the definition define default
search definition is quicker to write
than the process search you want to
traversing
just the graph for converting the tree
to the part
so in order to do the use we need to
have a parameter route the camera knob
and it's parent
when we traverse the tree
because it does search from the root we
can find out its parent right so we can
just add it backwards a link right so
look if not root we just repent
okay and then we just do this type of
search loop
turn left okay what's the parent of a
louder left
exactly yeah and what if i i'm going to
travel the number by three
yeah wow
okay and then look if parent even has a
parent then we get a link
and can you guess what's next
right and g1 look i have a loot
i have a parent
so
so i'm adding a link g loot upon parents
this direction g
parent parent dot
append right okay so and at the same
time we should note the
what are the leaves what are these notes
okay so i'm going to put a leaf note
here leaf
leaves equals a set okay
so what counts is a leaf note
if it does not have any kids right yeah
now we just say if not do don't left
and not do the right right if it doesn't
have any
children
then the leaves don't add okay because
it does not have any duplicate numbers
we can use the set yeah oh we're going
to use at least it doesn't matter leave
the add
load of value okay that's a leaf node we
might just be able to
store the values inside because it's
unique to g root of value
parent of value current of value load of
value okay so now we have this graph now
we do this press approach
how do we implement the preferences by
the way
okay qtq yeah we talk about this look so
one just a little bit summary okay four
five
six seven
so we have a q double and q q first in
first out right
and we use the dq double ndq means that
we can we can attend and pop in both
sides
we can use the list in python as a queue
right exactly but
the problem with the list is
is the operation on the left hand side
is very expensive it's linear so we use
the eq
to achieve
one constant the faster operation on
both sides a pen pop
a pen left
top left okay we talk about this when we
want to do this operation on the left we
have to
put the surface left otherwise right
before it's on the right so look
first of all we put a little e1 in we
take it take everything out right or
take one knob out push its kit it's two
three yeah so we can take everything out
and append that kit or we take one out
two it's kid is four five put it back to
the queue
three it's keep is six seven put it back
for you okay so every time we take one
note out or we take everything out we
push their kids back to the queue
they're two ways if we take everything
out of the queue and then we append
their kids back to give that guarantees
that at any time all the notes in the
queue belongs to the same level okay
q equals dq at the beginning we put the
kr k
k is
the target we
want to find k
because we're converting to a to graph
then we need to use the hash set to
remember the notes we visited right
usually for the definition breakfast
search on the tree we don't need to have
these uh
hash table to remember the notes we're
only traveling from the parents to the
kids we don't go back right but after we
convert it to a graph we can go both
ways
right so for example one go to two and
two go to one one go to two two go to
one we don't want that right it's a
waste of time just to do the cycles
so to avoid that we use this notebook to
put down the notes we have visited
in a notebook in a headset okay
so seeing
equal sent visited
y r q okay and with current equals q dot
pop left if the current is in the leaves
right if we follow this node we just
written current then we just find out
what its next note connected to it so
for n in g
current
but before we append it back to the q we
need to find out have we visited right
so if
and
in or if n not in sin if and not in sin
then c
dot at n and q dot append when we put it
back to the key we need to remember the
node we are visiting so let's uh take a
look at this time connective
for converting the tree to the graph we
need to visit all the nodes obviously so
each each node visited once
oh and time here one space is we're
using this dictionary right how many
edges for a binary tree the maximum
look if there are three notes how many
edges
two right
yeah for the three because we can't put
it yeah
this is the maximum number of edges for
one two three four five six seven seven
notes right so how many edges one two
three four five six so if the end note
there are n minus one edges right
the space complexity for storing three
as a graph is also immediate fine
because it's a tree it's not a complex
graph for graph is not a tree for n
nodes how many edges
therefore knows how many edges
the complete graph okay i can put look
how many notes on the edge one two three
four five six edges
right so every time i put another note i
can have uh
n minus one edges okay let me just put
this in the table right so one note zero
edges two notes one edges three notes
three notes
three notes three edges four notes
how many edges six edges right
five notes
finals 10 edges look at do you see this
uh
people in
15 edges right
plus two plus three plus four plus five
okay so the next note is what seven
ounce is 21 edges how do we get this
number one plus two plus
three plus four plus here
here n minus one right so this is the
this is the formula so n minus 1 plus 1
times n minus 1 divided by 2 okay so we
got the square right the space
complexity will be o n square right
performance 3 is o n because for the
tree
we don't have cycles coming back to this
uh for the breakfast search
obviously oh and space owen time right i
want space scene okay
yeah i talked a little bit too much
today okay okay so what have you learned
today what's the problem and how do we
solve it and how many steps are we
solving it come on the last question
guys
what's the problem three
yeah we have three what are we doing
with the tree
yeah we have given okay so we're given
the final tree with the unique numbers
and we also given that no okay we want
to find out the closest leaf node to k
and how do we solve it first of all we
need to convert a tree into a graph and
then we do this breakfast search
on the formula node and then we can find
out we can stop
once we found out the leaf node because
that's the closest using the buffer
search okay
yeah for you know for processors to work
the edges is the weight is all is
uniform it's all one right so it's the
cost of those traveling from one node to
another in the graph
is one it's all equal so that's why we
can apply the preferences to attend the
shortest distance from the note to the
leaf okay
okay let's turn space complexities on
because we're using that
breakfast search and we're using the
deficiencies to traverse uh the tree to
convert a tree into a graph and that's
going to take old on because all the
notes are visited exactly once and then
similar for the breakfast search yeah in
worst case all the notes will be visited
exactly once okay that's it for today
bye-bye
you