we are given a string so we want to find
out the longest
longest substring
with no repeat characters no repeat
characters substring continuous
no repeat characters so means we ought
to find out the longest the substring
contains only unique characters so look
at this
which one is the longest substring with
no repeat characters
yeah i
that's it
yeah and we can't get this yeah because
i is included yes repeat it okay
oh this is longer yes this is more so
this is longer
anymore this is uh five characters
anymore than that
okay substring continues subsequent on
the other hand doesn't have to be
continuous the substring has to be
continuous and then the container the
substring does not contain duplicate
numbers all the characters in substring
is unique so for substring we can prove
us if we want to prove for the
substitution what's the time complexity
you know so let's say
the substring
could be c n1 plus cn2 okay cn1
picking one out of n means that the
substring of size one picking two out of
m means the substring contains more than
one characters
right this is the total number of
substrings
right picking two what does it mean to
we pick one index for the left and we
pick one index from the right so that's
the total number of a substring that
contains more than one characters let's
the total number of substring contains
one character there are n possibilities
right so if we
compute this this is n plus n times n
minus one divided by two and that's
going to take n
times n plus one divided by two
n times at this if we're going to proof
of it that's going to take the o n
square
we start from the first note and then
check after
check that long check how long it could
be and then go to the network and start
from there and then drop off not very
convinced then
if the size is n how many substrings
look this is the total number of
assumptions
how do we check each substring
okay abc how do we check how many
substrings are there
six huh
one
a seven
a b
c
c c a b a b b c b c a b c a b c
okay empty okay suppose we don't want to
include how do we proof of this
if there are n so for
it you just do one letters range n you
just do one letter and then two letter
and then three letters
yeah that could be one way yeah yeah
yeah and by doing this sliding window
thing
wait look sliding window two pointers
okay look this is the
i look
for j
in range
we start from i up to n
right look
that's what i'm saying we prove us that
this i this is the left j
is right so the substring is what
s
i t j yeah
this is the way to prove us yeah we come
coco
what does this mean what are we doing
here the i and j what's i and j index
index yes i
i zero to one
one two n yeah
and
is
is i
thorian yes so what do we have now
two indexes yeah good great job two
index and what do we have is the two
index this mean is i to j plus one
so to j plus one
j increases j i j
j so okay so we have index i we want to
find the substring from i to j and this
is the substring okay got it
and once we have this substring
then we can check if it has this
unique all the unique numbers right yeah
unique carry so we can have if check if
f function if this is the this is the
valid string without repeating
characters then we can remember the
length answer equals max answer
and the length would be j minus i plus
one okay
yeah
answer at the beginning equals zero so
the f function define f function how do
we check if a string contains all the
unique numbers or unique characters
except
whether i'm using set wow you number
yeah we return lens because i got ingo
and mn retention a equals lens
well set a right
right look
we're converting the characters
converting the string into the set and
then we're checking the size right so if
the size look
eric we convert into
the set it's also eric right
and then both sides is for how about
look e-r-r-i-c
we're converting to set
we convert you to set what do we have
e-r-i-c
the size this is four the size this is
five so this is not equal
all right yes
okay so the time context as we said if
we want to prove us to the substring
this is o n o n square
and we're checking the substring
checking the substring oh n right so
time convex is o and qb
okay so we just let's avoid this one
e-r-i-c-r-y-a-a-a-n okay how do you use
the two-pointer thing right look we have
a
look at this is the
important part important part of today
look look we have a window yeah at the
beginning e
not the window is empty at the beginning
so we put an e in it right the e is not
in in that window so we put it pretty
easy right
then we we go to the right right look we
can expand to the right as long as this
character is not in the window so
the maximum is e-r-i-c okay now look
over r look eyes already in the window
so we cut it
yeah i see
so look i have a pointer to the left i
have a pointer to the right and now i'm
pointing i'm now from here this is the
new level character is r right look
because i this r
is already in a window right so i cannot
go further without
moving the left pointer so look i try to
take the e out
okay
look and then this is still in the
window so i need to take this out
right so then i can put this in i see r
y
okay
and then a look unique okay now a yeah
a is in the window right this is this is
the kind of window so how do we do it
we take the left we take it from the
left take it from the left it waits it
waits and here
this a is not in the window okay
why can't we do this because substring
is continuous so we keep doing that and
we record the maximum very good noise we
look at the maximum
length of the window
because each window is a substring
yeah how
are
you now we know
y
okay o is in this window right
so i erase the left
oh it's still in the window where he's
listening okay he's not in the window i
i put this in put this in okay so we
remember yeah
do you see how this how how this works
yeah but don't you have this like high
school
point because when when you have a
uh
another visiting
uh letter that is already in your window
yeah and
because it's like the windows that
it's it's uh seven so don't you record
that
good question yes
so every time we need to remember the
length of the current window the size of
the calendar and we remember the maximum
right yeah
okay so okay let me implement this and
then you tell me what's the time and
space complexity i know okay and then
you need to think about what have you
learned today remember
this is
one always the final question of the day
okay
define okay this longest
blah blah blah okay
s
so n we've got the size s the left
equals y equals zero we're gonna answer
to store the longest all right and we
got a window which is the set right hash
table the notebook yeah contains only
unique numbers so while the right
pointer
is not reaching the end right
so then we need to check wire
s
r
is in
if we see in the window right if the
character added
right
e r i c r y if this is in the window but
we do move it so
screen dot remove
if sr is in the window we remove this
character which is sl right
and then air plus equal one and then now
we have to win the at s
r okay
your question is we need to remember
right so now the size of it yeah answer
equals maximum
answer
the length of the window right length of
the window
and then
ah plus equal one at the end we need to
move the left pointer right and then
return answer what's the timing and
space complexity
[Music]
what's the space from last week
why is it going ah every time from the
left in the iteration is incremented one
right so it goes to the right the left
also increments to one way right
look the air does not go bad
the maximum maximum number of the
iteration is n plus
n right look so it's all
to n which is o and i
make sense look there are an and
airpointers
they only go
to the right they do not go back
let's make it all aware the space
convexity
what's that
oh n what's the thing you learned today
what have you learned today
don't deception without repeating
characters so what's the approach you
know today
so i talk about twos and two points
yeah we're done wow you're listening
to twitter what's the term complexity
for two for us
cubic
yeah because o and square to proof of
the substring and o n time to check if a
string
is a contains unique numbers what's two
pointer how do we use the two pointer
sliding window to solve this problem
i'll give you another example a b c
b a b d e okay
we just we just make our window bigger
until we have okay look okay so
so i'm nothing
okay now okay so now what do we do with
this abc when b is the winner window so
what do we do
look the column window is a b c b is in
the window so what do we do so that
means so that means we record it and l
moves this forward to b okay now
b is
okay and now okay cb hey right the
window is cba right
and then we move the left yeah
c yeah and then b yeah
and now what's next abd
abd right next yeah in every iteration
we need to remember look this is to
remember the maximum size of the current
window okay yeah okay
okay good job that's it for today bye
you