hello mr mr ryan are you right yes okay
so we're giving uh something
we said some words eric
eric
and
happy
ryan and
okay okay so we are given a sentence of
words separated by white space the first
one is eric the second one is ryan so
that could be many eric could be many
ryan in a string so the question is that
what's the shortest distance between
any error to any right in this string i
mean
two yeah yeah okay the shot is distance
means the number of words between those
right so look there are two words yeah
two words between everything right and
that's the closest all right
and okay if i add that right in here
what's the shortest distance between l
eric bryan 0 yeah 0. to repeat we are
given a string of words separated by y
space and we are given two words we want
to find out the shortest distance
that is different as defined as the
number of words between
any
what one on any one if there's no error
or if there's no ryan in the sentence
we'll return minus one okay
yeah first of all spread them that's
very good so first of all we split the
string yeah so array equals s dot split
so we split the string into array of
words so how do we solve this i just
need a general idea it doesn't have to
be a concrete
yeah we're going to enumerate and how
how do we do it
index
yes index of the word so how do we deal
with the index i visually see the word
so yeah you just connect this eric eric
you collect one index yes
and then what do you do suppose okay so
the index for ryan yeah index for ryan
is zero five right
i'm not index for eric is one two right
you
you find if there's like
do you just visually see this oh yeah
yeah it's still not yeah i understand
but fear not visually
yeah size which is this size this is two
it's yeah
and this is also two which is perfect
because you just maybe you just find the
smallest one
but this one is sorted so that's good
wait
this one is the smallest
and this is also the smallest
and and then you can just do like this
is the biggest and then this is the
biggest
this is roommate three and this and
smallest
one
this could be many many numbers instead
of two so it could be many many numbers
like zero two three four five okay for
the first one and the second one could
be many cases one two
six eight okay then you just do the
smallest one
smallest one yeah
see
you sure but look if the smallest one
could be like that
so clearly five this is four different
but
right here
the tree is starting with the maxima do
you see my point
so it doesn't work right yes we have
these two arrays sorted array
a and b sorted array
how do you find the smallest distance
between any two numbers in an array okay
that's the question man
what's the method to ask computers to
try
yeah
we can prove for them all right we can
profit the numbers but this does not use
the fact that they are both sorted right
yeah and in fact if we pull forcing the
time conductor will be o and square
right yeah orange square okay because we
have to find the pairs right right
this is too slow okay this is the key
thing today
yes this method could work if the size
of the string is small then possibly
that's okay we collect the index for
those words and i will try to pull first
any number from
ryan any number from eric and i try to
to see which two numbers
have a shortage distance right
that's very slow another way first of
all we obviously we need to split the
sentences forward we'll go through the
word yeah if it's the any of these words
right
then we check if it is the same as the
previous one if it's the same as the
last recorded one
okay if it's not then that's the
certificate we calculated
if it is we just update it i'm last okay
at the beginning i set it to 9. the
index here is 0.
this word is one of the areas in line
right it's in here we haven't made any
of these so i just set it to last equals
to zero right because it means that last
uh partition the last place that
any of these words appear is at index
zero okay
okay eric here
now i thought this is also in one of
these words so i check
if it's the same as the last one it's
not right it's not the answer would be
the minimum of these the distance would
be zero last i need to set it to one
right because this is one of the words i
we just met
eric is equal to the last so
i don't check the answer anymore
instead i update it to
2. to sum up we just go through the list
of words and then every time we update
the last index if we meet one of these
words right
and if this word current word is not the
same as last word we calculate distance
and remember the smallest
mean
mean distance as first of all ar equals
s dot split we split the sentence
at the beginning answer equals infinity
and the
last and the beginning we started to
numb this is the last place
that one of these words appear w1 or w2
for
the index and the current
in numerator what's eliminated
certainly
groups yeah yeah with what what's this
index what's this
i x in enumerate these so what what's i
index
one two three
what's the value of x
uh
yeah that's what it means so current is
the words the words right the words look
remember that eric ryan thing yeah
every lion thing this is the list of
words we converted okay
if current is in
w1 or w2 right right if it's in one of
these words if first of all last is not
not right because at the pin is not and
if the current is not equal to
that that stores the index it's not
equal to array last
right then we calculate the distance my
answer equals the minimum of answer
current index is i
the previous index is last
the number of words between them is
minus one all right the number of index
two this is eric this is ryan this index
is 2 this index is 3. how many words
between what everything right here
okay so how do we get zero this is two
index two this is index three how do we
get zero three minus two that's one
minus one yeah yeah we need to minus one
here look here's what i mean
okay and then look after every time it's
in the carbon right so we need to set
the last equals i right and then return
answer
if answer is not equal to infinity s
minus 1 right
if it's equal to infinity we don't find
anything here we don't find one of these
words so it's infinity okay
time for next t o n right space
complexity
we are using the array so let's space
complex p o n okay
to sum up what have you learned today
what's the problem and what have you
learned and that's it
what's the problem
the minimum difference of two words in
the sentence well not really something
yeah
sorry uh the distance between two words
in this kind of
long sentences
[Music]
and then check
the second one and check if it's
just same as the
last one yeah yeah you're getting there
yes and
if it
is
you just update it yeah
and you go to the next one
uh slightly
incorrect here so we always remember
that update the last one and if it's
only different right if it's the current
world it's different than the last one
we calculated this time all right
if it doesn't there's no point to
calculate right yeah
do you get it
okay that's it for today bye-bye
bye-bye