hello mr mr rhino you're right
so we have talked about the longest
substring we love repeating characters
longest substring we love repeating
okay we talked about this two days ago
eric ryan
and and what's the longest substring
that contains no duplicate numbers
e-r-i-c-r-o-y-a
yeah because look yeah i see ah
okay so
yeah we talked about this two days ago
long is substring substring continuous
yeah
as opposed to
subsequent which is does not have to be
continuous but substring has to be
continued now we talked about two
solutions proof of
there are cn1 plus cn2 number of uh this
is total number of substrings right cn1
means that they are the size if the n
characters we pick one out of n and
that's the substring of size one single
character their end choice cn2 means
that we pick the left
index and we pick a right index so they
are c and two of ways of picking the
index for one for the left one from
right and then
once we have this left and right index
we have the substring so let's represent
the number uh the number of substring
more than one characters and
if we simplify these that's going to
take n times n plus one divided by two
this is the total number of subtree and
look we have this n square thing yeah n
square thing evenly we divide it by two
this is the scale of o n squared okay
so it takes o n squared to
iterate o n squared to prove us all the
substrate and for each substring we need
to check if it has all the unique
characters and that's going to take on
time so overall the time complexity for
the for this approach is the only cubic
okay and we talked about styling the
idea is the idea is that we could expand
we can explain the right pointer as
much as we can when the character is not
in the window yeah yeah after to finish
your opinions otherwise it's too naughty
all right
tell me when you finish okay because
it's too much
okay
the idea is that we have this left
pointer and then we have right point
right
listen
so we
we
extend we move the right pointer as long
as the
character in the right pointer is not in
the window right so for example yeah i
see the current window is that but r
is in the window if we don't move that
pointer if we don't swing the window
no matter how far we move the right
pointer the substring is not ready i'm
right can you imagine that all right
yeah look eic i'm my current window is
here now r is in this window right so if
i don't move the left pointer what
happened i keep moving the right
the r is still in the window right so
the only way to make the string
substring ready is to shrink
to move the left pointer to the right to
shrink the window until the current r
character is not in the window does it
make sense this way yeah
yeah the time complexity is our n why is
that
so think it this way the left we have
two pointer
and the pointer needs to
goes to the right the r pointer goes one
way the air pointer goes one way so the
maximum number of distance that the both
pointers travel together is o two times
n right so that's in the scale of the uh
linear define okay longest
substring
s
first of all n equals length s
air pointer equals r pointer equals zero
right
the answer at the beginning we have zero
and now we use the window y r not
reaching the end
now we have to check y s r
is in the window right so if the
character and the right is by pointer is
in the window what do we have to do
now this r is in a window so what do we
have to do
we
delete er and then
so what do we have to do move the
arrow to the right right so so window
window dot erase
don't remove okay remove
sl
and then l plus equal one right
window dot at sr
r plus equal one okay and then
also we have to remember
the longest
answer length of the window right
and then return answer yeah
this is not new yeah okay
make sense yes yeah
yeah if this r is in the window if it is
then we check we keep moving at that
point right we don't know we move the
air pointer we don't know when right we
don't know when
the window contains only unique digits
right
right all right so we have to check but
here i'm telling you look if we have a
dictionary d
d if i tell you d
r
the character ah
last appear position is here
one okay look i'm visiting this r
yeah
so look i'm telling you the last r i
know right is here
can we just erase every every characters
to r right because look up i know i the
previous is here
so can i just move the air pointers and
erase everything up to r
yep yep okay so look in this way now we
know how many characters we need to
remove right right
okay so this is the slightly different
but both are okay okay so how do we do
it we use a d in order to do this we
need to have this dictionary d equals
dictionary we still need the left and
right pointer wire so before this so x
will be equal the current character is s
r right
okay and then
the i the last
appear position for x is d
b dot
get
x minus one plus one okay this is a
little tricky d is a dictionary
and we want to retrieve the partition
that the key of x x is the current
character by default right because we we
are declaring the dictionary just using
a very simple
syntax dictionary or we can do this d
equals this
this is the same
the key when the key is not in the d
right
you also have an error unless we use the
get d dot get the second parameter is
the default
value when x is nothing in the key
right so when x is not in the key so
when the the this letter
has not appeared before first term
return minus one last one that'll be
zero if this x has appeared before it
will return the index and the plus one
you'll be the the index after it okay
so wire
wire air and small and i right so we
want to remove everything so wind dot
remove
uh s air
l plus equal one okay so slightly this
is slightly different here
and then
after that we have to remember that the
the
least position so it will d
x equals r
okay this is going to here
we're updating the last position of x is
current partition it's current index
this is the index this is the current
character okay
we are removing every character up to
including the last r
if every time we do this then we can
make sure the window contains only a
unique character but the window
air and r right
window this is window a
we we don't have anything
of a appear so that
these would return
i will be zero right i will be zero so
it actually doesn't go in here doesn't
go into the loop to remove every
characters up to up to the previous a
right b a b the current winter abc
carol window abcd counter
right
b okay look
b
appears before right so we do moving
everything
to after p right so we do moving this
and then we remove it okay priorities
removing okay then our current window is
cdb right
okay c
yep so remove everything up to c right
okay
e
f g okay
all the rest are the same
the only difference is this bit how do
we shrink the window right
the previous method we just checked if
that window
does not contain this sr right when you
can if it contains sr we keep removing
we are using
an additional
space d dictionary to remember the last
to remember the last index
of the current character s okay what
have you learned
we learned what have you done what's
your problem what have you
same thing
what's the problem and what have you
learned what's the what's some what's
the new thing that you learn today about
the two pointers how to
delete the priorities
differently
yes okay so what's the
the approach today
we're using two pointers yeah it's still
two pointers we are raising
the copy the copy and before it
okay so
can you explain it a little bit better
eric can do another
explanation
so basically
uh we have we given this like uh you
know letter thing okay and then you have
to
[Music]
yeah you start from
yeah you remove this thing
so how do we make sure just cut it yeah
i know now i have i'm here and ah
ah this is r okay so how do we make sure
the window contains the normal r
so we have this
eraser
yeah so how do we remove which letter do
you know
okay so we know that
and before yeah yeah so ti is the last
position so in case you where i eyes the
knots are you remove everything yeah
yeah yeah and then you will keep doing
that right this is new today the day
before yesterday about two days ago we
talked about this we haven't used use
this dr think dictionary right we
instead
we need to we check the we just check
why sr in the window right so we just
check if this r is in the window then if
it's up in the window so we just keep
keep moving at that point which keeps
swinging
that window right yeah okay so which way
notice better you think it's better i
mean just
some sort which method you think is
better
i like
those are okay both are two pointer both
are sliding window both are o-n
o and space all in time but they're
slightly different so which one you
think is better which one makes more
sense
the shorter one so which one is your
other one
this one which one the left or right
okay so three
right right you think this this is
better right
yep this is shorter yeah because we
don't have that
we don't need to have uh another
additional degenerate we remember the
last position of the current character
right but this one we have an addition
[Music]
that's right there's no normal runway
just personal opinion yeah
okay but so which one you think better
ryan likes this one you think which one
is better
shorter one is which one
which one is the other one it's tight to
be the same which one is the other one
my one
this one here yeah yeah
because this one as i said we have to
additionally declare a vision okay
okay that's it for today bye bye bye