hello mr and mr weiner all right
we talked about graph yeah what's graph
can you give me an example what's the
graph three oh yeah three is a graph
three
three finally two yeah first one
finally
graph is the data structure with the
vertex and edges
so it's a collection of vertex and edges
vertex what's vertex
vertex in
the text here vertex and edges
[Music]
okay
uh can we say that again
vertex is uh
is more than one point
okay it's like now they are no no okay
in a
3d shape initially
in the 3d space the vertex yes tree uh
tree is the graph graph is not a tree
it's not essentially a tree right okay
so for example this vertex there's three
vertices one two three and the edges one
two two two two three if the edges have
directions we call it directed directly
graph if it doesn't have any direction
you can go both way we call it
undirected graph yeah we have weight on
the edges yeah we can say okay from the
cost from one to two is two the cost
from two to three is four right then we
call it weighted weighted class today
we're going to introduce a new
concept which is called strongly strong
strongly connected component
s c c okay
super cool candy
strong strongly connected graph
strongly connected
so it's not it doesn't end in a jig
though
a strongly connected graph yeah
strong
strong connected component sorry sorry
component yeah you're right strong
connected component sc component okay so
so look if uh
what does it mean it means that if any
node any vertex in the graph is
reachable from any vertex okay so if we
have these one to two right
uh the direction two to three
three two one at least as scc strong
connected uh components
any vertex can be reachable from any
vertex is it
yeah
it's not that strong
so can we reach
one from two yeah two three one can we
reach one from three three one yes
two can we reach the
two from one one two can we reach two
from three three one two three
can we reach three from one one two
three can we reach three from two two
three okay so basically a strong
connective component is that any vertex
any vertex can be reachable from any
vertex that have that so it does from
connected or if it doesn't have any
arrows
uh that good point that's a very good
point okay so usually if it doesn't have
any
errors okay that's a very very nice
point it doesn't have any arrows so it
goes both way right if it goes both way
what happens if it's a single piece
connected component that's a strongly
connected component right
yeah yeah yeah makes sense so now
usually we talk about sccs we talk about
on uh
and direct directive
graph okay so let me give you another
example
is this a strongly connected girl
that's right yeah one we can't go to one
from any other notes right two three
four left but these are
cycles they can go from you know
anywhere to anywhere from here right but
you're apart from one so you've got the
concept that's easy okay directly graph
with directional directive one we want
to find out if it's a scc
how would you usually do it i forget
about the python coding whatever so
given the graph how how you you know
even you visualize it i mean we look at
it we use a dictionary how how do we how
to check if it's
so forget about any algorithm
just talk to me given this bro how how
do we find out if it's an sdc how to
check look at arrows
look at look for cycles
look for cycles and then what
um
[Music]
so our task is to find out if any now
can be reachable from any noun right
if you look at it it has to be like
strong and one shape
in one shape one shape also it has to be
one in in one shape connected yeah
yeah okay but connect it doesn't look
this is connected but it's not as easy
when you look at it and you lose that it
looks strong and like hardened but this
one it has a tail waggy which makes it
look a lot thicker
how about if i reverse the edges
okay so now is this a cc
no
no why is that
because they have a wacky thing
come on what seriously what why because
the arrows and this
you can't really go anywhere yeah three
yeah exactly okay so look it's not about
the shape it's also about the edges all
right yeah okay so how would you do it i
mean how would you simplify this
scenario can any now be reachable from
anyone okay i'll give you one thing okay
come on i'll give you one here so we
want to find out can any note
any vertex be reached
by any any vertex yeah
we don't we want to prove this
so how about if i tell you okay so there
are two things i need to check the first
thing is that if i'm telling you for a
single any single vertex yeah for
example you like that's for simplicity
let's just take one so if i tell you
that i can
reach
any
vertex from one
okay so basically saying that okay from
one i can go from n to any
ass anywhere else in the glove okay
yeah so what else do i need to prove
that
in order to with with these two
statements i can conclude this
so i can reach any vertex from one and
then
the second statement needs to be true in
order to prove that then any vertex can
be
reachable by any vertex so look i can go
to anywhere from one
you can go
you can reach any b from anywhere
yeah that's the thing we want to prove
but now i can tell you that i can reach
any vertical one
like i can reach any
we need to
come think about it look this is logic
this is not about
programming algorithm computer science
whatever it's it's about logic i want to
prove that i can anybody can go to
anybody's house all right for example
anybody's house
from one
you can you know i just take any note
for example right you live in one yeah
it doesn't matter you can take two for
simplicity just one okay yeah because
look i want to prove that any note can
go to any number and now i'm telling you
that from one i can go to any note so
one
can go to any other note right for
example this
one can go to two
one can go to three one can go to four
right
so look
from one i can go to anywhere
but in order to prove that any interval
can go to any node
so look for two needs to go to any node
so what does it mean to do
one
yeah so two goes to one and then can go
to anywhere right
okay so what else do i need to move
[Music]
exactly perfect that's the thing yeah do
get it
yeah we're done that's very clever okay
i can go to anywhere
yeah i can go to anywhere i prove it and
i also need to prove anybody can go to
me
right so then how do we anybody can go
to anybody anybody go to me and me can
go to anybody so that proves that
anybody can go to anybody all right
perfect yeah you say perfect
yeah so anybody
any v can reach me
all right
okay so this the first one is what is
one can go to any v yeah
okay so with these two then we can say
any v can go to any v okay any vertex
goes back
you mentioned about a definition we can
do this type of search yeah even they
are n so given graph will give a graph
with n vertex from 0 to n minus one
right now we use the definition
we use step research we can prove this
uh from first the first point from one
to n in v with replacing single data
search easy why is that
definition recursion
now we just have to check we just have
to check the visited size is equal to n
right but how do we check any v can we
go to mean with a single data set
think of the opposite what's the
opposite
no no no i can go to
one to v one to two what's the opposite
if i want
so i just need to reverse the edge
i reverse the edge and then i do a test
search
yeah
then that proves that anybody can go to
me am i right make sense
okay so let me write this definite
search okay
with the definition we can usually write
it in two ways one is location the other
one is using the wire the you know the
stack yeah which one you think is more
easy to implement
which one you think more easy to
implement
i mean therefore search the two ways the
recursion and the iterative using the
stack we maintain the stack of ourselves
or we let the consistent maintain a step
by recursion so we try anything easier
yeah of course we couldn't filter it's
shorter let's define
check cc okay check see here
so strong connected strongly connected
component
so at the beginning we're given these n
the number of
vertex and we got given these edges
first of all we need to define uh define
a check functionality check function
we start with the current node yeah we
want to do a different search we want to
do a different search from covering node
to
we studies graph right using this graph
we have already seen equals hashtag set
okay
set say it's a hash table okay
so this thing
is used to remember the number of vertex
we have visited so we do a different
search from the node 0 or node current
and now we just have to check if the
size of the visited scene is equal to n
and if it's n it means that i can i can
visit any any node from current okay
we find therefore search we can define a
function inside a function look this is
defined we have a list defined and we
have another design okay we have a
defined function from another uh insider
another function we can have a list
defined function okay let's search
current
so look if we have seen this
vertex before we just return
and otherwise the first thing to do is
to add it to the notebook yes in the ad
current and then for
i
in graph we use the adjacent list so
basically g
one equals two three four what does it
mean it means that the vertex one has
the edges to two
three
four okay that's what it means the g
g is the default dictionary and uh
defaultionally the default type is the
list list of integer list of vertex
okay and then we just have to do data
search i
right and then look we we do this step
search
with the current
and then we start
with the current and we just have to
check return
length of the
scene if it's equal to n that's a search
okay so this function we want to check
if
if from current can we reach any node in
the graph that's what it means the scene
is a hashtag the notebook
it stores the vertex we have visited and
then inside we have
another type of search look
a search we have defined another
function with the comment look if the
note
is visited then we just return yeah and
then if it's not visited the first thing
we will remember you will visit it and
now it goes through there it's a it's a
it's connected it's a connected vertex
and we'll do a different thing this is
recursion here here this is the
recursion okay
this part yeah recursion
and i will do this stuff as such and we
just need to check the size of the
visited node is n
and now look at the first thing to do we
do the graph
g equals before
dictionary at the beginning we have a
a
graph attrition graph a tuition
and then for
a b in edges
then g
a dot append
b
and the reverse square why do we need to
reverse the edges we want to check if
any note can reach me right so the
simplest way we can do is revert the
edges
yeah
we want to check if anybody can reach me
now we can reverse the edges right if we
reverse edges okay for example two to
one three two two one now if we reverse
edges
then becomes one two one two three then
we can start with the note right we
thought we solved it and we and the
problem becomes the same
as checking if the note
if we can visit any node from
node one okay
g slash equals the same default
dictionary
list
and for
a b in edges this is the same yeah for a
in edges g
reverse edges how do we reverse the
edges look
a b a
there's a there's an edge from a to b
how do we reverse the edges
the ga up and b so how do we reverse the
edge if you can get this one
perfect yes
gb the open a
okay and now we have this key step then
we just have to do this check so return
check the last thing return check
check uh
let's start with the zero yeah glo g
and
check
cll g slash okay how do you call this
okay okay
so this is the reverse reverse graph
okay we will reverse the edges
and that concludes them to
prove that any node can reach an enough
okay the time and space complexity for
the single device search the times and
space complexity is all
v plus e okay v number at vertex e
number of edges
and we do this twice so it's g
these times two and we've only talked
about complexity we drop the constant so
that the time specs complexity is still
of importance okay
what's the scc and
how do we check if a graph is an acc and
what's the approach and what have you
learned today what's new have you done
something new today come on that's it
yeah
okay if we can uh
anybody can go to anybody okay so what's
the
what's sec strong connected component in
a graph so it means that if any vertex
can be reached from any vertex right
okay so we're given a directive graph
directly and weighted graph okay it
doesn't have matter if it's weighted or
not directive weighted
usually if it's undirected
if it's undirected it means that edges
go both ways then it will be very easy
to check if it's the scc right
we just have to check if it's a single
component right all right
yeah but for the direction of directive
graph how do we prove that any node can
which be can be reachable by any number
so how do we check
we know
like one can go to energy
[Music]
okay so that's it for today bye bye
bye bye