hello mr eric misawa all right so we are
given a string of
letters uppercase and lowercase letters
and we want to find out the greatest
letter that appears in both cases
alphabetically and if we don't find such
letter appears depositing application
okay so we return the empty string okay
so let's take a look at this example
so which letters appear in both
uppercase and lowercase
t yeah t is bigger than b
so we return the t in uppercase okay and
how about this one which letters appear
r a and p
ah so we return r how do we solve this
problem
um
the last to the first and then so the
first one we need we will capital it and
the case will be
much quicker we start checking from z
up downwards to a right and the first
letter that appears in both cases
in the string and we return it that will
be the answer how many possibilities
26 27 if
none of the letters appear in both cases
then we'll do that empty string so which
is
which is nothing okay
so let's check the letters from z to a
right so how do we check the letters
from z to a ascii what's asking to do is
remember i forgot
okay
it's basically you know
a mapping between the code and the
integer and the alphabet okay so
what's 65
mapping from 65 to what what 97 to what
do you still remember
the 65 i think is uppercase a wherever
the 97 is located
and then from left to the right we use
the chr chr function 65.
that will give us a and if we go back
this way orb
a that will give us
65 okay so 65 is a 66 is b 67 is c
etcetera okay
and the sun goes with this 98 lowercase
b 99 is low kc etc okay
so for
i in range
we start with 25 up to zero and
equipment every time uppercase letter
equals chr
65 plus i right
okay because this i
is from 25
up to zero
depending and the lower case
is chr 97 plus i
right
now we just have to check
if uppercase is in a string and
lowercase is in a string
then we return uppercase
and then return empty string if we found
nothing yep
anything we can improve here look
remember s is a string what's the time
complexity here
particularly speed to check our n this
is 26 iteration so that's a constant so
the time complexity is o n this is our n
can we make it better
see can we make it better yeah yeah if a
character in a string how do we make it
yeah we convert it to set okay so we
convert this to set
equal set x and then now then we make
this one constant okay yeah
okay so look this one
65.97 it looks like a magic number right
it's not very nice isn't it right
so we can improve this
so we can just do this for i
in let's predefine
ascii
lowercase underscore or uppercase yeah
it is lowercase uppercase let's iterate
our uppercase
and
ascii uppercase this is basically a b c
to z right and we want it in reverse
order so how do we reverse a thing in in
python the easiest way would be
minus one then these i would become
z
y
etc up to
a right
now we just have to check
so we don't need these two if i in s
yeah obviously this s still needs to be
converted to set
and
i thought lower
in s right
but if i is other case if it's in less
and it's lowercase in s then we return i
right and return
empty yeah
can you guess what the swap case mean
lowercase dot swap case so what does it
return
and
uppercase does work sub case
a and uppercase lowercase yeah
okay yeah that's what it basically means
if it's uppercase a swap case will
become lowercase if it's a lowercase a
you become uppercase for
i
in sorted we saw the s in the reverse
order so the original set strings you
know reverse order
if i is in s
and
i dot swap case
sub case in s
if it is in
s and its alternative
case is in s then we return
i dot after right we are not sure which
case is it but we cannot
otherwise would return nothing basically
we return the first character that
appears in both cases the use case of
the sword case another algorithm we can
use the set so first of all we can say
uppers uppercase
uppers equals
x
for
x in s
if x
dot
is upper right so we go through the set
we we get all the uppercase letters
and then lowers
equals
x for
x in s if x dot is lower i deliberately
change the lowercase into uppercase the
upper here i can get a set of both cases
then i can say uppers
and lowers
this is the same thing as upper stock
intersection lowercase so look at
uppercase here
uppercase
and then lowercase i also change it to
uppercase so
so the letters that appears in both
cases will be in the meter right in the
middle that's the uh both that's the
both those are here
all right
so now i just have to solve both
return
salted
salted both
in reverse obviously we need to reverse
it order equals true
and then the first one zero right
if both
as we return we should return empty
string if if there's no
such letter that appears in both cases
the both will be none right it will be
empty set
and we console the empty set we just
return the empty string
and if there's at least one element in
the post in a set of both then we sort
it and we defend the first one in a
reverse order okay
this is the same thing if we don't don't
reverse the order we can use the minus
one right you can use the minus one to
retrieve the last letter which will be
the greatest
coming back to the last question
what's the
thing you learned today i have talk
about four approach
um
the problem is we have these
letters
we have for what glasses we have letters
yeah we're given a string
both uppercase and lowercase letters we
want to find our writing where it is
letter
appear in
the application location
okay so to sum up we are given a string
of letters
we're asking letters asking letters we
put those application lowercase and we
want to find out the greatest letter
that appears in both cases and when we
turn the uppercase version of it i have
talked about four solutions today for
implementation basically the first two
is actually the same the third one is
slightly different the fourth one is
based on a set
yeah
if we
checking from z to a we don't need to
solve the original method
we checking from z to a and we find the
first letter that
appears
in both cases to read attendees right at
the beginning we need to
change the string to set that takes a
long time and then we will do this check
it takes at most 26 iterations then
that's one okay okay
the the first two approach are checking
the letters from c to a the third
approach is sorting the original
string and then we check the both cases
if it appears in a string and written
after the case of it the fourth version
is that first of all we get a set of
these letters this is lowercase letter
but particularly we change the lowercase
to uppercase here because we want to
find the intersection
right we want to find the intersection
so follows is uppercase in lowercase
this is the intersection both
uppercase.intersection lowercase
then we find all the letters that appear
in both applications and lowercase then
we can solve a common part and we find
the greatest part of it
yeah that'll be it for today bye
bye bye