[Music]
hello
so today we're going to talk about a
square root do you still remember
[Music]
the square root of 64 is eight
the square root of one hundred is
ten well done for this square root of
is 14. okay
[Music]
you got the idea so this square root is
also you can also write it as
as half yeah yeah to the power
of half yeah it's the same thing yeah or
sometimes
you can do it 0.5 so it's the same thing
yeah do you get it yes yeah
so now we are going to write a function
to calculate the value
for example why are we doing this look
this is
what's this triangle
and if i tell you this is 90 degrees
this is the right triangle right with
the right angle triangle
how about if i tell you this is three
this is four and
what's the length of this side do you
still remember
no if this is right angle okay and if
this is a this is b and this is c so
it must certify let alone
a squared plus b squared equals c
squared
is it easy look this is three it is four
so three squared plus four
squared equals five squared this is nine
plus 16 equals 25. okay
if it is a triangle and this is right
angle it must certify that
do you get it yeah yeah
do you understand how we got it no yeah
yeah we can prove it different way we
can tell i can show you to your next
lesson okay how how we get this formula
but
but this is not the point of today what
i
want to do is that if if this is one
this is one this is one and what's the
length of this side
it's one square plus one square equals
this side yeah let's try
c square so that's two square equals c
square c squared
yes no no no what once
2 2 equals c squared right yes
yeah so c equals square root of 2 right
yes
[Music]
c squared equal to y i i just told you a
squared plus b
squared equals c squared remember this
is a this is b this is c this is y
angle you must simplify that do you get
it yes
why isn't that now what do you mean
because if i tell you that this is one
and this is one
and this is one and this is one and then
what's
this side uh
it's gonna be square root of two
what square root of two yeah what's the
square root of two
it's a number between one and two right
and
it then how about we taking at least
value what
is it it must be between 1 and 2 right
yes because 1 square is 1 right 2
squared is 4 right
yes if we square it it's 2 so
how about e and precisely is between
one and one point five because one point
five square
equals one fifteen square equals one
uh 225 i know one point five is two
two point two point five right yeah one
point five square equals two
dot two point five look c square equals
two
okay and i say one point five square
equals two
to twenty-five one square equals one
so c is the value between one and one
point five all right
yes it's because it's the middle so so
that's very interesting because we know
this function square root y equals
square root x
is monotone remember the word
monotone
monitor increasing it means the bigger
of
x and the figure of
y right if x is increasing y is also
increasing right
all right yeah so if we plot this
function
right n this is going to be interesting
this is x
this one x is zero
actually one x is zero y is one when x
is zero
y is zero yeah we're done when x is y
y is what what do you say when x is one
one one yes one square of one is one
yeah so this here
one x is four fifteen
no no no actually small four square
square root of okay yeah we're done two
so this is one
uh this is two three four four here
and then there will be two right two
here yeah
two here okay so
when x is nine x is nine
approximately here yeah it's
approximately here so you push it
so you if you plot this line you'll be
something like that right
something like that okay
it looks a bit weird yeah yeah yeah
actually it's it's a curve
i i didn't draw it properly so it's a
curve okay it's a curve like a
monotony increasing curve now
okay okay yeah yeah i'm very bad at
drawing but you you kind of
meaning now so when x when x is
increasing
the y is also increasing yeah
okay so now look where's two when x is
two
yeah yeah yeah x x two here
and this is two this is two yeah one x
is four this is two
so here is between one and two right
yeah so this uh square root of two
here is somewhere here right yeah we
don't know yeah so we
we can you how can we calculate this
value
interesting i give you a hint final
research
yeah look if this moment is increasing
let's get the value right
if if uh let's get some value like the
the left left low left bound is zero
right it can't be
smaller than zero right yeah and the
right bound if it's more than one we
we say it's x now we find a denominator
and now we do this a s square to check
if it's bigger than the value 1.7
one point something yeah one point and
then if it's smaller than we cut into
half remember
one point okay so no
i show you the value later okay if
you're interested okay
let's do this define final square root
definitely close
x okay left column
okay so if x is smaller than zero we
return now because there's no
such value why because
you can't find any real number okay
let me check it yeah you cannot find
any negative you cannot find any real
number like square
equals negative all right what i'm
talking about is real number
okay you will have you will learn
other numbers other than real numbers
imaginary numbers later
but these these the numbers we use daily
like
one two three two two and a half yeah
yeah square root of two are real numbers
okay these are the numbers yeah
we know okay so look if x is
smaller than zero we return now okay
yeah yeah that makes sense okay now
if x
is smaller than one
left right if it's smaller than one
left and right left is zero always the
right bound
we set it to one right because if it's
actually smaller than one
square root of x is also smaller than
one yeah
yeah so we set it to we set it to one
okay ah otherwise if if x is bigger than
one the left is zero
why we set it to x because when what x
is bigger than one
the when x is bigger than one square
root of x
is smaller than x right when x is bigger
than one okay
got it got it yeah
yeah so now we we said after we
then we have at least
now we we need to have this meter value
that we set it to
counter value let's say we cut the value
and
middle value and let's all set it to
zero because the middle value is the
initial value yeah
then we can have y it's zero at the
beginning
we guess this this number is the number
we guess
okay we guess it's the square root of
anything is
zero this guess is not right right
don't worry we made the guess the result
is the current is the
mid times me to the power of to me times
multiplied by mean so now why
abs do we still remember abs
absolute value right yeah that's the
real value if this current value
corr minus x yeah
is b still bigger than an arrow arrow we
set it to
one e minus five so it's zero point zero
zero zero one it's a very small
difference right
when it's bigger than that then we we do
this meet
equals left plus y equals
then what meter meter how do you get the
meter from left and right
left cross right what divided by
two two yeah that's the meter we get the
middle
right which is misu
and current would be meat times meat
yeah this is the main
value we get is
carbon is bigger than the x
right so if this is bigger than x
so it means that it's in the lower half
right
because the gas value is bigger than
bigger than the
guess value guess value is meet me
transmit is bigger than x
it means that we get a value which is
larger right so now then we can we can
search in the lower half which is which
we need to say right
equals meat right else
as well not as economy what
if it's smaller than x what does it mean
it's on the upper side yeah so we say
the left
equals one mid
right yeah because look left left and
right
left right and then let's meet yeah
if current is bigger than x then it
means that
the value is not in the upper part it's
in the lower bound so we said
right equals mean yeah if it's in the
upper bound and we said left equals
mid right so every time we cut into half
cut into half
right yes and after this what should we
do return what
return what return meat or current
current
mid mid return means because myth is the
value
of the square root current is the square
root
times square root right is the it's the
variable result we are comparing to x
right okay do the coding
[Music]
um
okay so let's do that coding interesting
clothing party
let's do the coding yeah it's very good
okay let's do this look
what one means
yeah yeah yes enough okay let's define
square root yeah
square root x remember if x
is smaller smaller than zero
none yes if x is smaller than one
let's write equals zero one right
because they
if it's smaller than one its upper bound
should be one
right yes left to right
equals one zero over
x right yeah then currently
equals zero zero y abs
let's define let's add a parameter uh
error okay error let's call it error
small error which is we we allow the
error like
by default be uh five okay
if current minus x is bigger still
bigger than error
uh error okay
[Music]
okay hey ella
meet he was left past y
divided by what two okay
then current equals mid one
times meter right you can also do this
meter this is also power to the power of
two okay it's the same thing
if current is bigger than x
so what should we change
right equals one
let's do this for i in range 10 okay
let's do this
then print square root
of square root of
i is
square root of i okay
let's print it let's see if it works
okay tyson
sqrt does it make sense can you make a
can you check if
the values are all right the square root
of zero
is zero yes square root of one yeah
because computer hyphen uh look
because look the fight one two three
four
five yeah if if we change this error
okay
if we change the error by default to
uh to a and
and you can see what's the difference
okay
okay so you see they're more nice yeah
they're more nice
right so this is because computer
calculated and
using this floating point there's always
a small mistake but this
this value is very close to one and look
square root of two yeah the value you
want to know is one point four one yeah
all right so
we can click and look at seven and let's
try the number between one and zero okay
let's try let's try uh
let's verify okay print you want to know
that
one point four one yeah times one point
four one
four i think it's 1.454 let's let's just
uh
come sleep twice so you can do this
square
yeah print sqrt
sqlt let's say 0.5
okay and print sqrt
0.01
okay let's see if what does it come to
look look yes you see that its value is
very close to 2 so it means that the
value
because we what we just do is one point
four five one four times itself
is is equal to one point nine nine so
it's very close to two right
so the square root of two is that it
means it's correct
0.70 this is the square root of 0.01
uh yes square root of 0.01 yes because
0.1 times 0.1 is 0.001 okay
so this is correct yeah so let's let's
check if this you know no none is one
[Music]
so let's go through this again square
root with this arrow
and smaller than one we set the range
from we
basically this left and right is define
the range we are searching the value so
we define the range between zero and one
we search the value between zero and one
at least left
if x is bigger than one we search the
value between zero and x
do you get it yeah yeah
if it's x is bigger than one actually we
can search the value between one and x
right i'm right yeah so so actually you
can you can
uh you can change this point because
it can't be less than one right all
right
so if you if you run it again it still
finds the value right you see
yeah yeah it's still i still get it
so and then when we find when these
errors current value is
bigger than uh and x is bigger than the
difference then we find the meter
and then we calculate the value and if
the
x if the current value is bigger than x
then we know it's not in the upper bound
we search in the first half right
otherwise we search in the second half
do you get it
yes so you always repeat repeat wt until
find a
very very close to very closely
this abs current minus x this is
calculated
difference between these two values
current and
x right and then if it's bigger than the
error
then we always repeat repeat until we
find a value which is very close to x
when we find the current which is very
close x what does it mean
it means that the middle value is the
square root of
x then we return the mean okay
good job any questions no
okay good job today good job
good job job good job
bye bye bye bye
bye bye bye