hello mr hurry mr rhino right
what's this
a boundary tree finally three a tree a
tree
any aluminum grass a graph yes
this is the fine tree in 270 days we
talk about to get the
maximum average that's 274 days 274 days
subtree we want to find out on the day
we talk about the death search to find
out the maximum average of subtree look
at this note
this is a subtree right
the average is two this is average two
and these
average is also two two plus two plus
two divided by three probabilities
sub subtree so basically you add all the
numbers
and divide it by the number of the nodes
right and we want to find out the
maximum right and we use the data search
and then we want to find the maximum
two right let's see let's see what's the
this is this is two obviously
this is one yeah we have we have average
two one and what's the average of these
ten divided by one two three four five
also two right average this is seven
okay we got a winner what's the average
of the entire tree
five plus seven plus three
fifteen ten
fifteen plus one sixteen
sixteen plus six twenty two divided by
one two three four five six seven
twenty two divided by two divided by
seven so okay so it's roughly three
point something right so
the largest will be seven okay so have
you noticed what did i do you know the
two seven
that's seven this is excel with the
substrate so what in order to calculate
the average because there's seven
numbers
oh yeah these seven knobs yes you're
right okay so in order to calculate the
average what do we need to know
you need to know how many
and
and every
every night
the sum how do we calculate some i think
it's like exactly
the exact thing okay so what do this
mean sum sum sum divided by the number
of nodes yeah and we talk about the
depth search so in order to do this we
need this type of search function to
return two values can you guess what are
those you probably already know all
right
define definitely
root
and this is the maximum average okay
come on so if if it's an empty tree
we return to value can you tell me what
are these two values zero zero
what are these two values for the
definition to return zero zero what does
it mean
means
the sum sum
numbers
the numbers were n the n the number of
nodes yeah okay two values one for the
sum one for the number of nodes left sum
and left node equals definite search
blue dot left right
and then right s y n equals that's the
search can you tell me what what am i
doing here do the right
okay so now look we've got the four
values the left side left no number of
notes right sum
the sum of the
right trees and the number of the right
trees right and now we want to get the
maximum of the average we have this
answer equals maximum of answer this is
we want to get the maximum average right
so the average will be the sum left sum
plus right sum plus do the value right
and divided by left null plus right now
plus
so this bit the sum of the luxury
is
the sum of the right tree is rs and l s
plus rs plus root of value is the sum of
this entire tree okay
and then the number of nodes how so
what's missing here can you tell me the
left number of notes the number of the
notes in the left tree plus the number
of notes in the right three plus what's
the number of notes in the root how many
notes is in the loop one one
the number of notes in the loop come
okay so look this because we are
calculating the answer yeah but in order
to access this value we need to put a
longer
answer and then return
we want to return
we can again we we just need to return
these two values yes so this is 274 days
okay coming back to today's question so
we want to find out the number of nodes
that
is equals to the average of sub 3 so for
example the average of these three is 2x
so we count one two equals two how many
other nodes value is equals to the
average of that subtree can you find any
more
three
yeah of course the leaf node onto
counting the number of nodes that like
equals to the average of the subtree
so look the average of the leaf nodes
the average of this node
2 to a equals to except the average
number two
two okay up at least one three okay
how about this number
ten plus divided one two three four five
two so one is not equal to two so how
many notes one two three four will
return four that's what it means
okay
this is a different search look look at
this
this is the recursion
equivalent to find the largest the
maximum average of any sub tree right
we understand this approach to count how
many nodes
left equals to the average of that
subtree which line here is to calculate
the maximum average
the second last one
this one yeah okay good job so this one
is to get the average so we want to
change it
m plus r n plus one this is average
right
so if this is equal to rules of value so
if bluetooth value
equals this bit
length
answer
plus equal one that's it
doesn't make sense man
okay so what have you learned today
um
the problem is
that
there's a subtree
there's a tree yeah and we want to count
the nodes
the equal nodes to average
so we have a tree and
and we have the
want to calculate how much notes
uh like
have the subtree
of
the same value thing yeah okay and how
do we solve this
by using
different search okay so definite search
what's this
does the search what are these two
values
and the numbers of notes why do we need
to return a topic containing one of the
sum one of the
number of nodes what do we mean off
because then we can calculate the
average whether we can calculate average
and at this point we are calculating the
average
of the substrate of a loop right and
then if we just have to check if the
root of value
is equals to the average of that subtree
then we increment this answer right
this is basically the same as 274 days
which where we calculate maximum average
yeah this bit is the 274 day where we
use the recursive data search today
just slightly different you know the
code is pretty much the same except this
one right for that recursion that search
every time we return two values the sum
and the number of notes in the subtree
with these two values we can calculate
the average you can get this that
maximum average
or you can calculate
you can count how many nodes
the values equals to their average
the time convex the space complexity
time convexity or n because we visited
each node exactly once
the space compresses on right we're
using the recursion implies that
when calling stack the maximum number of
the recursion depth is n in a worst case
it will be a linked list if a final tree
is this way
look at the unknowns
or this way or it could be this way
right if the endnotes the step will be n
and that's the maximum number of the
stack usage okay that's it for today
bye-bye