hello mystery mr rhino all right
yeah right and what's your favorite
fruit
bananas okay maybe i also like apples
okay i post bananas and grapes also
oranges
berries as well
okay i like cat and oranges oh yeah i
like fast too okay look there are
numbers we have pairs of apples bananas
six bananas you know papaya pail banana
yeah six bananas here four bananas three
bananas yeah
those are just
balls
whatever
what what's that
my favorite my favorite okay six six
actors forever three actors you can eat
our apples okay oh bananas are apples
there are six apples forever three
apples you can eat our apples in an hour
if this pie if a pile contains less than
r apples you still need to take
take one hour to finish it
so basically for example if there are
six apples you can eat the seven apples
in one hour there are six apples here
and then you can eat seven apples in one
hour
but it means that when you find six
apples in an hour you do nothing it
still takes you one hour to complete the
first
so that's why i'm playing games yeah you
if you can eat the ar apples at the time
and an hour you still take you one hour
but if you eat two apples at one hour it
needs to take you two hours all right
yeah because therefore apples and you
eat two in an hour you can do that
possible okay it will be so easy
hypothetically okay
okay so now question is that we want to
find out okay so let's say you want to
find out the minimum number of r your
speed that's the speed
that given that you can finish the all
the apples in k hours right hours okay
so look k equals five here right coming
back to this theta here k equals five
hours we want to finish all these three
apples three pies of apples in five
hours so what's the minimum speed what's
the minimum
the minimum speed is the answer is three
i equal three when i equals three means
that you can easily address in one hour
so how many hours does it need to take
to finish the effort of six two two okay
i can eat for your first in one hour how
many hours
two two
how many hours one what so two plus two
plus one smaller or equal than k equals
time
okay
when r equals two can we do it so when i
equals two what happened how many hours
we need to finish the apple of six
two three how many hours
two how many hours
3 plus 2 plus 2
bigger than k which is not what we want
make sense
yep
so look if we have a bigger r if i can
finish all the apples in k hours using r
so if i give you this so how about r
plus one can we also finish with r plus
one the speed
my speed is i plus three
when r equals three we just verify that
i equal 3 we can finish only three parts
of apples in
five hours k equals five if r equals
four can we finish all the apples in
less than or equal in five hours
yes or no if i can eat more apples
in one hour
so the total time
taken to finish all the efforts will be
equal or less am right make sense yeah
so look the speed r is increasing
the total time will be equal or less
right
how do we solve this problem we want to
minimize r
so let's take total time taken
to
finish all the effort is smaller or
equal than k
we want to find the minimum r so that
the total time
is smaller or equal than k
the apples in one pie is
n and now our speed is r how many hours
needs to complete the highest of another
and y by r
very close and divided by r
but look this might be a fraction eight
apples the speed is three acres in one
hour how many hours do we need divide
eighty minus three the ceiling when i'm
ceiling look eight divided by three this
is not enough right it's two point
something but we want the ceiling
ceiling
ceiling this is ceiling look sitting
sitting yeah this is flaw yeah
what's this eight divided by three four
what is it two okay
silly signal means that the next integer
that is bigger than the current value
okay
2.01 ceiling what's the value
three three exactly and two point ninety
nine nine flaw what's the value t is
it's ceiling
and divided by r okay we want to find
out the sum
sum of it
this is somewhere yeah we know some of
it
n
divided by r
for n
in all the
priors yeah you know all the players
okay given the r we know how many hours
in total it takes to finish all the
apples we can proof us
i'm right what's the range of the
numbers we need to check what's the
range of r so we have a pile of apples
so we want to check the speed of r
how many acres can you eat the minimum
in one hour
do we need to check zero
one
small is very one yeah obviously yeah
you can eat up one airport right what's
the biggest number we need to check so
that there are piles of apples what's
the biggest number of r we need to check
look at it from here okay seven eight
six five what's the biggest number of ah
we need to check
yes eight
yeah hey where do you know it yeah so we
just have to check one two three four
five here eight right
am right so we check
which way we check we're checking from
one to to a or we're checking from a to
one we want to find the minimum so which
way we need to check from one to eight
or eight to one
i won't do it why is that
so the first number you get
is the minimum excellent okay so we can
prove obviously okay coming back to the
sentence i equals two
we can finish in k hours
so do you need to verify if we eat more
apples in an hour
can we achieve the target with the
bigger r
yeah obviously right i'm telling you
that i can finish all the apples in k
hours which when i eat two when my speed
is two apples in one hour right if i
increase in my speed if i'm eating three
apples
certainly i can finish it right if i'm
hitting 100
i can finish it
what does that imply when x increases
as x this is the function increases
or decreases we call it monotone
monotone increasing or molecular
decreasing so what accurate comes into
your mind if
x increasing and f x
increasing or decreasing the x this is x
look
when x increases the y increases
or when x increases the y decreases
monotonous
right so look if i'm telling you x 1
smaller than x 2 then i know f x one is
smaller than f x two which accurate to
shorten the time to
o
log n
what does that imply
when we talk about complexity what kind
of aggregate gives the o log n
so we can manually research this let's
define a function f r the speed is r and
this function returns number of hours
taken to finish all the players okay so
we have this input prior and we want to
finish all the peppers in k hours answer
equals zero and then for i in
piles right then
answer plus equals the ceiling yeah we
have this ceiling ceiling
i divided by
r right and then return answer this is
the function to compute the total number
of hours to finish with all the apples
all the tiles of apples
when the speed is up right so look these
can be simplified as return sum
sieving
i divided by r
for
i in pi sorry if this is shorter ceiling
i divided by r is also equal to i minus
divided by double division which is the
integer part divided by r plus one okay
this is the same thing then once we have
this rule first for
r in range the smallest is
one the biggest
m equals maximum of all pi m plus one
and then if
f r e smaller or equal than k right then
we return right this problem might seem
complicated but the code is very simple
you see look it's releases blue force
the time complexity look
here
m
and here they are p tiles okay and then
we need to iterate m so the times this
is o m t
right
we changing this we want to improve this
bit this is slow right we are iterating
from one in the worst case this
iteration will takes uh
m times one to m
and every iteration we need to check
this
computer total number of hours taken so
om times p left boundary equals one the
right boundary equals
the right boundary equals this angle
right so why are that's smaller than
equal than the right boundary and we
kind of mean the meter
so that then lowercase meter equals left
plus r
divided by two right divided by two or
you can do this left plus y shift shift
one this is the same then look if s m
smaller or equal than
k hours okay look
left right
meter i can finish all the apples in
k hours
okay so which way i should go left or
right
left
left way down so we want to move to the
right that's it so the right needs to
move to the middle yeah right r equals
meter minus one if look in the middle we
can't finish so which way we need to go
l equals
m
plus one well
l equals m plus one because look m is
too small we need to go to the right
right and then we turn
yeah okay the terms of negative
log
n
times p
okay o log m times p
this is final search sometimes you write
the slightly different you can say wire
air is smaller strictly smaller than r
right this is the same then
r
equals
meat and then as
l equals m plus one some some people
prefer this way you know using the
strictly small and then
you have to be very careful when dealing
with the boundary this is just i equals
meter instead of meter minus one and air
equals mid plus one is the same what's
the thing you learned today
about eating bananas
no no no we're not we are not learning
how to eat bananas we don't have bananas
here and how you don't need to learn how
to eat banana it's just purely skin
eating how to
imaginary empire so we are given a pie a
few piles of bananas let me see how many
do you see in k hours
we want to find out the minimum number
of ah the speed so that we can finish
all the piles of the apples or bananas
in k hours we want to find out the
minimum so we can proof us yeah we can
prove us from one two three four as long
as we we know how to compute the total
number of the hours taken to finish all
the bananas right
so that's the f function we check from
one two three and we retain it as long
as we can finish all the apples and
bananas within k hours another way of
improvement is to use the binary search
based on the fact that if we can finish
all the apple's bananas we see
chaos using the speed r and definitely
if we increase the speed of r we can
also achieve this right yeah make sense
yeah so we're using the final result
yeah and then the time complexity will
be improved to o log m yeah because this
is the space of the r search space of r
and we lock it right so it's a great
improvement times p p is necessary
because they take we all for each r
we check
we need to compute the number of
hours taken to finish all the uh efforts
okay that's it for today bye
[Music]