we are given an array of positive
integers positive numbers we also given
a number k we need to take exactly k
numbers
from the array from the beginning or the
end right so we want to maximize the
total numbers taken right so given this
example like look we want to take three
numbers
so
let's take each number one one number at
a time the first number we can take is
this one or this one right so it doesn't
matter so we can take for example take
this one the points we've taken is one
so if we take this number so the next
number we can take is this two or this
one right
so for example we can take this one
right
take this one then the number would be
two three four five six left so
we have six we can choose six yeah
so the total number we have taken is
eight we can take the numbers from the
beginning or the end and now we want to
maximize the total number of taken okay
so it's given this example what's the
maximum number we can take 12 because
one six five at the end one six five
okay so what's your strategy
why is it five six one
it's because you need
because you look from the beginning and
the end
they're both ones so you could
so first you need to have one and then
if but
the next one is two i think you always
choose the biggest one out those
so six is there and then three or five
so it's five
okay but look this is supposed to one so
how do you decide which one is it
because i just
look visually and cut in half because
because
these numbers are bigger than these
numbers it's because these numbers are
bigger than those
this is
value six on this advantage
but how do you i mean this visual i mean
this might be a simple example which you
can tell you know it's like where your
guess
the hunch
from just
just a count you look at it okay you say
okay maybe
it's better we pick from the right so
you keep doing from the right
[Music]
the separating those
okay so let's put it this way if we want
to prove false how do we prove first
we check
every possibility how what's the for
each possibility yes what's the age
possibility so and numbers there are k
numbers to take right yep
at each point how many choices do we
have come on let's say two yeah we can
pick from the beginning or the end now
to two choices so the k numbers we want
to pick k numbers and for each number we
have two choice so what's the time
complexity how many chores total
ign
2 to the power of k let's think of this
way all the numbers could be at the
beginning or all the numbers could be at
the end
all the mixed so some numbers at the
beginning some numbers at the end right
what's the opportunity look we want to
pick the numbers and maximize the
numbers
what's left look suppose look we could
have some numbers left
this is sub-array service so what's the
opposite we want to pick some numbers
from the beginning combine you know from
the beginning only at the end so what's
left left is the green bit okay it could
be any green big right the byte has to
be continued sub array right we want to
maximize the numbers that are not a
green bit we want to maximize look
suppose this sum is s s is the sum of
the ari okay a i i
i from i equals 0 to n minus 1 right so
this is the sum of the
total array right
this is when we know this we can
calculate it in one go go into all the
numbers sum of all the numbers right
some sum the numbers the green bit is
the sum
of uh any continuous sub array
so what's the numbers that are not the
green bit one six
one so that could be one choice
we want to maximize the
black bead
the total sum is six the black bit plus
the green bit is the s
so we want to maximize the black numbers
this is the green beam is a
so what's the black pink s minus green
is a right this is the number we want to
maximize we want to maximize this s is
fixed we know it it doesn't change so
what do we do with this a
we get smaller and least
so what does it mean what's the opposite
of maximize
minimize yeah so we want to maximize
this s is not changed it's a sum
yeah of every number so a needs to be
minimized so we want to minimize these a
right
the a is continuous we want to minimize
it look k equals three we want to pick
three numbers of the black bit
what's the size of the green bit
there are total n numbers and then there
are k
numbers we want to pick so what's the
size of these
i minus k
so n minus say this is continuous yeah
what can we do with this the minus k
four numbers
what's this
two pointers yeah two point starting
winner look ten
what's the sum of these two plus three
plus four plus five fourteen okay what's
the sum of these
okay look at the beginning 10
14 yeah
18 18
all the numbers added together what's
the sum quick 22 we want to maximize 22
minus a
we want to minimize this a so what's the
minimize 10 10 we want to pick the 10
so what's the value 22 minus 10
twelve
five plus six times one yeah so can you
explain to me what i'm doing here
what i'm doing here
it has to be connected block it can't be
separated and you just
[Music]
so we give an array of numbers
and we want to take k numbers from the
array at each number we can take from
the beginning or from the end at the end
so we want to maximize the numbers taken
so if we go for approvals we can take
for each number we can take from the
beginning or at the end there are two
choices and for k numbers they are 2 to
the power of k that's exponential which
is very slow so we can think of it the
opposite way right so we want to take k
numbers from the beginning or the end
well a is bigger than
the numbers of the
card points good point so we just take
everything right
all right i haven't took k numbers good
point you can't take more than k numbers
that's obvious
when we take k numbers what's left is a
sub array right it's a continuous other
rate so
we want to minimize the sum of the
continue the remaining numbers right
because the total number the sum of the
total numbers is is not changing all the
number the sum of all the numbers is not
changing minus
the remaining part would be the the sum
we are trying to maximize right so look
s minus a we want to maximize these so s
is not changing right s is given as a
constant yeah all the numbers
we know for sure all the the sum of all
the numbers so we are trying to minimize
with it
right so how do we minimize this bit we
want to take k numbers and they are n
numbers so they are n minus k numbers
left so the size of the window is n
minus k so we're just using the sliding
window to calculate the minimum sum of
the sliding window okay array
k numbers n equals length a
window equals
sum of
a
up to what's the size of a window n
minus k right so
size would be n minus k
at the beginning we want to go to the n
minus k this is the index right so we
need to move this to the end so why are
i smaller than n
we want to find the minimum right
minimum a so m a equals at the beginning
you'll be the sum of it so win
a
b c b if the size of window is four
right always move the window to the
right one position to the right what
happened to the sun
it becomes becomes one becomes minus a
and plus e yeah plus e minus a where
that plus e minus
so
wind plus equals
the a
i
i'm going
minus equal
a
now it's i what's the size i minus and
minus k
right
and then we need to minimize this
mean
minimize of the
window
and then i plus equals one and we can
what's the sum sum of everything
minus m a
so one
two three four five six one right that's
the array equal at k equals three so
what happened
so when equals sum a dot dot
so what's win
window is
window and n minus k
is a window since this is k
a minus k is four
right yeah four okay so win equals one
four
what's the size of the window
four okay so sum a up to four what's the
sum
ten yeah okay so that's right the window
here is ten okay so now i will be equals
to four right so zero one two three four
i over here why we haven't reached the
end so window plus a i so plus five but
we need to minus what
one yeah the next iteration
and this number minus this number and
this number minus this number okay when
now i goes to the end
we break this the sum of all everything
will be 22 the minimum a will be 10 at
the beginning the last question what
have you learned today what's the time
the next day
yes or when why is low end
because you need to
go through you know what goes on what
uh n yeah it goes for the other numbers
so you have this
yes
and so
yeah
so how do we solve this problem
two pointers
yeah
okay so how what's the two first how do
we move forward
by taking every possibility what's each
possibilities
the window and then i mean okay yes for
each number how many choices
okay two to the power okay what's the
sliding window so you have this window
it
is
it is the size of n minus k yes and
and so we basically
move it
and
to get
minimize the
window why do we want to minimize the
window
so your score can get the
highest
yeah because we will maximize the
remaining so we need to minimize the the
bit we want to minimize the sub-array so
the rest will be maximized right
okay at the time directly because we're
going to the
arrays uh
you know once we update look be here
for to update to to update the sum of
the window so every time we move one
element we move the window one to the
right so when we take the new number
we discard the leftmost number all right
that's the sliding window link
okay that's it for today bye