okay so yesterday we talked about this
problem yeah we're given this an array
of numbers and uh we want to pick k
numbers and for each number we can pick
from the beginning of all in the end
right and we want to maximize the
numbers we picked each time you pick a
number you can pick from the beginning
or the end there are two choices so
there are k numbers to pick so that's 2
to the power of k right that's too slow
and we also talked about the sliding
window right if we there are n numbers
and we want to pick k numbers right so
the remaining will be n minus k numbers
so if that sum of everything or every
number is s and if the sum of the
remaining is a so we want to maximize
this right this is the sum of the
numbers p we want to maximize this
we want to minimize this a all right
yeah yeah
for example this one if the window size
is 4 and we move one position to the
right so what happened to the sum
minus a plus e yeah minus a plus a so we
keep updating the windows right the sum
of the windows
instead of
recalculating the sum if we calculate
the sum that's going to take longer
right we want to talk about another
approach today it's quite similar so
look with one two three four five six
one right we want to pick three numbers
k is equal to three
we want to pick three numbers
so if we pick zero numbers at the
beginning if we pick one numbers from
the beginning
if we pick two numbers from the
beginning if we pick three numbers
beginning look if we pick zero numbers
beginning so what else do i pick
how many numbers i should pick from the
right
so k equals three so it means that i
want to put zero numbers from the
beginning three numbers at the end
pick one numbers from the beginning two
numbers at the end right two numbers
from the beginning one numbers at the
end three numbers from the beginning
zero from the end right so if they are k
numbers they are k plus one choice
all right
so we can do this we can brief of this k
cll number from the beginning three
numbers from the end so what's the sum
one number from the beginning two
numbers on the end what's the sum one
plus six plus one
eight
two numbers from the beginning one
number from the end one plus two plus
one four three numbers from the
beginning zero number from the end
one plus two plus three
so we just pick the maximum which is 12.
okay this is more straightforward am i
right yesterday we are minimizing the
sum of the sub array
but this subway is the remaining so we
need to minimize it and we use the
s minus the
minimizing the sum then that would be
the sum of the numbers we picked
yeah s minus a we want to minimize this
bit but now we are directly calculating
the sum so we are maximizing this
i want to calculate some of these
these
this array is not changing right we want
to be able to calculate the sum of uh
first one number first two numbers first
three numbers and we want to be able to
calculate the sum of last number last
two numbers last three numbers
so what comes into mind
can we calculate this
so we we use the accumulator remember we
use the prefix sum the sum of the first
element is one the sum of the first two
elements is one plus two
one plus two plus three we are
pre-calculating the sum
all right and then we talk about this
accumulate function remember
accumulate accumulate
so when we accumulate look this is array
when we perform this accumulator what
does it become
this is array right a equals this
if we perform the accumulate
so you become 1
1 plus 2
1 plus 2 plus 3
1 plus 2 plus 3 plus 4. so that's what
it accumulates
so why this is useful so we can just
look it up right what's the sum of the
first four numbers we just look it up
this value we don't need to calculate
when we need it one plus two plus three
plus four because that's going to take
longer
we look it up yeah because we know
already
when we calculate the prefix sum from
the left to the right we know the number
yeah we know the sum we can have this
running sum right now current sum is
zero the current sum plus one is one
current sum plus two plus three plus
four plus five
okay so the other problem is we know how
to calculate the sum of first few
numbers how about the sum of the last
few numbers
[Music]
think about it okay we know okay sorry 3
minus exactly yeah we know all of it and
then we know the first few numbers the
sum minus the few numbers is the
remaining define max
point
array
a
and we want to pick k numbers first of
all let's get the numbers how many
numbers
and accumulate we want to have this
prefix sum of keywords yes so prefix um
he was accumulate
hey
we want to convert it to a list
because accumulator returns an iterator
iterator
iterator is not at least is like
what's iterator
in the year thing so you i promise you
to give you at least a few numbers so
i'm not giving you
all at once when you ask for it i'll
give you one when you ask me for the
keyword when we put this list we can
write it on the list by the beginning
i'm going to put a 0 at the beginning
okay so look one two three four right so
when we do this accumulate you become
become what can you tell me one
three
what what come on
fill the banks six ten six ten okay
weather
i want to put a zero in the beginning
because look because we only pick k
numbers as i said they are k plus one
choice
so how many choices is this
four okay
so that k plus one right so i put a zero
means that if i pick nothing from the
beginning
we need to brief us all these k plus one
choice for
i in range
k plus one right we need to do this sum
as well sum will be everything and sum
of uh everything some a
that's going to take over time
look what we we iterate k times here but
let's going to take o in time so what's
the time convexity
look there are n times here there are k
times here so the time convex is our n
k is smaller than n so
o n okay
the sum the current sum
the current sound let's see okay c
equals prefix i
plus plus the overall we pick
here
so if we are at it fetching the value
if this k equals 3 we pick nothing from
the beginning
so we need to pick
three numbers from the end right so how
many numbers and numbers
right
so now we pick we need to pick k numbers
and then we pick nothing at the
beginning so how many numbers left k
minus i right
and then from the n from the end because
we are adding a yellow
so the last value will be
n the index here will be n
so it's n minus x right so is
n is p
n minus k minus i
right
so
but we need to
subtract these from s right
this is total sum
right
this is the prefix sum
so we do this as subtraction that would
be the last the sum of the last few
numbers right and then we just have to
get the maximum answer equals maximum
of answer
c return
answer
answer the beginning is zero okay
some people might be able to write this
using this one language this is not a
mandatory i actually prefer writing it
in a very clear way so okay what's new
today what have you learned
learned about
so many
points
what's the problem and what do we talk
how many approaches have we learned
today
that one has accumulate okay now what's
our q a accumulate is basically
like zero one three six ten what is
what's the meaning of the accumulation
what it means
in english i don't know
accumulate
accumulate put it all together
little by little
yeah
accumulate you can
impress and
basically like prefix
do you still remember why we need to do
this accumulate look okay what's the sum
of uh
two part three plus four
nine
okay
we are given this array all right we
want to calculate the sum of any
intervals
all right how how would you do it the
normal way would be
you just calculate two plus three plus
one right
okay so look if consider look
listen can see that this is a very big
number one to a minion
okay
one two three four
a minion i don't know okay
i know it could be many let's say i want
to calculate a interval somewhere
for example i want to keep cancer from
two to a minute minus one how would you
do it
the stupid way would be just two plus
three plus one right you're going to
take forever right
but how would you do it if i'm saying
this array is not changing
but how about accumulate prefix sum
so look i calculate one
one plus two three one plus two plus
three
10 et cetera okay so taking this example
so this number will be
prefix sum will be 1 3 6 10 15
21 okay and what's the sum of of 2 plus
3 plus four
is it equals to one plus two plus three
plus four minus one
yeah
okay so one plus two plus three power is
ten
okay what's the sum of up to one and one
so what's the sum
ten minus one for this array i calculate
once
so i can just look it up look it up two
values look at the two values and do
this subtraction
right
is it quicker
looking up is it quicker yeah
okay
okay so okay let me repeat
yesterday we talked about
these using the two-pointer sliding
window thing because they we want to
maximize
s minus a
a
is the sum of the remaining numbers
right
we want to maximize this so
it means that we need to minimize the
remaining numbers right
for the remaining numbers we use the
sliding window to keep updating
updating the sum of the windows size and
minus k
right that will work
today we are talking about a different
approach to pick k numbers we have k
plus one choice
picking zero numbers from the beginning
picking one numbers from beginner
picking two numbers from beginning
picking k numbers from beginning zero to
k layer k plus one possibilities
for each possibility we can use the
accumulated prefix sum to get the sum of
the first few numbers right that's easy
we're doing this lookup
but
we also need the sum of the last few
numbers in order to do that we use the
subtraction right we know the sum of all
the numbers we just need to minus a few
numbers then that'll be the sum of the
last few numbers am right
okay
okay and then the time complexity look
accumulate
a one time space over in space
sum or when time so it's o m plus o n
plus okay
okay so let's open time space complexity
we're using the accumulate prefix array
so that's all going to take oven
space okay that's it for today bye bye
bye