hello hello mr mr ryan are you right so
what's this
no
what's this what kind of data structure
is this
graph graph yes g
okay is it a tree
no
why is that because it's not connected
where are the perfect okay so this is
the quad graph is actually a collection
of vertex and edges
so robotics yes when you check the graph
graph what exactly that is okay i'm
gonna put a zero here vertex zero one
two three therefore vertex the edges
one two two three okay so a graph can be
directly or undirected so at least a
directive graph or an directional
look at this
direct means with the edges has
direction it is a directive
on the next graph
yeah because we haven't got any
directions
the number of edges connected to a
vertex it's called degree right for a
directed graph it can be an incoming
degree or outgoing degree right but for
this indirect graph is just degree right
so look the degree of this one is one
degree of two is two there are two edges
degree of three is one degree of zero is
zero so the number of edges equals to
the sum of all the degrees of each
vertex
right divided by two for the direct
graph the degree is the sum of the both
incoming or outgoing degree right income
look for the directive graph yeah
one to two that's incoming degree
two to three that's outgoing right let's
look at this undirected graph let's look
at this okay zero one
two okay this is a simple graph with
three vertex three vertex and three
edges so the number of edges is three
okay the number of degrees for the zero
is two right
the number of degrees for the one is two
two edges
the number of
degree of vertex two is two so 2 plus 2
plus 2
divided by 2 right why we need to divide
by 2
look let's graph the number of edges
connected to the vertex 0 is 2
connected to 1 is 2
connecting to two is two so i can say
the number of edges there are three
edges equals two plus two plus two
divided by two why this is divided by
two why do we need to divide by two
is in between two
sorry because
between
these guys
look look this
is in between
is counting twice all right look at
edges says two end points
so
edge is at two point when i counted
these vertex
the degree it counted once when i
counted here it counted once all right
so if i add it together divided by two
that's the number total number of edges
okay so now coming back to today's
question okay we're given an undirected
graph
and we want to count the number of pairs
of vertex that are unreachable for each
other so for example like this simple
graph this graph the number of under
which the pairs so look zero can't go to
one right because it's not connected
zero comes to two zero can go to three
all right so the number of pairs is
three
zero one is the same as
one zero
the number of the pairs we are counting
only distinct number of pairs right okay
zero one is the same as one zero so
there are three pairs which are
three pairs of vertex there and which
were from each other
zero
one
two
how many unreachable
vertex from each other
why is that because it's
connected connected yes every every
vertex can go to everyone okay another
example zero one two
three four how many pair of vertex that
cannot
reach each other 33 and 2 to 4
okay wonderful
okay
0 2 3
0 2 4
one two three
two two three two two four so how many
points six
how tall do we get six
by counting dude but this is we just
haven't is there a better way to count
this there are three how many connected
components here
two okay two
how many vertex in in the first
component
how many nouns three
how many notes here two
how do you get six three times two okay
another question okay so three four five
here
so how many pairs
nine nine pairs okay and how about this
two one two three four five how many
pairs
it's hard right
right i can sort this problem
um
let's see
how do salvador
bingo
i just got you busted
oh okay come on you're on youtube but
don't say the swear word okay come on
nothing you swear okay
okay
30 how did you get 30. wait wait
eight eight yes that's now okay so we
got a six here all right yeah let's
steer close right
yeah
and what else can we get five to nothing
and we can get three five
yeah
four five
and we get a still five we got one five
we can't get four five or three five
right they're not connected that's right
we're counting the the
the pairs that connect not connected so
how many of these six plus five eleven
well what was your answer again
uh eleven you never i'm going to check
the video okay
okay
actually i
[Laughter]
what's your thoughts about that um
how do we conquer this is the last
question how do we calculate
[Music]
so look
look we have a three notes here
dictionary
we have three notes two notes here and
one note there are three groups there
are three two one when we are looking at
these three notes in the first group how
many pairs can we form by
using the notes here
three how many notes together six no
right three notes here right how many
pairs of notes connecting to the note in
the first group
three times what how many notes together
six how many notes
are not in the first group
three six minus three there are total
six notes and the notes in the first
group are
the vertex in the first two by three
there are three
so six times
minus three is we know
times three
okay here
how many nodes are in the second group
there are two right
so how many nodes
are not in the second group six minus
two all right and times two okay how
many nodes are in the third group
one how many nodes are not in the same
the third group
six minus one times one right so if we
add it together we still need to do one
thing
three times three
three times with nine
four times two
eight
five times one
five five if you add it together how
many
are we calculated as 11 why is that
why should we divide it by two why do we
need to divide it by two come on because
what i said man no come on
22 we need to divide by two y uh because
because look when i say one two
is punch and then three is four how many
how many pairs
two
two pairs y is not four
when we count the vertex in the first
group
we multiply for the remaining the number
of the remaining vertex right but when
we count the remaining we're still
counting
extra so we need to divide by 2 right
look 1 to 2 that's a pair but 2 2 one is
the same so when we count one
when we are counting one
right so we we consider this two but
when we are counting two we consider
this one again so we need to divide by
two we can traverse on the graph what
kind of traversal accident can we use
dictionary what kind of treatment is
that definitely search breakfast yeah we
want to basically given the graph we
want to count how many groups
right
how many groups and also the number of
vertex in each group and then we can do
the math all right
i know we divided by two
yep
okay
do we understand this problem yep
we just need to
count the unusual pattern zero
one
two
three
four
five okay how many pairs
how many pairs one two three four four
do you even need to count there are
three notes in the first group there are
three notes in the second group so the
last one
is nine right it's fine
okay and then i add another one six
seven how many good it's harder it's
getting harder
there are two notes in the third group
three times three nine ten to eighteen
so
okay listen how many know how many total
number of notes three three plus three
plus two yeah in the graph layer eight t
equals eight
so i'm considering the first group now
so how many nodes how many pairs can we
form by connecting the nodes in uh by
using the nodes vertex in the first
group
so look 3
times t a minus three right look a minus
three
what does it mean a minus three means
there are five notes other than the
first group right
how many notes in the second group right
is the same three times a minus three
right
yeah we are considering the vertex in
the second group and how many notes
other than the second group
three plus two here
two here how many nodes are in the third
group two times a minus two right
look
so but you are adding these together
what's the answer
three times five
fifteen
fifteen plus fifteen plus 2 times 6 12
but we have to
divide by 2 right we talk about that why
we need to divide by 2.
what we talked about is the vertex in
the first group we connect it using uh
to the second group and group now when
we're calculating the second group we
connect it to the first good look
and that's we cut double counting we
count it twice so we need to divide by
twice so that's uh
42 divided by 2 is 21 now 21 pairs okay
so our our approach today will be
different search so we definitely search
the graph
then we count how many notes in each
group right
and then then we do this math
and we can also use the preference and
union yeah we're going to talk about you
know following filters this is very
important
define how
we are given
n n nodes from 0 to n minus 1 and we can
given the edges
we can convert these edges a to b if
this is undirected graph we can convert
it to a adjacent list okay g equals
before
dictionary and it's a list right
so for a
a okay there's a h coming from a to b
means the laser h from b to a right so
look zero
to
one two three right if we have this kind
of graph the g this is dictionary now g
will be a dictionary
of one zero would be two
one two three okay and then one would be
zero two will be zero
three will be zero so basically the keys
are the vertex and the values will be
the list of vertex it connects to it has
these edges so for for example 0 has the
edge to 1 2 3
2 has the edge to zero okay this is
called adjacent list okay this is a data
structure now we have this g
then okay obviously we have we want to
have this answer equals zero
and we we want to perform this step for
search and preference search in the
graph we need to use the hash set to
remember the notes we have seen okay so
sim
equals set
and now we're going to define a default
search
command now i if
if i in scene
so this device function will return the
number of nodes in the current group in
the calendar from the i so if i in sync
then we need to return zero
and the first thing is not visited we
need to add it to the
to the hash table to the notebook right
and then a equals zero a equals one
there's at least one node for
i
in gi
we're going to the
vertex it has added to language a plus
different search recursion i right and
then return a
okay
and then we can go
go through all the vertex and count how
many
how many notes right so for i in
in
range n
in range n
okay now we have this that if i not in
sin right if we haven't seen this before
you want to count how many nodes are is
it so c who has different search i so
c equals definition means that the
number of nodes the number of vertex in
the in connected connected to vertex i
and we can do this i'm writing here
answer plus equal c times total total n
notes
n minus c
right and then at the end we return
answer
divided by two okay our answer
answer shift shift one or divided by two
okay
can you describe to me what have you
learned today what's the problem what
have you learned today
there is a graph there's a graph yes
what kind of graph is it directed on
direct what's undirected it means it
doesn't have any direction direct it
doesn't have any direction
okay common sense okay so we are given a
directive graph and what are we doing
with it
we
are trying to figure out
count the unreachable
noise and reach the pair of vertex yeah
so how do we do it what's the mess
okay so look
is the no
zero one
two
three how many pairs of notes without
any items how many pairs of notes
that are unreachable
there are four notes
with no edges at all how many pesos
let's see
so what's how do we calculate wait i'm
just talking to that
[Music]
zero one zero two zero three one two one
three two three okay basically it's like
picking two out of four f
okay that's six yeah four times three
divided by two six six pairs
pressure the number of uh
unreachable pairs
i just told you six oh yeah the number
of unusual pairs in the same group is
the same right it's the same why is why
is that look
why is that zero and one connected zero
and one and then here is two and three
and four
so zero can form three pairs
one can also form three pairs right
okay so coming back to this question
what's the acronym we use today get the
search what are we doing with the
different search
we want to count how many notes and then
divided by two look
here two steps
that these that has two notes these has
three notes right so how do we get the
numbers two times how do you get the
numbers
we times them
yeah
that is 2
2 times 3 and and then here we will do
this that is 3 times 2 we add it
together and divide by 2 so that's 6.
but why can't you
just do two times three exactly that's a
good question why yes so in this
aggregate we are going through the nose
two two two yeah and then we count two
times but we need to go to these notes
again and three times two we add it
together
but the thing is that another group here
five six how do you do it
how do you do it using your brain how do
you do it
so you just say two times two times what
five
right now five notes here two times five
three times
four
two times five you add all these
together divided by two got it
yeah because
when i talk about this two times five
these has been calculated once yeah okay
when i call these three times
four
these has been calculated again so the
the connection between these has been
calculated twice what's about like this
two this five and this is this one
yeah so everything is counting twice
that's why we add it all together
divided by two
make sense
do you see my point that i i talk about
the the number of edges look
the edges have been counted twice right
look two edges here two edges here two
edges here two plus two plus two equals
six but how many edges here
how many edges there are three edges so
three six five divided by two okay
okay let's see for day bye
you