yes okay so we are given this the
underlying graph we talked about count
the number of unreachable pairs in an
alternative graph right so given this
identity graph and directive means that
the edges do not have these directions
and then look there are three nodes in
the first connected component there are
two nodes in the second connected
component so the number of unreachable
pairs we can have is
three times two there are six pairs look
each vertex in the same connected
component forms the same number of
atmosphere pairs right for example like
zero we can form a pair unreachable
pairs
by connecting to all the vertex other
than the components the vertex in right
so look zero three zero four and this
there are two right then one three one
four two two three two four two okay so
we talked about the differences so by
using the definition we count the number
of vertex in the component so
we have double such release then we come
okay so we know there are three vertex
there are five vertex over all right so
three
times five minus three
right so for each connected component we
only calculate the contributions once
first component has added this
contribution three times five minus
three five minus three is the number of
nodes other than the components that the
vertex is when we calculate these then
it's two times five minus two right
and then we need to add it together but
we need to divide it by two right
because look when we calculate three
times five minus three we have counted
the pair zero and then when we come to
three we counted the pairs three zero so
let's consider as
a center so we divided by two okay we
also talked about these the number of
edges equals to the sum of all the
degree of a vertex right
divided by two
i
vertex
this is the
in belongs to okay so it means the i
is
in the set of vertex
so how many edges
we can sum the degree of all the vertex
the degree the number of edges connected
to the vertex look at least we have a
one plus these two
plus these one two three three
plus these two
divided by two five edges
we need to divide it by two we talked
about this yeah because look edges has
two end points we added a contribution
twice so we have to divide it by two
the edges this degree has been at the
ones here and add ones here
right so for one edges we added the
degree twice so each edges
contributes to the degree of two that's
why we
divided by
this is the definition so with this step
research as we talked about we can use
the multiplication to
add the contribution of the unusual
pairs from the one component right so we
multiply the number of the components by
the number the remaining of the vertex
alternatively we can sum up the
contribution for each vertex for example
this one
so this one can form three unusual pairs
one two
three okay and this one
one two three and this one one two three
okay
we go through the vertex in the
connected component right so
we need to use the definition to count
the number of vertex in the component we
can add the contribution one by one or
we can just do this multiplication that
would be quicker because we know by
using the word deficit we know how many
notes in your connected component and we
can just do this to multiplication
instead of adding one by one right and
if we add the contribution one by one
and that means that for each vertex we
need we need to do a definite search
separately in the worst case the term
complexity will be o n squared or o v
square n is the number of vertex right
because for each vertex we have to do
this different search to count the
number of connected vertex and in the
worst case they're in a dialectic graph
there's only one single component guess
what we are going to talk about today
okay so what's processor
is when you breathe okay so which one
the last one
wrong answer okay give you one more
chance one
no
so eric if you're having a breakfast
what's this theory
why this guy has no hairs
these guys no ears
it's this graph press means that
horizontally
as opposed to definitive
thief
how do we usually implement the
performance
q dq okay
so q dq double and dq two sides so means
that we can push and pop from both sides
and then
they all those operations are one
constant
pq
let's
take a look at these three and we talked
about this a lot when we're solving the
problems of the trees finally chip so
what's the different search orders if we
visit the left tree first
left tree
and then which is the root the current
node and then different search because
that's the such
loose on right
okay so what's the order of these left
tree
node
right
one two four five three six seven okay
and how about the question search uh one
two three four five six seven
different search less visit
one yeah therefore searches one two four
five three six seven preferences is one
two three level by level okay so we use
the dq so first of all we push the root
in it yeah so that's one in that there
are two ways of doing this breakfast
search one way is that every time we
take everything out of the queue we
empty the queue and then we append there
we incube the trojan of all the nodes
one by one for example i take one out
what's the kit of one two three
i push it back to the cube now two three
are in the same level right so now i
take everything out of the cube
so i take everything out of here what's
the kit of two
four five what's the kit of three
six seven now look four five six seven
up
or in the same level right so then i
take everything out of the key four five
six seven i push that keep like nothing
that's one way the other way is that we
every time we take that one note up one
what's the kit of it let's take one hour
once again two three let's take one now
two
what's the kit of two four five
the next note coming out from q is three
what's the kid of three six seven
now i take the four it doesn't have hit
i take it five doesn't have to get six
seven etcetera okay so when we're taking
kids out of the queue it's on the left
hand side first interest rate right this
is configured
b q
when we push the kids back to the kill
it's called inquiry that's inquiry
define bfs
uh i this is the load okay so this is
the same thing if i in c
if we have seen this node
before we just return zero okay so we
don't need to edit twice the
contribution first sim dot add this part
is the same
uh answer equals zero
q equals dq right dq i
so why are q why we have elements in the
queue or why this is the same as we're
checking the length of the field one is
the element current equals q dot
left poplar if we don't specify left
what does it mean what's the meaning
right that's right if we don't specify
the direction you'll take it from the
right okay so why is it right
the default is on the right it's like
the stack
right is right excellent rider is right
okay the bike for the kill look by
default taking from the right it's like
a stack if we don't specify the left
it's actually a stack of pop
top is taken out from the right kill a
pen
is pushing to the right top left append
that the advantage of using eq over the
simple list is that
when we talk about the operation on the
left hand side pq is faster if we
perform the operation on the left side
only as a list on this list here then
you'll be on in here we take it out from
a queue and then we need to answer plus
equals one right
and then we need to push its kit for
x
yes for x in g
i we are iterating the
vertex that connects to i right
and then q dot append
append x
so we're just appending the kids
of the vertex that connects to i
and then we turn and
this is the basically we're just doing
implementing these speed level search
using the question search gi means that
the vertex that connects to i so g g
stationary right look
one
two
three
four okay and then we have these five
here if we want to store this and
directly graph in the dictionary so we
use the user g this is the partitioner
so g what does g have g the keys will be
the vertex one one connected edges has
edges to two three four right so
two three four
two
have the edges to one and five right
three have the edges to one
four have the edges to one okay so look
the keys are the vertex and the values
are the list of vertex that has edges to
connect it to so gi
means that we're going to the vertex
right the vertices like he has
connections too and then we'll append
the vertex back to the queue
right let's play for search level by
level right in the binary tree
or tree it's very easy to see it's a
it's a level by another thing right yeah
because three
upside down yeah level by level
what's level by level in the identity
graph
one
two
three
four
five
six okay so what's the preferred search
order
zero two zero one two
four five
six three okay look because the distance
the one and two are closer
zero one two
and then these two notes level one
all right
and all other notes
number two okay so it's zero one two
three four five six okay
there might be a problem here
because we have to check if the vertex
has been visited so we have to check
here if
x not in c right and then we do this q
dot pen and then
because in binary tree
we don't usually check if the vertex has
been visited we don't go back so there's
no chance to visit this same vertex
twice but in a graph it seems the edges
are undirected so the vertex can be
visited
more than one so so we have to mark it
as digitally so it doesn't go back make
sense what's the problem now what have
you learned today
there's
a
graph there's a graph yeah season
breakfast
we were given a graph and directed graph
and what what do we want to do with it
we want to count the
pad or notes
in it
why do we use the breakfast search
what's the professor's going to do
zero one two
three
four okay so how many i need to prepare
zero here
so the point for certain differences you
count the vertex in this component there
too right so how many knows all together
there are five so the contribution of
these three components is two times
five minus two
here the contribution of these is what
the same 2 times 5 minus 2 the
contribution of this one is 1 times 5
minus 1
right we added these together
we added all these we have to divide by
2 remember that's it for today bye
we are given a undirected graph we want
to count how many unreachable pairs from
each other right so look the note yes 0
four this is not very clear what's the
difference between undirected one and
directly graph one directly
in a direction that's right no direction
so it means that both way the edges
coming and go for the both way right the
direction
yeah so it means that zero can go to one
but not one go to zero okay and we also
talk about the formula the number of
edges equals the sum of the
degree for all the vertex i belongs to
all the vertex okay so this is the
formula
v is the sum of the degrees so the
directive graph the degree consists of
two parts the incoming and outgoing
right incoming
is the edges number of edges going into
a vertex the outgoing is degree is the
number of edges going out for example
this one
this is the direct requirement the
integral for the vertex one is how many
edges going into one one one how many
edges coming out from one
two two yeah okay so the in degree would
be one our degree would be two and the
degree for one is three one plus two
okay for the direction for an directive
it doesn't have directions so the degree
for any vertex is just the number of the
edges so for the the degree
for the vertex 0 is 3 by 3 edges so the
sum of all the degrees from the vertex
equals the number of edges that's taken
these examples zero
one
two
three right
zero one two right there are three edges
sum of all the degrees
two plus two plus two
yeah the six divided by two is three
three edges why we need to divide it by
two we talked about left right because
for one edge there are two end points
and two m means that
the number the degree has been added
twice right so look these edges we added
one equation for this vertex 0 we added
another degree for the vertex one okay
so we divided by two this part adjacent
is we usually we use the adjacent disk
to represent the graph data structure
the g default dictionary
the keys are the vertex the values of
the list of the vertex that it has edges
to right
okay so let's change the list look 0 1 2
3 look 0 the vertex 0 connects to two
three there's an another concept called
weighted or unknowated graph what's
weighted weighted means that
you have this label cost for the edges
so we can label the edges on the cost
for example like one
two three means that from zero it costs
one to go to one from zero it costs two
to go to two for zero it costs three to
go to the left weighted yeah weighted if
we don't have this weight over the edges
then let's unweight it and we can think
of it as uniform that's uh each weight
the cost of uh
between the edges are uniform it's one
you can use the adjacent disk to store
the weights as well instead of simple
this of vertex we can use the tougher
yes for example zero to one
is one and one one okay zero to two
is two is two two okay zero two is three
three okay we're using the recursion to
implement the temperature
for each component we only calculate it
once right that's why we have at least
if seen we check if it has been visited
so
if we are looking at these right we
count their three
and then we mark the
vertex in the same component
visited so the next time we don't add it
again right we can
add a contribution for each vertex
separately we will be taking a little
bit slower right so look 0 how many
pairs 2 so it means that 2 plus 2 plus 2
right so for each vertex if we do the
different search
it probably needs to take another n
times if there are n number of vertex so
the time conducts if we count it if we
added a contribution for each vertex in
the same component uh separate that's
going to create o and
om squared right ov square v is the
number of vertices right but instead for
each component we just do it overall
once so there are three so we use three
times two so any question about this
path
[Music]
that's good okay so this this bit this
is the adjacent list yeah we're
converting the edges to addition this
okay so now today we're going to talk
about a processor what's your breakfast
do you still remember what square
footage it's when you eat
no no not a breakfast breakfast
what's breakfast and when you use kiwi
yeah yeah yeah so it's never my level
right so we talk about breakfast bss a
lot when we are solving the problems of
the trees please our graph right here's
the graph what's the breakfast search
order
zero one two three four five six yeah
level by level we use a cube okay and if
we use another search which is in the
left tree first there therefore search
left
and then reaching the root
visiting the root one full and then
definitely right okay one four five zero
zero one four five two
six three we're done okay now we usually
we use the recursion to improvement uh
the definition right
we also talked about using the stack
right using the step we use the queue
double antique in python to implement
the preferences so how would you how
would you do it first of all we put the
zero the load in there right there are
two ways of implementing breakfast
search one way is look yellow i take
everything
out from the queue dq yeah and i push it
to kit
is one two three one two three
and then i take everything out and push
their kids one by one take it out and
then the kids for the one is four five
the kids follow two is six the kids was
three is nothing so four by six okay
that's one way another way is we take
one note at a time
so zero we take it off we push this kit
it's one two three
then the next
note to take out is one right take a one
out its kit is four five push it back to
the cube
two we take it out push it skip six
right three we take it out it doesn't
have any kids four we take it out
doesn't have any kids five and six
etcetera we just need to convert these
to breakfast search the rest will be
defined by for such the i
first of all the same yeah if i in sin
then we we just don't calculate okay
return zero so if i in c return zero it
means that look
so let all the vertex in the same
component we only calculate it once
because look we have added three three
times two when we were doing this
different search on this
vertex 0 we added the contribution of
the number of pairs and which is 3 times
and then when we go through this vertex
again do we need to add a contribution
of three times two
no because we have been adding it so we
will skip the notes skip the vertex in
the same component okay so that's the
same thing here
so uh seeing this is the same simple as
i okay and then q how do we use the q in
python
eq what's d mean
the blended
at this point we at least have one
vertex in the component okay so answer
equals one
y or q why we still have like vertex y
q means that why we have elements in the
queue so why there is at least one
vertex in the queue this is the same
thing as y length q bigger than zero
right
and all white landscape okay current
equals q dot top left and you mentioned
about this that means that look at the
cube top left we're taking the element
from the left hand side okay if we don't
specify left cue the top what does it do
right side the right side
a pen from the right hand side append
left from left side so basically if we
specify the left it's from the left if
we don't specify it's on the right okay
two sides yeah double-ended means that
look like the cube is
is two sides it's like a pipe and you
can take from the left a pen from the
left take from the right a pen from the
right okay so both sides so the four
operations one constant time
current kill the popular actually let's
make b zero an answer increment here and
equal plus equal one for
x in
g the graph g
current
so that means that we want to iterate
over the vertex it connects to the
current right and then we just do this
if x not in scene
if it's we haven't
seen this vertex before then we push it
back to the q q dot append x and then
we mark it as syn so c dot f x and at
the end will get an answer
so the rest will be the same c will be
the number of vertex in the
component and then we do this c times n
times c with sum
sum c
n minus c sorry sum t minus c so c is
the number of vertex in the component n
minus c is the number of vertex
not in the current kinetic component
then that's the number total number of
pairs unreachable pairs right because
all the vertex in the current component
can be
connected so look this is the all the
nodes here right on the left we know
here look there are two components or
maybe i add another one here too
so i'm visiting the nodes in this
component here right so look all these
vertex
there's three i can connect any node
here in these components to all other
nodes right so i can make a connection
right so each node be be able to
contribute
these number of edges and which book
edges so we just need to multiply that
c is the three and minus c is all other
nodes right
what have you learned today
what's the problem and what's uh the
thing you we learned today
that's a graph and direct graph yes
and you want to count the unreachable
pairs or vertex we want to count the
number of unreachable pairs using
breakfast yeah we're using purposes what
was the accurate we used last time
therefore search it's quite similar yeah
quite just different ways of traversing
the graph
traverse the notes in the class okay