hello mr mr ryan all right
okay so we have been talking about this
problem for like two days yeah so the
problem is that we are given an
undirected graph we want to count how
many unreachable pairs in this
undirected graph right and we talked
about the data search we talked about
progressive search the key point here is
to compute the number of the vertex in
this connected component
if we do the same percentage of purposes
of this connected component if you find
out the number of vertex is c they are
total and vertex so the number of vertex
that are not in these connected
components is a minus c okay
so
if we keep doing that we sum up c times
n minus z
right then we need to divide by two
that's the total number of the
unreachable pairs so definite search
breakfast search just differs the way
the order the traverse the vertex in the
graph in the undirected graph and for
all the vertex in the same component
connected component we only added the
contribution
c times n minus c once right then we use
the hash set to remember the vertex that
uh have been visited this is definite
search recursion preference search using
the queue
okay and the key point here is
c equals definition of reference c and
answer plus equal c times n minus c and
at the end we need to return answer
divided by 2 because look if we're
looking at this vertex here we form the
pairs and which prepares to to for
example like this vertex when we
traverse a component
right your phone and which per pair to
the front we already calculated so we
need to divide it by two okay
we learned about this formula the number
of edges equals to the sum of the degree
for all the vertex divided by 2 right
remember
the unknown edges equals the sum of all
the
vertex degrees divided by 2 and then i
belongs to
the vertex okay
look at this and directly graph
how many edges
one two three we sum the degree right
one
plus two plus two plus one divided by
two we need to divide it by two because
one edges contributes to the degree of
two because the edge has two endpoints
right
and for the undirected graph the degree
of the vertex is just the number of
edges connected to it and for a directed
graph the number of the vertex can be
divided by two two counts right one is
the incoming the other one is the
outgoing so the degree is the sum of
both incoming and outgoing
edges
okay so now
we want to talk about solving this
problem using a union file this joint
set right
remember we talked about the disjoint
side
so that vertex for example therefore
right
let's just do this zero one two three
okay so how many unreachable pairs here
four four two times two right so if
we're using differences we prefer search
we do this two times four minus two plus
two times four minus two divided by two
right we need to sum up the contribution
and then divide by two for example is
zero one two three zero one two three
okay so there are four vertex zero to
one
so zero and one it belongs to the same
group right so we add edge
three and two
okay two so there are two groups now
two groups then we just have to go
through you know we use the uniform go
through these and then we find out the
number of the size of it right yeah the
size of it so that's two that's two and
then we do the same let's say union five
equals disjoint set okay and now and
vertex
yeah we're going to implement this later
okay and then
for a b in edges
then we do this uf dot dot merge okay
merge a and b so it means that we want
to
make a and b
belongs to the same group okay
and then answer
equals zero then four
goes to the vertex
range and
c equals we want to get uh
get the size
you have to get size i
then answer
plus equals c times n minus c
returns
answer divided by two okay shift
distribution to the right one position
to the right that's the surface divided
by two
simple right so like the key thing here
is this joints that we implement this
before right this joint set and we talk
about remember we talk about merging
so which one is better is it better if
we
merge for these all things probably all
the vertex or bigger size into a smaller
one or put a smaller group into the big
one remember we talked about
why is better
because it's less decreasing
it's less confusing yes you're right yes
so look if we look we want to actually
we want to compress we want to minimize
the total number of the paths right the
distance that we have this operation of
to
compress the path if if we want to merge
two components we prefer putting the
group of smaller sides into the thicker
one we also have to add in the sketch
size the good size function we can keep
tracking of the size of the components
when we do this merge okay uh
whoopsie davies define
actually that's a class okay class cross
destroying set
initialization let's uh
construct
self and n
then we want to give a sector and is the
end that's the number of the vertex
number of the initial group
set of parent
parent at the beginning is
is least
range and okay so at the beginning each
vertex belongs to is a group of this
cell okay so that the group will be zero
one to r to n
and now we have a size
the size
will be all one right at the beginning
each vertex is
a group of one this is to find the
parent of a group
x we want to find the parent of x
we can do this iteratively all the
recursion right look if
x not equal self.parent
x
then self.parent
x equals
sign
say have to find x okay and then we can
set the pattern this is the easiest way
so
here this is to compress the path if
this number is not equal to the
it's not the top element right because
at the beginning the vertex 0 belongs to
the group 0. the vertex 1 belongs to the
blue one so if this is not a top element
then we keep finding keep tracking until
we find it so but we also need to
compress the path missing five is to
compress the path okay and we can do
this iteratively as well so
by doing iteratively first of all we
need to find the root right so why x not
equals to serve the parent x then x
equals save the parent x then we have
this parent uh
parent x which is the root
we can go through these uh paths again
and compressed by reassigning the path
so look we have a group of these we want
to find these the parent of this one so
the parent of this one is this so what
does it become so that's yellow one two
three
so
so look at the three the parent of three
is zero right so at the end
the zero
and then that's three right the two's
parent is zero as well so
one parent here okay
this is inefficient it's like a linked
list in the worst case it's old and
linear time to traversal right to find
it so we want this kind of structure to
make it like one constant time yes so
that's why we need to compress the path
this way
okay so this is the to fight find the
parents when we find the parent we do
this compression of the path much we
don't merge to
two groups x y okay
so look first of all we need to find the
group a b equals self to find
x
left of 5
y
right if a and b
if they belongs to already belongs to
the same group we just return first
right
there's no point to
merge them if they already belongs to
samples if they are not in the same
group then we have to check the sizes
itself the size save the size x is
smaller than
seventh of size
y
then we can
swap x y equals y x so basically seven
times x
x is now bigger right now we want to
merge the group of smaller ones into the
bigger one okay this is a and b yeah a
if we want to check the size
a b
equals b a
and then says the parent
b
equals a right now a is bigger so we
want to move the b to a right make the
group of b a
serve the
size a plus equals cell dot size b so
look this is a
this is b right i'm going to merge b
into a so what happens the size of a
needs to be incremented by size of b
that's what it means
here right
and
size of b because we want to have
another function defined size case size
right we want to use this function case
size
then we have to
reset size b equals zero
okay
along return true
okay size we tend to say the size
x okay so this is the disjoint set
and we perform we can use the disjoint
set to perform union fight right union
fight so at the beginning
they are n vertex so they are n groups
and if we go through the edges for
example if you laser edges a one to two
we merge vertex one to merge two right
and we have a guess size function to
return the number of vertex in the in
the group for example if it's c and
which of the pairs would be c times n
minus c that that part is the same
if we merge two groups then the total
number of groups minus equals one right
and another function is to check if it's
too connected
if we took connected we just have to
find look connected x y we just have to
check
if self define x equals self to find y
we just have to find the parent right if
the parents are
the same then that belongs to the sample
okay
what's the problem and what have you
learned today what's the approach we are
taking to solve this problem
the problem is we have these
graphs
okay let me do this okay it's yellow
okay so we don't need actually the
number
so how many are reached for a pair
terminator vertex
seven vertex n equals seven okay so how
do we get the number of the atmosphere
two
times seven minus two
plus
three
times
seven minus three
plus two
times seven minus two
can you tell me what's these why do we
need to subtract
two vertex
so how many unreachable pairs can we
form we can form unreachable pairs from
the vertex here to layer
all the vertex other than these two
vertex i'm right so that's two times
seven minus two seven minus two means
there are five vertex other than these
two vertex i'm right
the same but what's the thing we forget
that's it for today bye-bye
hey
hello mr eric mr ryan all right
okay so we're given this a directive
graph we want to find the number of
unreachable pairs right and which
repairs and we talk about the deficits
we talk about the breakfast search and
today we're going to talk about using
this the union find data structure union
fund to solve this problem by using
unified algorithm we also need to
mention this the disjoint set okay
data structure we have talked about this
before so we are given an undirected
graph we want to find out the number of
unreachable pairs
one two three four five the unusual
pairs is one three
one four one five two three two four 2 5
right so 1 3 is the same as 3 1 so we
don't count these uh duplicate pairs
okay previously we're using the
definition processors to solve this
problem the idea is to count the number
of the
vertex in a connected component
so
so the answer for example given this
identity graph is 2 times 5 minus 2 plus
3 times 5 minus three divided by two
so there are five five vertex total so
two times five minus two
means that we have we have two vertex
here and then five minus two is the the
number of vertex other than these two
vertex right so it means that look for
each vertex in this connected group we
can form an unreachable pairs by
connecting this vertex to all other
vertex
and same goes with this 3
times five minus three here
so but we add it together we need to
divide by two because that one three and
three one it counted twice we need to
divide by two right there we're using
the definite search question search
basically we just want to
calculate this sum c times n minus c
divided by 2 c
the number of vertex in each connected
component and n is the number of all the
vertex in this undirected graph today
we're going to use this joint set
data structure we want to find out
number of vertex in this connected
component using this disjoint set and
union finder
so this joins that when we talk about
the insurance set is the data structure
when we talk about unifying instant
okay so but all these
different search preferences and this
union fund basically wants to solve this
problem by
computing the c and minus c the sum of
it right the main task is to find out
the number of the vertex in the
connected component
if the direct graph is one finger piece
of component then the number of
unreachable pairs is zero so everything
is connected so it does not have any
unreachable pairs to other vertex
destroyer means that long overlapping so
at the beginning we have n vertex each
one has its own group its own set right
so this 0 one two three four if there's
an edge between zero to one for example
zero to one we just merge these two sets
at the end we just need to get the
number of the vertex number of elements
in each set okay so this answer the
number of identical pairs then we can go
through these edges these joints that
don't merge
a b okay this disturbance set at the
beginning we create a disjoint set with
the end vertex then we need to sum this
okay so i in range
and
c equals d s dot get size we want to get
the number of elements in
vertex i
and then answer plus equal c times
n minus c
and at the end we need to return divided
by two
or and the
shift 61 percent to the right the key
thing here is that we need to implement
this we need to
get the number of vertex in
in the group of i the advantage of using
this destroying set is that it provides
the near constant time in the operation
of at the new set merge to set on find
if a element in a set
in order to achieve the near constant
time we need to compress the path so for
example like zero one two three four
five right if we don't compress the path
every time
we merge let's say merge zero to one
zero to one okay and then if we merge
one to two
okay if we merge 2 to 3 et cetera if we
don't complex the path
it's it's like the
linked list and in order to find the
root of 0 it needs to take 0 and 10 so
that's very inefficient so we have to
compress the path so when we find the
root we can reassign
the root we can compress the path so we
can store the number of sizes we can
store the sizes for the group always oh
we can store the rank okay so rank is
like the upper bound of the height the
size will be more straightforward so
let's use this size size for example
like if we have a
element
here right so we have these this is size
one two three four and then if we have
another two here so
it it's better to merge these the
smaller size into the bigger one rather
than from the bigger one into the
smaller one class
disjoin set
object
define
init init is the constructor
self
and
so self top parent at the beginning the
parents is the
from 0 to n minus 1 so we give you the
least range
range n is from 0 to n minus 1 so the
parents will be from zero to n minus one
and the size it will be at the beginning
will be all one at the beginning each
number
is assigned to its own group on set a
set dot total component so total total
total size
equals at the beginning and so this is
usually if we merge successfully merge
two components we can increment this
total
much we want to merge a and b all right
so at the beginning we need to find a
and b equals five self-define okay so
let's define
a self define b okay
then if a equals equal b if the parent
is the same if they already belong to
the same group and we just return first
there's no need to continue now we just
need to find the size if
the size okay say of the size
save the size
a is smaller than self the size b
now let's swap it okay a b equals b and
this is the way to solve these two
variables so at this point the size of a
is bigger than size of b equal or more
than size of b and then we can we attach
b to a so says
the parent
b
equals a then says the size of a
needs to plus equals cell the size
b right so because this is the size of a
this is the size of b and we want to
merge these b into a
right so the size of a
has been incremented by the size of b
but at the same time we need to set the
size of b equals to nothing
b equals zero right so we can use this
size function later this is very
important
and
return
true
okay and now we need to implement this
fine function this line function we use
the iterated or recursion
so that replication will be very easy to
implement define find
self a
okay so with the recursion we just have
to check if a is not equal to served
the parent of a
save the
parent
e a equals self defined
save the parent a
okay so this is recursion
if a is not the root right
if a
is not in the root we might go go up to
the path right if we haven't reached the
root yes this is to compress the path we
need to compress the path and
this is recursion to find this loop at
the end which is written
serve the parent way
if a path is like that we want to find
the root of these
so at the end
these will be pointing to here and these
will be pointing to here you'll become a
balanced structure so the total cost of
tracing the node will be minimized if
it's like a linked list then finding the
root of this needs to take all in time
by rearranging the parents and we can
minimize the cost
so this is recursion we can also use the
lung recursive method at the beginning
we need to find the
root okay lu equals a
wire
root
not equals theft
stock parent root
this is iterative
when root
equals
cell the
parent
root
now we get the root and then we need to
traverse the x again
x equals a why x not equal served
dot parent x
right then we need to find out the
parent of it so p x equals seventh
the parent
x
and now set the parent x
now we need to reassign these to root
right equals root
and then x equals p x okay
and we tend we can root right because
when this function returns the rule we
just need to find the root parent of the
a and then this is to compress the path
so let union find right so union this is
union this is fine and this the whole
thing is the destroying set based on
these we can calculate the number of
sizes for each component define
guest size
self
a now we just return
self dot size a
okay property okay define count
and then save we can just return
return set save the total
but i want to merge it so because we
said when we merge it we need to
decrement this all right so before this
the return true we need to say cell
dot total
minus equals one because every time we
merge two components the total number of
components
should be decremented by one
what's the problem and what have you
done today the problem is we have
this uh
nose
yeah we are given this time
and directly graph and what's the task
we're going to
find solve number of multiple nodes yeah
unreachable pairs okay so given these
there are three components yes this is
undirected graph
the one there's edge here there's two
edge so how to calculate the number of
unusual players
so
so the number of
like connected things yeah there's
a connected thing
a part
the number of notes in the other parts
yes for example these there are
six notes right so the number of
original players is like this
times
one that's one note here times one times
four
five six minus one yeah okay plus okay
how about this one
two
times times
six minus two plus three times six minus
three okay and
divide by two yeah
all together divided right okay we know
the total number is six no six minus one
is all other vertex not in this
connected component and and similarly
etcetera and we add it all together we
need to divide it by two because
any pairs are counted twice that's why
we need to divide by two and previously
we're using the definition of purpose
search traversal and vertices
component disjoint set non-overlapping
set so we can use this data structure to
find the number of vertex in one
component and that serves the purpose so
we just have to count the sum of c times
n minus c divided by two c is the number
of vertex in each
component okay
that's it bye