hello hello mr mr right right okay so
give a list
okay
ah you click
three to the power of zero plus three
times two equals ten or obviously you
can you can nine
number to the power available zero
equals one a is not equal to zero okay
so mathematics speaking
zero to the power of zero is not defined
and another way is to use the square
root
square root
flooring growing yeah okay so the other
way is the aquarium
okay the leaves is flowing
this is silly
[Music]
the arrangement we talked about that
in
roughly 100 days depending
for example you're given three letters
and you want to put it in
the mailbox numbers from one to three so
there are three more
so you made a box you caught one
and then you have three letters yeah
three letters
it could be anything one two three
so
the arrangement is that the weight the
number of ways you can put these in the
mailbox but not in the box of yourself
okay so one cannot put it into one two
cannot put it into two so you can not
put it into three so we have three one
two that's good next
and also two
three one all right there's only two way
you know this symbol is factorial right
n times n minus one times n minus two
times q one and if you put this
exclamation mark in the front
this is derangement so
exclamation mark three equals two and
how about exclamation mark two equal
to
equal one
we have n letters and n boxes and how
many ways if we use this f n meaning the
number of ways to put these n items into
n boxes the one cannot be put into
number of excel if i'm considering here
the number here the this n i n item the
number s
i can put it into n minus one ways right
i cannot put it here right obviously
yeah but i have n minus one choice
and minus one choice
so if i put it here k for example then
one way is i can swap this k with n
right
if i sort it and the rest will be the
remaining will be n minus two right i'm
right because this item one is item two
so n minus two
and that will be f n minus two
right if i'm not working with the end
item then i have n minus one
f n minus one all right yeah so i plus s
and minus one
okay so this is the derangement
recursion formula f of n equals n minus
one times fn minus 2 plus f minus 1.
okay we just talked about this
we can implement this using recursion
and putting the cache right like a
typography number there will be a
dynamic programming top-down dynamic
problem okay so coming back to this
question so three three three we hope
can we make a ten so it's uh
this is two
plus three that's five
times
two equals ten
these are the four ways okay define f
and
and for the cash to remember the
intermediate value if n equal equal one
or zero right if equals zero equals one
return the value will be zero f s zero f
one
you know if n is to return
one right there's only one way and then
we can return
f
n minus one plus f and minus two this is
fibonacci number but we need times m n
minus one
okay this is the recursion with
minimization top-down dynamic
programming okay we put the cache
so the time complexity will be o n
because the the maximum number of states
we're remembering we're calculating is n
we can also use the bottom up dynamic
programming okay so we use the
array to store the values so we
calculate that f0 and then f1
f2 and we can calculate f3 f4 and here
fn this is like fibonacci number so
defined f and
obviously this is this sphere applies
so we use the pp ep for zero times m
plus 1 dp 2 equals
db2 equals 1 for
i
in range 3 until n
then
b p i
equals i minus 1
times d p
i minus 1 plus d p
i minus 2 returns d p
n or d p minus one so quite similar to
fibonacci number right this is the
difference
yeah this is the difference have you
noticed that dpi we want to calculate
dpi only based on dpi minus one and
minus two so you can use the two
variables to iteratively instead of use
the dp array right because this one the
space complexity with o n we are using
array to store the values so we can use
two variables so a
b equals zero one okay so we don't need
this
and then
a b equals b and then a
plus b times
i minus one okay and then we turn b
this implementation is the most
efficient right because they will use
the iterative and then we use two
variables to keep tracking the values
what have we learned today
[Music]
so if
it but you can't put
your letter or email or whatever you're
doing
into your own one
arrangement three equals two the range
of two good ones
right okay so okay
yeah so basically the arrangement we
talk about these arrangements there are
n items and we want to find out the
number of ways to put these and items
into lists and boxes and places but each
item cannot be put into the number of
each song and we want to find out the
number of ways of doing that so that's
quite useful in real life for example
like you and your friends right
preparing the gift birthday gift you
want to exchange birthday gift how many
ways can you do it right you can't
obviously you cannot give yourself your
own present
all right
yeah so that's the arrangement for
example like how many students you know
class
about 30 30 okay so that derangement
certainly so for example like all of you
prefer prepare the gift estimation of 30
right
this is a very big number so we can use
this formula
f n equals m minus one times
f n minus one plus f minus two
okay so this part is fibonacci we just
need to times it with n minus one and
the way to understand these we have to
talk about that as well this is that we
considering that looking at the end item
and then how many ways can we put these
and items there are n minus one ways
right obviously you can put it in the
last item you can put it in the first
and minus one items and suppose the one
we can put into the number called k
and then there's two situations one way
is that you can exchange you can swap
k and n
and then that leaves us the f and minus
two right because they're n items and
then k and n there are two items the
remaining will be f minus two
if not if we are not putting the k
at the end so there are f and minus one
i ways to do that right so that comes
with this
okay that's it for today bye
bye