hello mr and mr ryan are you right yes
yes
okay so look what's this look i draw
something
a graph yes a graph but particularly
what's this what kind of data structure
is this
yes well done financially so look we are
given this final tree a full financing
okay
blue
four binary a four biology means that
each node contains zero or two kids
right so each node has yellow kits or
two kits for the leaf node you don't
have any kit so we are given the value
two that two or four and two of us
yeah you can simply
two of us two values is basically tick
cross okay
yes no okay this is pulling
yes no
okay and then for the other note
we are given this uh o or n
right so we talk about this binary
binary operators or
a or b
what's all mean what's the difference
between on and what's the meaning or
else if you have a choice
one of yes of
true then it's true and it's the both
must be true right so we're given this
boolean tree
which is a full binary we want to
evaluate it so look first of all we
evaluate leaf node fourth and true is
false right so look we replace this bit
before
true or false is true yeah we have a
choice either is okay then it's okay now
we do tend to we are given a full final
tree which contains the
booleans and boolean operators right
it's a full binary means that each node
contains zero or two kit
and we want to evaluate it by the tree
we evaluate the leaves
so this bit
will be evaluated for us
right and then we continue evaluating
these
fourth and true is false true or false
is true and for the end
n usually using this symbol yeah for the
o usually simple
true
and true is true true and false is first
fourth and
fourth is first
fourth and two is
false
okay so only
only both are true then the results so
all others are false but for all
two or two is two
two
or four is two
fourths or two is
two
fourth or fourth is first okay so look
as long as we have at least one
then
then the result is so otherwise this is
first okay let's pull it
so we can evaluate these trees
uh by using what kind of aggregate uh
what kind of
three travelers are equine can we use in
this case
breakfast deficit okay questions
definitely so in this case which one is
better better search
better search is better right for
surgery is level by level
right because we want to evaluate the
leaves first right
so we go down the tree and then we use
the recursion
we evaluate the leaf node and then we
reverse
so we use the stack we can use the stack
to implement the definition oh we use
the recursion right so usually step
recursion it means that we go down the
tree as as deep as we can until we
reach the terminals which is the
difference and then we evaluate it right
and then we pass back we go back
okay so this is definition define f
root
so first of all if the note is a
terminal if it's a big note it doesn't
have blanket then we just return the
value if root of left
is noun
and
root of right is numb right so this
basically means that
it's a leaf node and we just return to
the value right
there's nothing we can do here
len okay so then we check if it's not
different now then we just change if
root of value
is n right if it's n
okay then we just return
return f rule
dot left
and
f
rule
dot right okay
look if this is n now we need to return
the leaf f dot f do the left is little
bit absolute right is this bit the
result is n right
otherwise return if it's a if it's not
and then it's all the return
f blue dot left
o
f root of right
okay
does doesn't make sense yeah
it's very simple right
okay so look
look at this recursion yeah so we just
go down like this is the leaf node if
this is the leaf node we just return
itself right look if it's a n
look at this if this noun is n it will
return f root of left least the value of
this sub tree as root of right the value
of the sub 3 and then it's n otherwise
it's all right it's all and f left or
left is these three the value of this
three the f to the right is the value of
the right tree and then we're doing all
and then that's it we go down uh the
tree as different we can so look we're
here so it's not this one it's it's not
n it's this one so we first of all
recall recursive we call this uh
function f root left and root of right
and then you will return the all of
these two trees
okay look f to the left
is a leaf node then you just return true
right f right is is a another sub tree
it's not a leaf node it's a n okay it's
an n and f root on left is this this bit
which is again evaluated root of uh
value which is fourth and then this is
little a little rain which is the true
fourth and fourth and true right
is fourth right and then we go back we
visit the trees
from top down
but when we reach the terminal nodes
that determine the levels we evaluate
the leaf nodes
and we pass the values backwards
backwards to the top so first of all we
call this calling calling stack when we
evaluate the leaf node we pass back okay
so this is recursion we can do it in the
iterative as well using the step okay
okay so what have you learned today what
have you learned
about
everything what have you learned today
okay so we're given a tuning tree which
is
pudding yeah putting true or false yes
or no
okay so what's pulling what's what's
this meaning in english put in
the
[Music]
flower
no
i don't know
so
it's a
it's a thing that you could
that you could blow
okay okay so pulling you can think of it
as two and fours two values two two
sides
the coin okay two sides you flip a coin
that's a boolean value the heads of tail
true or false yes or no
kicker cross
heads are test
pulling so look this is a pulling tree
the leaf nodes which do not have any kit
which is the pulling value two or four
of that and the other intermediate nodes
which are putting putting operators
putting operators there
we are having two here so which is all
oh it means that one of them is okay
then it's okay and it means the both
needs to be okay
both needs to be true in order for the
result to be true and we're going to
evaluate this this boundary okay and
then what kind of a government are we
using today
research we're using the data search
today okay and then using the
there are two ways to implement the
different search we're using the
recursion instead of uh using a stack
okay
the time context is on we are traversing
the tree now right now each node is
visited once so the time to next is over
the space convex this one because we're
using that because
okay that's it for today bye