hello mr mitchell rhino you right
yeah okay so today we talk about a
cartesian product we talked about that i
mentioned that a few times ago condition
product is the mathematic
uh concept okay so it's used on the set
all right in python we have set right so
look a is a set
condition for the b what do we get is
it's a set yeah
so a b
tuple right
and a is belongs to
a and b is belongs to b
yeah that's why it is let's take a look
at a very simple example
a
a if is is a set of one two
b if it's a set of three four
so a transition for the b so we take one
element from the first set
and then we can
do this all
combinations of the other sets
so it's
one three
one four
and then
two three
two four okay now your turn about a is
one two three b is
four five so a cartesian product times b
one four
one five
two four
two five three four three five
yeah exactly okay you got it yeah
okay so this is condition product in
python we can from
eta tour
import product
we use this product from the intertours
so let's take a look at this example
so look
in python let's say
a equals
1 2 okay b equals 3 for
c equals
condition per day for that
and a
b
this is a returning uh iterator so we
convert it to a list then what do we
have then you give us c equals one three
one four
two three
two four okay simple step let's
transition to that okay so
a cartesian product b is equal to b
condition product a come on that's a one
question no
no right it's not definitely a look
because look one three one four
two three two four and how about b
condition for the a three one three two
four one four definitely not right okay
so that's very good so how about the
carbon energy cardinality what's this
what
continuity
i don't know how to spell cardinality
this is basically the number of
the number of these elements in the
condition product so so look there are
two elements here and there are two
elements here so what's the number of
elements in the conditional product
okay so how about one three one two
three four five how many in the
transition product
there are two here there are three here
so how many all together condition for
that thanks yeah so
you can do that so we use these to mean
the length of
the cardinality so
a condition product b
is is equals to a
times b simple as that right we get the
cardinality of the a and cardinality of
b and i will multiply it together let's
see
total number of these
elements in the product we mentioned
about the graph graph algorithm the
shortest path remember the shortest path
accurate in the directive way to graph
we can use the uniform cause search and
we mentioned that we talked about a long
time ago if it's an indirectly and i
weighted gua we can use the vertical
search
and we can also use d castra okay i
don't know how to pronounce it thicker
we're going to
talk about that in the next few days get
stronger okay
we also talked about this flawed floor
there why are you getting thickest right
there's no eyes you can't take it
okay it's a name
a texture
between
b to i plus i to j
is shorter
than i to j
then we can replace
the cost from i to j with these shorter
paths right so for example look i have
another you know very complex graph i'm
going to compute the minimum shortest
path from from a to b right look at b i
found out like i to j the cost maybe a
hundred and then later i found out that
i to k is 50 k to j is 20. so how can we
improve the shortest path between a to b
my current shortest path from a to b is
through this path right look it's
release path
yeah
now i found out that i to k is 50 k to j
is 20.
i can replace the i to j with this
shorter path right because 50 plus 20 is
smaller than 100 so i can replace this
path
from here so it will provide us the
shutter pass right that's the spirit of
this angle okay so it's basically like a
dynamic programming so
for
k in range
it's uh the time to next is the ov
cubic
n
and then for
i in range
n
for j in range
n right and now we can say look if the
shot is part d
d i j
yeah
is the minimum we only get a minimum d i
j
and then d
i to k
plus d
k to j right so that's
the spirit right
i to j
and we found out that k right so if the
i to j the cos is bigger than i to k n
plus k to j then we can replace i to j
using this part right that's what it is
for k to n that takes n iteration and
each iteration takes n iteration and for
each iteration takes any iteration so
that time connect is o and q h okay so
for this this one yeah look this is i j
i j yeah this is the
tuple right so we can use the
cartesian product so look because look
this is the same yeah this is the same
so basically we can replace this one for
k
i j
in product yeah we can use this
syntax for that what
product
range
range n and then we pass the second
parameter repeat
repeat equal three times okay
look so b three four loops can be
replaced by this one for loop this is
the time complexity sphere o and qp
for k i j right k i j that's a topper
basically this range and
cartesian product itself three times
that's what it means okay so condition
products can be done in multiple sets
a
conditional product b condition product
c contingent verb b
a b c d right
then
a is belongs to a b is belongs to b c is
belong to c d is belongs to d okay
that's what it means so
one two three four
five six the cartesian product will be
will be one can you guess look if the a
is one two b is three four c is five six
so what's the condition product
we've last reset
yeah is it like one three
one three one you need to take one for
each set one three five yeah one three
six yeah
one
four five
one four six
two three five
two three six
two four five
two four six
you got it yeah okay so that's the
beauty of the condition problem we can
replace these right look
o n o n two o and q b by this
right
yeah okay
and that's the
shortest class when we talk about this
algorithm any questions today what have
you learned today that's it
okay so what's this what's what what
happened come on combination product
condition product okay condition
all right so okay so can you tell me
uh
a if it's an empty set yeah a condition
product empty empty in mathematics using
this
a condition product empty what do we get
empty yeah so it's equals to empty
condition product a but generally a
condition product b is not equal to b
condition for the a okay we talk about
that okay yeah
because
we will be doing it yeah that'll be it
for the day bye
bye
you