okay so
today remember uh what have you learned
yesterday
night book no that was the day before
yesterday we're saving numbers no
yesterday steps remember stacks
oh yeah and then you have to draw this
tower remember
yeah yeah yeah sit down please
so so look the stack the important
thing to remember about stacks is the
every time you take the item it's always
on the top right
so you put the item first but you take
it last
right yeah okay so this is called stick
first thing last off okay
so today we're going to introduce a
difference
different different data structure
called queue
you notice one cube is first thing
first off yeah suppose you you you you
wait in the line let's say yeah
yeah suppose here let's air it and
that's ryan
so you have to do it okay okay so look
so who gets to serve the next time the
next time let's suppose we're selling a
ticket yeah
picky man that's a ticketman so who who
gets next
yo yeah eric gets next and then ryan so
then now the new people join the queue
yeah but they they need to wait in turn
that's call
first thing first out right because you
join the two first you get served
first yes get out yeah
okay so again we can use the list
in python to serve the purpose of q so
in
in the python we how do we create a list
we use this square bracket remember like
a stack yeah
so you can say stack equals this or you
also can have this cube
you q-u-u-e equals that okay
right okay so look
so let's define a q okay let's let's
put a pretty simple q equals
at least and now another person joined
yeah yeah a pen
yeah a pen let's let's append
eric so what do you think what happened
what do you think what will happen it
will append
so let's look this is the queue this is
a queue and now
after this we will have eric here yeah
okay and now kill the append
equal depends right open
ryan what do you think what happened
so now the kill will become can you
please
eric plus one yes
[Music]
who's your favorite friend me
now who's your best friend who's your
best friend
do you have a best friend that's cool do
you mean yeah yeah yeah i need friends
just give me a name
leo how do you spell oh
okay so what happened next man the kill
will become
what erway
ryan lin
i know no one is isaac okay do you want
me to give her a name right eric
i know
okay so what do you think what happened
everything yeah we just put it at the
end yeah
ryan lee
no no that's it enough we don't have
space for so many people
okay so look if we want to have
pick in you know this peak how do you
how do you do you know what's the
meaning of pete pig
like like like p
copy copy yeah
ryan pick is like a look look
look without taking it
yeah so this pic means that i want to
have a look at the next item to
be dequeued to be out of the queue
without actually taking it so you give
me
so you give me this pic will give me
like the first
first item to who who should be served
next
me eric because eric goes in first so he
needs to be served
first right so he needs to how do you
see this
eric so now the click operation
is just simply as q
look this square bracket is zero okay
zero means the first item right
yeah yeah yeah yes
okay so remember yesterday we talked
about steps and if
i want to get the pick the last item of
the step what is that
how do we do it we use this q
minus one okay yeah
do you understand this is kind of the
first
item minus one okay so yellow
can you please require otherwise
otherwise i'm not going to talk
right zero the first item
last item and now if i want to actually
take it out take every out
so we use the similar remember yesterday
the stack
yeah let's take what do we do with that
look this is peak okay let me just do
this pick
this is peak peak
belongs to q okay at least it's stacked
okay and this is stack
and this is kill okay okay now
how about i want to take it off
first in life first industry
first thing first i was q first thing
last r is stack
okay so now we want to take it out
we want to pop so which is pop yeah
pop to k in a q we use this
top zero and in the
stack we just use pop okay pop
okay so look like eric i can say eric
equals q dot pop
zero okay so what what do you think what
happened
the airing will be taken everything will
be taken
so that this becomes y and liam oven
okay and how about next one y
n equals q dot pop
zero pop zero means i want to pop the
first element out so
y n will be gone and now this will be
leon
over and the next one
[Music]
no leong is leon
can you remind me how can i check the
size of the queue
on the stack remember size how how do we
get the size we use the air
okay then q and then here will be l e n
stack okay okay so that's the difference
look at it the major difference is
this bit the peak this is to pick
to get to pick the first item this is
pick the last item
this is the top the first item this is
to pop the last item without a parameter
this is with the first pair with us
so how can we make use of this queue
it's just
a different order right the the stack
is uh first thing that's all the queue
is first in person okay
okay okay so then let's
let's single example like we can make
use of the queue
define look for example if
if we given the numbers like 1 2
3 4 5 a list yeah this is the numbers
and i want to make it return return
is square so that i will return one
square
that's two times two three times three
four times four
five times five okay okay this is the
task
so let's say define
yeah he's fine let's say only define
square square square okay square root
square
not t square not root okay that's square
just square it
numbers okay so how do we do it
how do we do it let's put the answer
here okay answer
okay okay then we cannot using the
q remember while the q is not empty what
do we do
why we can treat the numbers of this we
can treat it as a q
y length
numbers bigger than zero
one nice numbers in the queue in in
these numbers yes
we take it okay here we take one element
from the left
from the queue so what what you should i
do pop
x stop pop
yellow right remember we want to take
the first eye item yeah
then we put it in the answer so answer
the append append
x plus one x times x y
we know the square yeah yeah
and then what's this return what
return what are we return what
return answer well done
okay so look what happened here
look what happened here it seems it's
pretty simple okay so this numbers is
one two three four five
answer is empty
length and numbers is five is bigger
than zero so
every time i take out i take the number
the first number the left
most left left most number from the
numbers i take it
out i square it and put it into the
answer and then we move it
remove because pop i wouldn't move it so
it will be moving
okay so one question if i want to return
as
25 16 9 4
1 how do we do it
how do we do how do we reverse how do we
reverse
remember we we are using the kill first
in first out
and now we are going to first see nassau
so
how do we do we want to take the fight
yeah
so how do we do it you just need to
change you it raise one number no no
now you just need to erase it remember
one is using without a parameter you
take this class yeah
no because this is the same yeah i'm
right
so do you understand yes
with nothing in there you're taking the
last life anymore
yeah no space is fine when you put a
zero in there
you'll take it outside of it when you
put nothing in there you'll take the
last element
and always take it and it raises it yeah
when there's items in the list
you take it you raise it and then put it
square it and put it in the other way
okay does that
make sense yeah is that is that good
yeah okay because you want to put it in
your computer please okay
good good job today