hello hello hello mr eric hello mr ryan
hello
mr ryan hello this is the teacher yeah
we're done today okay so today we're
going to learn a little bit about
these mathematics we're going to talk
about this pythagorean theorem
okay yeah pythagorean zero so
if you really want to know in short that
percentage theorem
is it means a 12 plus b
squared equals c squared easy to
remember right
yes so what does it mean it means look
we talked about a little bit
yesterday a right triangle if this is 90
degree
okay if this side is a this side is b
and this side is c so a square plus b
squared equals c squared for example a
equals three
b is four and then a c is five okay
so how do we get these how this is quite
magic right
it's look if it's a right triangle and
it's you know
both sides you know any two sides yeah
if you're not a c if you know the a you
can know b right
you can calculate the other side given
two sides
so why why is this this is very
important okay very very important
mathematic
called pythagorean serum okay so how do
we get that
look so this is the triangle uh
this is a triangle nice taste in my
mouth
why is that i just feel this taste
okay so this is triangle and then right
angled
yeah so now um actually let me draw it
the other way okay so it's better okay
okay so look these
yeah one triangle this is the this and
then we can draw another one
another one how to draw uh another one
yeah let me draw how hot it is
i'm the coding teacher okay so roughly
like that okay
so this four triangle yeah oh you need
it yeah
yeah this is water
this is look this this is if the longer
side
is if the longer side is b okay
if if look if longer side is b and then
smaller size a and this is c okay so
this is c
right this is c this c yeah yeah
yeah so that so this the the area
the size of the big square is what
c this fixing
c square and what does it equal does it
equal that
i sum up with the four terms of these
yes yeah
and plus this one okay all right so four
times
the size of these the area size of the
triangle
how big is this is it equals two half
half of a times b right yeah
and how many of them how many of these
how many
four four and then what's this look
this is a little square right what's the
size of it
you say this thing is b right
yeah and then this small thing is what
[Music]
this is look this is b this is a
right so this is
b minus a right b minus
a square yeah
okay so look this is 2 a b
right and then plus b
minus a squared is b squared
plus a squared minus 2 times a b ba okay
do you notice 2a b minus 2ab
it cancels out right yeah
so what's this b squared plus a squared
we just prove it c squared equals b
plus b squared plus a squared okay
or a squared plus b squared okay so
this is very interesting this is the
very important mathematics
so now now if i give you a value
c if i give you a value c
and i want you to write a program using
python
to to list all these kind of pairs
all the preserving theorem pairs
so for example i give you five right
yeah you should tell me you should print
3 square plus e
4 squared equals 5 squared if i give you
you should give me 6 square plus a
squared equals 10 squared
any idea how to do it
do you know how hot we do this we know
that c right
yes and what's the range we can we can
ask computer to try every number
a from one right
to c to c not not including c
but if if we we say if
a is strictly smaller than equal b
right yeah so we we start from one
once we we determine once the a is fixed
so what's the b b square
equals one c square minus
a we're done so c we know one yeah we
know
right yeah a is fixed once we know it's
one then we can calculate b
square right so look if b
is b if it's bigger or equal a so b
squared
is also bigger or a equals a squared
right
yes so leasing c squared minus a
squared bigger than a squared
so what does it mean c squared bigger
than 2 a squared right
yes so c squared is bigger than 2a
squared
so we can search these a
and here is bigger and here this
is not satisfied and after that
we can calculate b so once we know the b
square we need to check
if it's a perfect square number right
if b squared equals 15 do you think it's
a
we can find a b which is integer sum up
to
15 square to 15.
no right because 16 is 50 it doesn't
have
any it's not 20 square okay so that's it
that's easy look let's define define
f c okay yeah
a equals one right
[Music]
why
we just know c square minus
a square is b square right
if c squared minus a square
is also bigger than a square bigger or
equal to a square right
yeah all right then
we need to b square b b2 let's say
b2 equals c squared minus a square right
now we need how can we check if b is a
perfect square number remember we use
the binary search but we can use the
built in
square number look b then is equals
let's let's do it sqrt remember
b square but we have to convert it to
the integer power
right if it's integer then we check if b
times b if it's equals b
square right now we can we know
twin a b c right
a b c okay yeah
yeah should we try it on the computer
to get it so basically we given c
so we just try a from one to
this yeah a range and once we know a we
know c
now we can calculate b but but we need
to make sure b
is the perfect square am right all right
yeah because if it's not perfect square
it doesn't it's not a pine sun green
theorem okay yeah you know how to say
this in
chinese goku go
goku didn't three four five okay okay
let's do it on
computers can you turn your own please
ryan
ha ha good boy okay
can i sit here can you not shake please
is everywhere is it clear it's mostly
to the is it buy me
can you sit there please let me let me
adjust the anger please
okay
can you sit down please the screen will
be shaking
yes perfect
can you
okay so let's let's cook let's do it
let's call it p
okay i'm not going to worry about this
python four stars four star one
is the beginning four stars
no no that's okay let's let's do a fee
fc yeah remember
yeah so a will start for one right
yeah y c
times c minus a times a is bigger than
or equal to
a times a right yes so this can sum up
to list so many
times look this can move to c times c
equal
bigger equals to 2 times a times a can
you sit down please
people are not seeing me please okay and
then what what
what b square equals c times c
minus a times a right yeah
and now we need to try to calculate b
value which is
integer of sqrt squared
b2 right but in order to use this as
square function we have to import them
in max imported function from the math
module okay then
now we we have to check if b times b
is b what is p2 right
now we find it we find this uh we can
print we can do this
d uh we can print this d square
this is formatting okay don't worry too
much about it if you don't understand
where's d from d is means integer yeah
it's not it's a format then after that
we can please
in plug the value in okay then
let's try that's it uh we have to
increment oh i forgot this a plus
equals one right yeah so
let's try uh for
let's say no no no let's try for a a5
right a test f10
800 8 of
200 okay let's see
okay three square plus four square
equals five okay i forgot the five
five square the square thing the square
thing here
square thingy okay so let's make it
clear
look three square plus 4 squared equals
5 squared 6 squared plus
a squared equals 10 squared 28 squared
plus 60
96 squared equals is it true i'm not
sure
that's why okay look 28 times 28
plus 16 96 times 96
okay is it this one yeah it's 100 square
that's that's great let's try
let's try this 56 56 times 56
plus 192 times 192 equals
four four uh four hundred
four forty thousand okay and then
another one
a hundred twenty square plus sixty
160 square uh
oh look they find two pairs you see yeah
yeah you're too fine to pay us okay so
any questions no it's interesting yeah
you want to see it again
yeah cat yeah cat means to display the
content of the file
i save it into psp5 right
is it today is very simple yeah but it's
very interesting you get to know
this but today the most important thing
to take away today is
what a square plus b squared equals c
squared if it's the right triangle if a
and b
are the shortest sides of the left right
triangle c is the slope
to get it the longest side yes yeah
okay okay good job today uh good job
good job i'm going to
advertising bye bye bye
bye good job today good job good job
okay good job