and waited
and waited because the cost between
vertex
is the same right if i put the numbers
here like one two then let's weight it
right because the cost
from zero to three is one from three to
four is two
you can treat it and weight it as the
cross between the vertex is all one even
as the edge okay the given is directed
and weighted graph also given a list of
the star and stops for example like two
four one three okay what's the sum
of the shortest paths
between all the pairs for example like
two and four the shortest path between
two and four
look two to go to zero three and four
that's the only one that's only where
distance is three right because three
hops one two three okay
three
plus one two three
one
two three another three if i add another
edge then you'll take this edge instead
so that'll be one got it
yeah if there's no such uh
path right so for example if one
cannot go to five right if i put a one
to five
if one there's no path between one to
five and we turn zero that's zero okay
because
yeah yeah it's it's not connected right
even it's connected sometimes there's no
path because it's directed so look one
two two
and then
uh three so there's no path between one
to three right
can
canvas
if there is no path so this bit the cost
would be the distance would be zero so
we just need to sum up it but
pretty simple just consider this graph
directly anointed graph we want to find
out the shortest path between
any two vertex so what kind of algorithm
comes to your mind
um breakfast
breakfast search yes staff assessing may
work but you need to explore all the
paths that's not very efficient remember
we also talked about the iterative
deepening
iterative difference
such meaning that when we set the max
mass steps equals to one and uh we do
this dfs and we stop and match that's
one and now we increment the math steps
to two right and then we do this
definite search and the definition will
stop when
the distance is it sees the mass step
okay so that's the way of using the
depth search in iterative deepening
search to find out the shortest distance
between two vertex right okay but
breakfast search is more straightforward
right because it's directed
and weighted because the thing is
unweighted if it's unweighted it means
that we can use the breakfast right but
if it's weighted
then we can't use the preferences if
it's weighted we probably need to use
the uniform because she has a uniform
concealer should we talk about that
yeah
this truck
okay we will talk about that all right
thick strap and then
floyd we talked about that yesterday
remember we mentioned that
floyd what's up okay the
most important thing about this a floyd
warsaw agreement is that it's a dynamic
programming
so
remember we talked about this i to j
we want to calculate the shortest path
between i to j and at some point we find
the k vertex
and then we find out that i
distance i to k
plus distance k to j
is smaller than distance i took i to j
so what does it mean look
we want to find a distance shortest
distance between i to j and then somehow
we find out that i to k plus k to j is
shorter right don't look at this
triangle triangle
any triangle
we have the sum of any two sides is
bigger than
the third one right yeah for any
triangle look any triangle any two sides
the sum of any two sides is bigger than
the other side i'm right look any two
sides the sum of triangles any time
the sum of two sides is bigger
a b plus ac is bigger than bc it cannot
be smaller than bc right because the
distance the shortest distance between
two points two point a and b the
shortest distance the stroke is
different between a and b can you find
the path that
connects a and b and it's the shortest
a straight line a straight line yes
perfect a straight line so this is the
shortest right and this c is somehow you
know not always a b to make it a
triangle right
you just say this is the shortest so ac
plus cb must be bigger than a b am right
what is c
if you see it's there that's a good
question then it's not a finger it's a
straight line
but here this is not triangle right what
i'm saying is that the cost between i
and j
right we can find the shorter path by
jumping to k so i plus k that cost maybe
look
a hundred
now
it takes a from to travel from i to j
the cost to travel from i to k is 50 and
k to j is 20.
so which one is shorter from i to j
yeah you take this yeah because look 50
plus 20 is smaller than 100 right this
is what it means
yeah yeah yeah but so yeah i've got this
supposed to be shorter no no no don't
confuse with it i'm saying this is not a
triangle this is you know yeah but
that's not that's shorter but and this
is longer
but
but this one these profits should be
considered
yeah yeah consider traffic
can see the traffic look um
[Music]
20 is not the same as 50 though
yeah but
these are basically the damn same thing
yeah just let's say
i'm saying look it take a take 100
minutes
if we go the straight way to london
right but you might travel to i know i
don't know maybe what's this what's the
city you know island kimberjee and
london
edinburgh
okay okay this is the edinburgh okay
anyway so look
[Music]
with the cambridge
dude
but it's so much longer than london oh
something like but
in tokyo
fine tokyo
okay
and besides tokyo is not even in united
kingdom yeah it could be something like
liverpool or liverpool okay so cambridge
we want to travel to
manchester okay manchester
all right so if we directly travel to
manchester yeah it's 100 minutes but now
i'm telling you it's not manchester
united
it can be each
maybe 15 minutes like 80 watts of
manchester 20
[Music]
to minutes
you could change engine bro
like something like that
what's the
name any city between cambodia and
manchester um
uh i but i thought liverpool was a
football team no liverpool well the
liverpool play and and there is
uh
sheffield
yeah
okay cool
okay but anyway coming back to this the
core idea of this uh flowing water
shortest part is that we can replace the
distance with the shorter one if we find
a third vertex i plus kj is smaller than
i j okay so at least this aggregate
provides us this uh o and
o and qp or ov cubic n is the number of
vertex right but it's a multi-source
shortest
path
means that if we perform this aggregate
we can find any pair is too far away any
pairs distance b i b j we can find the
shortest path between vertex i and
vertex j okay so
we talked about this we infinitely say
yesterday so we just need to uh
implement this again
so we are given this graph is a adjacent
list okay attraction list what
suggestion is look one
two two
one two three
and one to four and the adjacent is
instead dictionary right so look one
energy three yeah one
uh maybe two two three here the one is
has the
vertex edges two two three four five
so look at the key inside the vertex the
values is the list of vertex that it has
connected to
right and then vertex two connects to
three okay so what that's what it is and
we want to convert it to adjacent metric
adjacent matrix adjacently if we want to
convert it to adjacent measurement with
this accurate we need to assess this dij
the cost right so it's better we convert
it to addition magic right so we're
using these two dimensional array two
dimensional array to to store the cost
between vertex i and vertex string so we
given this and we know this n vertex
here and
vertex
this is the rotation list then we need
to convert it to these adjacent metric
so if gl is i equal equal j
ers
infinity
for
i
in range
and n is the number of vertex right then
for
j in range
n
okay
so adjacent list we convert it to
adjacent matrix so it's like zero uh
you know one zero zero one zero zero
zero one zero zero uh zero zero one one
zero one
like something like that right something
like this it's a magic and the diagonal
the value on the diagonal is all one
because because when we consider the
vertex i can travel to vertex i okay
right so for example like this value
this value is zero one two three
this way we want to access this value
this value is d
row 3
column 0 1 2 right so it means that
there's a path between 3 the vertex 3 to
vertex 2 so vertex 3 to vertex 2.
okay and how about this one this is
this is d
zero
three right
zero one two three so it means that
there's a path between gl to three
okay so this is d d is the adjacent
matrix we're converting the adjacent
list to adjacent matrix four
k in range n
for
i in range n
j in range n
d i j
is minimum of t i j
and d i k
plus d k
j okay let me draw again i
j
and we have a k here right
so
if we find out
i to k plus k to j smaller than i to j
then we replace the shortest path d i j
with d i k plus k i j that's what it
means great very simple
very simple idea the time conduction if
you look at this
o and q b right we talked about the
product yeah cartesian product yesterday
remember we can replace this with one
for k i j
in
product
range
and
repeat
equals three okay so range end
cartesian product is by itself three
times and then we get this topper kij
which serves the purpose of this one
okay and then we want to calculate the
sum of these return
sum
d
i
j
if d i j right if d i j not equals to
infinity
if there is a task otherwise
s 0 and 4 i j in
in i don't know in array okay
and i'll be what have you learned today
given a
directive
a direct unweighted graph we want to
find out the shortest path the idea of
this agreement is that
it's based on dynamic programming so we
want to program okay listen
just listen
d i j
is the value of the shortest path
between vertex i to vertex 3. so
we want to calculate the shortest path
between i to j the cost and at any point
if you find the vertice k and then we
find out that i to k the shortest path
the the cost between i to k and plus i k
to j is shorter than i suggest and we
can replace this bit with i plus k k
plus j okay so anyway
you can replace the
that
distance between r to j with r to the j
it but anyway can you summarizing using
our let's ryan did a good job now your
turn
okay so you find out the cost
yeah we want to find out the cost
between adjacent
so i took a plus k k k today uh e if
it's uh what uh becoming bigger i just i
plus
i to k
plus i okay
uh
this is it
yeah we also basically we want to find
out the minimum yeah okay
the minimum of these parts i to j and i
take a to j okay so for example in a
later we have another t
right i to t t to j
so we can
get these parts instead okay 100 yeah
yeah
[Music]
yeah yeah exactly let's that's it okay
the time for next o n q the space
complexity
r n square right because we're using the
adjacent matrix to store dehydrated
shortest paths between
any pairs the this is a multi-source
shortest task
d i j so it means the shortest path
between vertices i and vertex 3
okay that will be it for today bye-bye