hello mr mr ryan all right
okay good so yesterday we talked about
finding the shortest path on directive
and weighted graph okay directly means
the graph has these errors and weighting
means the the cost between the vertex if
less edge
is uniform is one we can think of it as
one this equivalent freud is a much
thought shortest path aggregate
multi-source means that by running the
equilibrium we'll be able to find out
the shortest path between any pairs of
the
vertex so this is the o and o v cubic
equivalent o v cubic times an o
v square
space okay because we need a
ov square to hold the shortest path
between any pair okay so this is not the
most efficient but it allows us to to
find the shortest path on the directed
or iron directly weighted or unweighted
graph and how about the graph has these
negative values negative cycles does
they have a shortest path for example
like this one look
one
this is
two
three
four
okay and then five
okay
so look
this is a directed
direct directive weighty graph okay
let's say cos10 here
minus five
one
two seven
so given this directive uh waiting for
do we have a shortest path can we
calculate the shortest path
look at this is waiting to where
so yeah good question from one to five
look at this uh directed way to grab do
we have a shortest path between one to
five
one
two three
three you can go to that
okay so maybe here
okay this is a cycle okay
so you can go that way
so look at this directive way to go
right there's no shortest path why look
down the cycle you could go around you
can go round and round because like the
cycle
what's the sum of this cycle minus five
plus one plus two
minus two okay so what does it mean i go
one cycle
what minus two i got another cycle minus
two always shorter distance if laser
negative weight cycle then there's no
shortest path flow is the shortest path
that can be applied in directed or
undirected weighted low and weighted
graph and then the term complexities or
v square the speed complexity is all
these two okay v is the number of vertex
or you can say o and cubic o and o n
square okay
okay this graph is directly unweighted
one and
right and you said we can use the
breakfast search because it's uh
unweighted right because it's unweighted
then we can apply this breakfast search
do you still remember how do we use the
preference session p
q t q yes q whatever search can be
applied on the graph right and then
three is a graph right so we talk about
like trees that
are essentially a tree tree is a very
special kind of quick water the thing
about a tree is that
we can travel
to love children from a parent but we
cannot travel from children back to the
parent okay we can travel from current
to children but not a vice versa so
that's the key difference between the
trees and graphs photograph if it's a
directly undirected graph you can all
usually travel
fourth and backwards right look
if it's uh
directly on that requires goes both ways
look one can go to two two can go to one
so that cost is a problem right if we
use the breakfast search whatever search
what problem we have to remember the
vertex otherwise we're traveling between
the vertex forever right so we use this
hash map great for search the q
yeah the q eq
in python we're using dq double and dq
double ldq means that we can do this uh
pop
a pen
on both sides left and right so on the
left hand side is top left
and a pen left on the right hand side is
just top and the pen
and these four operations are 0 1
constant time
so it means that it's better than we
using this the simple list in person
because
in in python we're using the list like
that
yeah if it's a on the right hand side
it's a one constant time if we want to
do this operation on the left hand side
it's our linear time so it's it's not
very efficient so we prefer using the dq
for the breakfast search how do we
improve graphics search first of all
we want to get the shortest path between
a
a and b right you might travel at some
points here right
okay let's leave here a
okay let's put it numbers zero one two
three
four
so this is a directive angle we want to
find all the shortest paths between zero
to three so in the beginning at the
beginning we'll put a zero we incur the
zero in the queue right
and then we take everything out and
we'll turn it keep
one
when we take everything out
we append each kid so from one we can go
to two three four right so look two
three four
now we have three here we know we have
three so let's distance between zero to
three how many steps one step two step
okay
so
we talk about the breakfast search we
have two ways of taking out the items dq
from the from the queue right we can
take one at a time or we can take
everything out of time so in this case
we can do both right so
so we can take everything out of time or
we can take one hour at a time
define breakfast that we want to
calculate distance between i to j
at the beginning look at we have to
check if i equal equals j then we just
return zero right
if the source is the destination there's
no point to perform the perfect search
which is written here then q equals dq
at the beginning we put i in it
right now we have a electric unit that
distance will be zero
right so wire
q
uh before that we need to have a
scene equal set we want to remember the
vertex we have visited so we don't visit
it again and again why kill this is the
same as
checking if there are elements in the
queue is the same as y length q
of length q bigger than zero okay this
is the same thing every time
we take everything out of the queue then
the distance will be increment by one so
d plus equals one and n equals
the length of q this is the next number
of the notes that in the next level so
four and
we need to take n items from the q in
range
and
c equals q dot poplar we take the
one element from the q
then for x in gc
c means the vertex that connects to c
so if x not in
in scene
right we haven't visited the scene the
first thing is to put it in the notebook
at x
right and then q dot append
x
so c equals q the problem if at this
point we find out that
that is j then we need to return right
so we need to add that here if c equal
equals j then we need to return
d minus one right because we already
plus one here if we can't find the j
when we do this better search we need to
return zero the cost is zero or infinity
depending on the requirement so this is
the preference search so
we are taking everything out of the
queue
so we can use this d to
compute the cost the number of steps
right so when we find us j
when we find the destination that d will
be the distance
if not if we take one element out of q
we have to
put the top up we have to remember the
cost by the vertex so we can push the
uh like i and then the cost will be zero
when we do this ink you're putting an
item back to the key we need to
increment the cost by plus equal one
this is another approach okay
let's pray for search any questions so
far
really okay so what have you learned
today what's new
about breakfast
about finding
the
[Music]
that's very good yeah for the unweighted
graph we can use the preferences but if
it's weighted grab we cannot use the
preference session for the weighted
graph we can use the uniform cross
search or we can use the dick saucer or
we can use fried washer there are quite
a few different uh shortest parts like
maybe different different scenarios we
can apply each algorithm too okay the
qualification is quite useful real life
application can be visualized can be
modeled as the graph problem and we can
find the shortest path right we can find
the shutter pass
okay let's see bye bye
bye
you