hello mr ryan all right
look so we've got a few numbers here so
each number represents the the number of
candies bananas okay the number of
bananas for each pie
okay so let's play again right
look at this they are one banana three
bananas two bananas six bananas in a row
so
you played it and i play this game put
your time first you can pick six bananas
yeah you can pick the bananas from the
front or the back at each time and i got
to pick next so you pick first i pick
next and then you pick i pick
so we take turns right so can you win no
matter how i play so so put it this way
so you and i both play optimally right
so can you always win for this one so
what's your strategy i take the biggest
number okay you pick six yeah you pick
six and then i pick uh i can pick two
right you pick six i pick two and then
i pick three you pick three and i pick
one yes no matter you because you you
pick first you pick six if i pick one
you can pick three right you always win
but for this one you get to pick
can you win
that depends on who starts first you
always start first that's a good
question you've always suffered can you
win no i said
that depends on who starts first i see
so so i mean in this game you pick first
so can you win
no right because you pick one i pick 10
you pick this one i pick 10 right
yeah so the question is that we're given
a row of bananas and you get to pick
first
and i get to pick next so each one take
turn
so you both play optimally ultimately
yeah please look
optimal
so we want to find out if you can always
win no matter how how good i am okay you
get a dictionary and write down with
you how many scores
okay that's a good one
dictionary so what what's to do with the
dictionary you write down your scores
yeah okay so we use the dictionary to
write down the store okay so what's the
strategy i mean
always pick the biggest in front or in
the end right
it's not always i mean this this
question is not about
um
how to find the maximum
right it's not about how finding the
maximum
score
it's about winning right at each term
you if you get to play you have to join
you pick in the front or in the back
right
you only have two choice so we can
obviously we can prove us right all
right so
for example
if i were you i i i owe you here i got
to pick
i got to pick this one or this one so i
only have two choices right so i can
roof off this if i pick this one
then i have a smaller size of problem if
i pick this one
i have a smaller size of problem and
which one is is bigger right which is
bigger
i always pick the one which gives me the
most
advantage right
and a disadvantage if it's more than you
this is like a two player zero sum game
right two player i picked one score
yo i'm trying to maximize the numbers i
pick and then you're trying to minimize
and we talk about that mean max scan
mean max
right so this game three right
remember
so and here i'm trying to maximize two
and three right and and your turn is
trying to minimize and then maximize
minimize maximize minimize each term two
player right i'm trying to maximize this
you're trying to minimize it okay so
look this is all positive positive
numbers
so i'm trying to maximize so i can add
numbers you're trying to minimize
and you can subtract
so who will win if i'm winning so the
sum will be positive am right
yeah look if i pick six and you pick
seven
six minus seven smaller than zero you
win if i pick six you pick two
the difference would be four and i'm
winning so we're just trying to compute
the sum right i'm trying to maximize i'm
trying to add the numbers you're trying
to subtract the numbers
i know even the sum
is positive i'm winning if the sum is
negative you're winning right
so um
we talk about the mean max min max
function we can have this
you know we have this 10 right 10 whose
10 is it and then we want to give a
range from two right i and j right
i and j means that the the sub array the
sub array
who is 10 whose turn is it on the sub
subarray and this returns a score this
is score if it's bigger than zero i'm
winning if it's smaller than zero you're
winning right
but since uh this is a two player game
so if i'm adding this number you are
subtracting this number we can get rid
of this term
right we just have to subtract in it so
so to put it this way
to put it this way let's define the
function define
f
i j right look p p equals this array
right f i j means that start from index
i up to
index j inclusive so we want to find out
the score
as i am picking right if this num this
function returns a positive number then
i'm winning if it's a negative number
you're winning right remember that right
so look
if i equal equals j
we're trying to prove something at this
point if i equal equal to
so if only number so what should we
return just return itself right at this
point i'm picking right
look at this there are three bananas
here
my turn
so what you do pick it yeah that's three
that's the return
p i right rpg doesn't matter we have two
choice right so we have two choice we
want to pick to the maximum we just
return maximum maximum what
look
if i'm picking the left
right
picking the left so it's p i this is the
number right here
and then the next you're picking right
you're picking so you pick the numbers
from the i plus one to j right because i
already picked the i here right
it's minus look f i plus one
j
p i
this is the bananas
if i pick the left most
right and then your turn your turn is f
i plus one j but you have to
neglect this remember i'm trying to
maximize you're trying to minimize right
this is the
subtract yeah and the other way if i
pick this one right look
if pick the brightness so as pj
f
minus can give me this
look i picked the right mouse so what's
left
we're done i to j minus one
and then i just have to say look if we
turn f
zero from zero to length of the p minus
one
this is the score right and if i'm
winning if if i can always win so this
number needs to be
bigger and yellow or smaller than zero
bigger bigger than zero well done yeah
what's the missing what's missing
where down before i don't put the cash
that's a blue form
yeah i'm every time i have two choice
pick the left or pick the right right
and then we just
make it a smaller problem by recursion
but that's going to take ages because
some of these sub problems might be
calculated over and over again if i put
a cache
if i put a cache means that i want this
f function to be remember the values to
be remembered as long as we have it
right so look i is from 0
to n minus 1 j is from 0 to n minus 1.
so
for i the m choice for j they're in
choice so all to get less n times n so
we have n
square
state because we put a cache so the time
complexity is o n square the space
complexity o n square right we're
putting in cash this is basically
top-down dynamic programming we talk
about it right remember recursion with
the minimization it's basically a top
down so we're given this f zero for
example f
f 0 let's say 10 okay now in order to
calculate f 0 10 it will calculate p 0
minus f
1 10
and p
10 minus f19 right
which one is the maximum get the maximum
oh
right you'll calculate this value right
yeah because in order to get f zero time
you need these two values look f110
again you need two value f1 9 again it
needs two value so this is the third
string this is the search tree right
f function is basically a search tree
every time it has two values
you will take a two value and some of
these values
may be calculated over and over again so
that's why we have this cash function
to remember once we have it this is like
fibonacci number when we calculate this
value we store it using the notebook
cache remember it so basically saying
that okay
let's say
somehow f34 i have calculated again the
first time okay the value is five and i
put down in the notebook
no book right no book
so the next time okay i need the f3 for
our value again i look it up
it's there then i just return instead of
calling this function recursively to do
it do you get it yeah
this is top down we can convert it to
butter up right we can convert it over
using the arrays to two dimensional
arrays to uh to store it so we can do
this
we can do this okay this is the same um
so dp value
and
we know this area n equals length p
dt equals
zero times n for this is a two
dimensional rate of underscore in range
and
for i we need to initialize the value
for i in range and
dp
i i right dbi equals pi right look dpi
equals pi because if i equals zero if we
have only one number
if we only have one pi banana we just
take it we will just rotate it right
yeah
you're not allowed to skip by the way
okay
yeah
this one ten one
then you can just drop that you go first
then i would say okay you go first
nobody will start speaking so cpii i if
from i took i
a single pile of bananas which
return is
okay for i in range
start from from the right so i will go
this way i will go this way
so we start the index i this way
and then j will start from
here okay from i to the end
so from
for i in range m minus 2 to minus 1 -1
we start from the second to the last
index backwards
and for j in
range
i plus 1 to the n right so now we just
have to do this
so dp
i j
equals
so
basically
is least the same
p i
minus d p i plus 1 j
or d p j minus d p i j minus 1 so so
this expression is the same and then at
the end we just return dp from the zero
to the minus one so
meaning that this is that we are given
these uh uh the entire piles and bananas
we want to find out the score if it's
bigger than zero right
yeah so the the left one is the top-down
dynamic programming this is done by the
question with minimization the right one
is the bottom-up dynamic programming
yeah look
we're using restoring the values in the
dp array
and then we can compute
the values ourselves right so let the
time complexion space complexities for
both implementations are the same
but practically speaking
the one on the right the bottom up is
generally faster because we we don't
have risk overhead of calling the
uh according to recursion okay
yeah
okay so what have you learned today
right what have you learned today
okay okay so
speaking
whatever
what accurate are we using so what's the
problem what's the picking the effort
and how do we
okay okay and then what are we doing so
each turn we can pick
we have two choices pick the front and
pick the right right pick people back
back
and you want to find out how you could
win
you can always always win
no matter what no matter your opponent
and you can't skip you can yeah your
opponent comes
both players can't skip and your both
players play ultimately right ultimately
so we want to find out that
programming programming fij means that
we want to find out the score the you
know because i'm playing i'm trying to
maximize you're playing trying to
minimize it's a mean mag tree
right it's a mean back tree if this
score is bigger than zero then i'm
winning if it's smaller than zero then
you're winning right so to calculate
this function we need to find out the
maximum of these two values so the first
one p i minus f i plus one j basically
meaning that if i pick the first one
if i pick the first one then that's the
remaining
if you pick the last one that's the
remaining and now we put a negative
sound because the next player
right i'm maximized and then you are
you're minimized you're subtracting
right right
so look one
nigga will be minus one
and nigga that will be one right
so every time you call the recursion the
mi max three the sign will be negative
and that's that's just like two players
playing you
i'm trying to maximize and you're trying
to minimize it and that might turn
maximizing again and your turn
minimizing the game okay and then if
this score is bigger than zero then
then great i'm winning if it's smaller
than zero length
your wing and if it's equal to zero
then that's a draw right
yeah if it's equal to zero this function
is it returns you know then it's
um it means that you're not always
winning okay that'll be for today good
job bye bye
bye