right
on the space 2D Space X Y right X Y you
know this is
the condition X Y right so any we we are
talking about any four points any four
points on the space can you tell me
if we can use these four points to make
a square yes
so how do we check if it's a square
edges so edges by these four points you
have P1 P2 P3 P4 is not given in order
so you know it could be P1 here P2 here
P3 here P4 here so as long as uh these
four four points computation we can make
that square then return true so any idea
I mean each he said edges the distance
given two points on Space how do we
calculate the distance
you know this here here how do we
for example if this one is X1 y1 this
one is X2 Y2 if we are talking about 2D
Dimension so the distance distance
how do you calculate distance
is
is what so easily this this is a
triangle right triangle yeah we talk
about this right triangle
okay this is a this is B
this is C remember yeah so what do we
have a square plus p square equals c
square right very important this is y
times 90 degree A and B so look at this
speed this bit is X1 minus X2 or X2
minus X1
yeah this absolute value okay this bit
y1 minus Y2 or Y 2 minus y1 right so if
we Square it
squared plus y1 minus y 2 squared and
then equal this the distance square
equals distance square right look so
so we just do this uh square root of
both sides right so that become D
distance equals square root of X1 minus
X2 square plus y y minus Y2 Square now
Four Points so we can just prove us the
distance we calculate the distance
between any two pairs any two points
and then we put it in a set
so how many different distance do we
have if it's a square come on this is a
question if we calculate any pair of
distance
how many possibilities if it's a square
how many possibilities okay so look
maybe my question was not clear so if we
calculate the distance right so between
any two points so how many possibilities
if it's a square right if it's a square
how many possibilities how about the
values how about this the diagonals okay
yeah
so how many possibilities
two two yeah yeah look at these at least
yeah look at least four same
the diagnose the same right
so so simple Four Points we prove us the
pairs
yeah if it's different like you'll
calculate this distance distance
distance distance
and we put it in a set and if it's a
square then
the set the number of distance different
kind of distance in a set should be two
right because it's but there's a very
special case
it's not it's not enough look how about
look if P1 P2 and P3
the three values they they are the same
they collect
in one point and how about P4 is here so
how many how many distance here some
distance two right the one distance P1
and P1 distance to P2 is zero so zero
and that is also two so but we have to
is through this this situation am I
right yeah okay so the idea is that we
put we compute the distance between all
pair of combinations of vertex therefore
right so we can prove something easily
and I will check the size of the
distance set it has to be two and also
we checked
the distance of zero it shouldn't be any
because if it's any means that two
points or more they are the same right
they are the same points they just
Collide in space
okay so okay coming back to this this is
the coefficient distance for the 2D
space and we can extend this to 3D space
as well look look what's the distance
between
please please send this look XYZ right
the first street is 3D for the 3D look
this is 2D right 3D
X
y okay if you have to imagine and Z okay
so 3D space
x y z
okay let me just write it here
okay
so therefore Point P one p two P three p
four okay T equals D4 fictionally we're
going to count right we don't count the
distance the keys will be distance the
variables will be uh how many times of
this distance an array equals we put it
in a sample P1 P2
P3 T4 and then for distance for I in
range 4 right we are given four points
for J in range for J in range I okay so
then we can calculate the distance of a
r i to a r j so the distance would be
distance d i s t a r r i a r r z
okay we come back to this all right
distance actually is very simple Define
distance
uh a b V10
sqrt square root square root square root
of a0 minus B zero
Square Times 2 plus
a 1 minus P1
times 2 squared okay this is a distance
so d d okay then we use t d d plus
equals right we take it at the distance
with plus equals one we count how many
how many times the distance appear in
the in a in a sec in this is a
dictionary okay and then at the end we
just have to check
DD
t zero needs to be zero right
we don't allowed any two points that are
the same right zero distance zero should
be zero
and
men's T needs to equals how many how
many two yeah
why I love it right what's the time time
like see if you look at this
yeah because we're working on four
points and we just do some calculation
what have you learned today what's the
problem what have you done today
The Violet Square we have given four
points
square if we can make a square out of
these four points right so how do we
check we count
the distance between the vertex right
if it's a square how many kinds of
distance do we have two yeah but also
there's a very special case we have to
rule out which is
this one three points actually the same
analyze P4 because look if you calculate
the distance there will be two right
it's yellow because the points Collide
the the distance zero right the same and
pin one to P4 another one okay
bye-bye bye