hello mr mr rhino right
what's this
square oh yeah square oh what's this
data structure
cycle
yeah so what kind of thing we are
talking about when we talk about cycles
the thing i'm looking for here okay wow
okay so look
imagine this is the bus stop right zero
therefore bus stop and then there are
cycles yeah the bus stop so the
distance between zero and one the vertex
here in the graph is one and one to two
is two two two three three three two
four is uh three to zero
undirected weighted class and directly
radical
wait wait it means that
the edge is between the vertex that
is noted right
here
okay so if we given a start and stop
right for example like we're given a
star and
here
and a stop and here we're given only two
vertex here so we want to find out the
shortest distance between them so what's
the shortest distance between perfect
zero and vertex one if you look at this
graph yeah if you're looking at let's go
ahead and this one
one one okay if i put this eight what's
the self-existence between
maybe not eighteen okay what's the
celtics this one between zero two and
one that can be that's impossible why
because they would they have the same
length
but they have different lengths but yeah
i know fuck it up at least it's weighted
yeah at the bottom it's three but at the
top is
we're not actually looking at the length
that's why we say weighted what's the
shortest system between zero and one or
one two two nine how do you get that
yeah so basically how many choices can
we get
travel between two stops in this
particular and weighted direction i'm
waiting wait
yeah yeah in this square and direct
weight graph remember we we have list
here too yeah so we want to find the
minimum of it we are given uh undirected
right both way and directly means both
ways weighted graph means the
cost between the edges are different
right if it's a weight and weighted it
means the cost between the edges are all
the same we can think of it as
one or equal yeah
okay so
if an aggregate can be used on a
directed
graph then it can also be used in the
undirected one am right yeah if a
aggregate can be used on a weighty graph
then it can also be used on the iota
graph this is a simple question we can
just like uh compare the minimum two
parts to make sure the first index
always comes before the second index we
can compute the distance of these and
then the distance of that and we could
get a minimum define the shortest
distance
in the graph right in the graph we given
this the distance and then we have
released the star
and we have a stop
so the star
star may come after stop in the ground
right the star maybe comes after the
stop so in the in the case we can swap
it so if star is bigger than stop
then we swap it how do we swap two
variables a and b how do we swap a and b
here
a b equals one b
easy only in python you can do this but
if it's other problem in language we
need to use that another variable
another variable to do it so for the t
equals a a equals b
b equals b right
yeah
we need to
to make a copy of the value of a and
before i assign a new value b
right and then this this is to restore
the value original value of a so this is
the traditional way of changing two
variables using the third variable
if start you can stop then start stop
uh equals stop star okay we're just uh
changing these two variables so after
this
so the star is always smaller than stop
okay now we want to calculate the
distance here this distance
d1 equals
sum we're using the sum right
some distance of uh star
up to stop
this is this thing how do we calculate
this this bit
how do you get this bit come on there
are two ways of doing it this bit is d y
which is calculated d1 equals sum b star
to stop what's the distance of this bit
how to get that
two way there are two ways of doing
adding
adding yeah we can add it or we can do
this subtraction yeah we know if we know
this all together if we say d
d
zero equals sum of everything d
right so this is every chord then with d
two would be t 0 minus b 1 right right
the total cost is 18 plus 2 plus 3 plus
4 minus 18 and of course will be the
other part the cost the distance between
other times so we just return the
minimum
minimum of
d1
and then d2 here this is star
and this is stop
another way will be
calculate this bit
this bit plus this bit okay so
so this d2 can also be written as
sum
of the
d up to star
plus sum b
stop
to the end right
one way
we know this t1 yeah d1 is start to stop
here
so one way is to to do this
subtraction the other way is calculate
the distance between the star and the
distance after the stop because these
two
these two
runs up a circle right look at this
these two wrong double center
yeah
one last question what's the problem and
what have you learned today
what what do we have here what do we
have here this is bus stop mr bus stop
and what do we have
we have
a graph we have got what kind of graph
is it
i directly weighted one we want to
calculate the shortest distance and
there's only two possibilities this is a
very simple graph it's a regular graph
uh okay so we let's talk about the
concept the graphical graph regular
graph is that any vertex in the graph
has the same number of neighbors for
example each vertex in the in
has a same number of vertex right the
number of same number of neighbors this
is the squad which has a cycle it's a
regular graph it's a connected graph
right all of uh neighbors can be visited
by any all the vertex can be visited by
any vertex right and then it's a
indirectly it's a wavy graph and then we
only have two possibilities we just
iterate we just pull for 6 right the
time complexity is o and if n vertex
right because we want to calculate the
distance the sum of the distance between
a newton's stop okay that's it for today
bye bye
bye