hello mr mitchell
okay okay
okay
so yeah today we're going to talk about
this very famous the shortest path
excellent called backtrack how do you
pronounce this
that is that's right it's a shortest
game
this is
the name of a person so he invented this
okay so texture is a shortest path
stop this price
single source circuit pass angle so it's
called sssp
finger sauce shortest path
okay so when we talk about the guava
this is a weighted and directed right
weighted and directly
waiting means look at these numbers
labeling the edges so you can imagine
this the vertex this abcdefg you can
think of it as a town a bus stop right
we talked about the bus stop yesterday
so from a
to c it takes three minutes
from c to d cost four minutes right this
is and
uh directed so it means both way but we
can put a direction as well
[Music]
yeah so it's a graph i mean when we talk
about weighting don't look at the actual
distance okay so maybe
that if what's the shortest path between
eight 635
what's the shortest distance between a
to
b uh
let's see
three four one now
yeah two
three four one
three three one two no yeah three one
three one two yeah so that's six okay we
can solve this problem if it's a very
small one right but if you imagine if
it's a big one so it's not easy to put
it at glass and for computer we need a
algorithm to find out the shutter speed
so this is what the back structure the
texture is the single source meaning
that if i start from a i can get the
shortest distance to all other vertex
yeah all other vertices
so the the texture angle actually is
quite simple let's just two steps so
first step is update the estimate
update the estimate
the second step is to pick the next
vertex pick the next vertex
okay so look we have start from a right
so the distance
a to a is zero we know that right right
we are here so the distance here
we notice this we put it in the set
right so we are here the distance to a
is here obviously all other vertex this
is called an x4 right this is exposed
explore these are unexplored so we don't
know yet so we call it infinity and look
this is infinity in mathematics this is
infinity we don't know right
yeah
okay now let's update estimate so now
look
this is i i take this one this is the
current vertex
here right
i can go to
i can go to c and cos three i can go to
the c and cos three right yeah
so it's better than the infinity right
right because the estimate is infinity
for c but i can go to i now i'm a i can
go to c at cos 3 so it's better than
infinity so i i change this
to three
i use the red color to represent the
estimate and i i can go to f at two so
the estimate is zero plus two
is better than infinity right
so two okay
now i found the first step the second
step pick the next vertex how do we pick
the next vertex so we pick the vertex
which is in unexplored is the smallest
distance this is
the idx four f we are exploring and any
source is this way with a small distance
with small cos two or three
two right okay two so right here repeat
two
f two
c
two plus three is five it's bigger than
three so we don't update it right we
don't update it because the the previous
estimator c is three is better than our
current estimate 2 plus 3 right
f to e is 5 5 is better than infinity
right 2 plus 2 is better than infinity
so we update it to 5.
f 2
b
is 2 plus 6
infinity we update it to 8
f 2
g
7 right 2 plus 5 better than infinity so
i update it to seven okay these two are
extra
and all others are understood so what's
the smallest vertex that in in the
unexpected
c right because look three five seven i
pick a three
yeah
so now i'm here i pick the three
remember
a c
the numbers with the numbers these are
exposed i pick a three
c to d three plus four is better than
infinity so i change it to seven
c two to e
right so it's the three plus one equals
four four is better than five right four
is better than right so we change it to
four
right that would be it the all edge is
connected to to it right
one two
three four i explore right so which one
is exposed so we could pick a we pick
the b we put c so in the aliexpo we want
to pick the smallest distance so it's e
is e right it's e
because e we haven't explored it yet
okay so now let's could do this
estimate again e to
b right four plus two six better than a
right
we reach the b right so b six is the
smallest right who answer the six you
say six right yes okay
so look
two steps update the estimate pick the
next vertex which is an explore and then
with the smallest cost
so this is district and look remember
when we explore when we explore the
vertex
we
assume we already have the best answer
so that's why it's fast the term
complexity is if we're using the
classic area so so it's o h
plus v times log of v v is the number of
that vertex
okay
yeah
so look
it doesn't work with the negative weight
sometimes why is that look
when we explore the speed right we
explore this p which is six
so we we assume we get the shortest path
but if this edge here if this is a minus
a hundred and certainly you know any
path passing through this would be
better than these six right so it
doesn't work why is that because when we
explore the b
e
it's the shortest we know it's a
shorting we assume it's the shortest why
can we assume it's certainly because all
the edges
all the edges are positive so when when
the vertex x is 4 it means that we
cannot find a better solution by adding
the positive way right look because look
if those two here uh
this is 1 is 2 a b c
right so we explore this c here which is
the costly it means that it's the best
we cannot find any more edges
connecting to it by
by making it better because all the way
all our edges are positive right so it
means that this method only works for
holograph which doesn't have a negative
weight okay
single source uh shortest path right and
then when we implemented we're using the
priority queue so textual we we
mentioned about like uniform cost search
this is actually a variant of dextro so
there are many many factual variants so
they can classify it as the best search
so have you got this look pick the next
vertex from the from the unexplored
vertex which has the smallest cost
remember the breakfast search remember
yeah we use a queue
first thing first out right
so we are replacing the first universal
with the priority queue first thing best
out yeah so this is the variant of that
shot so for the press research it only
works on the
unweighted graph although all the
weighted gua with all the weights equal
or with the equal weight yeah and
weighted graph
right i already got but for this extra
variance it works on the you know
weighted one
because the cost is different right the
cost is different
so the difference between processors
yeah well let's talk about uh lisa
database preference search preference
search is using a queue
buffer search and this texture
all the ucs right
this is the variant
so this one is using the queue this one
using the priority queue or hip priority
queue or hip
all right
so they
it was on now and weighted and weighted
guard and 20 qualities it works on
waiting for so if it's only weighted
well if a grain can be used on the
weighted graph it can also be used on a
vertical right because the weight equal
anointing
is is a subset of vertigo
i'm right
because the
weighted graph
if we set all the weights to 1 to equal
weights that will be unweighted right
so and the time conduction for this
processor usually we can
think of it o v e plus v in the worst
case then all edges all vertex i exposed
and for the texture is o e plus v log of
v right because we're using the heat
here and each time to extract the
minimum from the q is low v time and
then in worst case it'll be ov right
right
uh okay so let's implement this a little
bit okay so we will talk about a uh
uniform course search uh again in in the
next few lessons so that's what define
that
so there are many variants of texture so
for the one i shown before is that we
have to
put all the vertex in the an expo set
beginning but there's no point of doing
that in the practical use so we will
write a classic dark shot okay
uh g
and and
star
and
so
distance equals before at the beginning
this default dictionary
infinity right infinity and the
beginning t is the
theme is the distance to all other
vertex remember this is a single source
shortest path so t s
is zero right so start process we know
this
is the cost is zero and we we need to
have a heap right so q equals at the
beginning we put a
cost the vertex of the star which is
zero the cost and the vertex
and then we also need to have a
a hash table to remember the vertex we
have explored so we have to distinguish
between the
x4 and it's four sets right so why
y of
y y iq then we take one element so we
cause the the vertex equals equals
keep
keep proof
pop q right we we take one this is to
extract the minimum to extract the
minimum from the heap from the other key
with the minimum cost right so now look
if if v in sync
if we haven't seen this if it's already
in x4 we just continue
otherwise we put it in the headset
single f v for
uh
for getting the next
vertex next weight in g
v right so this is to getting the edges
edges the the vertex and the weight
connects to the vertex v and we have to
check if
uh
if the cos the current cost is c plus
this v
is if it's smaller than d
d x right so we find a better we have to
find a better uh path a shorter path
then we update it dx equals c plus v
and we have to hit push
he push
q
c plus
uh
actually c plus w c plus w x
right and then return
return t
e
look d e
d is the dictionary right so deposition
right if we can also use the
dot equals these but
if we use this one we have to
be careful when the key is not existent
so this has to be changed as to d dot
get
x infinity so by default by default the
value is infinity means that if we uh
the initial cause to the vertex
x is infinity right
this is the extension okay so texture is
very famous because
based on this assumption that the other
weights are positive so it can achieve
the optimum it's usually the optimum
solution or ignorance right
to compute the shortest path between a
point s to any other vertex okay so
after doing this we we get all the
shortest paths to from s to all other
vertex right this is talk complete and
remember when we find the breakfast
search
yeah usually we'll find the destination
and we just return and this is not
complete right because it doesn't find
the shortest path between s to all other
vertex right but this angle is complete
okay so yeah this is direction it's very
useful and there are many many variants
and this is one of the variant that uses
the priority cue okay uh so okay so what
have you learned today
fixed diagram shot is fast accurate okay
so what did you get
so
so okay one question can the shot can an
extra egg run work on uh and weighted
quality yes yes yes because it wasn't
weighted quality of course you can work
on our way to go right so professor is
working and waiting for uh wow you can
work on waiting oh yeah yeah and way to
go okay the point massage can only work
on a weighted graph okay uh have a
deficit
very good question definitely usually
not suitable for the finding the
shortest part because it has to exhaust
all the parts in the graph but we have
this
tax limit such and combined with the you
know iterative deepening then we can
achieve that just finding the shortest
path by by combining of these uh depth
limit search with iterative detailing
yeah we mentioned that before
okay that's it for today bye