yesterday we talked about actual which
is the single source shortest path echo
so texture is the shortest path that we
can use on weighted graph so if we can
use the weighty guy it can be also used
from angulated graph right this
extra icon cannot be used on the gua
which has decent negative weight because
it has this negative weight then
sometimes it does not give this optimal
result and you know because we assume
that graph contains only positive way so
that's why it's fast the time complexity
is o
uh
e h plus v times log of v
log v comes from these extracting the
minimum yeah
extracting the minimum from the heat of
500k so with this g g is the adjacent
disk something like that it's a data
structure that we use to install the
graph we can use also the adjacent
metric right this in this case is
adjacent list which gives the keys as
the vertex the values is the list of
verses it connects to so for example
these graphs
one two three one to two the vertex one
connects to two and three vertex two
connects to three and four vertex three
connects to four and five right so this
is unweighted but if we don't use this
same thing to store the weighted graph
instead of storing a single vertex we
can store a tatter with your weight we
also talked about breakfast for a long
long time right the breakfast search is
the shortest path algorithm we can use
online and weighted graph
let's take a look at this question again
and you can find a lot of similarities
between breakfast search and directra
and
also the
you know the uniform course search we
talked about the uniform costs that ucs
in day 387 right you probably forget
yeah so prefer search we use the queue
right first in first off in python we
use the dq right
q equals dq so at the beginning we push
the s and the source in and of course we
need a
hash set to remember the the vertex we
have visited if we apply the preference
search on trees so we probably don't
need a scene the hashtag table because
the only way we can travel is from the
parents to the kid but in an
weighted graph especially if it's a
undirected graph then we can travel
between the vertex here here and there
right so we have to remember the vertex
we have visited so we don't go back you
know visiting it again
so why are q
y or q means that way we have these
elements in the queue or why the q is
not empty why the length scale bigger
than zero the length so we take element
take element z equals q dot pop left
right
and then we have to check if v in
scene
then we continue we have visited this
before we can otherwise we put it
if
if it's not visited we put it in the
scene table in dot add
at least and then we travel the next
vertex right we append the kit
for x in g
g
v right then we append it back to the q
so q dot append
x right so here we forgot to check if
we have to check here right so uh put it
here so if v equal equal e language we
10 we find it yeah we return you know we
can return
if it's a automatic wall we can return
the
destination or return the
the path we can have a variable uh uh
storing the distance from the stop
between the distance for example if we
push the distance along with the source
so
here is still s right so now we have
this cost
c v right then we return c here
right and and then instead of append and
open x we can append
the
c plus one x right because when we visit
the kids the distance is incremented by
one
right and if we can't find it we just
return infinity or return minus one
right so look this is perfect search do
you see the difference and similarity
between the question search and that
shot here kind of difference
processors on and weighted graph
texture on weighty graph
right buffer search the time complexity
of e plus v
extra o e plus v log of v in the worst
case all the edges of vertex will be
explored by a point search
right and here
we're using the dq
here we're using the
heap
they both use the hash set to remember
the vertex it's been visited this is
similar to append
right look this is quite similar but
here it checks the update november this
structure we update estimate and we pick
yeah it has an extra step of
updating the estimate this is updating
estimate
if we find a shorter task we update
d and here it uses d
d
stores the shortest path just this
distance between the source to all other
vertex but here we don't have these data
structure to store the shortest path
from the source here we just find a
single source find a certain distance
between s and e we just find this
surface
distance between a pair of vertex when
we perform this texture we have this d
it's complete so the actual is complete
process search here in this case
particular is
is not complete we talk about ucs ucs
uniform cost search is the variant of
that shot right it's a variant objection
so
we can
change least bit
slightly then you'll become a uniform
constructor you'll be amazed at how easy
it is to remember like uniform core
search
so the idea is that every time we take
the best out we visit the best uh
instead of the first influence now we
just change it to
first in best up priority out okay
so okay i'm just going to squeeze here
so uniform process okay i'm going to use
the green
so here this is the same
so we change it to
q equals
is a hip
right this is the same
all right
q top top left we use this so this one
we followed it
yeah
and this one we just follow this one
okay
i like it
so look
with the breakfast search we change
three places and it becomes a uniform
course search first of all instead of
using the queue double ndq first
infrastructure we use a heap
which is a priority queue first thing
best out right here
we get it up
and then
instead of
a pen and we need to hit push
and we don't have this step of updating
the estimate right this is uniform
clusters which is the value of the xr
and the time complexity is the same as
the extra
right it's not complete because as long
as we find a destination we just return
the function right
instead of finding all other shortest
paths to all other vertex to sum up the
uniform course search uniform code
search in day 387 uniform code search is
a variant of texture both use the
priority queue or keep first invest out
with the texture he has this update
estimate it's a complete it computes the
shortest platform from single source to
all vertex for the uniform core search
is not complete it's more similar to
processors
the difference between the uniform
construction professors is that the use
of queue or priority queue
or others are the same
okay that's it for today bye
[Music]