hello hello mr mr ryan are you right yes
okay okay that's it that's it no more
yeah
okay
yeah yeah that's it
we talked about the graph ignorant for a
few days now we talk about backstrike
we talk about
floyd
water
we talk about
breakfast search definite search
and also
one is missing
uniform cross search these currently are
five churches plus equal right now okay
extra
weighted yeah we can use it on weighted
freud water weighted as well
breakfast search and weighted deficit
and weighted uniform cost is the
variance of the extra which is weighted
right
the time complexity this one o
e plus v
log b
formulas are always
cubic breakfast search o v plus e
therefore search is the same just
differs the way that expand the notes
minimum cost search is the same as that
okay
this is the time consistency okay so
when we talk about the context for
example the preference of the
differences we usually like to represent
it as a v-plus inverse vertical edges
but sometimes we can also use this o
b
d okay b d
b to the power of d b is the branching
factor so for example a tree right a
tree we talk about the trees a tree
branching factor here is two right
because each node has two kids crunching
factor two d is the depth
okay
so you can imagine that in order to do
this definition breakfast search on this
tree
binary tree the time complexes out to
the power of d
right because at each step if we
increment the depth number of nodes with
the bw we also talk about
the iterated deepening long time ago
iterated differently
this is basically like a graphic search
and deficit combined together the
problem with breakfast search is that we
need a space to store all the notes in
the same level so the space complexity
for this one if we talk about this b and
d is o
b to the power
b
the space convexity or o v right
but for the default search we only need
to need to store the look we need to
store one note per level so the space
complexities of the the preferred search
gives this optimal result
on an awaited graph if we search the
first node e5 is the shortest to the
source
the problem is that it uses too much
space the default search
it uses
less space but it's not optimal for
example like if the the optimum
node here is here right and the death
massage finds another number here and
you return it doesn't find this one
right it's not ultimate it's not
complete
iterative deepening search on the other
hand is it's a combination of death
search and preferences so so we have a
limit so we have a d so at the beginning
we said that d equals one then we
perform the definition but when the
nodes are beyond this d the depth still
stop
if we find it
great that's the
optimum right because d now is the
minimum right it's a minimum and then
now we if we don't find it we increment
d to b equals two and then we perform a
definition with the
dfs actually we perform a deficit
with maximum depth equals two sometimes
we call it that's limit search
okay and if we found a node that's the
ultimate node but if not we keep
incrementing the d until we find it one
so now that we want to find is uh
somewhere here this node yeah productive
search
to list right do this
for the preferences
here we find it this is the optimal well
for the test limit search iterated
differently okay so we set the limit to
one node so we perform a different
search and that's it we increment d and
we perform the of search
that's it we don't find any and we
increment d and
we perform a different search
and we still don't find it and when we
increment the d
we perform the differences
okay and then we find it
so this way we combine the different
search and graphics search we uh
into this iterated deepening
we have talked about this iterated
deepening a long time ago okay so look b
equal at the beginning we said zero so
while d smaller look we have defined
this uh iterative
depending search with the graph
and we want to find the
shortest path between s and e so look at
the iterative differences usually we use
the only and weight equation okay
y t is more than the maximum
so usually we want to give a maximum
depth right so
in a graph the longest the longest
distance you can travel is the number of
vertices right
yeah
the longest so we can say n equals the
length of g if this g is adjacent matrix
attrition this
answer
equals
that's the limit search
with this g we want to find the s to the
n
and with the depth right
if answer is we found it if we find it
then we write an answer
otherwise we just increment
that right and then return here will be
written not found
right so look at this is internally
different so it's just a while to
increment it
the depth max of death
if we don't find it we keep incrementing
the d
this is the depth and search that's
limit search dls is basically dfs
plus a
max
depth okay
so what makes them is that
if the depth goes beyond a d now we stop
we don't uh continue
okay look this tree might be very deep
right
okay so if i'm saying d the maximum d
equals three
okay then if we perform a depth leave me
search what happened look
what's the death zone let me search like
one two
three four five six seven eight nine
okay so if we perform this limit search
on this squad on this tree
and with the limit three so what's the
order what's the definition order with
the maximum level three
one
two
four
should we go beyond
because it reaches limit then we go back
three
five six that's what it means yeah if we
don't find it we keep incrementing this
depth let me search iterated deepening
okay that's great okay we can implement
that that's limited but first of all
let's implement the deficit and now we
can change it to definite research
define definition we want to find s to
the n right
okay
so if s equal equal e language
we find it right if let's start is the
same as the destination and we find it
okay
then if not then
answer at the beginning we set it to
infinity for
the next vertex in gs
an answer equals the mean
answer
d f s
v e right need to plus one here
yeah need to perform and return and
so look at this this stafford search is
not very suitable in finding the
shortest path because it needs to extort
all the paths and that's very expensive
okay that's very expensive
but one thing we can improve is
uh here
the the problem here is what the other
thing that is that if we're using a
graph we need to remember the nodes that
have been visited otherwise
look if the one goes to two two goes to
one and then
we don't want to go going for them back
right so we first of all we need to add
a
sim here
a hash map and then we can say
if s in sin
then okay return infinite if we have
found this before we return infinity
and
if not with the first thing is to put
this s into the uh the vertex that we
have seen so s
scene dot at s
okay
and before because we added so before
that we need to restore it so seeing the
erase or remove
remove s
so let's this is the step search
okay so now we want to change this to
depth limit search so we have to add
another parameter called d
and then here as well if d smaller than
zero line will return
infinity right
and then we just have to
give this parameter d minus one here
right and that's the that's the message
simple as that okay so the advantage of
iterative deepening is that it's
complete as the breakfast search it
allows us to find the solution the
optimal solution if there's any it also
uses the same memory as the data search
right because look at the deficit
we don't need to store the nodes of the
same level right we don't need to
maintain the cube we just need to
remember the
the path right this path
you know
it uses the less space than storing the
nodes of the same level right okay so
tell me what's the iterated dependent
search it's like breakfast
it's a combination of that for surgical
search right
so it's already different it's like we
are performing the data search
right but we are performing in an
incremental order let's do a different
search and then let's stop let's not
explore the notes beyond the
distance one
okay if we find it would return this is
the optimum right
okay we don't find it right like one
meter we don't find it in one meter okay
let's increment the next step to two
meters
right and let's perform a test research
on
on this graph along with the graph
with max distance too
if we find it great we return we stop
the iterative differences if not we
increment the depth to three right the
time complexity for this one is actually
quite tricky
so if we perform this on this three for
example right so look the last level d
only explore once right so it's b to the
power of d the second to the last level
exposed twice
so it's
two times b b minus one
the third to the last expo three times
right so it's three plus b b minus 2 etc
so but the most dominant thing is this
one so the time complexity is the same
as the definition of breakfast is also
ob e to the power b
right okay the space complexity is the
same as f search which is the
od
okay
that's it for today bye bye
bye bye bye