hello mister with mr ryan are you right
okay
so a few days ago we talked about the
bus station remember that the bus
stations are in a circle
simple graph
zero one two three if the cost one
two three
four okay let's make this bigger if this
is nine so
what's the
shortest distance between zero and one
this is a quad right a regular graph
right we talk about the mother
19 and three are about the same okay
especially this is the weighted graph
right so this is a simple regular graph
we talk about a regular graph regular
graph means that each vertex has the
same number of neighbors right and
for this particular graph problem we can
just use the mass the shot is distance
there are only two ways right either is
this bit
or it's this bit right
so we can just do a simple math we talk
about that since we can treat this as a
weighted
undirected graph then we can use the the
graph aggregate the shortest path we
talk about lots of jobs about that
baxter
these can be used on direct or and
directly radio and vertigo right but it
does not work on negative
weights
we talked about uh floyd
wasa
uniform concert
this is the variant of this the bfs dfs
does know what this in this case
why is that the devastation breakfast
search does not work in this particular
case why is that anybody
unweighted
yes so therefore certain purposes can
only be used on unweighted graph okay so
that means that we cannot use these two
angles to do this right and we talk
about iterative differences which is the
combination of different searching
preferences
okay so we can use these three shortest
paths again okay so let's use this for
you also when you talk about that let's
just review this by solving this problem
right the foreign water is uh o v cubic
uh 30 stars actually can be used on uh
weighted or hybrid graph directly or
another one and it's a matty sauce musty
sauce
meaning that when we perform this
shortest part again we can get the
shortest parts for any pair so we we
have this i j
is the
represent the shortest path between the
vertical side vertices okay the spirits
of the fluid water is this vertex i and
then
we want to update the shortest path
between the vertex side to veltex j and
we keep updating this keep
iterating the vertex k
if the distance d i j
if d i
k
plus d k j right look we talked about
this if it's smaller than d i j now we
can replace the distance of shortest
distance from i to j with with this part
right
look this i to j
may be a sub problem of of a bigger part
of of a longer distance for example if
these distance a to b
if the shot is fine look we want to
calculate the satisfied between a vertex
and a vertex b
right and at some point
we realized that the distance to i
from i to j can be replaced by i to k
plus k to j right so then we just
abandon this
right so we can just replace this with
this
because this one
is a sub problem and it provides a
shorter path a better result
okay so in order to apply this algorithm
we need to convert these into
into a graph into this right and then we
can apply it okay
i'll try to destroy water
so
this uh
foreign sauce with ov cubic
compared to dextra is o h plus v log of
v which which one is bigger which one is
faster
this one is faster yeah because factor
makes assumption that all the weights
are positive so it's kind of greedy
right so the remember the the direction
again two step update the estimate and
pick the vertex next vertex with the
smallest weight in the ionix
so it based on this assumption so it's
very critical so it's a
and if we implement it using a priority
is the time complexities of
e plus v log of v because the log v
comes from
the step extracting the minimum the
optimum from the priority queue up here
the frying wasa is much soft and it
works on
negative weights as well right it was a
negative way so it's a slower but the
advantage of this floyd water is that it
can be used to compute the shutter path
between any two pairs it's a microsoft
this is a single source okay single
source means that the output of dextra
produce this p array b
d array right so from zero to n that
gives the shortest path between the
source to any other vertex define the
shortest distance
and then we're given the distance of the
array distance distance away the
distance i
is that the shortest
is the distance between vertex i
to vertex i plus one right so we need to
convert these to the graph and we want
to get a zero system between star to the
n so first of all we need to use the d
so the number of vertex lengths of the
distance
so now we can construct this d away
theory this is the d
two dimensional d i j right we want to
have this d i think this is a two
dimensional e equals at the beginning we
set it to infinity
times n
for underscore in range n
and at least he starts bij if we
certainly set the initial value dij to
infinity right so we
so what does it mean it means that look
if we have this uh
remember the bus stop
and the bus stop zero one two three if
we do this it means that we haven't put
the edges in so the distance between any
two vertex
is infinity because we haven't added the
edge now we want to add the edge
so we just go through for i in range
n minus one we skip the last one because
the last one has a connection to the
first one right so now
d
i
i plus 1 equals d i plus 1
equals
distance i
okay so basically this means that we set
the distance i that's the distance
between these uh the neighboring vertex
right and c i i plus 1 equals d i plus 1
i it means that it's undirected right
the distance between these two this is
the same as the distance between these
trees that's what it means and then the
last step is to add the edge of this one
so t
i zero
actually is t
t zero
n minus one
all right c g of n minus y equals t
n minus one zero equals distance
uh distance the
last one is minus one okay so we have
constructed edges right four
k in range
and next and then for
i in range
and
for
j this is the
what the o and cubic obq becomes one
okay
in range n
d i j d i j equals the minimum of d i j
and this is basically the dynamic
programming
d i k
plus d k j all right we're up keep
updating so we so basically the outer
root is to iterating each vertex and
then the inner two loop is to iterate
any pairs so we're iterating any pair i
to j right
and now we iterate another k
so if we find the shutter pass by going
to this by jump to k i put i to k
different plus k to j
then we can replace i to j with this
shuffle path right that's what it means
then we turn
we just return distance star to the end
right and then you give this answer
and we talk about the
product it's a two or four function here
so this bit can be replaced by
k
i j in it
it's a tour eta tour
from italy import
product
and range
and
repeat
equal three okay so range n
cartesian pressure excess three times
is the same as this for loop right the
time connects the lv could be the space
convexity of v square why we use the
two-dimensional way
okay the bus stop problem is a regular
graph
you know with a circuit with the vertex
in a circle right
the first step problem right we're
talking about a mass formula just to
compute a minimum of two parts distance
between any two bus stop vertex
can be only two ways right right there
are only two ways because they form a
cycle yeah it's a
regular graph today we're using this uh
floyd water we talked about that this is
the matty sauce
shortest path acronym
that works on
directly and directly weighted iron
weighted ground and the weights can be
negative as well so basically this is a
very very powerful aggregate
it works on many many scenarios one
disadvantage is that it's slow it's all
we kill it right this
can be visualized as a guard problem and
we can apply the shortest path again to
it can we use the texture algorithm to
solve this problem
um yes yes yeah we're done okay
so you have this
that's right yes and and numbers yes i
know we what are we trying to do find
the shortest part
okay uh yeah we are trying to find a
shout
shorter distance between anything faster
so what's the egg room we are using
today floyd wash washer fluid washer
yeah it's a mattress
okay press it okay that's it for today
bye bye bye bye