hello mr mr ryan all right
yeah
on day 179 yeah we talked about to
delete
the even leaves in the finance
the sub tree so as long as any subtree
has all the even notes then we remove it
the even leaves
six
so we remove that even this
and now these become even dips we keep
removing it right now
two we can remove it for we can remove
it
no more because this is odd right
so we use the recursion we use the
recursion to recursively remove it
define
remove
evenly
leave
of a binary tree a loot which is a three
note right it's a three note
we can specify the type
and then it needs to return a tree now
okay three note if not root if this is
already empty that will just return
return or return none
right so now look we are here root right
so this is blue dot left you know it
might be a subtree rule.right it might
be a subject right
so now we just because we call this
function right so
blue dot left
which is this bit move dot left
we want to recursively remove the evenly
so root of that right so if
we move we call this
itself remove even this
blue dot left okay
and can you try the next one
right
yeah so we just copy it basically glue
them right right
to the right do the right this bit and
we want to
remove the even leaves of the noodle
right so we are cleaning we are removing
the even leaves of the left tree even
leaves of the right tree so there's a
possibility that all the subtree has
been deleted right and all the right
trees have been deleted i'm right
so when it's deleted
how many possibilities if i'm removing
this so there are two possibilities
after removing the even leaf this bit
has at least one note or it's all gone
right we can remove everything right the
only two possibilities right if we are
removing
everything on the left to your virtual
at least become the newly then we have
to check if it's evenly we can take this
out am i yeah
on the first example you
you didn't remember
good point that's a very good point
because i have i still have to check if
this is the event
okay yeah correct me yeah yeah
i was not entirely precise okay we can
remove this note now if this bit this
tree has been deleted at least right
three has been deleted and also this
dude is even now right now we can take
it out if it's odd now we can't right if
do
we can just say not rule or left
and
not root or right right so this is
just basically saying that
the both subtree has been gone if one
states what happened if one state this
is not a leaf now right
this is not leaf though this this
becomes the new leaf node if both
subtree has been depicted
and root value is an even node it's an
evenness so we can use n1
equal equals zero all modulus too right
modulus two equal equals zero this is
also the same
and one equal equal one okay both are
the same
when we remove it we just return none
right
otherwise we just return the root
recursion
beautifully done right
if we're using the other
egg not be complicated but the recursion
this location is the perfect case use
case in this scenario okay so today's
problem given the spinal tree we want to
remove every subtree not containing one
okay so this is removing the leaves
right we will because we're removing the
even leaves right what are we doing here
today is that we want to
remove
every
sub tree
not containing one
so every substrate not contain one okay
so how can we use this
so
there's only one thing we need to change
here what is it which line needs to be
changed not containing one look we are
removing every structure we can we can
first learn
yeah this is obviously the function yeah
we're done
pruning or remove you're just pruning
okay pulling the tree
pruning binary
okay we first of all if we that's right
we have to correct the
function
okay so this speed is the same a little
bit yeah we recursively
removing the subtree on the left subtree
if it does not contain one and remove
the sub tree knocking in one and then
this becomes a sub tree right a
leaf node and
so we have to check if this is not one
this is you know this is one right yeah
the top one the top left top left is one
right
there's nine there isn't anything there
okay so this one yeah
yeah
okay so we want to remove every
substrate that's containing one
right
not containing one so we can remove this
this is actually not containing one
right
so this is gone
anymore this contains one this contains
one because this is not delta so
obviously any subtree that containing
this cannot be known right so this is
zero right if this is zero so
we don't know this yeah we can remove
the leaves
because the leaves is the smallest
substrate right we do more relief and we
remove this at least become a new leaf
and we keep removing it and this is a
two different way of saying the same
thing right we are removing every
substrate not containing one so what's
the smallest substrate
leaf a leaf yeah so it's basically
saying that we want to remove every node
every leaf because every leaf not one
right so what was the previous question
we want to remove every even leaves we
want to repeatedly delete
that evenly and now this is the same so
we want to repeatedly
recursively evade
the leaves which are not white which
lines of color we need to change here
yeah okay so we just have to change this
to
not containing one
so what does it
mean is not containing one it's not one
right because we are here we are
checking because here look we don't move
the animation
yeah why not so look at the left subtree
is gone the right subtree is gone and
the root is the new leaf it's a new
subtree
and we just basically have to check if
root top value
is not equal one right when we turn now
previously on day 179 we talked about
the recursion recursive agreement to
delete evenly
which is uh recursively calling the
function to remove the evenly from the
left subtree and right subject and once
the both subtrees are becoming empty
that means the root becomes the new leaf
and then we have to check if the root
is uh even not if it's a even now we can
take it out right
this is 179 and today our problem is
that we want to remove every sub tree
which is not one not containing one
yeah it's quite tricky not containing
one so it's basically saying that so we
want to remove every
leaf now which is no one it's the same
thing yeah because every subtree not
containing one
then we can start checking from the leaf
node because the leaf nodes are the
minimum substrate even the subtree the
leaf nodes are substrate if it's not one
not containing one not containing one
it's not one
so not containing one for sub three it's
the same thing as if the leaf node is no
one if we leave now it's not one we take
it out so basically
just we just have to change one and of
course okay the time temperature we are
traveling the binary using the depth
search recursively like that research
each node has been visited once the
space complexity or when in worst case
the binary tree is a linkage if the
final tree has only one kit for each
note the binary tree could be like that
right
zigzag to each note look each note has
only one kid left or right then in this
case that there are n notes and the
depth of the final tree is n okay so
what's new today what have you learned
that's why we have a
tree yeah we have a tree yeah binary
tree
which
we wanna
delete every sub tree which doesn't have
any
thing okay yeah
and then yeah
so how are we doing this if i'm looking
at this code how do i doing this
we're doing it
by
uh
yeah recursion so what yeah so i mean
half
so it's the same thing as what
we get like the same thing
deleting every is
that's it for today bye-bye
bye-bye
you