hello miss erin mister ryan are you
right
yeah
okay so we talked about the binary tree
the uh low is common ancestor okay we
talked about that on day i don't know
100 days something like that
of a binary or binary search tree what's
a what's spinal retreat
what's spinal tree and what's binary
surgery
[Music]
okay so which one of these is binary
search tree
let me just do another one
which one is finally search three and
which one are the bottom one is one
research three and all of these are
financially right yeah finally search
notes on the left are strictly smaller
than the root the notes on the right are
strictly bigger than the root okay
that's a tricky one how about this one
is this a fine is a tree
why is that
[Music]
excellent okay so look on the left hand
side these notes need to be strictly
smaller than 7.
even it's bigger than 6 but it's not
strictly smaller than seven right right
okay so on day i don't know 114 probably
yeah we talk about finding the lowest
common ancestor of two given notes so we
we we are given two notes in the binary
tree
right and then we want to find out the
lowest common sense for example like if
we change this to
all right if we given seven and nine
what's the lowest common ancestor of
seven and i i said what's this mean
ancestor what's the meaning in english
what's the opposite of ancestor
descendant
yeah basically this means their parents
you know parents or parents parents or
parents parents yeah
what's your lowest common ancestor
eric here
ryan here what's the lowest common
ancestor
mommy and daddy here right
yeah remember
daddy's a sister has a
has a son you met him before right yeah
but that is a sister this is teddy yeah
that is sister that's my house
okay daddy's sister you call
what do you call this auntie uh auntie
google what do you call google in in
english
daddy's sister so what do you call
auntie
i'm not sure okay so um okay let's say
i only got the sun i don't know cause
the han okay
yeah
so what's the common
ancestor of eric and
daddy and auntie's uh
parent
grandma in connecticut
okay
so
common ancestor
yeah
so basically this question is asking
what's the common note that has this
descendant as it has a descendant yeah
that's that's what it means okay you get
get it yeah okay another question what's
the common ancestor of uh
seven and eight
exactly what's the common sense of six
and eleven
that's a tricky one guess eleven you
know yes so a node is a
ancestor of itself and it's a descendant
of set okay that's the concept
okay so we talked about this lowest
common ancestor in day
114 probably and when we are talking
about that binary it could be a binary
surgery okay define f
load
p we on that day we talk about the
recursion
so
we want to find out we are given these
three loops we want to find out the
common sense of p and q q p and q are
given in the binary okay so let if not
good right then we just return okay
return
if root of value
is in
p dot value or q dot value
then we just return root right
if p dot value and q the value right is
equal to root of n if if the current
given tree the root is the p and q
either of it then we return it right
look that's what it means look
all right
p and q and at least it's also a root
and
then as we talk about a loop is
a node is a common system we said so we
redundant okay uh f
a root or left
first of all we find out the left tree
and next we find out the right tree
if we can't find if a is now or not
right if if we can't find it on the left
tree look here is the root right
and then when this is moved on that this
is blue dot y if we are trying to find
the common ancestor in the left tree if
we can't find any like it must be on the
right right
but same thing if we trying to find the
common ancestor in the right tree
if we can't find it where is it
left left yeah so that's what we mean
return if a is not within b if b is none
return a right okay
right otherwise if we can't find both
then there's only one possibility the p
must be on the left humans only right
right
so in this case which which one is the
common ancestor right look what i said
you remember
yeah
okay so this is the previously we talked
about recursion so
let's
talk about it again so first of all if
if we solve this simple case if p
and q
are p
uh all q and p if it's something like
that if the loser is one of these if p
is the root then we'll determine p if q
is the rule then we don't keep right
because the node is a common sensor of
itself
if not we're trying to find on the left
tree
and we're trying to find on the right if
we can't find it on the left
if if p and q is not on the left if p
and q
in here right then
it must be here right look that's what
it means if a is none a is not on the
left we can't find it on the left so it
could be
p and q could be here right
or p and q will be here that's two
possibilities in either case we return
this one right
so
the same thing if we can't find it on
the right it must be on the left if we
can't find both right if the common
ancestor is not on the left tree and not
on the right tree so there's only one
possibility p and q is on left and right
separately then in this case dude is the
common ancestor
okay so let's recursion
okay how about if i'm telling you this
is a primary search tree but that would
be even simpler
all right so look
6 1 5
10. right so look
what's the common sense of a and 10
yeah if you look at here both values a
and 10 is bigger than 7 so where is the
command sister right right 3. okay where
is the common system
four five if you compare to this
on the left right yeah learning must be
okay so then look though
it's simple if these three is a binary
sentry we could just say okay if
if both notes are smaller then you must
be on the left tree
if both notes are bigger they must be on
the right trick otherwise which you know
if one note is smaller one note is
bigger which one is the command system
the root easy simple logic right similar
logic so we can implement this before
going to this here another way is to
okay another way i'm not going to write
the code here if this is a binary
now another way is to look we're given a
root right so we can do this type of
search your breakfast search passing
through
uh define different search all right
loot the parent
parent we will do this type of search if
not root
return
yeah okay then we do this pepper search
and then we can we call that this is the
parent yeah right this is a dictionary
and we can say parent dictionary the
parent rule the pair equals parent right
what do we need this parent for look
given the root note we can travel from
parents to the kids but we want it to
look in the reverse way right so we want
to record the parent of each node so
given this then we can do this uh p we
can do this p how do we do this we can
travel backwards to the root and we
remember the notes in the
table so look at this one five
okay so i put it in the same table right
five put it here
six put it here seven put it here okay
this is the table from travel from p
upwards okay and how about eight
is a in scene no right what's a parent
nine what's it's nine in c no what's a
nice parent seven
seven is in c so seven is the common
sense right simple logic right so first
of all we do the left search to remember
the parents for each node and then
with p or q if we do this with p we
remember the note by going up right
going up here and remember the note 5 6
and then now a or 10 yeah right it's 10
in sim no transparent nine yeah because
we have done this 10
19 now
nice parent seven 17 okay
so seven is the lowest compensation this
is another way okay coming back to this
okay
financial strict okay easy it'll be easy
we can do this there in two ways
recursion and iterative recursion easy
symbology okay
define f root
p q
okay look if not root return
just to prevent the root is empty okay
now if p dot value is smaller than root
of value
and q the value is smaller than root of
value if p and q both on the left-hand
side then
return
f
what p q can you tell me
if p value is smaller than root this is
root right if p is on the left side p is
on the left hand side so return f
recursion this is recursion so what we
need here
[Music]
left okay
and then again if p dot value is bigger
than root of value
and
q dot value is bigger than root of value
return
calling itself
root
y and p q yeah easy
right here otherwise return
otherwise return
loot yeah perfect
question iterative this simple iterate
this is recursion every question calling
itself here here
yeah yeah we navigate it to the left of
root.y we actually
making the problem smaller so we can try
to solve a smaller problem right that's
what the recursion for it basically at
some point you need to solve this
problem otherwise if an application
don't end what happened it's just
calling itself it says
and the computer just repeats the
recording exam without solving anything
all right
yeah remember that the exclamation mark
right
f n equals n times m f n minus one
right so s n minus one according to n n
minus one times f minus 2 right look at
this one is n minus 1 times
f minus 2. so let's please keep keep
recursing but we example we need to
solve it when n equals
zero
zero exclamation is one right now once
we get still zero estimation equals one
then we go backwards to solve
a bigger problem recursion
but recursion has this problem that may
sometimes if the recursion that is too
big then we have respect overflow right
stack overflow
okay so learn this one the same uh load
wire load
this is the same yeah look
if p the value
is smaller than q uh load of value this
is some basically copy but we are not
returning we go to the left rule equals
rule.net right
a if
p dot value bigger than root of value
and p dot q dot value bigger than q dot
value bigger than root of value so in
this case what should we do blue equals
one
so now we have loaded here we need to go
to the right right blue equals blue dot
right
otherwise errors else we just break and
then at the end we just return root
yeah okay so these two are the same
recursion
it's rated okay
okay so to sum up yeah we talked about
this problem uh in the early days
but
on that day we talked about recursion to
solving this problem on
uh binary tree but the title was
incorrect at that time the title was
final research trick so with spinal
surgery we can apply this simple
approach
yeah the time convexity if it's final
search tree the time complexity is o h
o h
actually it's the height of the final
thirty right because every time we go
one level so the maximum distance we
travel from the root to the leaf
right every time we go down one level
it's height in the worst case final
search tree
the height is the number of nodes right
you know the final surgery is degenerate
like like one two three
four so it's basically a linkage you
know it doesn't have two ways right so
look at this the final surgery right
every time we can only go to the right
it's a linguist right we're we're not
using the characteristic of bonuses to
the left and right strictly because they
know left nodes okay also one two and
then you go to the left it will be 1.5
so every node has one
kit
then
the height is
equals to the number of nodes
let's face max the uh
this one we're not using any additional
space this one we're using recursion but
sometimes the location can be optimized
okay so
if it's a binary string if it's a binary
we can
still use the iterative or recursion
right and we also talk about using the
uh set so basically we do that perform
the definition breakfast search from the
rule to the kids so we remember the
parents of each each node then from p or
q we travel backwards to the root and we
remember we put those nodes yeah we will
pronounce nouns in a hash set right and
then we travel from the queue backwards
again and here it means the first note
that is already seen by key p right yeah
that's that's what you do when you're
trying to find the law is common and
sensitive okay
okay so
what have you learned today
finally
okay so
okay so how do we find the coma assets
the lowest commerce system financial
street so p and q so if they are both
smaller than a root then where do we
find the lowest commands
left tree and if it's all bigger than a
bye