hello mister here mr ryan are you right
yes on day 28 okay on day 28 we talk
about how to check if a binary search
tree is valid yeah
what's binary search tree it's a tree
it's a tree
[Music]
why is that because
minus one isn't
greater than yeah that's right so
finally surgery obviously at the
beginning it should be a binary tree
final tree is that each node has at most
two kids right but this is the blue the
notes with no children are called leaves
there's only one which doesn't have any
parent that we call it dude for each you
know it has at most two kids let's
finish it and finally surgery has this
additional criteria like the notes on
the left trees are strictly smaller than
the parent the notes on the right three
are strictly bigger right so look this
minus one is smaller than two but
it should be bigger than one
so this is not a binary search tree but
if i put these here one point five is
this a finishes tree
yes this is the perfect advantage so on
day 28 so we want to check if a banana
tree is the finest tree
at that point we talked about a
recursive agreement so basically we we
have a maintainer window so minimum
value and maximum value maximum value so
we maintain this window for the node
value
so one look at the beginning we don't
know the window so we set it to minus
infinity and positive infinity right as
soon as we travel to the left or travel
to the right if we travel to the left
look this window yeah left and right
it should be bigger than the left and
smaller than the right
so if we travel to the left what
happened
look
the range of the value for the current
node is from
infinity minus infinity to positive
infinity this one is at this strength if
i go to the left
what happened to the window
smaller yeah look at this one so the
window becomes minus infinity to one if
we go to the right what happen
the number should be bigger than one and
smaller than infinity right so every
time we travel to the left we update a
window and
accordingly if we travel to the right we
update the window accordingly and at
each node we just check if the value is
inside the window all right
okay so can we have these duplicate
values in the final research
why is that because
because
because if this duplicates it it
wouldn't be strictly smaller exactly yes
because we're talking about strictly
smaller and strictly bigger if that
duplicates that then certainly doesn't
mean this requirement okay
this is a very straightforward recursion
algorithm we just keep tracking of the
window and then if we move to the left
we update the window if we move to the
right we update the window and then we
validate the final retreat to see if
each node is within that window okay
let's define
f at the beginning root the window
minimum value and the maximum value
right at the beginning we can set this
mean value maximum value by default
minus infinity to positive infinity okay
if not good
if there is no losing validity we just
return to
right so now look
if this value if root of value
is smaller than mean value right
or the root of value
is bigger than the max value
now what should we do return two of us
current window is mean to
max not
equal right because as we said we don't
have a duplicate value so it's strictly
bigger than mean smaller than uh max so
if this value turned out to be at
somewhere here or somewhere here
then we should return two of us
if it's not in the window we should
return two of us
first perfect
we just have to check the left tree the
left tree has to be the final search
tree and the right way has to be a
spanish tree right in order for the
whole tree to be a binary surgery right
look if this is a one and then this is
the left tree this is the right tree
okay so
we want to check if this expiratory is
the financial stream right so now the
i'm telling this one is within the range
so we have to check if at least this bit
and this bit is a balancer shift and
this bit is a balancer stream right this
is a sub problem because if no problem
so look we have to check f blue dot left
this is the left tree and then the
window the window thing
we go to the left we go to the left the
left boundary does not change so this is
mean that v
what's that right what what should we do
with the maximum
if we go to the left what's the maximum
it's going to be this window
the node here what's the maximum
if we go to the left what's the maximum
of this now
one right
load of value but not equal to right
and okay now we go to we check the right
so if we go to the right what happened
to the mean value
what happened to the remark if we go to
the right what happened
what
what's here
if we go to the right what's the mean
we rule the value yeah
and what's the the right country does
not change yeah if you go to the right
the right boundary does not change okay
so localistic location time connects to
o n whichever every node the space
number is the
yeah because we're using location here
technically i mean more precisely the
space complexity is o h okay h is the
height of the boundary in the worst case
h equals the number of nodes
and we can tell these on a day day 28
we'll just talk about recursion but we
don't talk about how do we turn this
into iterating we can use the iterative
right the point is that when we maintain
the stack ourselves for the recursion we
we ask the computer to maintain a stack
right so the you know recursion calling
itself right let's computer calling
excel this maintains the stack class so
we can maintain the stack ourselves but
for the elements in the state every time
we need to push the route the the
current node and the left that value and
the right value the window right so now
we can validate the values
sec
yeah back at the beginning we put it to
the root and then
at the beginning the window is minimal
infinity to positive infinity
all right this is the type of content
three elements what's trouble what's the
difference between topper and a list
change table
right
this can yeah it's immutable in mutable
content right so for example a equals 1
2 3. i can't say a 0. i want to change
it to
6 i can't do that this is because in
mutable but if i say a equals this this
is the bit 1 2 3. if i say a 0 equals 6
then what happened a will become
6 2 3. okay we change it right this is a
tupper immutable this is the least
mutable okay at the beginning we push
these loose elements okay if not good we
better to check if not return true okay
we push the root the minimum infinity to
positive the window is huge right
infinity at the beginning now we check
wire st then we get the root
the lower the right equals s t dot top
top
and we we check
if
root of value if load of value is
smaller than r or smaller equal our rule
of value
is bigger than equal and island will
determine fourth
and then
return first then
if loads are left if we have a left kit
then we push apparent append
attenua apparently the left
we go to the left we update uh
the boundary the mean the left is the
understand which is the air the right
boundary is blue dot value right
and then the same goes to the root of
right if root and right if we have a
neutral right
we see the append
blue dot right
ruler like the left boundary becomes the
root of value the right boundary stays
unchanged
and if we finish this iterative search
then we return through on the right this
is just the iterated version of the left
which is the recursion this is one way
another way about final search tree so
look what's what's so important about
binary searches what's good thing about
banners why are we organizing the data
in such a way like the left that's more
than the writer figure what advantage
can you get
[Music]
okay so we we are separating the data so
so write this as string so if we want to
look for a value in the binary search
tree then that would give us advantage
by using the binary search right yes yep
it's like if i want to look at this if i
want to look for 1.5 it's bigger than
one
then it's definitely on the right right
it's not on the left
if like that has lots of big data we can
just ignore that right because it's not
there it's bigger than that is it on the
right tree if it's smaller than two it's
on the left tree right
right if this binding surgery is highly
balanced right highly balanced means
that the
maximum difference between the left the
depth of the left tree and the right
tree are no more than one that is highly
balanced highly balanced if the end
nodes
on average the height the height equals
the log log n right so
log in
so if we want to look for a number in a
tree with n numbers then we just need
log n right this is the major
improvement and the linear search right
so
if there are a million numbers
unsorted a minimum number
in the worst case if you're really
really unlucky if you want to find the
number in a million numbers how many
times can you try in the worst case
yeah yeah you try from the first one
second one third one until the end right
it's linear right but we if this number
is sorted
right remember we talked about binary
search yeah the same thing goes here
right final search if the numbers are
sorted
right one to a hundred remember the
guessing game i have a number in my mind
can you guess fifty uh fifty yeah you
guess always in the fifty i say okay the
number you guys is bigger um 75
is bigger than
yeah you go for the lower half okay so
always cut in a half right so this
speeds up so logan okay okay so coming
back to the spanish century in what
order if we travel the final surgery in
what kind of order that gives like all
the list
okay so we perform which order on the
final surgery then give us the order
sequence
in order yeah in order now we get to the
left tree
root and right here
if we perform this another thing then we
can
check if the root value if this value is
the bigger than the previous one right
if it's smaller than the previous value
then it's not true right so okay let's
quickly divide it do you understand this
if we travel the financial tree in in
order and we always remember the last
value
right and the last value should not be
bigger or equal than the current value
right so the previous one previous one
equals at the beginning minus infinity
right
this is the lower bound
define that massage in order root right
if not root
return true this is the same
okay
now look if
do the value if this value is smaller on
or equal than previous
if it's smaller than previous then we
return two of us
this one
zero
two so this is the current blue value
previous value is this one if this value
is smaller or equal than this one what
happened
if this value is smaller or equal than
the previous value so what happened
previous value in order what happened
return two of us if this value is
smaller than the previous value in the
in order so what one fourth depends on
we just have to update previous equals
new daw value and now we just retire we
just keep checking we just keep checking
the right tree so which is that's my
search blue dot right okay
okay
to sum up this ignore the traversal
because we perform another travel
traversal final surgery then we give
another so we when we do this in order
we use a previous to remember the last
value so the
last value in
you know before before this current
value right so if this root of value is
smaller or equal if it's smaller than
the previous one then obviously this is
not uh sorted after the inorder and it
is not a binary session right but at the
same time conducting on time
our space
we can also turn this into the iterative
okay iterative i'm going to quickly
write it iterate it
and
that will be and just think about what
have you learned today for the last
question everyone
st equals
at the beginning empty the previous
equals is minus infinity
where
st or root
wire loot we keep pushing the left
st dot append
blue
blue equals glue the left so the idea of
this iteratively so we keep going to the
left as deep as we want and we push that
we will push the key to the to the stack
right and then now we get it out r
equals sp
then we compare if if root of value is
smaller or equal than the previous one
then we return false
all right otherwise we remember the
previous one equals rule value
and then we go to the right rule equals
rule right right this is the standard
approach of cleaning these
in order from the execution to the uh to
the iterative and and at the end will
return true
okay
okay at the same time complexity and
space can relax what have you learned
today come on the last question about
that
what what's new today so on day 28 we
talk about recursive uh ignorance to
validate the balance sheet
so the first angle we talk about is the
window window thing we go to the left we
narrow the window we go to the right
with narrow window so we just check each
node to see if it falls in the window
this can be done in recursion and
iterated today
what's this what are we doing here
yeah so what do we do
yeah we usually know the traversal to
travel by necessary and then we just
have to validate the finances to
validate the no to see if it's strictly
bigger than the previous note in a
sequence because let's based on the fact
that if we perform you know the
traversal on the binary search three we
get an order sequence right so we have
to check if it's smaller or equal than
the previous noun and it's not a binary
question i know obviously we can do this
in recursion and iterate okay that's it
for today bye bye
bye bye