mister mister right
yeah look at these
numbers n times and magic in mathematics
n times and magic and in python we can
at least array two dimensional ray
metric right so let's look at this three
times three metric
so the rows are three two one one seven
six two seven seven and the columns are
like this our task is to find out the
number of pairs are equal to each other
so for example the
row i and column j if not equal let's
count how many of it so for example look
277 right this is 277 and then 277. so
there's one pair
these pair this pair so we return one
and how about this how many pairs of
these are equal the rows and columns are
equal to each other
um
can you tell
one
three two
which one which one
two four two two and then here we have
two four two two twice right so look
this one and this one one pair these one
and this one two pairs so
anymore yeah three one two two okay two
one two okay so look three one two two
two photo two two four two twice right
two quarter two times without the coding
just tell me how would you saw it i mean
this is a very straightforward how would
you count it uh
[Music]
refreshing is a good way here so through
forcing so we can just go through each
row for example if we go through this
each row three one two two then we count
how many of the columns are equal to it
right if there's one we plus one and now
we go through the second row
and we
go through it right
third row and then we check the columns
and count the columns with the same
numbers that equals to the rows right
okay for blueforce the term complexity
would be
huge why is that because look we have to
go through the each row they are in row
right
there and rows and for each n rows we
want to times up the n columns
right we need to compare if they are
equal right we have to compare equal so
we have two times another end
o and cubic to count each one if we
match each other if it is then we
increment the one right
one better way would be to use the
dictionary counter right we can treat
these as a you know as a thing that we
count how many of these
all right so for example this one three
one one two two
three one two two we use the topper okay
so you want to do that one time right
one four four four
one times and then two four two two
once let's count the columns first okay
and then two five two two one times and
then this is column
and then we have little rows here
rows again three
okay rows uh three one two two
one
one four four five one right and then
two four two two
one two times right but as long as we
can call this we can count this then
what's the answer what's the answer how
do we get three out of these numbers
so first of all three one two two
we times the look this is one and we
find the corresponding key which is one
to two so one one times one plus
one four four four here nothing right
sorry one times zero is zero
two four two two here is two right so
it's one times two
two five two two there's no two five two
two here so it's zero so the answer is
one times ten plus one times two right
three yeah it's three okay so look we
separated counting by the rows and terms
then we sum it up right if this key is
not existing in other one so
it's before by zero you can use the
default dictionary all the counter right
in the counter the keys the keys here
what's this what's this remember we
talked about last thing what's this
what does this mean in person
so look we use the tupper to
represent the rows of columns right and
then we can use the template to as a
keys
to the dictionary
deformationally on the counter because
these couple are immutable we can use it
as a key right we can hash it
we will talk about hashing function but
if it's at least it's mutable uh we
can't do it right so we have to make it
immutable
like
define
f
message
so the rows the rows equals counter we
can use the default dictionary let me go
if we go before dictionary okay before
dictionary
at the beginning integer
default dictionary as opposed
traditionally default dictionary gives
the
default value when the key is not
existent in the dictionary integer the
default value for integer is zero okay
so we can go through this for
are in m
then ah
okay
r
plus equal one okay so these three
things actually can be
converted to
r
equals counter okay we talk about
counter
tapa
r
for
r in
n okay this is the same thing we can
duplicate these to change it to c but
for r in n is this right but we want uh
to get the column right this is the
another important thing here right for r
in m then it gives us the
uh the row one by one right look and how
about if we want to get the columns
any idea
look eric right you mentioned something
look we want to get a
column
the rows here this way the columns yeah
you mentioned a chip from here okay so
why why can't we use the g function
together these
columns look the difference what's cheap
from here what's the chip
chip
one two three
four five six if we tip this what do we
get
what do we get
remember one two three
four five six if we chip it what do we
get
what do we get four three five yeah okay
exactly look one four it's a tuple okay
one four
two five
three six okay
so this is zip if we want to find the
columns
this way so
this is the two dimensional array right
so it's a three two one
one seven six
two seven seven
so it's a two dimensional right and then
if we use this
star
m
star m means that star i want to remove
the external bracket
right and then if i use the jit function
then we get that three one two two seven
seven one six seven so three one two two
seven seven one six seven is exactly
what we are looking for we want to get
the columns right so if we want to
duplicate these we have to change this
for r in
chip
star m then we get the columns and c
copper
c plus e cosine now we can return
written sum
r
x
times c x
for x in r all for x in c doesn't matter
right so the point is that we want to
multiply
the values of the same keys in both rows
and columns the keys has to be in the
rows right in the rows or we can iterate
over the columns it's the same
the time complexity okay let's analyze
the time context
the time connection we go through the
rows which goes through the columns
right this is the most dominant impact
so there are n rows and columns and for
each one we need to
do this hashing function okay let's
assume this is n right this is our one
constant okay
right so the time convex is om plus o n
plus we want to sum it up
right sum it up
sorry about it another one right
if each rows are different and each
columns are different then we need to go
through the instrument so the time
convex one is so much better than the
previous one i went through bit but this
one r probably has to go through each
element to make it copper
so if this is o n and the time template
is o n square i it's still better than
the previous one or in qubit okay the
lower the better i'm right yeah
the lower the better right we want to
look for the
solution which gives the optimum time
and space the computer is very fast but
if you ask him to do the job in the very
you know stupid way it's going to take
time right so the important takeaways
today first of all is the zip function
yeah
g function and if we want to get the
columns
we need to chip start n
g function we will talk about the chip
longest as well if the two
thing look it's one is longer the other
one is shorter the g function the
shorter one according to the shorter
length look seven right
chip
one two three four five six seven
then the result will be one four two
five seven six
if i have cheap longest
then you will have actual element with
which is nine
seven okay
yeah make sense
okay
and the other takeaway is that we use
the tuple as the keys to count the rows
and the columns and we sum them by
multiplying uh together as a sum okay so
what have you done
about this what's the problem
and
trying to count count what the number of
pairs of equal
numbers rows and columns right so we can
do as you mentioned earlier we can proof
us
the time complexity i will incubate but
if we use a counter hatch map right
to count it now we can make it faster
am right
okay
okay that's it for today bye bye
bye
you