[Music]
hello mr mr ryan are you right so we are
given an array of numbers right uh each
move you are allowed to pick a number
and delete all the currents of it right
so for example if we pick a two there
are two twos then we can remove them
so the question is that what's the
minimum number of moves that in order to
reduce this array to half or less 2
how i mean what number you pick
two
two moves right all three moves uh wait
wait i mean like how many numbers five
three
five uh two
three five and two yeah
first of all how many numbers did you
make here
one two three four five six seven eight
nine ten eleven twelve i think
four
eight ten so yeah
we want to reduce the array to half
right to half
so to five numbers or less right
five numbers so you pick three
so if we remove these
there are six numbers left if we pick
five
there are two numbers so it's less than
half of five
ah ah okay okay we'll pick half and then
the remaining is three numbers so we
only need two numbers right
okay so how would you solve this problem
i mean normally if we give it a number
how would you solve it counter yeah we
want the counter so why are we counting
the numbers why do we have to write them
the most popular number where the most
popular so we count the numbers for
example here three how many times
four times
uh two how many times four
five how many times
three seven how many times one okay so
how would you pick the numbers
so which numbers you pick three
uh-huh because these four is the largest
and the next one five five yeah okay
we're picking the numbers in such order
that you know from the popularity we
want to pick the numbers that are most
popular with the highest frequency uh to
the lowest frequency and now we need to
check yeah because when we pick this
number right we know that all the
numbers is ten numbers so we pick three
four numbers
now we pick four numbers it's not enough
right it's not bigger than half right
now we pick three numbers four past
three seven numbers it's more than half
then we return
two numbers right
all right
okay so culture yeah we can use the
comments so
culture is from
this is from collections yeah collection
import counter we know that already
counter is basically a dictionary right
decently we can say b equals this
dictionary then we go through this
number for i in numbers
this is the same thing as d i plus one
right
right all these three convert it to d
equals counter
called uh
numbers
this is just a
shortcut much better way to
make it simpler okay we have this thing
so we want to find out the most common
we want to get this part so we have this
function called
the most common we have this one so what
does it give us you give us
this
a list of uh three is four times the
second popular is five is three times
two is two times and seven is one time
right
right so look
most popular
right three appears four times five
appears three times right this is very
convenient for us right
so
we can use this most common um by
putting the numbers if we put a two then
we will return top most popular
this number the parameters
so if we want to use this command to get
the least comment how would you do it
which part is the least common
this is the most term
so so what do we do with this comment
for example if we do the same thing and
then
the list
no there's no such function called this
comma but we can use most comments to
get the least comment how would you do
it come on it's very nice most common
and
look this is most common so which part
about this woman what youtube cars are
these comments least common multiplier
um
yeah yeah yeah so look this is a list
right so this comment we just have to
get it from the right right for example
this command one is the minus one right
right uh actually minus one right so
even together these two
we can do this
uh minus two to the n and we reverse
this part right or we can use this uh
formula
column minus n minus one
minus one this means that we want to get
the
last and element in the reverse order
right because this is the least common
this is the second this comma right but
the least
most common just give this in the other
sequence we have to reverse this
this most common is very convenient a
equals
we have this d right the thing we need
is just this one and we don't care about
what value am i right it doesn't matter
right this three changes to a million
doesn't matter these five change to
a trillion doesn't matter the most
important thing is the counter how many
times they appear right
x
for
y
x in
d dot items
right and then we can just solve this a
dot solved
eight also what look x is the number of
times y is the key
the value indeed items and we can just
add a store reverse
equals two because we want to pick the
most frequent one
okay
and once we have this a okay so let's
put this in the a equal left for example
answer equal at the beginning we pick
nothing so for
i in
a okay let's assume this a is the most
common is this bit right so about a
equals
we want the least number right so it's y
for
x y in
b
most common right and then a will be
something like this for a then we add it
right the number we pick this is the
four three two one right in this case
the a will be four three two one it's at
least four three two one
and then
we want to have a counter t equals zero
the total numbers we have picked t plus
equals i
and answer we have picked one number and
if t
plus t bigger than equal and the length
of all the numbers
right and then we just return answer
okay make sense look yeah
a is four three two one four three two
one so we pick four numbers we check
we pick one one time we pick four
numbers we check if it's more than half
this is not more than half we keep
picking pixel in number now we have pick
seven numbers
so seven is more than half right seven
plus seven is bigger than ten
then we determine answer in this case
would be two all right the time come
actually it's a bit tricky
very close
[Music]
most common
soft
[Music]
obviously we're using the addition rate
so that's one
we're using the dictionary oh and
if the numbers are within the range
right if the numbers for example is uh
bigger than one and smaller than a
hundred it's a lesser range then we can
also use the pakistan we talk about the
back is talking yeah we have a hundred
buckets right then we can count how many
times they appear right for example
three then we increment three bucket one
so in this case the numbers we have in
way are we in the range well now we can
you should package something and the
time complexity can be improved
okay so what have you learned today come
on what have you learned today that's it
about
what have you learned come on what's the
problem and what have you learned eric
so how do we reduce it i mean we use a
counter and then we have these numbers
yeah we have the numbers at each time we
can pick a
number and
remove one
of it
this number all of these occurrences
right
and then and then what do we need to do
counter
what do we
what are we achieving yeah
reducing the number of
number of numbers by half
so
we want to find out the minimum right
yeah minimum so how would you do this to
achieve the minimum
yeah this is the approach but how would
you do it strategically i mean how
what's a what's your approach
what's your approach dictionary why do
so which numbers would you pick
the biggest so so what are three and
fives the biggest
the what pick is this is the number this
is the number terminal
number
we want to pick the numbers we use the
highest frequency so every time we pick
the number with the highest frequency i
will remove it from the array and then
we pick the second highest frequency and
then we remove it right yeah the time
the next is our login because there's a
sorting here the most common and thought
right let's all know that space
complexity is oh and because we are
using a dictionary okay that's it for
today bye-bye
bye