hello mystery mr lauren are you right
yeah
okay so
i put a zero here so another stop array
right sub array continues some array as
to subsequent
subsequence is not continuous separate
like one two three
if this is a ray sub array one two three
one two two three one two three continue
subsequence does not have to be
continuous one one three two right so
sub sequence
and sub array what's the relation
between subsequent and separate
is sub array or subsequence or is
subsequently separate sub array is
continuous right subsequence doesn't
have to be continuous so it's sub array
a subsequence
suffering
yes but it's subsequence of suffering
no that's right so subarray is a
subsequent so subsequent outside right
the coincidence yeah someone right here
right somewhere
so okay so zero i have an array contains
only zero you want to find out the
number total number of sub arrays
containing the zeros only for example
like how many sub arrays containing
zero in this case one one exactly
how many sub arrays containing zeros
how many
sub arrays are there not empty you know
empty is also a subreddit but we're
excluding empty here so how many sub
arrays here three three okay yeah so
here is one here three okay keep going
if i put one more how many sub arrays
six six
okay i put one more
ten
okay so what's the new thing what
happened
so what's on the next
15 okay what's the next
228 one okay so look if n equal if any
so how do you get this if i want to
generalize this so when n equals 10
what's the
answer how do we get it adding one more
becomes 15. how do we get 15
so if we know dn
what we have now is 10
right look
we n equals four we have ten if i have
one more n equals five
why is it fifteen why is the fifteen
come on when n is four i have ten when i
add one more zero what happened
how many more can we get how do we know
is fifteen here
this is 50 right we need to add five so
what happens why is this 5 coming from
if i add a 0 here why is it 5 extra
look i have a 0 here
if i had one zero how many extra
how many episodes right how many extra
why is it two
which two are actual
which two are actually i put a zero here
so which two are actual quantum count is
three
[Music]
yeah okay okay so what we have got is
the new one right we add one more zero
in new one and
the one the previous one right the
previous only one connects to it so
that's another one how about this
another two so if i add one more you
know how many
the original two we know is three yeah
and then here we have three more becomes
six
[Music]
right yeah what are the other two
the one of the beginnings
yeah okay so you see you get the excel
here and here right
yeah and then here right
okay
the same thing go here i put another
zero here
so what do we have
one
two
three
four
five
correct so if i add one i have n more so
this is the same thing as one plus two
plus three plus four plus and and at
least we know this
what's this
you notice
one plus two plus three plus four plus
two hundred what's the answer
what's the answer plus n equals two
hundred what's the answer
[Music]
value so this is the sum of
i equals 1
to n
and i right so here n equals 10 so this
would be n times m plus 1 divided by 2
yeah we talked about that in the early
days how do we get this so when n equals
4 4 times five divided by two
equals ten when equals five
what do we get five times five plus one
divided by two that's fifteen right
we are given an array of integers
so we want to find out how many
subarray containing zeros the previous
one we only have a array with containing
all zeros now we have an array with
numbers not necessary to be zeros so we
want to find out the
number of us sub array that containing
zeros how do we do it
how many sub arrays containing zeros in
this case
so what's the approach i mean look i
have an array
containing numbers not necessary to be
zero so we want to find out how many
arrays several were containing only
zeros
so how do we solve this problem
could you buy
where down grow by
how do we count so first of all we call
this right two we know how to count it
previously
we can learn how to count it we have how
to count we just add it together right
okay so how many sub arrays and then
zero two three yeah we know only three
how many here one how many one yeah
three plus one plus one right yeah we
use the group back this is array right
we talked about this little tours
from italy's import go back so what do
we have if we have ether to us this is
the package stock grew by
we talked about that through by
ar so this is an iterator if we say
for
a b
in group i so what what is a it will
give us a
a would be
a will be what a will be when a will be
one
then
this is the iterator right then the b
will be the integrator of the
actual continuous value so you'll be one
and then zero you'll be two zero
and then one will be one
okay and then zero will be one zero two
will be zero
and then zero will be zero so basically
if we run this it's a true or group five
the a will be the unique values the b
will be pointing to each group so
look if we have two zeros here so zero
and then you'll be two zeros another
example two two
two three
three two
okay so what do we have is a would be
two pointing to three twos
but this is a iterator okay three
would be
two three
and two would be one two okay
so if we go through this b the length of
the b right if we learn the length of b
which is n then we can count how many
a sub array containing the
zero so it's n plus n times one divided
by two right we can verify the value
when n is one one times
2 divided by 2 is 1 right 1 n is 2 2
times
3 divided by 2
2 times 3 divided by 2 equals 3 right
that's one way we use the group right
well the code is pretty simple okay so
let's just
read the code
out without writing it okay so
answer equals zero
for a b iterate to stop going by array
if okay we have to check if a is zero
right if a is not zero we don't count if
a is zero
then n equals length this b
and then answer plus equal n times n
plus one divided by two and that'll be
right another way would be originally
array and we use the counter zero
representing the number of zero we have
met if it's uh if it's not yellow we set
it to zero right if it's zero we plus
equal one
if i have a zero here i have m one more
zero then this zero contributes this
number of uh sub array right so look if
i have uh
three zero now right z equals three
i have one more zero so
the
total contribution of this zero is
plus
what three or four z will be
the number of zero before
and then the total number of
contribution will be
plus equal z right so define okay count
zero
array
answer equals
zero at the beginning
equal 0.
for
this is the the number of continuous
zero we have messed over for i in array
if i equal equals zero
right we have one more zero then c plus
equal one
answer plus equals z
errors will be set to
z to zero and written answer wow that's
so simple right
the time to maxi anybody the time
conductor we're going through that right
away exactly let's take honestly
a one yes so this is one way okay look
z
see here if we make one zero if we were
1 0 this is the
number of zeros we have met so far
continuous right if it's not zero we
reset it to zero right
and the answer plus equals zero
look zero we have one zero right c
equals zero so z equals one
right the answer will be the answer will
be one right
okay i have one more zero now
i have one more zero so
zero equals two
answer plus equals two
three okay now i have uh
i have one so what happened here this is
not zero so we set this to
zero right it's not zero okay another
zero what happened i increment this
look i increment this to one
and the answer plus equal one okay
okay your turn if i have one more zero
what happened
if this is one more zero what happened
to here this is the number of zero we
have made right so we need to plus equal
one right so two plus equals two okay so
if i have one more zero what happened
what happened
what should we do with these two
change it to 3 to 23. i know what should
we happen to hear
plus one plus b plus three okay okay
okay and i have one here what happened
what should we do now and we set it to
zero
okay okay zero what happened
comes another zero whatever
one and plus one
another zero one
three two plus two right
analogy one
three three plus three okay
and then i have one here whatever
reset it we set it to zero okay this is
simple right we just set it this zero
means that the number of zeros
continuous zero we have now including
the column
why we need to plus the z
as we said
zero
we have one and if i press one more zero
we need to plus two right if we have one
more zero
we have plus three right if we have one
plus one right y plus one
here one
two
three four
okay accumulate this is one way the
previous one
ether to group i
right when we use that function then we
can count how many
zeros in one group
if it's n n equals
list
b okay
for a b in italian go by
array
right and then answer plus equal n times
times n plus one divided by two okay
we use the mathematic formula
right
answer equals zero
and return answer
okay two ways easy
which way you prefer
okay last question which which way you
prefer which way
you think it's more easy to understand
that one
this one
using my eater tooth okay
one one last question what's the problem
what have you learned you know i'm going
to ask this question anyway okay so
anybody ryan you want to give it a go
learn about
yeah
how to
so what's the problem
and what are we doing is a list a list
of numbers numbers and then we want to
count how many
how many sub arrays that containing zero
right
right so at the beginning i show you how
to count
the number of zeros if it's an array
with only zeros right and then we just
have to
count each group of zeros separate and
add them together am right
yeah
okay
you want to give it a go
what's the problem and why have we
learned so far what's the approach
[Music]
a list of numbers we're done okay
would you okay even if it's a array
containing all zeros and the length is n
how many sub arrays
yeah the formula is less right what we
have to do is
count zeroes in each subroute with only
zeros and add it up together right the
time to next though and stay converts to
be a one okay and that's it for today
bye-bye
you