hello mr missouri right yeah okay
2 to the power of 0 what's the 1
2 to the power 1 2
2 to the power 2 4
2 to the power of 10
20.
[Music]
come on you need to remember this number
because that's very special in in
computer science is it
256 no
256 512
and what's next
yeah this number is very important 1024
because in computer science it's binary
and 2 to the power of 10 yeah 10 24. if
you talk about 1024 people know okay
you're a programmer you're a software
engineer right because it's uh it has
this special meaning for programmers and
you know in computer science
yes i think i don't think people think
they'll program it because like
oh um
why why
yeah because because i have a hair
another one is like if you say oh i have
1024 half
yeah
[Music]
okay okay a to the power of b we know
yeah is that a times a times a
how many a's b b times a yeah
a to the power of zero equals one where
a is not equal to zero zero to the power
of zero mathematically no different not
valid okay that's a very special case
good question so one zero what's this
zero to the power of
a
where
where a is not equal to zero equals zero
right zero times zero times zero times
zero a million zero times to get a
square here am i
okay
what space i know
mass
m a
t h s okay yeah
okay okay so today's question very
simple
given a number like uh two four
ones you know
can you rearrange these digits to make
it a power of uh two two out of yeah
yeah okay how about
two zero five six can we rearrange the
numbers too yes yes it's already in it
no no one yes yes why what zero two five
okay but we don't want to be in zero
because matching is
there's no leading zero in front of
other teaching people
okay
so another example 46
can we
uh yeah six people okay
yellow
um
no no no one
[Music]
okay so
you get this question yeah so we want to
rearrange the numbers to find out if it
can be a power to power 2
and when rearranging the numbers we
don't want the leading zeros okay so how
do we do it all right how do we do it
come on let's see
yeah yeah i'm not erasing that okay come
on okay how do we do this
numbers
close
close up
[Laughter]
[Music]
so i mean what's your source how do we
solve this problem if we're given an
integer positive okay positive integer
positive integer how do we know if it
can be a power of two if we are
arranging a digit
[Music]
is a good start what's how do we perform
we check every possibility
46 how do we know if it's a it's a hot
pot
yeah
i mean what's this 46 and 64. what are
those two if we launch this
the same
what's what do we call it
what's this one two three
one three two two one three two three
one three one two one four two one okay
what's this permutation permutations yes
permutations we talk about the
permutation you say
one one one given a n
element
yeah if a string has n elements or an
array have an enemy what's the number of
uh
permutations the full permutation what's
the computation what's this look there
are three numbers here how many
permutations of these
six if we have four numbers so what's
the number of total communication
if there are four numbers three twenty
four yes
another five five
twenty four times five equals one
hundred twenty yeah so what's this
what's this smart
24 120
120 720 what do we call these numbers
triangle numbers no
one times two two one times numbers six
what's this number time no no no what's
this what's this factorial factorial yes
factory
how do we come up with this factorial
how do we know it's a factory number
here
the first element we have n choice the
second element we have m is one choice
the third element we have at minus two
and the last animal we have one choice
so let's n factorial
yeah okay
here's a real spider
okay
it's green yes so it just
it has hair dye
one two three four five six seven eight
okay
come on can we just uh continue the
lessons please come on man
please
okay let's see
can i have your pen please
okay this is not actually not a plan
this is called
markers
it's like marcus okay
the full communication we know is
antarctica
yeah
permutation like what's the difference
between permutation and
coordination
yeah combination
combination is
okay so permutation yeah one two three
we know there are six yeah one two three
one three two two one three two three
one three one two three two one
combination
one two three
kicking two
one two one three
two three
one two is the same as two one one three
is the seventh three one three two
is the same as two three
now that two three two three okay
so you see the difference
this one permutation
the sequence matter the combination the
sequence do not matter three uppers
picking two
how many ways three three ways
one two one three picking one
two is the same as speaking to one
the combinations
[Music]
and we use the p and c right p and c
picking two apples out of three is the
same as picking one apples out of three
i'm right look
if you pick one two you have three if if
you pick one three you have two if you
peel one two three you have one right
it's the same
so
we can generalize this speaking m out of
n is the same thing as picking n minus m
out of n all right
c
p permutation
permutation is a sequence so if we pick
the items using the combination we have
to do this full permutation of these two
items all right so look if we pick these
two items and then we do this uh
permutation
full permutation of these two items then
we can get this permutation right so
picking m i 10 out of n is the same as
first of all we pick m items out of n
and then we do this for permutation of
this right and then we know p
a a is the same as a factorial right
yeah there are three efforts how many
ways to rearrange that
six ways
five apples how many ways to rearrange
them different orders
quick mess come on five five factorial
100 a million
twenty spaghetti
t
n m
on the number of ways the antaction
divided by n minus n factorial and then
c n m is
n factorial divided by n minus m
factorial and divided by m factorial
because we have to divide the m
saturated for communication for each
group
and on day one on one we talk about
recursive arguments to generate the full
permutation okay so the idea is that
look one two three four and here and
there an item we want to do is a
recursive communication agreement how to
do it so first of all look
for first one we we can replace it with
other right
these could be
in the first place and also the one
could be in the first place for example
if three can be in the first place then
we swap it so we stop it it becomes
three
and one and then we can do this full
permutation on the smaller size problem
and then after that we can swap it back
okay
the time conduction for that is because
there are n items
for pigmentation and factor define
per mutation term
hey
this is the index
index
to the end and we have current numbers
so if we are reaching the end
if we reaching we end and we have a
solution we have solution when we can
yeah
yeah what's here promise i give you that
when we have it i'll give you that yes
yes num
okay or for i in range
we start with k to the end length nums
now we need to swap yes look num
i and nums
okay equals num
okay num right we need to hear from
right yeah from this is a very magic
keyword recursive year from
yeah from
term
okay here from k plus one
and then we need to do this again to
swap it back
so look this is the how we implement the
permutation
and we also talked about combination and
some some other days
but in python we don't need to reinvent
the wheel okay instead we use this
package from
eater tour
we use lots of function from this
package
import
permutation
per
mu
tations
and all combination right combination
and that's it then we can use this
permutation how do we use the
permutation
permutation is the iterator so if a
equals one two three right and if we say
permutations
a then you will return an iterator one
two three one three two so your iterator
okay iterator of one two three
one three two
etc okay
for p in permutations a then
p will become the topper of one two
three one three two those kind of thing
so it's very convenient for us
combination for example like for x in
combination a
comma two so we're picking two out items
out of a then you return one two one
three two three okay so coming back to
this question all we have to do is to do
this permutation on the digit right
yeah we do this communication with
bitches and i'll find out if it's a
power of two all right so look we can
just do this for
a
in
permutation from italy's import
permutation from permutation
permutations
and str the number is n right
so now a
yeah we're converting the integer to
string and we do the permutation
this is to permutate to do the
permutation of the digit right if n is
is one two three okay and then a would
be one three two one two three thousand
thing and that's six right
a then we want to check if a is the
power of two how do we check if a number
is a power of two
[Music]
how do we check how do we know that 64
is the power too
how do we know 120 a is power how do we
do because
we
divided by 2
and divided by
divided by 2 divided by 2 divided by 2
and here it can't be divided by 2 right
or it's 1 right if it's 1 then we know
it's power 2 let's one another way we go
on the calculator and times two we talk
to until we get that number
and if it's
if they skip it
the number is not
that's that's good yeah so this real
reverse way you're talking about
dividing right 64 divided by 2 32 16 a 4
2 1. okay once you've got one it's a
total of two right another example
is 6 power 2
6 divided by two three three cannot be
divided two and it's not one so it's not
divided by two right and you're talking
about the other way one
two
four
eight sixteen thirty two sixty four okay
we got this okay how about 65 is it uh
no okay 64 times 2 128 is bigger than 65
so no right that's one way but if it's a
power of two then we can do something
special because finally one in binary
zero one is
one right this is the decimal this one
and binary this is one
how about two
two is one zero
four
one zero zero eight one zero zero zero
sixteen
one zero zero zero zero thirty two
one zero zero zero zero zero you see in
binary we only have one and zero and if
the power of two is one followed by some
zeros i'm right
so we just have to check if it's this
format right yes yeah so look if it is
minus 1 what happened look if it is
minus 1
if it's power 2 minus 1
1 1 1 1 1 if it is minus one one one one
one if it is minus one one one one
one one one
zero
definitely
well ten minus one does not equal one
no this is binary
binary okay in mathematics binary if we
want to check an integer if it's a power
of 2 we can use if this is n we can do
this n bigger than
uh if it's n bigger than zero
also and
n and
n minus one
yeah it needs to be zero right because
in finally one zero zero zero we
subtract one now becomes zero one one
one if we do the n
cl and one zero zero and one zero zero
and one zero one and zero zero
right so we can do this
another way
yeah we can do the log function right we
lock the function if we look to master
log two n
and if this is a whole number right yeah
log 2
64.
what's this 2 to the power of something
equals 64. how many times or two
look at 6 7
4.
64. so how many
six
six yeah so this has to be a whole
number right yeah so we just have to
check if this is the whole number how do
we check the number is the whole number
so we can do this n dot is integer wow
so simple yeah we can just use this
method
right or if we can do this convert it to
integer
log to n right and then we times it back
so 2 to the power of these means equal
to n right
2 to the power of 6 is 64. so this
number could be a whole number or could
be some fraction number flow number like
3.5 right
if
2 to the power 3.5 decimal you could
have decimals then we can double check
we can check it back
but the most efficient way is this this
method
right yeah because it's just using the
bit this is finally it only works for
binary uh if we want to check the number
is the power of two okay so we can
iterate this number
the digit we just check if this a
we need to check if this a
not b zero right we don't want a leading
zero right
and also we can use the method bin if we
convert it b list a but a is a iterator
a topper we need to join it okay x
equals
dot john what's john eric john a let's
join
split we're done opposite sleep okay so
look one two three don't split
uh one two
two
three if we just split
spray comma that would give us a one
two
three right
yeah
and then the opposite way we just do
this uh comma dot join
john putting things together as a string
as it's a string then we need to check
if x yellow
not equals zero
right and
and
we just need to check if x is a power of
two then we can uh first of all we can
do this y equals
uh integer of x and
and y
and
y minus one equal to zero right we can
use this of
y is integer
or
into y log 2 y
uh actually no that's actually it's this
one dot is integer
or
or we can convert these and two to the
power of left equals y okay
another way would be to use the pin
function being
15 and that will give us a string zero b
one one one one you'll convert integer
to a binary and then we just have the
call list if it only has one one right
bin
x
one
needs to be one right
in binary you can only have one one all
right yeah
so the time complexity for this one a
little bit tricky okay computation if
the integers n how many bits is log two
bits
like two bits
and then we do this four communication
is bacteria
and for each one we need to check if
it's a it's a power of two and that
needs to come not to n okay
if this n is uh with a range bigger than
zero is smaller than
10 to the power of nine one followed by
nine zero is smaller than two to the
power of 32 right yeah we can use the
counter for
i
in range
32 okay
c equals counter we're going to count
one str
one
shifter shift i
uh 31 actually so this is actually we
are checking 2 to the power 1 2 to the
power of 2 2 to the power 0
2 to the power 3 etc and then we get
this number here
which is 1 2 4 8
16 32 and then we convert it to a string
right convert it to a string
and then we counter we counter we make
it count that we cut the digit
now we just have to compare if this is
digit
if c equal equal counter
counter lambda n right str and
then return true
otherwise return first
okay but this one we can move it outside
okay for example 46 right one digit four
ones six ones now if we iterate chicken
bees eat away chicken b 64 and then we
find out okay
the digit we are using for 64 is the
same as the digit we are using as 46.
then we have a match right
we can use the any keyword right because
we are trying to find a match so return
any
any what counter str1
[Music]
yeah
equal equal
these
four i in range 31
the time complexity this 31 is a
constant and then this is a constant so
we are actually requiring these
and these so this is log two
there are not two n digits
right
the time the maxi as i said
we are iterating 31 this is a constant
and
we just need to check lock to end digit
and then space complexity the counter
right
so this is more efficient because we
know that n is within a range so then we
can do this 31 here
okay so to sum up what have you learned
what's the problem what have you learned
and that's it
the problem is we have numbers
one by one i'll take you first and then
next time you first so we have numbers
and we want to reorder them to make them
a
power
too
yeah we have a positive integer we want
to find out if we can make it a power of
two by rearranging the numbers
okay okay so what's your solution how do
we do it
we
communication for permutation that's the
first one the second way is to do it the
other way as long as we know that n is
within range and we have a limited
possibility we just check from the
opposite side the counting and we use a
counter
what's the problem and
there is
a
integer that's an integer and a positive
integer and we want to find
if
it
is not
if the numbers can be permanent power to
buy
by what
rearranging the digits right and how do
we solve this problem
perforce by permutation of the digit
right and this is the second way is to
go from the other side yeah we just
because n is within a range
so
we can calculate the power of two within
that range and we check
if the digit can be used yeah so this is
for using the counter okay
okay that's it for today bye-bye