hello exactly
all right yeah so today we want to talk
about this what is the database
any idea database where you store data
where we started where you saw data base
what space i mean it's a place where we
started okay that could be it okay so
database uh
yeah it's related to computer obviously
research pokemon database
excellent yeah you search online yeah
you use the browser to search the
procurement database so database is the
place where we organize data yesterday
okay so it's a place we organize
something
okay database
okay so for example pokemon how many
pokemons are there about 905
are you sure yeah they're guessing more
905 and it's getting more there's more
they're getting pokemon scarlet and
violet
and it'll be released on
on i think it's the 8th of no 18th of
november i think okay anyway
905. which pokemon is the strongest i
mean like speed
yes are they fair okay
okay and what's the second strongest um
alternet charisma
anyway okay you already know that and
how about the third one
um
you don't know yeah it's hard right okay
and how about that if you want to find
out the top ten
strongest sorted by speed right for
example like speed right
well that's easy you're already lucky
so what's that ninja
says
electrode aerodactyl yeah aerodynamic
pterodactyl okay so yeah given this
scenario what i meant is that uh suppose
they have 905 so the computer needs to
know to store these data somewhere right
so that's the database we can install a
pokemon like image files and everywhere
right here layer but it's not easy to
find to search
right for example if i want to know the
top 10 pokemons
i mean not like
by most people okay for example like
this question
then
it's hard to to get those information
and then to do a query on that but
database is the place that we organize
these data into you know at least
905 pokemons for example like uh you
have you could have pokemon name
you know you could have a speed you have
a attack attack defense
you have different columns yeah
that's right yeah different so it's it's
basically we it's a table we can store
those
improvements in this organized data of
organized format obviously if they are
more coming then we can edit append it
at the end of table so it's like the
central centralized place okay but it
doesn't have to be centralized it could
be decentralized if i store the pokemon
let's start with a to z or a to m
the first one
is somewhere here and then m to z
somewhere here so basically we slipped
the data c and z
into half into two places that is the
snowman okay so these two places
okay okay what did i say so the pokemons
could be we could partition the
datas
into two so the
pokemon let's start with a to z
a to n the first half of alphabet we
store it in london for example and then
mgz we could store it in
cambridge for example okay so database
is a place to sum up it's a place we
store the data in an organized way we
can retrieve the data right from the
database or we can store the data
in the database we so retrieved to to
get store we could update right we could
append a new document or we can change
for example that these arcs we could
change the speed
to 100 a million right so that's a
that's a
little bit yeah
there are only 905 people completed
there's there's some more but they are
not completed i see
speed can be like a million billion
because
it depends on how many candies and how
you train it okay yeah okay okay yeah
yeah yeah sure
okay so they have a few keywords what
they tell me
uh database i give a few keywords which
is what first of all is the
organized yeah it has to be organized
station organized data and we can store
retrieve
over the manage right manage manages uh
something like uh you know we could
duplicate the data we could install them
as a store copies of that yeah we could
add a user like who can access the data
or we can have this different privilege
and assign the previous to people right
for example eric you can manage the
database
and ryan you can also manage your
database but mommy cannot manage the
database because she's not interested so
we don't have to give her the permission
to access the data yeah right it could
be you know some data storing database
could be confidential yeah you know
what's the confidence
cookies
no confidential you know what
secret hierarchical data cannot be
anymore yeah yeah i know confidential i
think confidence at least it's the word
to say okay data is secret
we
some people cannot access it the
permission for example mummy doesn't
have permission to access the data in
the database okay
uh this is manage store retrieve guest
store as i said we could insert a new
pokemon at the end of the database yeah
or we could update we could be big so
last few operations see that means to
retrieve
update we want to increase the speed of
all pokemon by 10 right this could be
one example
delete we want to delete a pokemon oh we
want to insert a program we never delete
the pokemon
i don't know maybe maybe a pokemon i
mean it's been deprecated it's gone
we found out that it's not very
interesting anymore like pokemon game
yeah pokemon go yeah yeah like pokemon
go often me too is not in the game now
yeah and also
yeah the database is for computers yeah
to store the data electronically yeah
electronically
you know training okay so previously we
have different kind of storage right now
nowadays the computers look how do the
computers remember the stuff like when
you power on
yeah you can still remember the stuff in
the middle yeah when you save a fire
right it remembers how by storage right
then previously on the you know these
look at this look at this this is floppy
properties yeah
floating ticks you know this take a look
this is one point four four four five
picks
yeah
it's not it's not very widely used
what's this
don't break it don't break it no no no
look so it's basically like uh we have a
this is supposed to open
yeah
i don't oh i don't have it here but
somehow
so so you see you just plug it in insert
it and the computer can read it it's a
magnet inside so don't touch it that bit
okay the computers have released the
back ahead to read from this it's very
slow like this yeah yeah it's very slow
yes
if you have a magnet right then you
could destroy this probably okay so
don't stay uh
stay away from magnets okay and this is
very sad thing this is uh very slow i
mean the computer really very so this is
the old technology i mean when i was
your age right when i was your age like
20 years ago we used this to store the
data and then it's very limited it only
has that
you know 1.44 megabytes so it's very
very small capacity capacity very small
and this one a ram
right look look at this the ram
the ram
where is it
when another ram
run them
random access memory so it's plugged
into the computer right so when it's
power on what's the black thing don't
touch it it's a magnet you know inside
it's a hard drive in a hard drive it has
this uh
disc
unless this are made of magnet
anyway what is this thing
it's a floppy disk
it's a old technology to store the data
okay so what random access memory when
we put this into computer when on power
on we can store the data but only power
off
the data on it it's gone right so this
is short-term memory for computer
instructor memory this is long-term
memory
right nowadays we have this hard drive
all right yeah that's right
um okay i show you okay maybe i have one
okay i have one i'll show you
just give me a second i have one
[Music]
oh i i have even more to show look this
is the
dvd yeah this is also
uh
storage okay that's this this is storage
for the dvd to install the data and then
this is hard drive look hard drive
all right so inside it it has a lots of
these disks inside when you plug into
the computer the computer just spin and
run and run and read it has this head to
read it very quick
okay read and store the data okay this
is our storage this is long-term
memory for computers okay so we install
the data in the database to persistent
we say it's the persistent data you have
to store them in computer okay okay so
let's see for today what have you
learned today database database so
what's database
it's where you hold data we will hold
data but
more
precisely you know we can hold data here
and there in different storage but
database is that we store the data in an
organized way okay why don't i use it
i don't know we store the data in an
organized way so we can
store retrieve manage the data easily
more conveniently am right yeah
okay
what have you learned ryan has answers
everything uh what have you done
we can store the data here but what's
database
[Music]
yeah yeah it's a place you see so we
store the data in an organized way so we
can retrieve it store it and manage the
data
electronically okay yes
sorry how do you put this put it in the
computer look at that's a big pc box
okay
okay maybe i'll show you later okay
that's it for today bye bye
bye