hello mr mr ryan all right yeah okay so
you have given me this yeah a piece of
paper with six pokemons on it and you
write lots of the basic stats
yeah so
then i translate this to here right so
what's the advantage comparing to these
and then
what's their language
that one's more easier to understand
this is more easy
on there is
yes that's a good point yeah because
look for each one you have to
write the attributes right separate
right
the most important thing is that these
data are here and there it's not
organized this is organized we talk
about database last lesson right so
these are organized so
i put all the data in the table
in the table
okay yeah obviously we can extend the
columns these are the columns these are
the rows rows for each row
is a pokemon each column is an attribute
hit point attack defense spatial attack
special defense
speed
gender okay generally the data you give
me is a percentage so i 0.5 is 50
percent
one is 100 okay
and then also there's one is in it
yeah also there's a two term right i
didn't put total here because i think
it's uh the total value can be computed
here right for example like this one the
total is 720 this one
the last last one 720 is basically the
sum of these these
liquids right so there's no need to put
a
total here because if i change this
value i have to change the total right
so this total value can be derived from
those six columns so if i put a total
here let's call the redundancy data
redundancy
we asked computers to store the data in
such format in the organized way this is
also called relation database are the
relation database
are the um
as relation database management system
relational relational yeah so we can
have different tables for storing
different kinds of data
okay so look by this so can you tell me
which one has the most
fastest speed which character
so what are you looking at so which
column speed
is online so this one 110. if i only
give you this can you tell me which one
is the slowest speed
it's not easy to see right but here i
can only look at this color the slowly
this one
yeah
you see it but around here right this is
organized so if we ask computer to do
this we have this sql
structure query language structured
query
language
so if i ask computer
tell me the name okay specific the name
of the pokemon who has the strongest uh
speed uh the fatigue speed oh yes okay
so the computer could first of
okay okay so maybe i have raised my
question can you ask the computer to
solve the taper by
solid pokemon by the speed then we can
ask computer to do this select
okay see that see that we can see that's
something right oh here's another column
it's another name okay let's say it's
another name
comma
and speed
wrong
okay
this table okay let's say this type of
name is pokemon
pokemon okay pokemon
from somewhere from this table this is
called pokemon
okay
and then if i do this right the the
computer will just return
the name
and the sp you give us these two columns
right
and then i can say order
order by
sp
right all the biases then you would
rearrange the rows in such a way okay
the first one is 120 the second row is
80 75 60 50. okay all the by 54 is
ascending okay so we have to
specifically descending d esc okay and
we also we can say asc asc is ascending
desc descending
look this is one sql
slab so basically it has this format
select something from something
where
where something okay i haven't talked
about the way okay
so i write another sql and then you tell
me why it returns okay
select
name
from
pokemon
where
where uh sd
equal equal 105.
so what what does it return
okay yes because look slab name i
supposed to ask for the name lenfield
from pokemon yeah where st equals 105.
like you're telling me this
this is the condition i'm going to write
something more complex okay i'm going to
write
where where's here
we have here select the name from
pokemon where
where d is
is smaller and equal than 100 right
and
a
is bigger than 80.
okay so what does it give us
it gives us
black choice
okay so look this one is okay yeah and
then this one
d is more than 95
100 yes 95 smaller a is bigger than 155
okay
and any other ones
metaphrase
or 125 name otherwise has defense it
can't be more than
it should be less than equal than a
hundred right
okay
so it returns two names right two names
you can written
see that's something you can select name
hp whatever by by doing this yeah or you
can if you want to return all columns we
can give it uh
these
what do you call it wire char okay
wire chair so it means that everything
select everything from pokemon or
retainer table this where statement the
computer needs to check row by row and
if the pokemon has like a minion program
like it's going to take time right yeah
because that's linear search
and we talk about that and
we can
add the index index to it
indexes
right so what's the index remember we
talked about binary search tree
the binary search tree used to speed up
the search if it's bigger than 100 it's
on the right if it's smaller than 100
it's on the left the same thing here we
can add the index up to a particular
color
then you know different kinds of index
for example one simple way would be okay
if the attack from 0 to 50 it's
somewhere here if it's 50 to
51 to 100 stories somewhere here so if i
say okay well uh attack
where attack is 35
then the computer will just
look through the records in this this
bit right and not this big right
so we use the index to speed up the
search otherwise if now table does not
have index then computer can only do the
search in a very stupid way do it one by
one right and if it's a minion there's
the minion pokemon it's going to be very
very slow right because it has to check
a million pokemons to find out the
criteria the pokemon which matches your
criteria am i right
select something we can apply some
functions to it as well for example we
can say select
max
we want to select max attack from the
pokemon
then you'll tell us is 135 right
max mean
average right most kind of function this
is called aggregate function or sum
it's less sum right select sum hp then
you will tell us is that these numbers
ethically again
right that's that one basic
format of sql select very important slab
remember we talked about database to
retrieve the data
we put the data here
we can use the sql to retrieve the data
to quickly structure query language to
create a database right
select something from something
wear something ordered by something okay
wear something otherwise we talk about
all the way
yeah
makes sense it's easy easier it's easy
to understand all right
okay okay i'm going to give a quiz okay
we also find out the name and the hp of
the pokemon where it's attack speed
attack value is bigger than the
difference how can we write the sql
you don't need to look for it just write
the sql
select
from
pokemon this is a table name
and
where
attack is bigger than defense so a is
bigger than d
that's it and then the computer will run
through the vehicles and find out
the name and hp which the attack is
bigger than
defense so this one
this one
this one yeah yeah that's it from the
record we can order by we can ask it to
order by
name alphabetically or ordered by the a
or d right ordered by a or d or whatever
right this is all the fields so you can
give a give a multiple column ordered by
these if there's an equal value then we
order by the second value
right
so this is how we query the table for
like these these kind of things right
yeah you search the browser for the
pokemon right
wait that's behind the scene basically
something like that right
this is one way rtms one way of solving
the data but we have other ways of
storing data but this is rdms the other
way you would be you know something like
that right stories
here layer right
it's not relational right
think this question will talk about the
next lesson if we want to store the
fight yeah different pokemons fight each
other right yeah
the result would be win lose draw right
all right
so how would you do it how do we store
in this table or is it better to do
something else if you do something else
that's right because yeah perfect
yes
yeah what's type of
very effective um
four times
affected for weaknesses
because some pokemon has venuses and
and scrubs okay dragonite and sleepy
both are dragon types and dragon is
super effective and dragon and dragon is
weakness against dragon and also that is
the same for ghosts
okay maybe i didn't explain the question
clearly what that means
we want to store the date the fight the
outcome of a fight between pokemons so
it's better we don't
mess up with this table because this
table it just restores the basic steps
right we can extend active columns right
but we can store another table called
called fights yeah we can have another
table called poison types are no
effective metagrams and for the type we
can have this pokemon a pokemon p
and a result
you see what i mean
okay
well it's not very effective against
dragonite
both means poison toxin
[Music]
my point is that we can store the data
in different tables we can store the
data in different tables so one table to
store the
basic style for pokemon one table store
the five results what else do you have
in your pokemon like
strengths and weaknesses string venus
does the pokemon have this equipment buy
the equipment no people can't buy
equipment they only need the train
account and then you poke a dollar but
when you lose to a battle against
another trainer you need to give them
money yeah
when you fight a trainer and
if you lose you have to give poker
dollars to the winner and
and if you win we're gonna have to give
you pocket dollars to you okay so
there's a kind of items and then you can
use the money to buy pokeballs potions
escape routes
pokemon can hold an item oh yeah pokemon
hold a item so one pokemon how many
items can you hold one just one
okay well if you want another one you
have to get rid of the item they're
holding
you have to remove one item there's also
ability and some ability mega venusaur
question if the pokemon i say if like
you can hold two items so how are we
going to store here it's not easy right
because look the problem with this table
is that one column
column rows columns right if if one
let's use one pokemon silicon has two
items how are you going to put it here
item one item two
you're going to squeeze two data into
one cell technically you can but it's
not very ideal so in this case
we're going to decouple this we're going
to take the two items we can have
another table called pokemon items
the columns will be pokemon and item
right so we can have two rows which is
silicon
silicon item one
and
second row will be silicon item two you
see what i mean
okay okay another thing i forgot to
mention is the table each table usually
have a primary key primary key
so here let's say primark is named
it has to be unique you can't have
separate rows called silicon
somehow here right because primary key
has to be unique so each node represents
a unique pokemon
primary key is kind of like index right
it's index also it's unique
okay so to sum up what have you learned
today about pokemons
so you know
about what what have you done what's the
takeaway today database q sql sql
perfect this is the structural query
language select something from somewhere
where the criteria met and we can have
order by right this is a basic format
and we're going to talk about the join
where sql can be joined let's see that
can be joined right we can select
something from these tables
now we will just left from one table we
can start from multiple tables for
example we can step from pokemon and
pokemon fights or pokemon items we can
join the table by some columns right
yeah i will talk about that in more
details in the next few lessons okay
ryan
what happened
something
something what
what have you learned
last question
about database
database particularly is sql right okay
yeah select a name from family
where age is 10 okay so what does it
give us
okay select an age from family where
whether name starts with r
what does it give us me selena h from
family where the name where the first
name start with r eight
eight
okay this is the square okay let's see
for today bye