hello mr mr ryan are you right yeah
what have we learned last lessons sql
what's sql structured
structure query language so basically
it's a programming language it's a
language that we use to interact with
database right database organized data
remember
in relational database
we use the tables right tables the
columns the rows
the columns these are metadata
attributes right look hit point attack
defense special attack special different
speed gender and each row pokemon right
and we talk about the select the
basically the select is to retrieve the
data we want to filter out some data and
retrieve the data from the database this
pokemon table could contain a minions i
know we're only interested in a few so
we we can use the synthetic
so that's something from pokemon a place
where the conditions yeah we use the
square statement to figure out the data
we want right for example we are
interested in the top five
pokemons which have the largest
hit point okay so we can do this select
name hit point from pokemon
where you know we can skip this
order by hit point but it returns all
the programmers sorted by hitpoint we
only interested in the top five for
example then we can use the keyword top
see that top five or some sql version is
supposed to limit like mysql
order by limit five it means that we're
only returning five okay
slap top
or
limit limit five
so we use the select to retrieve the
data what kind of possible operations do
we need to talk to you know to deal with
this table plus
plus what's plus minus yeah plus or
minus
okay yeah plus is insert
minus is what
we want to put the new data in it we
call it insert we want to remove the
data in it we call it the div okay so
insert and delete
one is missing insert delete and what's
the other one
you could possibly think of wait update
where then update yeah you just want to
update this value for example to 100
right
so these three
together is the select okay
are the four
most popular sql statement a database
could have many tables right pokemon's a
table fight
pokemon fight each other right we stole
those outcomes in a separate kisses
so we could have some table like this
pokemon fight
we have a name of a pokemon one
name of the pokemon two and five results
okay
and maybe a date time so when they fight
before we talk about those four
statements we can use the create
database to create empty database so
insert insert keyword okay let's talk
about insert keyword so we can say
insert
into pokemon
right
the column and release the columns and
then values the syntax for user is
insert
into
table okay pokemon
and
we're going to have this hp
a essentially and then values
values hp will be a hundred a would be
something 90
okay and that would insert a new record
at the end another thing that would be
insert into set
hp equals 100 comma a equals 90
okay
did it
it's quite similar to a select
delete from
pokemon if we just say different
programmer and everything will be
removed
but we can add a where
where hp equals 91 then first of all it
will locate this 91 and you just remove
it from database delete from something
where condition
it's english
insert into
set the new record hp equals 100 a
equals 90. so it means the numerator
has the hp equals 100 a equal 90 and
blah blah blah okay or insert into
pokemon and you specify the columns and
values that's another syntax and update
can you imagine that what's update
so update tokens
right
set
i want i want to change this i want to
change this so
update performance set
a equals
for example 90
where
where okay if i don't specify where what
happened
this column will be changed
to all 90 right i don't want to do that
so update pokemon set a equals 90
where
name equals viral
from right now whatever okay so look at
this name
this name is a primary key primary key
in database is a special column which
unique
identifies a record record the name is
the primary key each table has a primary
key it's recommended to have a primary
key for each table like a primary key is
a special column in a table that
uniquely identifies a record right for
example like there's only one
pokemon called the villa plum right
okay vile vial
clean wire from okay you can put another
document called the via premiere because
this is the primary key
if we insert into pokemon
and then we set set name equals
via prompt database where we call error
say okay we already have a via prompt
here you can't
tell me to add another record okay
so let's update
okay if we want to remove everything we
can use the db from right we just say oh
we can use another keyword called
truncate let's truncate
truncate pokemon and then that means
that we remove everything but keep the
table structure we keep the table
structure we remove the content truncate
the token is the same as td from pokemon
what have we talked about today select
select top select limit select top
but we're returning the top five or top
we can select top 50 percent something
like that or we can see let limit 10
returning only the first 10 uh
performance okay insert
delete update another syntax insert into
pokemon inside into document select
from another table so we are selecting
something from another source another
table and then we try to import it uh to
try to insert it in here for example
like we have a
pokemon one is this one right
and then we have another pokemon too
we want to copy all everything here to
pokemon 2 so we can say
insert into pokemon too
right
these columns i select this column from
pokemon right they get it so so
basically we are trying to copy all the
records from the source from see that
source into another also we have a talk
about create database job database job
so we want to drop everything in a
database
a database contains many tables for
example like pokemon's contains uh two
tables program one pokemon two
now we want to drop database programming
and then pokemon one and pokemon 2 will
be
removed
everything will be removed okay so sum
up
how many keywords create database
job database
truncate table truncate truncate pokemon
it select something from somewhere where
condition
limit or select top
insert
into table columns and values inside the
tables column equals value 1 column 2
equals value 2.
okay
insert
into and then select did delete
delete from tables data from tables
where to remove the records from the
database update
update tables
set column a equals something where
condition we want to change specifically
a value or two values multiple columns
one question we want to update
all the attacks
we want to increment all the attacks by
10 we want to increase this column by 10
every value increased by 10. update
pokemons
set
a
equals a plus 10
right and that will increase everything
here or we can say we want to increase
the attack by 10 if it's lower than 100
right if it's lower than 100 so how do
we marry
update
pokemon that table
set
a equals a plus 10 where
a is smaller than 100 what's happening
after this
so we choose two columns which is three
columns
so here this three yeah
so this will be changed to 85 this will
change it to 90 this change to
92 okay that's what it is what have you
learned today
okay so what operations can we do with
the sql what are the keywords you
learned today update
update and delete delete
insert
select select
shirt from closet where clean equals one
and color you construct
yeah select something from somewhere
where conditions claim equals one means
it's green grain equals zero not cream
dirty and color equals black so we
probably have to give a black this is
the constant string yeah okay that's it
for today bye-bye
bye-bye