hello mister reviews the right night
right
yes
what's combination
we talk about that
c
three two three four speaking two apples
how many ways
three um three yes
so one two three yeah picking two
one two one three two three that's it
okay and three one two one
okay
three apples picking
one apple how many ways
one two when you pick one two you have
three one quick one two you have two i
picked two three
you have one okay we talked about that
right combination the items without
orders yeah picking two apples out of
three we just pick it and we don't need
to worry about the order of the
apples but if we want these two apples
to be
different
with the sequence right one two is
different than two one
and all we have to do is use this p
permutation right
three apples picking two apples but one
two is different than two one then we
have two
times the factorial right you see first
of all we pick two apples after three
and then we
commutate through the floor permutation
on two apples
and we know full permutation of n is n
factorial the first one we have n choice
the second one we have n minus one
choice the third one we have n minus two
choice etc till the end so p and n is n
factor
okay so this combination we talked about
this combination a little bit on day 93
today we're just going to review it and
with a bit extra details so how do we
calculate c
m out of n how do you calculate this
number
okay so i give you a hint all right so
we can think of it recursively dynamic
programming how look i have a
n apples
and apples
okay
and i want to pick m
okay so let's take a look at this one
how many choices do we have for the
first apple
how many choices
yeah what are those uh picky i'm not
picking we're done okay pick it do not
forget if we pick it how many apples
left
[Music]
and minus one yeah
if we pick it we have n minus one apples
but how many apples we need to pick if
we pick one apples already if we pick
this one how many apples left we need to
pick look and apples
i know we want to pick m apples pick and
address
okay so you say the first level we have
two choice
we can pick it or we don't pick it when
we pick it we pick one app off we want
to pick mappers we only pick one apples
how many left
we have n minus one upper left to pick
and how many apples we need to pick from
n minus one right because we pick one
and yeah there are n minus one right
okay
if we skip it how many hours left
we need to pick stair pm how many of us
we need to pick from look we skipped
this one how many hours here
yeah here only here is n minus one right
so is c n minus one we want to pick
and where
c
and m equals c n minus one m plus c n
minus one and minus one
right this is how we get this uh
recursion relation for the combination
okay let me repeat this we have n r plus
let's look at this first f particularly
if we pick it we need to pick n minus
one more from a minus one of us if we
skip it
we still have an apples to pick right
and
12 and minus one letters right
because you said to choice you can't eat
it you pick it don't skip it you don't
eat it okay there are enables how many
ways to pick another part there are
three apples how many ways to pick three
apples
um
one there are three episodes how many
ways to pick nothing
yeah one
okay
we talk about that c and
m equals c and n minus m right
yeah
picking two levels is the same as
picking one up picking one apple is the
same as picking together dnm equals what
is m bigger than n right let's see it
first i want to pick 100 how many ways
what should i put here when m bigger
than n what's the answer
is it right zero well this is impossible
right yeah
zero okay
define
c
and m
if
m bigger than n
return
zero
m equal and n return
one
right
if
m equal equals zero return
one right we talk about it and otherwise
we tend
c
n minus one picking m apples plus c
n minus one picking n minus one letter
if we
pick it if we skip it okay we'll talk
about it easy python code what's missing
here okay cash without the cash the time
complexity will be very complex will be
exponential because
these intermediate values are calculated
over and over again we need to use the
hash table or the cash simply cash to
store the intermediate results okay
this is the dynamic programming top down
dynamic room any questions on this bit
we talk about this on day 93 the
question this is recursion
cnn cash
1-1 what's this
do you still remember it
but this value any value this way
pascal triangle
yeah look this value
is the sum of the value
above right
see this is cn yeah why is it above and
is the triangle this way
if i write it
this way
the number
is equal to the numbers above it but why
i write it this way
because in computer sense rectangular
let's go ahead and match it
particular term so this is particular
triangle look i want to calculate cnm
here
it's a sum of
c n minus 1 m
c n minus 1 and minus 1.
right any number is equal to the sum of
the numbers above it two numbers above
it
top down
top down we use the top down right cm we
want to calculate c and m
then we need to know c n minus one and
and then c n minus one
and minus one right and again these will
be spun into two
right so we have to
remember the values
right for example somewhere here
this value could be the same as this one
and then if we spend huge amount of time
in
in spawning the trees here
there's no point to do it again when we
meet it the next time
so we use the cache
the other way is use the butter area we
talk about top down this is top down we
want to calculate from the bottom up we
need to use the array to install the
values
this top down is very simple
very easy to understand right
yeah and then the advantage of using
this is that the computer take care of
most details when the n and m is out of
boundary and intended cache we don't
need to particularly tell the computer
how to remember the values it's just
like okay we ask computer to remember
this value when you see it the first
time you remember magic keyword cash
without cash without cash for the up
okay
define
c and m again you know there are three
edge cases where when m is bigger than n
return zero if
m equals equals 0
or
m equal equal n and return 1.
we have to store the value in array
let's say dt array
dp equals at the beginning we store it
as a 0
times look at the values here has a
triangle
so this is
n rows
here we want to have uh m columns we
need to create a two dimensional array
times
m for
underscore in range
and
look these values we know we don't need
to calculate this is the boundary value
this is the boundary value right for
i in range look at that let's say this
is the first one is the zero and then
the last one is n so actually this is m
plus one
and m plus one
the row number from zero to n plus one
so we going to prefer this column which
is dp
i 0 equals 1
right
on this value we need to do it
as well so for
i
in
range
and n plus one
right
so d p
i
equals one so we are feeding these
values
and then we need to calculate for i in
range from second actually to n plus one
for
j
in range
second column to i but this i could be
bigger than the m so we have to get a
minimum i
and then
m
d p
i j
equals d p i minus one okay i minus one
j
plus d p
i minus one
j minus one
and we ten
d p
minus one minus one
minus one the index minus one is the
last variable so basically this is the
same as dp and m
we need to fill the triangles each
number is the sum of the two numbers
above it
right this is the way it is
so the j the inner loop the index will
be going from one to the n but not
including this one this one is one right
so which we have
completed yeah
okay so as you can see if we write it in
butter out it'd be non-trivial so it's
difficult to get it right because of the
boundaries because we are feeling this
metric ourselves but using the top down
we don't have to worry about details we
don't need to worry about where to store
the values
here we store the value in the
two-dimensional array
but in the previous version where do the
values stop we don't care
we just asked the computer to store it
using the cache
the computer just stole the cache
somewhere right start the value
somewhere but here we are telling the
computer we want to store the value in
here
then we have to do it ourselves
but the advantage of this one is that
it's practically speaking the
implementation is a bit faster because
there is no function call remember
previous one the top down we have the
recursion calling itself right calling
itself but here we're just calculating
the pascal triangle from the top to the
bottom when we calculate this value the
two values are already calculated above
it right look when we calculate this
value six
we calculate this value which is three
plus three
these two values are already known we
don't need to
go through from the top to the bottom
too in order to get these two values all
right because we already store it here
yes
[Music]
this value is only based on the two
values above it right
there's no
point to store these values we don't
need it right we can just use the one
dimensional array am right look every
time i calculate the value one value in
a two pascal triangle i only need two
values right this value at least ready
any value i don't only need two values i
don't need the values prior to it
let me select i don't need to store it
so in order to do this we can have a one
dimensional array which is this this pip
and then one and every time we calculate
it backwards
so this is the same but with the dp we
just have to change it dp equals at the
beginning the first value 1 plus
0 times
times m
and then for
i in range how many rows is it so
they are n rows how many times i have to
iterate so n plus one here
and then d p
i
would be one
this is setting the right boundary so
remember the first triangle one one one
one one one one one this dpi is setting
these
for j in range
i minus 1 till 0
minus 1 so i go from
i
backwards
then dp j plus equals dp j minus one so
this is basically say dpi minus one j
plus dpi minus one three minus one and
then we turn
pp
the last value which is the same as tpm
the space we only use one dimensional
array and here we're using the two
dimensional array which one is better
here this array we only use in one
dimensional array
this two-dimensional array the space
complexity here is om the space
complexity here is o
m times n so which one is better which
one is better yeah this one is better
the time complexity both the same right
there are two roots
two loops o n times m okay
so this is the most uh optimum solution
in terms of time and space
okay so what have you learned today
combination
more detail yeah combination
combination on day 93 we talked about
this combination actually this is a bit
more detailed here right we using the
bottom up these two are the previous one
is top down
with the cash recursion with the
minimization remember and then the
formula
c and m equals n factorial divided by n
factorial divided by n minus m factorial
right
okay
okay that's it for today bye-bye
bye bye