going to talk about triangles purple
triangles
i think the new stuff hello mr eric
hello mr ryan
hello mr mr mr b
hello enough enough enough
okay thank you hello hey hello oh so
today we talk about
a passcode triangle plus costco
this is useless let's join the bin
is on the floor
[Music]
this is a person's name triangle
the person's name yeah so basically it's
like that
one one two
okay so i can write it this way one one
okay this is the beginning one
one one so one in
this side that's one but now i can put
one more number here
i can put two this is the sum of each
shoulders so it's one plus one so number
one oh
yeah one plus two
three two plus one three
okay one here okay so one one plus three
four three no nothing
six six six six four four
one you see so this this side if you go
this side these are all ones yes
and these are our ones and now one plus
four
uh five you just get two three four five
ten and
okay so you know this pattern this is
called past container so what
do you notice why is it useful no
what one what's that eleven yeah
what's this one oh yeah it has eleven
times tables
yeah and if you times it again that's
that's this number
yeah is it interesting yeah this is one
thing i don't
find how is eleven tables
one eleven to the power of zero is one
eleven to the power one is one eleven to
the power of 2 is
125. 11 times 3
11 times 11 times 11. so 121 times 11.
uh look it's one three three one okay
yeah so 11 times 11 times 11 is one two
three one
even times eleven again then this is
this number every time is given again
okay
still get it and now nothing
and this thing has many many interesting
you know things like this
but another thing is that uh if you sum
up
this is one right yeah if you sum these
two right some digits
you just keep doubling yeah if you sum
the digits
that's another thing yeah yeah okay so
today
our job is to print this
yeah easy to understand yeah so
so so we can use these
we can use i okay yeah we can use the
fact that
each number yeah yeah look
each number is the sum of its of its
shoulders yeah always shoulders so if we
tilt it this
if we tilt this triangle you have to
make it
make it the right triangle so what what
you will become
what you have become is what you will
become is look all right
one one i write it this way right look
yeah so it's it's once so because what
we're doing is because this
is the uh the list in computers that we
have listed list
right all right yeah so it's easier to
to create a list for this
uh six four one okay so getting this
distance this kind of challenge
so we can do this we can do using this
let's do this define f
f eric and the first parameter let's
call let's call this number
uh row the row index and the column
index
okay so which row which index and it
returns the pascal integer
is the integer for that for the parts in
in the pascal triangle okay
all right look at this look at this
please
r and c for which row which c so if
if r equals zero
or c equals zero the first column or
first row
or r equals c
if it's the if it's the the
one yeah once then we do turn one right
yes i'm right yeah
and add our last one all right so
what should we do no if
then we return return
f we call itself right r minus one
c plus f r minus one
c minus one right that's it so this
returns the number
recursively returns the num the sum of
the of the two
integers right above it row
row that's always previous row yeah the
current column
and the previous column right so look
remember
look if r is if i is one zero one two
three
and c is zero one so three one it will
it will be it will be value of the sum
of
of this number plus this number yeah
this number is
r minus 1 c r minus 1 c minus 1 is this
number right
and in all in again you call this
recursive function
so if c is 0 you'll return 1. this
number will be
returned this number and this number so
these will be returning one
okay right so but look look this is
recursively function and every iteration
actually we are calling it multi
multiple times
i'm right yeah now we can actually
we can save this value so
how do we save it look for example if we
if we
look if we're calling this number yeah
we want to calculate this number
now we need to calculate this number and
this number right and then this number
this number
and this number but if i again i want to
take your least number
then these two numbers are already
calculated but we need to
do it again so we can save it because
because your function yeah
it's a recursive call so remember we use
the notebook right
but by using the notebook you you need
to modify the parameters and then if you
need to check if the
notebook has these numbers later
normally if it is by just returning
otherwise
i need to calculate this and save the
result in the
notebook there is another way to do it
which is faster you can do this
you you can just about a function you
just do this
add lru cash
cash we just put it max size equals num
okay so this is the this is to tell the
compiler that we are using a notebook
magic notebook and then you will you
will remember all of this
right okay i will show you with the
coding later another way of doing it
without uh look remember this
this this way yeah this way is i i want
to calculate this and i from a button up
so i need to get to the previous number
and you know this is from this direction
yeah
bottom up button up yeah
now we can do this the other way which
is top bottom top down
so top down so top down is that we
calculate from
phone look defined let's do a row by row
right rows
then columns and then we call we can say
the
data okay data equals now we set it to
zero
rows times rows
okay so now we have this row and then we
can do this for ah
there are range rows
yeah theta this no no the first one is
one right yeah
the last element which is which is what
ah
is also one right all right
and and then we need to for
c in range
ah
actually we are going the other way we
need to calculate from the right to the
left so it should be wrenched range
r minus 1
0 minus 1 so start from r minus 1
till t 1 not including 0
every time decrement one and then we can
do this theta
c plus equals theta
c minus one and then we can print this
data
yes clearly
so we are we are this way we this way we
are constructing the row each row from
top
top to the down each row
yeah we're constructing this law which
is this data and
printed so look out will be
if i want to pass eight rows and then i
will be
printing a rows and each row at the
beginning i set these two
boundary of the triangle which is set to
one and then i
fill this the intermediate values
which is the sum of these previous
of the values above it and the one on
the left
right yeah yeah okay so let's do the
coding we can we can do it and we can
print it
so you should be fine okay
[Music]
can you please not every day okay
you shaking the screen or shaking
continue
can you sit down alright can you you
want to sit down they can't
see you is it clear is it very clear
it's very thin
can you i will just doing this can you
please oh my god
yes you're blocking
yeah i know you see is this all right
yeah no i think it's
i think i need to move this a little bit
save
okay so everybody happy yeah
everybody okay let's do this triangle
thing okay
pasta let's call it pasta pasta triangle
okay
try and key right let's do the first
thing
first first recursive version okay press
you
let's we can from uh we need to
function the tools import this rc
iu cache okay you don't need to remember
this but it's good to
know we have this let's define a row and
see
right if
r equals 0 or c equals zero or
r equals c what should we return return
one one because the boundary yeah
return f r minus one c
plus fr minus what cus
c minus 1 yes okay let's let's
print this first we need to define this
cache
are you cash to make it faster okay
next time it was not okay let's let's do
this okay
four i in range let's put in the a
right for j
in range i right
then we put this current row i know
because this
is current uh row equals
a row yeah and
f i j
and then we print cameron road
does it work let's see is this shaking a
little bit but that's okay
you see does it oh no look the right
most number is not right so let's fix it
we are not we need to arrange
range to it should be range uh
i plus one right i'm
all right it'll be zero to
yes now it's it's working you see yeah
we're missing a number
at the uh in the previous version
[Music]
does it make sense this one and then add
three and six okay so
so let's do another version okay
let's do another version
let's print another version okay so
let's say define pascal
rose we only print the row a number of
rows so let's say
theta equals let's set it to the rows
okay so there are rows then four
are in
[Music]
no no no no i think it's in r
uh minus one
uh let me let me check r minus one
zero minus one and then theta
c plus equals theta c minus
return data queen data bring the current
load okay
let's see if this works uh just pass
curve eight
your point two uh oh there's a problem
okay yeah not putting the data we need
to print
but look we have we don't need to put in
the zeros right we're not don't we're
not printing a zero so how can we fix it
because we're printing too much in line
24 we're printing too much
right so currently current row is
is only so we need to so print
um plus we only print the first r
element yes this is the slicing
always the array slicing complexity
it's just oh uh let's call it oh and
if there are are rows that will be all r
squared because
in each one yeah you're iterating r
times
and then for the rows and r for the
columns
so that will be r squared
so uh um so is this does it make sense
this one
doesn't this make sense you want to have
a look at the code again
now so there are two version which one
is easier to understand also the first
one
you just calculate the numbers and the
triangle
and row r and column c right
yes because in the row zero and z zero
all
r equals c is will return one otherwise
it's the sum of the previous row
with the with the number above it and
the one
uh on the left to it right right
yes for the pascal thing is you
just top down this is top down so you
start from the first row
and then you construct this ryan you're
blocking the views please
so you every time for every row you
check you
you set the first and the last element
which is one which is the boundary
the age of the triangle and then you
feel the in
the intermediate the middle numbers
which is the numbers
of the sum that of the two numbers
yeah in the previous one okay and then
you just need to print the
r numbers for the r rolls right because
you printed
the list of the data you print
everything including the yellow right
yes so this is the thing
so this is pascal triangle okay it's
very useful remember
what can we use it it's the 11th powers
table yeah
and it's the sum of the digits in each
row of the triangle
is the in in two times table or two
powers yes
two four eight okay uh
interesting and then we will come back
to the in the next time
when we talk about the interesting
properties of this pascal triangle we
can use it
as a to calculate some more complex
problems like the combination
something like how many ways you pick
like uh two apples out of three
yeah if there are three apples different
apples and you want to pick two of it
how many ways can you do it
[Music]
i can show you one is four
no two no keep guessing
why is it eleven what's the question
how many how many ways if you pick two
apples out of three
how many ways to do pick two apples if
there are three apples and then you want
to pick two apples how many ways are
picking two apples
three yeah why is it three
uh
okay i asked you another question how
many ways if you want to pick
uh
pick four apples uh
four apples are two apples out of four
[Music]
four apples out of a two apples out of
four
seven now keep guessing no
no two apples
out of four
two apples out of four so look
like i can show you look if you don't
like ryan
wheels please so previously you
want to pick two apples out of four
so it's c is is two
and four right so zero one
two three uh one two three four
and then one two
zero one two so it's three right
and then if you don't put pick two out
of four
zero one two three four
out of four two zero one two
so it's six you see so this triangle can
allow you to solve this problem how many
ways
if you pick x out of y
pick x x out of y so y
is the row pick x out of y
pick three let's do it again pick three
two out of four
zero one two three four
out of uh that's four right and two zero
one two so six
okay yes okay good job today good job
good job good job today
okay say bye bye bye
bye bye