[Music]
am I right
okay let's uh look at this very
interesting problem come on listen to me
that's ready
[Music]
it's naked and you just don't have free
hairs naked okay I'm just putting on
some clothes on it okay
okay
I'll do it even better okay um
already
okay that one is running out so we can
just throw this away okay slowly in the
way
ah better
thank you for that
what's that huh my legs are not less
short
okay
do I have at least a big hands
okay that's it how can I have your pen
please why yeah because this one is good
okay so look there it is here let's say
Eric all right doesn't matter
so let's say I'm starting a petition one
why and then you are starting a
partition too okay it's too far for two
let's put two
two okay
and obviously say start star equals one
and it's one line okay it's one
dimensional Teddy will go left or right
only there's no other direction just
left or right and then right is here
right or Eric Ryan Eric okay just do it
right all around okay okay everyone
sounds cooler yeah all right
it's mixed together
listen listen
the question here
30 can only move left and right one step
okay is right that way yeah yeah because
yeah right left 30 can only move one
step at a time I can go right or I can
go left
so the question is how many ways if I
want to touch you let in exactly three
steps
okay I'll give you an example so one
yeah I go to the right one step is two
but that's not enough because I only
take you only take one step
good job okay so that's one
zero right
and then one
and then two how many steps one two
three three steps one two and
three
two this is also okay right also one
two
and go back one
two right so that's three ways
if I want to touch you
using three steps on the first one you
already touched good point okay let's go
find it okay we can cross it but not
touch it no the thing is
you can fly over you said so it's two
days and forward backwards so it's too
deep it's like a video game
okay okay I did not rephrase it
correctly okay so the question is that
how many ways that uh for Daddy to end
up the innocent Petition of Iran
exactly using exactly the case steps and
suppose that you can only move left or
right well if you can't do it good point
so can you imagine what what kind of
situation that we can do it forever for
that you can't touch that around well
yeah sorry
when Iran is like a hundred a hundred
yes exactly yes look there are a hundred
meter and then K is too small if Iran is
a hundred and eight three steps the best
you can reach is that one two three but
it's is
what
Star right
right okay but
on the left side so we need to do this
what's this
we talked about this absolute value ABS
remember
yeah
one
absolute x equals x when X bigger than
0.
equals zero when x equals zero minus X
when X is smaller than zero okay so it
basically is that distance
look
X is here x is -5 so minus five absolute
value is five it's basically the
distance
online to zero right
if it's on the left hand side for
example this is minus 10 what's the
distance what's the distance if uh if a
run is in minus 10 11 yes minus 10 minus
1 minus 11 right
but we are getting the distance so we do
this mathematically we do this we give
it a two vertical paths which means that
we want to get the absolute value and
for any negative
values the absolute value will be the
negative version of it okay
when we're done there's also another
situation that we can't reach in in k k
step I'll give you an example
okay so one two how about if I say k
equals two
can I ended up in Iran using two steps
if I'm at one that is one and you are
active you run at two and then I'm
saying in two steps can I no no why is
that because it's too small why is it
too soon no I can touch you but not in
two steps I can touch you in one step
but not two steps so what's what's the
problem here you can do two steps so if
you go to around once then you you have
you have enough stability so you are
because going back or
passed amen
yeah and what's the problem how can you
describe this kind of situation I mean
yeah I understand that you understand
this problem right right Eric do you
understand this
look I'm at one you are at two
the distance is you know
uh small right k equals two so I'm
asking can I touch you I cannot end it
up in two using two steps
why
because
um
[Music]
are you all right yeah okay too heavy
yeah yeah okay so what's what's the
problem
um what's the problem
yeah yeah I know but I'm saying what's
the problem on that
it's possible yeah it's impossible but
why it's possible I said it's possible
huh look
what did you do
I think that's the only difference a
three okay okay
I know you understand it but you won't
try give yourself is it like um because
the difference between is one that's
right the difference is one okay and and
so for two you can okay equals two okay
so you can um
so you can go to it around but you also
like
[Music]
so what's that thing what's that thing
okay so I give you another example how
about t equals one and K
equals equals five can we do it
um yes okay how about
it B has to be odd number right how
about if T equals 2 and k equals three
can we do it
all right okay how about Key T equals
four and k equals I don't know eight can
we do it no yeah yeah yeah let's just
look at the without checking the
distance without checking this okay I'm
not talking about this I'm talking about
it but you're right so if T is the odd
number the K has to be odd number if T
is an even number okay it has to be an
even number right all right in order for
for 30 to end up in Iran right okay
we'll get it
okay now that's good so we we know these
two conditions to check okay so now
think about it how do we
how do we calculate the number of ways
how do we calculate the number of ways I
need to give the how do we calculate the
number away I mean it's hard right but
think about it how many Choice do I have
you okay one step I'm one step two
obviously okay that's a good stuff I
think we have two steps left or right so
let's say if I have a function called f
star and then I've end and I need to do
the case step this retains the number of
ways
for Daddy a star to end up in N with K
step all right so but you say method it
has two ways so the next one will be
F star I can go to the left right which
is star minus one right and then n and
how many steps I need to make I make one
step how many steps I need to make
um it came on the front that's fine and
another way to the right so F star to
the right
okay an end
K minus one right they're only two ways
so we need just need to plus together
right with this condition we need to
check be fine if the ABS
star
minus n
is bigger than K and we turn zero right
there's no way to do it
all right I take it at the distance if D
is bigger than k
if K is zero yes so now if K is is zero
so what happening no no okay the K step
so what means yeah I can move so what do
I need to do
if I have a picture with you then I will
turn zero if I'm just stand on your spot
then return one am I right because I
already ended up in your petition if
star
equal n then in this case would return
one otherwise will return zero all right
yeah
daddy can't move
right but in this case
if I'm already in your position then
return one because that counts as a one
way am I right I don't need to move it's
still 100 because I'm already in your
position otherwise it will turn zero
makes sense do you mean you're the
person
can be in the same spot as you yeah this
is the corner case all right because
you're given to style and I can be in
your spot
and if K is zero and I don't need to
move that counts as one solution
okay otherwise otherwise return
f
star minus one n k minus 1 plus F Star
Plus One n k minus one okay
so look
this is what we talk about right yes we
can move to the left or we can move to
the right and the answer will be
the sum of those
I was missing you okay cash yes it's
cash we need to remember the stage right
if we don't remember the state it will
be
the time convincible being for
explanation why is that look look let's
start n and then every time there are
two branches coming off going to the
left going to the right going to the
left or to the right that would be
duplications here for example if this
style is calculated here and then you
might need it here again now if we don't
store this value what happened we if we
spend like 10 minutes
calculating this picture and then it
means that we have to do this again and
that's at least the better things add up
to the time complexity which is the
exponential but if we put a cache it
means that well remember we're
remembering any state of time star and K
the end is not actually not moving right
look these three parameters which one is
changing which one is not I just said
is changing which one is not okay
you just stand there so this is top down
dynamic programming without this cash is
you know profiles simulation proofers
because we are just simulating going to
the left going to the right but with the
cash this magic key was making a
top-down anime programming because we
are remembering each step star times k
the star could be many right it could be
many but we are limiting it we are
improving by checking this if the
distance is bigger than 10 we just
return zero if the distance between 30
and around is more than K it means that
there's no way
to catch it right for Daddy to catch
Iran there's one thing missing we'll
talk about a lot and even right we need
to put it here as well which is look if
T is N1
is equal to K is not equals to K and one
then returns zero right we talk about
that this is very important if K is an
odd number D distance is an even number
or if K is the even number P is a odd
number then there's no way to end it up
in end exactly using K step okay so this
is but we can do it mathematic
turning to the left turning turning to
the right all right
so if I'm saying that it takes Daddy
needs to turn them using air step
L to the left 30 needs to go to the
right using R step what's the value L
plus r
okay all right
because I need to
spend three steps
and air step to the left after to the
right A plus I equals K what's the
second thing
look
here star here's n
so here
to the left
R to the right
to the right right look R to the right
minus L to the left equals one
ah minus L equals one look the distance
here this is distance
I'm here
I go to the right
I go to the right after
I go to the left air step
what's R minus there on this picture
what's R minus l in this picture d d
okay we have this equation can we solve
it
L plus R equals k r minus a equals T can
we solve it we talk about this in early
days
um two hours yeah we ended up together
look
L plus r plus r minus L right this bit
equals a plus d
this comes out 2 times R equals K plus t
I equals this
divided by two this is known this is
known this is known so ah no one
okay so what is this useful they are K
step I need to make a step
and R step to the right the case step
and I need to pick our step to go to the
right what was that layer take apples
layer K apples
I need to pick our apples to eat there
are three apples I need to pick two
apples they are combination yeah they
are K apples I need to pick our apples
to eat when I eat an apple I go to the
right yes so the answer is c k
ah which is K plus C divided by two
This Is The Answer amazing right so we
talk about you know with I don't want to
repeat last lesson we talked about three
ways to calculating the combination
number in Python we have this
from Mass
import we can import com which is
combination.com
k k plus d divided divided by 2 or shift
Shifty one which is also Okay so
one last question
what's the problem and what have you
learned come on just give me a two
sentence to summarize what have we
learned today
so then
two guys two guys yes are you sure it's
two guys not two girls or one boy one
girl
two humans okay
and one of them and we start
is uh trying to get to the end with
Cambridge yeah exactly okay move okay
Okay so
that's the problem and how do we solve
it
how many ways we solve it man what's the
conditions
what's the condition that the the answer
should be zero there's no way impossible
what kind of scenarios that we need to
say okay don't try to move because it's
impossible to
hi Jeffrey
um
um when K is our own number and
and the D is it even number or okay even
number and
oh
plan
and where
um
with with with the diff D is
uh bigger than
k
yeah because okay because it's too far
if K is 3 and D is a hundred right
so the best thing I can do is just to
move three to the right one which still
makes 97 distance right so that's one
thing okay Ryan what have you learned
about about humans trying to get to each
other okay but uh you do you understand
these yeah yeah okay okay and also
there's another way which is bottle up
because we you know these from this uh
dynamic programming right star minus
what we can use the d k which is the
step and then the distance right we can
use a distance which is let's say DP k d
the number of ways to reach
the distance t
using K step and then it's based on BP
okay
minus one and then t plus 1 and K minus
one
B minus 1 right once one to the left one
to the right we can solve this using the
bottom of dynamic programming okay and
because dpk is based on dpk minus one so
it's more like a pascal triangle right
but it's a little bit different because
it's two numbers about the shooter so
it'll be something like you know two
three and then there's a zero and then
right and then that will be the five
something like that so dpk will be the
sum of the dpk minus one D minus one DBK
minus one K plus one okay so we're not
going to dip into these uh because uh to
implement this bottom up is non-trivial
like the combination the Pascal triangle
remember the the values equals the sum
of two numbers above it and if we're
implementing using the butter up
approach it's non-trivial and we can
make mistakes when implementing such
things because there are lots of details
to consider especially when handling the
boundary it's better we use this uh
cache right cash
let the computer handle the recursion
and the boundary educated or we can use
this but the most important thing today
is this and we want to pick the K plus 3
divided by two step to the right there
are characters we want to pick at least
a number of apples to eat
when we eat after we go to the right
okay that's it for today bye-bye bye bye