hello mr ray mr am i right yes we given
this uh two dimensional matrix okay so
you can pick the numbers for simplicity
let's assume all the numbers are
positive
will become more complicated if we allow
the negative numbers okay just for
simplicity
we allow the numbers only to be positive
and the test is very simple just pick
the numbers once you pick one number you
can you can add
[Music]
obviously yeah you can't pick the
numbers next to it
okay so you'll be disappearing around it
sorry you mean around it
yeah and also because that's not next to
it
okay let me rephrase when you pick the
numbers in the first row you can pick
any number in the second row or in any
number above it for example like
yeah you can't put any number above it
so this row well if we pick this number
these roll these the numbers you can't
pick it and also the numbers next to it
so these two numbers one and six you can
pick it but you can pick five
i don't get like what how you just
do the like lines you cross them out so
you can't use them that's right you
can't tell me you can't use one seven
six five nine
okay so let me repeat when we pick a
number we can't pick the numbers that uh
in the adjacent lines so if we pick any
numbers in this this row we can pick any
like all the numbers in the next line
and all the numbers in the above lines
okay and also one addition requirements
that we can't pick the numbers on the
same row next to it right so two
requirements
first of all if we pick the number at
the
row
column now we'll pick this number if we
pick this we can't pick any of the
numbers
at
row minus 1 and row
plus one
and also we can pick the two numbers
at
row the same row yeah column minus one
and row
column plus one we want to maximize the
sum
this is the requirement when we pick a
number we can't pick any numbers that in
the above row and in the next row we
can't keep any num the two numbers
basically and uh next to it so you know
the one on the right and one immediately
on the left
so for example if you pick one
then i can't get anything here
what's the maximum you can get here
why which one is 20 um seven five eight
two wow okay any more bigger than that
okay seven five one two okay so look if
you pick this one you can pick this one
but not anything yeah
does it have to be three times four
no yeah good question the metric could
be any size so the thing here is i want
to pick this number all the numbers next
to it
right so these two numbers just just
disappear right we can think of it
disappearing when you pick this number
all the numbers in the next row
discipline if we pick this number all
the numbers above it disappearing and
all the numbers below it disappearing
okay yeah
this is two dimensional okay we're
picking it in the middle
we'll pick the middle sorry see if we
can do it so if you have a free time
free one and you pick the number in the
middle it's useless
it's use this if you no no no sorry for
example if i'm here like i put a minion
here obviously you want this yeah you
want to pick up media and not know the
numbers i don't care because all this is
the biggest right yeah
okay
yeah but what if it's like this
um
so we talked about a one-dimensional
problem haven't we
remember that a street there's a street
a street each house has some money in it
some money yeah
and you want to go yeah i see if you
want to you know steer from the houses
the thief can't steer two adjacent
houses otherwise the police will be
caught
the alarm will fire off and remember
this this is one dimension right so in
that problem we want to find out the
maximum sum of non-adjacent numbers
right
yeah so for example one two three four
five right one two three four five
so we want to pick the sums pick the
numbers that sum up to the maximum but
we don't want to pick the numbers that
next to each other if we pick two we can
pick one and three but we can pick four
or pick five
at the time we we talk about five sorry
i'll pick five yeah but you can pick
more so pick five three three
one one
yeah that's maximum right i'm right
yeah like that's eleven yeah that's
eleven that's the maximum you can get
okay so we talked about that remember uh
we talked about the dynamic programming
here we use this one dimension now
how is that useful on how is that useful
if this is one dimensional if i'm saying
this is one row okay
one row
if i'm saying this f row
returns the
largest
non-adjacent sum
right
if i'm saying that f row returns the
largest non-adjacent sum for the row for
this row so how is that useful this is
2d this is 1d
if we are looking at this what's the
largest non-adjacent adjacent just for
this one if we can pick two numbers
next to each other what's the largest
sum you can pick
here
seven five okay 12
what's the largest sum here
um
12 12 nine yeah
these two yeah these two yeah what's the
largest sum here
[Music]
um ten
ten yeah
ten a and two okay
okay now
looking at this one dimension low by row
we know this yeah
okay
so what about these three numbers 12 12
10.
it's the same we can apply the same
equivalent again right 12 12 10 what's
the largest sum you can get it's like
210 yeah
22. so another term is 22. if we pick
this
all the numbers next to it disappearing
the number on the left disappearing the
number on the right disappearing because
on each row we can't keep two numbers in
the row right so we can apply this
aggregate the police and rubber problem
one
so look at this we can get two f if by
looking at this row only if we can get
12 on the second row we can take ten one
zero always pick this number the number
all the numbers next to it
the above and below on the
adjacent rows will disappear right so it
means that if we pick the number 12 here
we can pick any of the numbers on the
next row right
yeah
so it means that we can apply this all
right two three five
seven
six one two three
two one two four
three six seven two okay what's the
largest long adjacent sound if you can
find
pick in this matrix
what's the sound
okay so what's the first one you can get
what's the sum of the largest languages
now just look at the first row what's
the 10
yes this is 10 yeah
so it's 10
it's 10. okay what's the second one
nine right i can pick this and this nine
right
what's the third one
six six what's the last
one okay now
given this
what's the maximum you can pick 20 20.
so it means that we can get 20 by
picking
this one
this one this one yeah is this
satisfying requirement if we pick this
number
we can't pick any of these and not this
one we can pick this one not this one if
you pick this number we don't pick any
of those yeah we can't pick any notes
yeah so the set is very equivalent yeah
got it
largest sum
of
noun
how do you spell adjacent
j a c and d f
numbers
we talk about
a different solutions the core idea is
the dynamic programming fi
means that the largest sum that if we're
looking at the from the beginning to the
i
number so f i equals maximum
for this number yeah look
there are few numbers
this is ice number yeah if we're looking
at this f i what does it equal is equals
to
f i
minus
1 right
this one but once we have this we can
pick b
right
or f i minus 2
if we pick here
then we can have these plus nums
i right
if we pick this number
we can pick this but we can't pick it
so f i equals the the maximum of
f i minus 2 plus this number
right
or f
i minus one i know this is dynamic
programming yeah we're remembering is fi
we don't need to calculate it again and
again
so i'm just going to write a
uh
iterative version of it yeah and you can
do it in the
top-down dynamic programming or
bottom-up dynamic programming and then
this is much more like a fibonacci
number
define f
numbers and equals the length of numbers
if n equal
0 returns 0 nothing that will return 0
if and equal equal 1 if there's only one
number then we return it return numbers
here okay then
a b equals 0 0 for i in
num
a b equals the b maximum a this is the
first number plus i and b
and return
b
the idea is that we're going through
every time a and b
a means the numbers that the largest sum
we can get by
picking this number and the numbers
priority
to it but not including the immediate
previous one
b is the largest sum
by picking the previous number but
obviously we're gonna pick the
one okay
so once we have this f function for this
two dimensional and we can just return
max return
f
r
for
r in original metric
then we apply this again with an f well
we
calculate the sum of each row
and
then
[Music]
and then what
so we calculated this largest sum
you know how to solve this
one-dimensional problem right
you're applying this as a function
right
yeah and then you um calculate the sum
of each row and then and then you
and then you
calculate um
the
the greatest sum of
[Music]
why can we do this first of all what do
we need to do with these numbers
um
[Music]
you um like
if you pick a number you can't use the
left or right to it
so
and you can't use the row
below so the sun works as
like
it's not next
to each other like um
a day
whatever situation
[Music]
so there are two requirements so let's
look at each row so if we pick one
number we can pick two numbers next to
it right so that's the
one-dimensional problem of the please
the sieve problem right
all right
and then if we have this the largest sum
for each law particularly we can apply
this uh aggregate to it because the if
we pick one number from firstly we
complete any number of the second law
right so if you look at the that way
perspective then that's another
dimension of the police uh and you'll
see what they're right above exactly so
the takeaway today is that if we we are
solving this kind of problem we can
apply this one thing
solution twice to solve it
am right ryan what have you learned
today about numbers what do we do with
the numbers
get try to get the biggest number so
what are the requirements when we pick a
number you can't
if you pick one number you can't pick
the number on the left or right or the
right above or below yeah don't worry
so we want to find out the largest sum
for the long adjection
numbers of each rows right and those
numbers then we can apply it again
so for example least the largest sum for
the first row is
is one eight right
with eight so i'm gonna put a here
the last sum of the second row is
fourteen forty the last sum of third row
is
[Music]
the last number to fall right
i know what what to do with this person
oh yeah yeah sorry
yeah all right okay
so it doesn't matter anyway so what that
what do we do with these numbers add two
the two um greatest numbers which is in
this case fourteen and ten
and then you add a mark 14 and ten
why for the intent i pick 14 i can't fit
10. oh yeah so what are the numbers
10 and 8
10 yeah okay
because we pick any number of the second
we complete any number of the zero so
if we
transpose it
we just have to apply this again this is
how we solve in the one dimension all
right f i equals maximum of
f i minus 2
or f i minus 1 plus
f i minus 2 plus the numbers at i
okay and this time complexity is one so
we applying these twice the time
complexity is t o n right so o n o n o n
o n
i don't get this number o m okay that's
it for today bye bye
[Applause]