all right
how would you put the data on a piece of
paper for example like you want to tell
your friends all right what's your name
what's your age how would you write on a
piece of paper
I didn't want to send your you know too
late in the envelope
and then you want to give it to other
people and then tell your name your age
how would you write it I mean suppose
this is a piece of paper
I know how to write it this someone
so you write a sentence right can you
find out the simplest way just to tell
to let a lot of people know what you
want to say
yeah okay are you writing a sentence
okay I see okay so right and you're
writing like numbers by eight right and
then put them here right okay so let's
uh color mark
yeah okay
good okay so you yeah
okay so anyway okay so y'all the idea is
the writing a sentence all right all
right obviously writing a sentence that
people can understand it all right and
why your idea is to write the keywords
right and people can understand right
yes the bills are okay these are both
humans right so the idea is that we want
to come up with the data it's
interchange format so the easier for
humans and for computer to understand
so we want to exchange this data for
example like the name the age and I will
come up with something like this
Eric for example
age
10.
okay look suppose this format it's easy
to understand right because that sounds
familiar the key is very impaired it's a
lightweight
data interchange
in the change format and that's uh easy
for computers and also for humans to
understand the computers we have an
efficient argument to pass this string
the text format this is a simple text
and this is quite similar to the
dictionary in Python so that's the
format that we are going to talk shortly
this is called Json
it's very popular it's a format text
format that we used usually to store and
transfer the data between the client and
the server so for example the computer
here right in the browser have you seen
the login window
can lock in window
the username the password
and there's a locking button right
okay so when you follow Eric yeah
and the password one two three four
obviously this needs to be encrypted all
right and then you click login what
happened
your computer you need a browser we send
a request to the server server in the
cloud right what's Cloud remember lots
of computers
somewhere right for example the cloud
the computer may be in London how does
this data exchange so you could be in
this Json format Json is one of the top
species right so you could be
constructing a format named Eric age 10.
and then the cloud takes it and then
you'll be able to external information
the name and the age
and the password okay we are talking
about the password Here okay so this is
the thing data in the change format so
so in Python we can use this import
Json and now we can say Json
stop
loads
we can load uh
adjacent format
parsley and store it into the variable
all we can do this opposite which is
thumbs
you can thumb the variable and into a
Json format string Json contains the
object or array there are two
possibilities one you know one is this
curly brace
with the key value pairs right each
value
could be another object or array so it
could be nasty so you can have them you
know like Alias something that I left
right and the keys
codified double coat right double quotes
only but in Python you can do it in
Singapore but Jason the standard Jason
format the keys should be coated in
double code the values could be array
the numbers right okay
and then array okay so we talk about the
array in Python what what's the array
using this one two this is array right
so this is a validation and this we can
say
uh numbers
five one two three this is a Json right
and uh foo foo and then you can have
another object and then we have another
bar
uh array one two or four bar what's
what's next p t t Okay and then it'll be
values some one two three
okay so you see the curly brace comes in
pairs
right the arrays
this is like this that we will define an
array in Python the numbers
so the numbers the values we can have
the numbers one two three we can have a
value string
string hello why
clothing in double quotes or we can have
a three special uh constant value which
is true
fourth
and noon what's new what's the reason
what I mean noon what do you mean
nothing nothing noon 2013 values
one thing about Jason is that we don't
have comments
what comment
when you write the python code you start
with a hashtag
and everything after the computer will
just ignore it that's for humans you can
say okay Eric is amazing okay and then
computer what is this sharp sun and we
ignore it it's not part of the code but
in in Json you can't have comments
everything is data all right everything
is data so you can have something that I
like why look so send the Json for my
only store
array okay but some other standards
allow the you know just storing the
values difference
okay
Okay so
today what's Jason and can you both
write a simple Json here the easy
situation
and that's it what's Jason
can you write an example of Json
just test your knowledge that's it Ryan
you want to have a go
simple Jason remember one day I talked
about the Jason
just simple Jason
[Music]
yeah okay so what's Jason what can you
write this thing for this Jason
you can do it very simple and that's it
you know what did I talk about the
objects and the way what's the simple
what's the empty object what's the empty
array how do you declare an object
dictionary in Python how do you declare
empty arrays in person
what's the key value pairing number you
start with the double chord and then
what a string can be a validation
what what do you want to write anything
Ryan name
okay
okay Karma okay but if this is the key
you have to do this with the you're
missing one this curly braids okay and
then calibrates to end it and you can
add add more
this is Jason this is not okay
remember Jason this is Jason this is the
Jason this is a Jason all these one two
three situation or two or two four
or noon right yeah so can you write a
pick one yeah
just speak organized
what's what's this how do you improve
this in computer
um there's no such thing as least what's
this
age is a number right okay then
is that how we store
and transform the data format right like
like at the beginning said you want to
tell the name column
by an age per say something like that
and people can understand right because
it seems if it simply give the values
people may not understand what it is am
I right if you buy a 9 on a piece of
paper give it to Eric
I really may not understand what the
night meaning is you have to put the age
before it am I so this is for computer
to understand your data this is the Json
structure array string values numbers
and this is three special meanings
their calibrations for object this is
the keys this is very it's like a
dictionary in Python right in Python how
do you declare additionally
how did you get additional you just do
this right like uh you just do this a
equals this is the dictionary and we
talk about the partition right it's the
same thing the only thing that is so
special about this is the adjacent
format the keys has to be encoded with
double quotes but in Python you don't
have to uh stick to the double so it
could be a single chord right Jason what
does this stand for JavaScript object
notation okay JavaScript
this is another programming language you
just know it's a problem JavaScript
object notation huh okay okay so what
have you learned today that's it
you're letting the Jason from what is
this that's one sentence
information yeah for sending information
uh to a computer yeah for for computer
to store
and transfer the data and this format is
also easy to understand for humans all
right yeah
okay
what's that post
I left it for today bye-bye