finally yeah we talk about binary in
computer we use the binary binary zero
and one Community is powered by
electricity
so we power on WE power off the two
states the electricity the high voltage
low voltage there are two states so it's
zero one yeah
so
the numbers in binary only have two
digits zero and one we talk about the
binary okay let's look at the first few
numbers the zero one two three this is
the decimal the numbers we're using
today right decimal so can you tell me
what the corresponding binary this is
decimal this is binary I give you a few
examples okay
zero one what's two one zero zero and
then what's next
[Music]
um one zero zero zero
one zero zero one
um one zero one zero one zero one zero
oh is that the one again one zero one
one
one one
zero there one one zero one one one one
one one okay so look at these start from
this one okay this is two to the power
zero this is two to the power one this
is two to the power of two
this is two to the power of three
uh and then we have one more six things
one zero zero zero zero okay two to the
power four okay so can you tell me the
common things about this uh Power of
tools
so what have you learned from this
um well uh
and the
Power of Two is the amount of zebras
they have
so it's one one followed by you know the
number of powers zeros after it all
right yeah okay so this is binary okay
we already talked about how to convert
between binary and decimal in the past
okay okay so today's question uh this
binary is related to this value so the
first few integers one two three four
five six so let's look at these numbers
integers so one is one two is one zero
three
is one one right look
and first of all
we convert the integer to binaries and
then we put it together yeah we we put
this together in binary form so that
these we want to get the value of this
so what's this in binary one one zero
one one how do we convert a binary to a
decimal
[Music]
that's right yes we'll count it yes how
do we count it look this one yeah this
is one
this is two each one is doubles for
a
16 yeah so this number is like 1 16 plus
a plus
we skip four right because this is zero
one two plus one so this is 27.
all right
so any idea I mean we're given an
integer n
for example if you get n equals four and
we need to get this 4 is one zero zero
so we put this binary together so we're
going to get the value of this in
decimal
[Music]
so what's your thoughts I mean you don't
have to dig into details just tell me
how just all this problem
Rufus is a good idea yeah so look we
know how to
how to convert this uh from numbers to
Binary right and then we put it together
and then we convert it back all right
let's restart okay so we can do this
first first of all we need to get the
binaries for the numbers and how do we
get a binary numbers we talk about uh
the egg right but in Python we have this
pin function remember the PIN three zero
B one one okay look pin 15.
give us
zero B one one one one so low is prefix
with zero P which is binary okay so if
this number is n array first of all
array equals
ping
I and we want to remove the prefix we
start with the
third character onwards so it's two to
the end
for I in range
1 to n plus one right so it's one to n
inclusive
and now we have this AR which is a r now
equals one
one zero
one one
Etc right so we want to
put these numbers together from another
way what function can we use
to put all the things together using
this sorry join okay join by empty space
join yes we're done John AI so once we
join it now we want to convert it back
to integer right yeah so this is
function look so we just do this end
and then the second parameter base two
which is finally and that's it all right
so you can even do this in one line so
return
into this this ARR yeah I think it's
here okay
pin two yeah the time the next day
I end up here and look for each one we
need to convert it to Binary right let's
login to this so it's the time commence
is o n Times login any question on this
one
okay look at this three number so let's
look at it one so what happens if we
move to the next integer it's two right
it's one zero right so we put a one zero
what happened to this one
it moves two space to the left all right
when you move one space to the left
whatever when you put a zero at the end
will happen if you don't
you put a zero at the end will happen
this is one
you put a zero What's this
you put another zero what happened
foreign
I need to move two space to the left so
I move two space to the left so what
happened to this one two to the power of
two right look another one so this is
one one zero so okay another one let's
look at this one one so what happened I
put a one one here what happened
so this number
move two space to the left right
so every time you move the one space to
the left it doubles
move to Space 2 to the power two we can
just scan these numbers and then we get
the length if we know the length we know
how much we need to multiply how many
space we need to move the current
integer to the left
four
okay this is answer right answer at the
beginning equals zero for I in range
1 to n plus one right
so now look I we want to convert I to
Binary right so let's finally P equals
pin I will talk about this right bin I
why are we converting these the numbers
to binary
yeah one these two two converted final
is one zero so then we know one needs to
move two space to the left so you know
what the numbers to put
yeah numbers to put here we can just
simply add the numbers I here but the
most important thing is this one needs
to move two space to the left
so why do we need to convert the numbers
to binary
because we want to find out how many
what's left
spaces what spaces the length right
because we want to find out the dance
look four is one zero zero we convert it
to Ping this is the length now we need
to do this lens get the lens we need to
subtract two why do we need to subtract
two this pin 4 pairs US 0p 1 0 0 so why
do we need to subtract two the lens of
being this is the size of this is one
two three four five but we need to
subtract two
because
what's this we don't need this right the
binary is in this one huh
yeah we just need a lens of this right
so subscribe to and then we have recipe
what happened answer need to move the
space shift shift
be partition to the left
and then answer plus equal I all right
so look one moved one move two space to
the left for the two zeros at the end b
equals two right move two space to the
left and then plus I
eyes here one zero plus idea right so
it's one one zero here got it
and then return answer the time
complexity is still o n okay because
look this pin from here this pin
function is taking time we just want to
get the length of the binary right do we
need to check it for each number look
the length of these look what happened
uh let me write it this way look at this
one just just look at this think about
it I'm going to write a binary here
right 0 1 1 0 1 1 1 0 0 1 0 1 1 0 1 1 1
1 0 0 okay enough look at this pattern
yeah look at this pattern this is binary
I'm going to convert it to a string and
then get the lens the lens one one two
two three three three three four okay so
do you see the pattern when does the
size increase by one
one one one one what's next one zero
zero zero zero now this is sizes for
this size is five so in what cases the
integer the length increment by one
when is one one is what when it's one
one is all one it's not increasing look
one one uh one zero it's not increasing
it's therefore but one is
so what happened
it turns to one zero zero okay so one
two two
yeah two to three
three to four four to five this is the
number I when I
is what then we can increment the length
when I is is one and ends with zero so
what's n with zero so what's this what's
this number yes
it's
in binary one followed by lots of zeros
what's this number is 2 4 8. power of
two exactly okay in binary because look
in final we just talk about binary one
followed by lots of zeros how many zero
and zero here right so what's this
number two to the power of n right this
is power two we don't need this now in
this case we don't need this right so
what do we need to do we give up the
current length current length equals
zero and we don't need this all right
this is current uh let's let's just put
a b equals zero okay
okay then we'll just do this if I is
power of two right I is Power of Two
I is power two okay we are coming back
to this power of two then we increment
the length B plus equal one all right
so how do we check if number if the
integer is power to the last question
how do we check if the integer is
powerful how do we know 32 is powerful
how to know 64 is equal to
and then he'll eventually
become
zero sorry
how do how do we check if the number is
power of two there are quite a few ways
last time you talk about you know
multiplier two every time right all
right all all divided by two that's one
way is it definitely
yeah yeah yeah lock-in solution but what
I'm saying that look look at the binary
yeah you just tell me that it's one five
followed by loss of zero right look at
this okay
if we subtract one to this what happened
one followed by lots of zeros if you
subtract one what happened subtract one
to this what happened one of the digits
is gone and
we're done okay then how about if I do
this end you know logic n both things
are true then it's true so if you do the
n what happened what's the number here
two n a and b a needs to be one B needs
to P1 otherwise it's all false so zero
and one is four so that will become zero
right if
I am I minus 1 is equal to zero of
course I is to bigger than zero right
right because I is bigger than zero so
we can ignore this so we can just say if
I and I minus y equals zero is a power
of two then B plus equal one and then
that's it and because this N is a one
constant so the time complexity is om
it's better than previous one look less
and look we need to iterate the numbers
from 1 to n and inside is for one
constant previously the pin function
takes login so oh and login now we're
improving this pin and to o1 right
there are quite a few other ways like
you said multiply it by two until we get
this number of big energy oh we divided
by two until we can divide it or we get
one right or we can do this get the log
function Master Lock
to phase two and we check if this is a
whole integer dot is integer or with 2
is x equals we first get the integer
part of the log I2 we get the log
function here and then we check if 2 to
the power of x equals equal I log
function log A to B what's this equals c
we talk about log here log n what's the
login what's log function
um
is it like
look ABC
we can get a to the power C equals B log
log 2 x equals y right so we can write
this as 2 to the power of Y equals X
right
2 to the power of Y equals X so we can
say y equals log 2 x am I right
yeah make sense
okay so to sum up what have you learned
today
[Music]
not just a single word tell me what's
the problem what are we trying to solve
here what have you learned what's the
approach uh try to say three to four
sentence
okay that's a good exercise to you okay
so can you say what's the problem and
what are we trying to solve here what's
the problem and how are we solving it
and that's it go
so we
um have these numbers and uh
and
so we wanna
so we won't like the number like
the binary numbers and yeah binary is
concatenation of binary numbers and then
we want to convert it back to integer
right we don't get this number right
yeah yeah so we just
figure out the convert the numbers to
Binary and then we can see like um
how many
like
like uh spaces we move forward I think
uh energy minus two because you don't
need a Bo stuck
okay yeah so we convert it to Binary
here because we want to find out how
many lengths the length of the next
integer in binary format and because we
need to move this answer to partition or
three partition B partition to the left
and plus I will just police number to
you know on the right on the right got
it okay okay let's see for today bye-bye
bye
nice hello hello Mr Ryan are you right
yeah okay so we talk about binary in the
past right the binary
finally numbers yes in computers
computers I understand binary zero and
one
the other one is two there are two
states one is that two states the
computers
yeah the computer the binary is uh very
friendly to computers why because
they're because the power yeah something
to do with the power because there are
two states you know the power you plug
it in on and off and the power we can
defend the circuit to represent the zero
and one using the high voltage of low
voltage right so zero one binaries
everything in computers is the in binary
let's look at the first few numbers yeah
zero one two three four five six seven
eight nine ten eleven twelve thirteen
fourteen fifteen sixteen okay let's look
at this 17 numbers so in binary I write
a few can you write the next okay so
this is the decimal and we want to
convert it to Binary zero one obviously
texting them the numbers we're using
today the number 16 we're using today
zero to nine that's the number 10 digits
zero one two two nine right so when you
plus one to nine it carries over to one
zero right and then continue to 99 when
you press one here
it becomes a hundred right because nine
carry over to zero carry one here to
zero
one yeah okay
so what to do in binary one zero one
zero okay three one one four
um one
one zero zero yes five
um
the first one here so what happened nine
zero one okay next
um one one one zero yes we're done keep
going one one one yes
um so we are running after our digits
here so plus one here zero well done and
then
one zero zero one yes
um
one one zero one zero yes
um one zero one one well done wow you're
on fire today
um one one zero zero yes
yes
okay one zero zero zero zero well done
look this one too
four
four eight
sixteen can you notice that something in
common about this 2 4 8 6 what happened
they will add just one and zero one for
Blue by some zero right one
followed by zero yeah follow y one zero
that's two to the power one followed by
two zero two to the power two all right
look how do we convert this in binary
this this is one this is two
this is for this is a this is 16. so
it's 16 plus eight plus one
right yeah this is 25 okay so look if
it's a power of two then all the rest
will be zero right yeah so look this is
each each digit yeah on its own is power
of two so that's the way we check if the
number is Tau of two okay so we're given
the integer n
so for example n equals three so we put
a number the integer number here one two
three okay what's one in finally one
what's two in binary one zero plus three
in battery one one weather okay now we
put this together so it becomes one one
zero one one so what's being decimal
okay so we press these together which is
the
27 right how do we solve this problem
any idea right
um we
look we first of all this is the digits
we convert to Binary we put the binary
together concatenation of a binary
string
and we convert back to the text symbol
from the boundary
well that's another more which is which
is for
if we have another digit 4 which is one
zero zero
one zero zero right even numbers always
yeah yeah I know we convert this to
decimals
yeah
how would you do it
any idea okay
I mean you can ask computer to do the
exact step right all right let's move
forward we can ask the computer to do
exactly the same thing first of all we
convert numbers to Binary I will put it
together and we just convert it to
decimal look each step is known and we
can do it right and it's n right we know
this n so first of all we want to get
the numbers one two three first of all
we know we want to convert it to Binary
which is one
one zero one one right so we use the
function called bin yeah we talk about
the equivalent right how do we get a
binary from the decimal so you know how
to convert from binary to decimal from
decimal to Binary right one easy way
look how do we convert the 7 to Binary
seven
divided by two three remain one
three divided by two one remain one
divided by two zero remain one once is
zero we call this backwards so it's one
one one
make sense
[Music]
pin three equals
zero P one one okay so let's string the
final string you prefix with zero P bury
this in mind okay for example pin
hey you will give us 0p 1 0 0 okay
this function pin stands for binary not
a trash bin okay rubbish so we use this
pin function so array equals pin
I
for I in range
1 to n plus one inclusive
one to n okay basically but look at this
pin as I said there's a prefix a we
don't want this right
we don't want this glob so we can just
cut it from the third position to the
end two to the end right
then
we have this array right we have this
array and we want to put it together so
look we have this
we have this how do we put these things
together we use the function we want to
join it right so we can just join it
Jump by empty space join away
and once we have this string we want to
convert it back to integer in the
function convert it back to integer base
two this second parameter two means that
first parameter is a number in
base 2 which is final okay so we can
even do this in one line right return
end
empty string join this whole thing two
and the time complexity we as we need to
iterate overly and integers
all right so let's o n for each number
we call this bin function so that's
going to take o log n times so Ln Times
log n but we can do better
look I have one now now the next number
is 2 right I know it's one zero in
binary
so what happened to this one Lexi
integer coming one zero what happened to
this one
what happened
um what happened it was originally on
this place but it now moved to this
place it moves two space to the left
right yeah so another individual one one
comes one line comes what happened to
Karen in numbers it was like that now I
squeezed two numbers in so what happened
to this look at this way now one I put a
zero at the end one
one zero what's this two one zero zero
what's this four this number one I put a
zero at the end what happened to this
value one two one zero what happened to
the value put another zero at the end
what happened to the value I have put
another one zero at the end what
happened in
it doubles the number it doubles the
number that's the thing one what
happened if I put a zero at the end what
what happened to the value it doubles it
doubles that becomes two if I put
another one it becomes four right it
works for an integer for example this is
one one zero what's this value is four
plus two
is six right because I put a zero here
at the end what's the value
12 12 right
and then 34 exactly right and it works
the other way around if I take a zero if
the value divided by two all right any
value right any value I put a zero there
each value
shift one partition to the left it means
that it the number it represent the
value we present on that single digit
times two
right times two so the whole value times
two
okay so now coming back to this
one one zero the next number is one one
the one one is two digits so the
existing values
shift two position to the left the value
doubles twice right
now we can do it this way look
I okay now current value is one right
now comes another one zero okay
so now current value needs to
shift to position to the left right
shift to position to the left and plus
this value now it's one one zero now
comes to eleven I put two earlier and it
means that the carbon existing value the
carbon value moves two position to the
left am I
answer equals zero for I in range start
with 1 to n right so n plus one
not including n plus one is n okay now
the current digit is let's say x equals
the pin function right pin function I
convert the I to pin but we want to get
the length right we only get the length
length of it we need to subtract two
answer
shift shift equals x we move we shift
the X position to the left and then
answer plus equal I return answer
okay you see two steps
now I'm one right the next number comes
is one zero right so first of all what
do I do with this one x equals two right
x equals two one zero the length is two
digits I put a two zero
only one right and then I add the one
zero
oh yeah so it's become more window
simple that's two steps that's it the
time can let's see look we need to
iterate n digit and numbers
for each one we're still using the pin
something so it's all and organ as well
right so it's not improving it's not
improving but we can actually do it
better why is that look just a third
this person okay what happened to the
lens one one zero one one one zero zero
one zero one one one zero one one one
one zero zero zero
look at the length one digit
two digit two digit three digit three
digits three digits three digits four
digits
four digit five digit
so do you see the pattern when will the
length the tip the number of digits
increase
yes okay so look you see
one to two
two to three
three to four
and then here is four to five so in what
cases what number we can increase the
number of digits
what happened here one two two one zero
we increase one digit two to three we
increase one digit three to four we
increase one digit so you see the
pattern here
what's the pattern so look what my top
number increase
one important number increases a digit
by zero
okay so look at least number two
what's this for what's at least a what's
it is 16. so we can increase when the
number is 2 4 8 16. so what's this
number
two for a sixteen what are those numbers
power of two right yeah Power of Two so
we can increase by power of two one
followed by a lot of zero right and
zeros
2 to the power M this number binary is 2
to the power of n we don't need to
calculate the lens every time x equals
zero right at the beginning then we
check if I is power of two yeah if I is
power of two then we X Plus equal so we
incremental length if x is power two
then we increment the length so how do
we check if a number is pi over 2 right
how do we check if the number is power
two how do we know 16 is power of 2 by
17 is not power two there are a couple
ways
you go to the beginning number zero you
well you add one and then you do and
then you double it and and if you pass
it
um
you can keep time from it we're done one
two four what's the opposite way
dividing it without always yeah you can
do this times
um multiply until it's equal or bigger
than it right or you can divide it if it
aren't here it's one or you can't be
divided oh it's an odd number I'm right
this is the power of two right look at
these numbers
they are Power of Two
do you notice the the pattern the power
of two in binary one one zero one zero
zero one zero zero zero one zero zero
zero zero okay so do you not notice the
pattern if a number is power of two in
binary it follows by this pattern am I
so if it's a power of two single one
followed by loss of zero am I so what
happens if we subtract one from this
number
did you left one digital and this
teaching gone and what's next what's
this number one one what's this number
one lots of one right yeah
if we do a n
needs to be true one and one is one all
others are zero if we do a n operation
or these then you become zero so that's
a quick way to check if a integer is a
power of two so we can do this if
integer is I then we can say if
I is bigger than zero obviously it can't
be zero right I thicker than zero and
I and I minus 1 needs to be zero
right look but here look I is from one
so we can get rid of this so we can just
say if I and I minus one the N operation
is zero and then we increment the length
two numbers two English n operation a
bit operation the end of exclusive or
you know those kind of thing is all one
constant so this time complexity is just
o n
a loop with n iterations and everything
inside is constant
there are a couple ways as you said we
can check the numbers uh even if to see
if it's a power of 2 by multiplying or
dividing we can do this another way we
can check the block function we can do
this master lock
I2 right and this is written
a number but we just have to check if
it's a whole integer okay
it's a whole integer that's also okay
remember if it's a power of two then we
can say log 2 to the power of uh what's
the block function block to n equals
why
look what's this
lock
we talk about log functions right it's 2
to the power y equals n right and we can
write it in log function look log
function of a this is equal to three two
to the power of three equals a
right this is a number that it's not a
problem two then this number is not a
whole integer right so another way we
can get this number for example and
convert it to an integer in and then we
check backwards so 2 to the power of uh
this integer if it's equals to I
then it's a power of two okay that's it
for today bye-bye