hello Miss Larry are you right
so Eric and Ryan right they arrived in a
city like Cambridge right for example
Eric you arrive in a city like arrive
yeah you know you know for example if
you're going to go to Cambridge to have
fun
okay so let's say Paris
visit Paris and Ryan wants to visit
Paris as well yeah
[Music]
that's okay you don't need to speak
French to be there right okay so the
point is that for example if you arrive
arrive at tens of March
all right and then you leave you
departure at the 15th of March
okay
yeah
and Ryan somehow
arrived at 12th of March
and leave at 22 of March okay
so we want to find out how many days
you're both in Paris
and what are those three days
12 13 14
sleep
12 13 14.
so 15. you post that in Paris make sense
yeah yeah so 12 13 14 15 right but not
16. on 15 what happened you're still in
Paris all right you'll probably take a
plan but you're in Paris
okay so the question is asking how many
days you both are in Paris in the same
place yeah so four days you just need to
tell me these four days okay so for
Simplicity we're assuming the year is
not a leap year
what's leap year
the leap year affects only on how many
days on February right if it's leap year
how many days in February
um
[Music]
okay if it's not a leap year it's 28 am
I yeah
so for Simplicity it's not a leap year
we're given four days one with your
arrival day
arrive departure days and violence
arrive departure days how would you
calculate how many days you first stay
in the same place
logically I mean but for this one I
I just really did
[Music]
you can
uh well I can well
I don't know
to hold you how do you notice there this
this is like Eric arrives early and
and make sure that both at least one day
oh is it because with the like zero days
yeah it could be zero days for example
like you know you are here and lying
here all right in here right
so basically we are calculating the
intersection of two intervals right yeah
the interval look this is you Eric this
is you Ryan could be here or here yeah
how many possibilities so this is you
right Eric how many possibilities of
Ryan Ryan could be here
here
or here
here or here or here am I
this is my drawing do you understand my
drawing here this is the bottom one
thing at the top one
oh yes you're right yes okay
good spot so look this case
it's yellow days right am I
and all these we can calculate the same
way all these
of all the intersection what's the
intersection look here in this case it's
the least space in this case
is here here
and here
right
so basically this question is asking the
asking for an intercession home the the
lens of the intersection for two
intervals right because you arrive and
departure let's say interval right but
how do we go now the intervals how do we
convert a date
for example the date 10th of March is 03
10 right uh 15th of March
obviously 15 this is a stream how do we
convert these into a interval put it
this way how do we measure the date
between these two how do we measure how
do we calculate the date remember we
talk about how do we calculate the date
between two dates of the same year uh
if it's the same month you can
that's a good one but if it's not a
seven months what happened
if it's like what how many days between
30s of January to
25 of March how many days between
if it's a not a leap year if they are 28
days in February uh that would be one
the B
um let's see
how do you calculate 54.
killing it you just count it yeah you
can count it well computer how do we eat
that computer remember we can as look
look at these two days look I'm saying
yeah this is the beginning of the year
and in January 36 yeah
20th March 25 is here okay so is this
enough hint how many days between this
so how we can do it by what
how many days so how do we calculate it
minus yes so first of all we need to
calculate the number of days from the
beginning January 1st to this Thursday
and then we calculate the days from
January 1st to the second day I will do
the subtraction
is it simpler than your approach
all right is it simple
yes be confident it's simpler okay this
is not a question this is this is just
saying it's simpler okay we want to find
out the number of days between two dates
in a calendar year
all right then we can do this
subtraction
by calculating the number of days since
the first of January and we do the
subtraction right that would be easier
that's the way okay otherwise what would
you do you just count okay how many days
until the end of January plus the whole
month of February plus the days
in March right you need to do these
things it's complicated so this is
simpler okay then we can convert this
take the numbers then look for example
like we can convert the base numbers I
know we just have to check if the
departure day of Eric
today I'm Ryan
is before the arrival day of Eric or if
the arrival date of Ryan is after the
departure date of Eric then there is no
intersection then we return zero right
so what's the intercession is this bit
right is this bit so we want to get
these speeds this this bit is the
departure day the minimum of departure
day
and minus
the maximum of arrival date right yeah
okay this is one scenario okay how about
this
the minimum of the departure day is this
minus the maximum of departure day is
listed right it also works and how about
this
the minimum of departure day is this one
the maximum of arrival that is this one
so we minus
this one this one if there is a
intersection there are only three
possibilities how to calculate the
intersection the minimum of the
departure date minimum Risk 2 which is
this one oh and minus the maximum of
these two which is this one the minimum
of
departure day this one minus the maximum
of arrival date is this one right it's
listed the minimum of departure day
which is this one minus the maximum of
arrival day
this one which is this big
okay so first of all we need to know the
days right Define uh Define the days
Eric Eric
[Music]
one every two
volume one
volume two one is the Arrival Day two is
the departure day okay and first of all
we need to get the day of the month so
we we say months my state equals
for 31 28 31 yeah Etc right and this is
the number of days in each calendar
month so now we need to define a
function define the function f State
date
will be in the format of least uh the
month contacting it by a hyphen and the
day now we need to get it split this
yeah we need to split it by the
hyphen
so
the month
s months the date
equals
Theta split
then we talk about the split function
and we need to map it into integer
because it's a character we map it into
integer so it becomes uh integer right
look 15th of March so how many days
since the January
how many days since the generator 15th
of March
how do you get it look how much is this
one January February March here
so how would you do it
this is the first two I did together and
in 15. well done so we sum up the base
of the previous months and plus the day
of this month right return
some for Simplicity or you can just put
a zero here right so we can sum
empty up to
the month
right up to the month
then you will sum up the days in the
previous month plus the T right we need
to find out if there's an intersection
right
so
if Arabic
this is Eric one right this is Eric too
this is Ryan one lion two lion one lion
two so if Y and two
if Ryan to
okay so let me just write this E1
E1 E2 R1 R2 okay so if
so if R2 smaller than E1 or R1 is bigger
than
R1 is bigger than E2 then return
zero let's write and see here right hand
is here you are here there is no
intersection between zero otherwise
we can we need to do this absolute value
so we want to get a minimum of f
this is E1 E2 R1 R2 we want to get the
minimum of least departure day so E2
f r 2 minus the maximum of arrival date
which is f e 1
F R1 what
and then we have the plus one for the
end days right look
why do we need plus one match old one to
match O2 how many days
two days right so the plus one is
increasing okay
do you understand this approach
[Music]
so what yeah
R1 and RT and e r e are mainly a one and
E2
R1 and E one are the
uh they arrive and and e t and RT are we
going to leave yes
um
MD is the month
uh
every amount of days in every month
because
um
okay what's a key takeaway for this
approach what have you learned from this
approach
well
yeah
so you
please like that
minimum like starting day
and and and see the difference of it
like
minimum leaving day and the maximum
starting day weather yes the
intercession this video so we want to
get the minimum of the departure day
which is this one and the maximum was
the arrival day which is this one and we
do the subtractions this one it works
for these three scenarios at least one
this one or this one left I thought
obviously we have to check if there's
intersection okay so here this is the
day we we have to do this F function for
you as well right so maybe we can save
this variable yeah we can save save this
well but day one day two you know
okay okay so that's one way but a second
way yeah very similar right and I'm
going to talk straight away and it's
very convenient how many days in a year
uh 355 and 356 on Olympia okay in this
case it's not Olympia right so it's 365.
so how about if I probably this is 365
from the you know from the zero one to
Etc tier 364.
it's yellow the first thing okay so look
nice you know so I start with zero yeah
anyway you are here obviously the life
function is still needed right we need
to convert one state to a day since
January so if we're here look
if we arrive here right this is a run
with the numbers 365 number so if I'm
saying you are here you arrive here I'm
going to plus one here
and then you leave here
and then you leave here and I need to
minus one on the next day right so if
you leave
on the fifth of the if you departure and
the fifth of March then on the 6th of
March I minus one
okay only six months
yeah yeah I know I know just some
example here here okay right so now
Ryan Ryan arrive somehow here right so
you need some plus one here
and if if it departure uh this one and
then you do minus one on the next day
okay so he's covered this period I have
this 365 of uh 65 packets you can say
the counters by bucket integers so for
example you are here 90.
first one and you leave at 95 minus one
and then y incomes that 93 plus one 98
minus one
that's something like an example
once that that's very simple and then I
can just go through this
I have a content right at the beginning
it's all zero zero here so look
zero plus one is one
what
and then I can do this accumulate right
one one one one two two two two two two
two two one
one one one one one one zero
okay so what I'm doing here so how many
days
how many days
how can we know which days are two
people in the same place so what numbers
are we looking for
two exactly we are looking for two
accumulate so if you get it so it's a
ruler a ruler you know each number on
the ruler right the represent a counter
a number
and I just have to Market you increment
one on day 90 and equipment on 95
because they're living right
and Ryan
comes arrives at 93 leaves at 98 right
so I just have to do this uh plus one
plus one minus one minus one but this is
not enough I just have to go from the
beginning with the counter now it's zero
zero zero zero one okay
and then we are looking for two
how many days we just have to kind of
days blind sweep
from the left to the right
usually encounter oh we can do is
accumulate using accumulate right
remember not accumulate what's
accumulate one two three four accumulate
this we turn this into a cumulate let's
accumulate and then you become one
one plus two one plus two plus three one
plus two plus three plus four yeah
accumulate quick example yeah we talk
about that one three
six ten right
yeah
okay I'm gonna divide the term for this
one okay there are 365 days so let's do
these days
equals
at the beginning zero times I need to
put it as 3767 because I I need to
Market it next day
minus one right I'm leaving at
day 90. but I'm still in that place on
day 90. I'm away I'm not there on day 91
right
so we need to plus one okay let's say
you want E2 ah one uh
plus two
uh 300 that's a good question okay
365 days all right on on not until they
leave here and nearly here 366. how come
she plus two that's a good question or
LF function okay F function you know the
F function this is the number of things
generate and that's a very good question
yeah it is 366 but F function returns
one number one for first of January
all right so this function returns
number one on the first of January all
right the day
zero is actually not used so we start
from 1 to
365 right and then plus one that is 1 to
366 but in order to use the index
366 you have to add okay 367 because the
index style is zero right like this yeah
you're listening that's very good
question and
let's say you want YouTube it's already
converted as a date right it's a it's a
number integer right so we can just do
this base
E1 plus equal one
face
E2 plus one eh now tell me why do we
need to plus one here minus equal one
and days
R1
plus equal one phase
R2 plus 1 minus equal one okay look I
live on Friday so which day I'm away
so Friday I'm taking an airplane
so I'm still at a place right so I plus
one the next day the Saturday I'm not in
that place or I'm not in the Paris
yeah so I need to pass on here yeah I'm
leaving a Friday but I'm still in Paris
on Friday so I'm not in Paris the next
day plus day okay yeah
make sense
okay and now we just have to do this
like the answer equals zero and then for
I in range we start from the first day
to 360
six right
then
there's a counter C equals zero C
plus equals these days
I right if c equal equal to then answer
plus equals one right return
answer all right this is called the
that's what we're saying like zero zero
zero zero one one one one one one one
two two two two one one one two two yeah
that's why it's basically we install a a
prefix prefix sum
accumulate some in a c and we check if
it's a day to use layer 2 2 means the
two people on the day right and we
increment if it's a two then we
increment
obviously we can do this better so we
can accumulate 10 is into accumulate so
days equals this accumulate days right
then we do this accumulation and then we
just have to check in return
days
.com
two right look a little bit simple come
to next day
what's time complexity for this one uh
is it very tricky oh one yes why is that
one because it's the numbers yeah
because look constant right they're only
365 days they come be more the most you
can run is 365 days the iteration right
the previous one
is still one right we have two in this
conversion and then they're only 12
months we are only 12 months and the F
function also takes the o1 constant
because they're only 12 months the
maximum the maximum number of two ratio
you need to run to get a day since
January is 12.
comes space Bozo one okay so what have
you learned today and can you tell me
what have you learned there are two
solutions what have you learned which
one you think is better easy to
understand
okay what's the problem what Solutions
can we apply
which one you like and that's it
uh well
uh
uh two people yeah two people and they
guarantee this hotel yes and
so we
say they have a arriving day and
believing day yes and so we want to work
out uh how many days Days uh there they
are
in the same place in the hotel yeah okay
so what solution what's the first
solution what's the second solution well
so we so we have e e one E1 and R1 uh of
arriving days and
ET and artistic of uh leaving there so e
e so so the maximum of
of arriving day
the difference
is the maximum of the difference of the
maximum arriving day at the minimum of
uh leaving the a well that's the first
solution during subtraction okay and the
second solution what's this
so we say for sorry
we have this
kind of number line or something of some
sort uh 366
um Dave and
and
so three plus one for the arriving there
and minus one for the living day the
next of the living day right yeah and
then we do this scan from the beginning
to this accumulation anyway what are we
looking for which number we are looking
for
uh two and what's two mean there's two
that's right yeah and that's how we
count it and we can do this accumulate
some right using a community over to
this simple I post common spaces over
okay let's see for today bye bye
bye bye bye
nice hello hello Mr Ryan all right
right yeah so let's look at this uh
interesting problem Eric and Ryan right
Eric and Ryan you're going to Paris okay
you're going to Paris Eric arrives in
Paris at the 1st of March
and he left Paris at the 6th of March
okay and now Ryan okay he arrives at
Paris at I don't know second of March I
leave at 10 no match geez
at least there's no luck before you like
Eric guys one to ten and we go seven to
twenty that's fine okay so the question
comes that how many days you post in
Paris
um
this departure you still counted in
Paris okay five how what are those
well the second third fourth day fancy
okay so it's this video two three four
five six okay so five okay for
Simplicity let's just only assumed you
both arrived in the same calendar year
okay so you first arrive and departure
in the same calendar year and also for
Simplicity we assume it's uh not a leap
year do you still remember what's leap
year
yes it's been February has 29 days okay
when it's the leap year the February has
29 but when it's not leap year 28 days
okay that's good so we assume it's not
Olympia so February has 28 days
I give you like the day for example Eric
arrives at uh
when I arrive and Eric leaves
so can we visualize it look Eric here
right if you have arrive departure and
then you arrives departure
so how many possibility look
Eric Ryan okay I give a few Solutions
right the possibilities Eric
Ryan
right I arrived early Eric
come back again no no no one finger Go
Eric
Ryan
anymore
um
all right and when I go I arrive before
him and leave before him
we're done okay so basically this in
what cases there are no days you both
spend together so there's zero days you
spend together which is two cases there
are no intercession so basically looks
the the one at the right top right yeah
these two okay so you see so we're
visualizing the program in intervals so
basically we want to find out the number
of days the intersection between two
intervals right so here in this case
look this one this one there's no
intercession all the rest look all the
rest
the they are intercession right so how
do we find all the intercession look at
this okay let me let me put this a
little bit longer okay so look the
intersection is this speed right
all right
this intercession
right this intercession this bit this
insertation a little bit okay all these
four scenarios
we can visualize it as this one
all these scenario four scenarios we can
get an intercession bye all right look
at this ends this is E1 E2 and this is
R1 R2 okay okay so we want to find out
the integration so this intersection is
the minimum of E2 R2
okay minimum of E2 R2
and the left bit
is maximum of E1 R1
okay
look at this and hold on is that look E1
E2 R1 R2 the minimum of E2 R2
a maximum of E1 R1 okay the minimum of
E2 R2 is this one the maximum of E1 R1
is this one so the intersection is this
speed yes it's right look E1 E2 R1 R2
the minimum of E2 R2 is this bit right
the maximum of R1 UI is here right so
intersection is fifth
and and again here E1 E2 R1 R2 the
minimum of E2 R2 is here the maximum of
E1 R1 is here right you see okay
so we can take the intercession by this
it's from the maximum this one to
minimum so we go to the subtraction and
do this abs
at the low Value Plus one we need to
plus one for the end days right because
you arrive on the first leave a second
how many days you spend together in
Paris two minus one plus one is two days
you call it a day on your departure as
being in Paris I mean we are given the
Theta will be something like this first
of all we need to convert a date into a
number so what number how can we convert
this into a number
all the data in the one calendar year so
we can count how many days since were
they
so I give you two days like
can you tell me the number of days
between
fifth of March to
1st of May
how many days in between
how many days between 5th of March to
1st of May how many days in between
how do you come I mean let me answer
this question how many days between
fifth or March to 1st of May
um
what's 31 days
[Music]
but how do you come use your finger like
start from Counting from fifth
31 minus five thirty one twenty six okay
yeah okay so you kind of remain again
yeah but you have to find out that the
remaining days in the next government
right and plus the next home month plus
next whole month all right so basically
you don't reach this way right look
uh this is each month yeah so 30 plus
2016. okay so you are counting here all
right so basically 56. okay look your
approach is counting look this is fifth
um uh match you count the remaining days
in that match you plus the whole month
April you plus the date for the May
right
yeah you do it counting you added this
yeah
is there other ways to do it I mean look
how to do it what's here generally fast
so how do we use this how do we count
the days
how do we know this piece what's this
bit you want to know this thing right
your approach is added up these three
segments right but let's say if I tell
you okay I know that how many days since
January 1st to May
is this bit
yeah and how many days from January to
here is this week so what's this bit
so I know this bit I know the speed so
what's this bit if this is a and this is
B so what's this see what's this C
equals what a minus
a minus B okay how do we calculate two
days in one calendar year you get the
number that you know that it ends
a little bit and they made the first
and you came from January the first
yeah let's give that an A and what
um and then you count January to the
5th of March the first number yeah and
then you get B
the same thing for people and I used to
the subject that's normal taste the key
thing here is that we can count how many
days between two days in one calendar
year using the subtraction we need to
count how many days since the first of
January and then if we do that we can do
this subtraction okay so suppose we have
this function f f day let's test the
number of the things the first of
January in that calendar year okay
yeah I function and now we can do this
if I want to get the number of days D1
to D2 then we can do this fd1 minus fd2
abs
plus one okay then we can map the date
to the number of days to the integer now
we can do this simple math here all
right of course we have to check these
two conditions when there are no
intersections if E2 okay so the E1 E2 R1
R2 okay so if R2 is more than E1 or R1
is bigger than E2 there is no
interception now with the 10 0 otherwise
we return this ABS mean E2 R2 minus
maximum E1 R1 plus one so E2 R2
E1 R1 E2 R2 are the integer on the
number of days since
1st of January and that can be obtained
by this F function f function I'm going
to Simply write the one okay now all
three hyphen 05
a string then first of all we need to
split this right Define f day
a a equals Mac
integer D dot split
hyphen
Theta spray hyphen and we got a way with
two string o305 and now we need to map
to integer convert it to three and five
once we have three and five so I'm going
to place M months
and Day date
okay months and day these are two
integer and now we need to count how
many days since the first of January
right look how many days in January
31 right 28 February it's not a leap
year 30 31 Etc right second of February
March doesn't have 30 days
April has five days of March of 31.
thank you see so much how many days
between January 1st to 50 March how do
we count it
how would you do it at 3128 together and
then plus five right
so okay so you sum up the months before
that right all right so we'll return
some
elements then we can say days up to
up two months right but up to months
after a month we put the extra Jailer at
the beginning right so but because we
are not getting that the month is one
one is January and the index style is
the zero so we put that extra zero at
the beginning so we sum up that and plus
stay right that's the day that's the
first approach basically a function we
we take in the string of date we split
it we convert it to integer and then we
count how many days
the whole month
right up to the previous months and plus
the extra day right extra day of the
government and that F function retains
the number of days in January we using
this estate F function will be able to
map the string date in an arrival they
departure day into
integer and then we compare we just
basically transform this problem into
checking if their intercession between
two intervals yeah and they are quite a
few possibilities am I right yeah
okay the time complexity and space
versus oh one constant here because they
are at most 12 months 365 days am I yes
another way it will be quite interesting
it's called and we will be able to uh
use this prefix sum accumulate remember
accumulate so look how many days in a
year
365 right
not a ruler
it moves okay the first day
second day Third Day Etc okay to 265
okay
that was not equal I know I know the
example so the days are too big okay so
look first of all you know there's an
Arrival Day right something that I like
right I need to convert it to a lumber a
number right so I have uh E1 E2 E1 for
the Arrival Day of Eric E2 for departure
day of Eric R1 R2 Arrival Day for Orion
departure day for Ryan and these are
four numbers map to this right map to
this ruler E1 this here is E1 right
and here is into
and for example here
is R1
here is R2 okay
at the beginning all these 356
365 63 packets right you can send it in
the packet each packet contains a
counter number
so E1 I need to plus one here
and E2
e to the next of E2 I need to minus one
right because Eric is still in Paris at
E2 but not in Paris when E2 plus one
right here
and right and again here plus one and
minus one the next day after the
departure I have a counter okay counter
zero zero zero one
okay
two
two two two one
one one one it's yellow
yeah okay let me do it again look it's
yellow zero zero zero zero plus one one
one one two
one
okay so let me know this so you could be
like that zero zero zero one plus one
here
plus one two two two two two two two
minus one one one minus one zero two
zero so how many days the your post in
Paris
how many days you posted what are we
looking for is what are we looking for
here
um what are we looking for here in this
land look at what I did yeah I came in
the air counter zero zero zero zero plus
one one one one one plus one two two two
two minus one one one one one minus one
zero zero zero zero I have a counter so
what number
are we looking for at least here we need
to count which number as uh two what
does it mean two by two
bang sweet from the left to the right
right I have a line sweeping yeah okay
yeah so first of all we have released
the counter day days at the beginning
equals zero times 367. okay why is this
367 because the day start from the first
one so it's we need to use the index 1
to 365 right but we need to plus one
thing why as I said the minus one
what happened when should we minus one
the next day of departure am I you're
leaving at least Saturday you're still
in
Paris on Saturday right you are not here
on Sunday so we need minus one the next
day of departure so that's why we need
to pass one is so the index we are
looking for is 1 to 366. so we need to
do this times uh allocate and array with
367.
right we are not using the first index
anyway
okay and then now it's easier base
f
E1
plus equal one base
f e 2
plus 1 okay departure then the next day
depart today minus equal one
days
f
1 plus one uh R1
plus equal one
that is
f r 2 plus 1 minus equal one okay the
next state of the departure then we just
do this here answer equals zero C equals
zero for I in red we start from what
first day two
right 367 okay
C plus equal base
I if c equal equal to answer plus equal
one right and return answer look see the
counter and I need to check each day
from 1 to 366. C plus this one that he
was doing counting zero zero zero if
it's two if it's two then I increase
right
base we can do this we can use the
accumulation so first of all we
converted the accumulate right a equals
this
accumulate accumulate
base
and then we just need to return a DOT
count two one what's accumulate one two
three four an array with one two three
four what's accumulative when you do the
accumulate you accumulate returns an
iterator you'll be convert it to a list
it will become one one plus two one plus
two plus three one plus two plus three
plus four right this is accumulate so
each one
become the sum
from first element to the current
element right one one plus two one three
six ten right so exactly here
plus 0 plus 0 plus 0 plus 1 plus 1 plus
1 minus one minus one minus one yeah
okay
next this complexity is one constant
because this problem we are given two
days and then they are maximum 365 days
and a maximum 12 months it's about the
problem so the time and space complexity
is a one
okay okay so what have you learned today
what have you learned today what's the
problem and how many ways were you
solving this which way you like online
okay can you can you try to say a few
more sentences okay not just say a few
words come on try to for example I'm I'm
just to explain to me what have you
learned today
[Music]
calendar
what's the problem come on try to
explain them all we want to find how
much how many days are we together okay
and how do we do it we used
um we
line thing line method
what's the alarm method
is when you zero zeros and you're
looking for two
how many days
yeah accumulate somewhere so the problem
is that we are given two pairs of
arrival and departure days right E1 E2
represent the Arrival Day and departure
day for Eric
and then these four dates uh in one
calendar and we are assuming it's a not
a leap year there are 365 days and 28
days in February the question is that we
want to find out how many days that you
both African lion stay in the same place
right we need to convert the date
actually date a stream into a number and
we can do that by counting the number of
days since January when we're converting
to the dates to a number it's easy to do
the math to calculate how many days
between two days right all right for
example Eric arrive at the 1st of March
and departure at 5th on March you cannot
subtract two days easily but you can
subtract two numbers easily okay so the
first way is that when we do that we are
actually mapping the problem into
finding the intercession of two
intervals on the line right and then
there are two possibilities that there
is no intersection when the departure
day
of the Ryan is before the arrival date
of area or when they Arrival Day of Ryan
is after the departure day of Eric
there's no intercession otherwise we can
get the infrastructure by the mean
E2 R2
minus
Max
E1 r1s we just showed it before okay
that's one way the second method is that
we have a 360
566 bucket with the numbers a counter
right and then we can plus one on a
departure day and -1
on the next day of departure day and
then we do this accumulate some
a prefix sum from left to the right
let's call line sweet
and then we are looking for the value
when it's become two that means that
uh two people are on the same place okay
that was Agron takes one time in one
space because this is the bounding
problem okay that only uh 12 months 365
days okay that's it for today
bye-bye bye bye