last time we talked about Jason
JavaScript object notation it's like the
dictionary in Python right something
like that yeah curly brace
it could be in the form of curly brace
like defined as an object on an array
name the keys are interval code name
like Eric
comma
and H okay something like that and it
could be another object and then it
could be another curly brace or it could
be an array right this is Json pretty
much similar like the dictionary so why
do we need a Json we need this to store
and transport the data it's used to
carry the data right it's used to carry
data especially in application between
the client and server and look at this
moment if you write this format if you
store the data in this one you can give
it to other people and people cannot
understand it right it's pretty
stressful one right
yeah and the computer is very good at
passing this data How about if the
values has that code now let's just
tested how about if I want to store the
code double code in in the value field
so we need to escape it right we need to
escape for example we want to store the
e r i c with this code so I can't just
put it here right this could be causing
the problem so what do we need to do is
we just have to do this
a backscape Escape Escape
you know you can find a key
just around the
where's the key where's the basket is
here this is a part of the above the
answer right so this is just to mean
like the next character yeah
we it's actually the code the value we
want to store it's not part of the you
know
part of the syntax
all right okay so this is Jason So today
we're going to talk about another
another format data format called XML
which is very popular as well so this is
Jason this is XML XMS stands for
extensible expensive markup languages
markup language okay
so what does it look like
a person
name
Eric
named
h
10. age
and then Hobbies uh games for example
you want the game right
again so we have to do this game
and I don't know what can we like
Pokemon
Pokemon also you could be running away
right
copies game program so again I'm running
out of space no game and then this
should be
Hobbies right Hobbies
and then puppies
and
game and so we have a Pokemon so Pokemon
okay game okay I need to close it Eric
is 10 years old and it's Hobbies is is
games
okay so again similar to the Json it's
very easy to read right this is the
format the syntax of the XML so
as you can see look these so if you have
this person yeah this is an element and
you need to close it by forward stash
this is called element element
right
and each XML should have only one loot
element only one loot okay you cannot
have multiple rules
okay you can put another thing here
called the address
so each xml5 has only one nude element
so each root element can contain text
txt text could be a string or you could
input template it as an value like Edge
and you can also contain some other
elements look this person contains other
elements okay okay so and another thing
about XML is the element can contain the
attribute so the name you can have a
name and then you have this type
can attribute title Mr
all right and then Eric
name okay
look this is the element star element
and end element with this syntax and
then look at least attribute key value
key value pairs key value you could have
multiple attributes this is called
attribute so to sum up a XML file
contains only one Loop element and then
it could have other elements uh the text
attribute and it could be mixed on them
so XML is used to carry data right and
then it's only carries data it doesn't
do with any other logic so it doesn't
tell you where the data is for it
doesn't tell you how to display the data
right we're probably going to tell about
HTML in a browser yeah you type in the
URL for example google.com yeah http
as google.com and then there's a search
box and another search here right this
is the page displayed in browser so what
describes the page the layout is HTML
it's quite similar to this XML but XML
is used to store data only to carry data
on the HTML HTML
is used to you know describe how the
page looks like okay so if none element
load element does not contain anything
because for example you can say like
copies yeah Hobbies if you don't have
any copies you can do it this way and
this is to close it
oh you just you know just do this hobby
with nothing in there right even there's
nothing there's no tax inside a text
look this is start ending tag you can
just do this change this here and put
okay this means that it has an element
copy but it's empty okay yes we talk
about elements in XML we talk about the
attribute we talk about the text we talk
about the empty tag okay so we could
have a pollock in XML at the beginning
of the XML document so it looks like
something like this so in XML prologue
we declare the versions The encodings so
the default encoding is utf-8 we could
have utf-16 or different encoding
specified in the XML document the XML
prologue is optional it's not mandatory
I like Json it could have a comment so
Json does not have comments everything
is part of the data in XML we could have
comments declared in this way so this is
not part of the you know data it's not
part of the syntax this is just for
humans okay so and here let's take a
look at this simple XML and the XML can
have only one loot element and which we
can have different uh XML text nasty
inside another so here look this C tag
does not have any closing
packs here but instead we use this
simple syntax to close it if there is
nothing in there and then we have
attributes we can have a different
number of attributes for each tag so
okay so let me write a Json and then can
you convert it to XML there is no right
or wrong answer just to test your
knowledge about XML how it looks like
what Pokemon comes into your mind well
um Christmas
okay
name alternate
Christmas audio space n
e
c r
V and a
and then does it have a any attributes
right the psychic type type
psychic
p
s why
c h i
C or do we convert this to XML Pokemon
name you want to give a joke
yeah because this is Jason XML
you need to have one root element
remember we talk about so probably I'll
fix this for you so have a Pokemon right
Pokemon and then start here at the end
there's a Pokemon
[Music]
yeah
okay
uh
you can have tests so you don't need
this right and then you need to close it
okay that's good just that yeah and then
what else hey
what's the time here
and then uh
-huh yeah yeah look and this is eczema
so it's basically we use this kind of
thing to carrying the data huh
and then you need to close it guys close
it
okay we need a double clue to wrap up
the values right but if the value
contains the double code you need to
escape it right how about here what kind
of characters we need to escape here
so it doesn't confuse FIFA this one yeah
look this one yeah we need to capture a
leaf right escape this these two left
right for example if I want to carry
this data like the a we don't carry this
data in XML so if you put that name here
what happened
you confuse the XML so is this an
element or is this the text right yeah
so it's a text so how do we fix it so we
use it
now we want to we want to start it how
do we store it so it doesn't confuse the
XML it's a tag it's an element so we can
use this
will change to n
t Okay least we change it to n
GT
what does it mean look less
greater and and end is the
the thing on number seven number seven
not basically this symbol and semicolon
okay semicolon yeah this is how it is
heavy so we we can do this here
LT
GT okay so but in this case we know this
is a value this is not attacked same
thing here look if we don't have a
double quote a in a name right in that
name we can't just write it here like
that right because they're confused with
the Json is this starting uh or is this
an ending
ending the value type you can add a
backscape we can escape the double chord
here okay so what have you learned today
and that's it what have you done
about
um XML
x m a extensible markup language
so in computers in many many
applications programs computerized
programs we use the XML to store the
configuration look which leave
it's easy for human to understand right
it's very easier very straightforward we
have this efficient algorithm to pass
with XML look if I want to get the value
type then I can say Pokemon DOT type
hi and it's a path now we know then
computer knows to get a value here
document okay and here's the same this
is the entire object right the third
type
one question for you think about it so
given a same data right if I want to
store the name and type which one you
think is shorter
which one you think is shorter Json yeah
obviously because look this has the
overhead storing that element text right
yeah which one is easier to understand
simple to read XML it's very rare
structures right the element has the
names but this one is just the key value
pairs right okay that's it for today bye
bye bye bye