yeah yeah so what's this uh three uh and
it's a tree and it's also a
um binary and also it's uh
is it a Furniture tree
no it's not oh yeah on the left is to be
strictly smaller than a little down the
right should be bigger so this one is
not right it's not balances a tree it's
a graph right and for the trees it's
like the direct a cyclical right
directly a cyclical directly means that
the only the parent goes to the kids
like this is the parent node the kids
now parent to the children notes
the ones we love the children we call it
leaves the one without the parents we
call it loot there's only one loot in a
in a tree right and there's the only
maximum two kids per note in a balanced
treatment okay so given these are buying
a tree I mean it could be any vanity so
with numbers okay positive numbers and
we want to find out if there's a path
from a loot to the leaf that equals to
the Target 22. you know can you find the
parts to the leaf beef note that the sum
of all the notes equals to 22 in this
particular binary
oh yeah five from eleven two yeah five
or eleven two Okay so
how did you find these two I want to
know how how did you find this look how
did you find that thing You Know Carl I
mean how do how did you find this
particularly pass that equals the the
sum of the all the nodes equals to 22.
you're trying right you're trying it's
it's possibility I'm right
a deficit deficit and
will you talk about these two algorithms
when we're solving a lot of the three
problems right so for the trees most
likely you use the one travel cycle
which is could be pepper search or
perfect search there are quite a few
different deficitors right remember the
traveler
the pre-order
in order yeah
close order yeah
B3 and also you know reverse in order
the pre-order what's pre-order pre-order
is the note left to right right in order
is left and now right those are the
reason left right now okay if we're
going for this pre-order so what's the
order of the default search between
order the note left to right so what's
the pre-order five
full
eleven
seven
two
eight
thirteen four one eight well done okay
and how about the breakfast search
all the whatever eight eleven thirty
four seventy one
so it's basically a level by level yeah
we use the Q remember double mdq yeah
the Q first thing first off we go this
way this is in Q we put push an element
to the Q we take one out of the Q okay
Okay so coming back to this question we
can solve this using the default search
right it doesn't matter which order it
is right as long as we need to carry out
the sum right so it could be done with
two ways so when we do this type of such
recursion we can store the current total
sum from the loot right
and this is one way and you tell me
which is the other way okay current time
is five current sum is nine current sum
is
20. current time is 27 countenance time
is 22. current time is 5.
and here is 26 here is 17 and 18 right
so we pass the current sum to the leaf
notes on the way we traveled in
different search am I right we
accumulate the sum right we still
accumulation from the loot to the
current node what's the other way what's
the opposite why are we storing the
accumulation from the low to you know to
the current node so we can compare if it
is equals to Target right is it sorry to
figure out
if it's 22 no yeah to figure out if it's
22 and also it has to be a leave now
right and what's the other way instead
of adding we can well
so yeah whether we can structure the
notes from the Target and I'm going to
reach the thief notes it has to be zero
all right so 22 okay now I visit here so
I take five out which is 17.
I take four out
13.
take 11 out which two
take two up is zero okay so I'm reaching
and leave now and it's the sum is zero
so we found one path all right
yeah the other way is to edit so current
sum is zero plus five
plus four
plus eleven plus two is twenty-two right
so this is the recursion deficit and the
Order of traversal the tree does not
matter and we can implement the default
search using the recursion and iterative
right the iterative I'm going to talk
about that in the breakfast next lesson
because it's quite similar like only
difference is that we can change the Q
to stack and then it becomes the
iterative deficit okay so I'm going to
write this okay Define that first search
so loot and then current sum which way
you like to accumulate or to subtract
plus then plus okay so look at this is
current summary current sum
so first of all if not root
then we do 10 true or false if the tree
is empty we do tend two of us
question okay that's a very good
question if the sum is yellow and that's
arguable right if you're given an empty
tree
and then you say the target is some is
zero in this case you return true or
false
all right it's a it's arguable but let's
say we do 104 right because that it's an
empty tree how can you sum up an empty
tree
S Plus equal right
value right
then if we check if s equals equal equal
Target right
and also the current loot is a leaf node
so how do you check if a note is a leaf
node
uh if it doesn't have any children so
and do the left is none
and
Pluto y
is none okay we can also say if not do
the left if not do that right right land
return true right
we need to recursively check the left
tree and right three right so return
that first search
left
pass down the sum and no o
here is no off
this should be n or or one question for
you this function because we check if
the current subtree is starting with the
loot
right and the sum
can we find the path that equals to the
Target
right on each note we updated the sum
and pass it down to the left tree and
the right tree
so here let's show it use the end or all
so oh yeah obviously look in the left
tree or in the right tree right so here
we should use the O right if we want to
subtract which way we need to change
we accumulate the sum from the root to
the leaf node and if we want to do this
opposite way which is to subtract so
minus equal n what else should I change
yes
yellow okay and that will be it okay so
therefore search each note is written
only once so the term complexity is O
and and N is the number of notes in the
binary tree okay and the space
complexity we're using a recursion as
the implicit
um usage of Stack the complexity is o h
okay H is the height of the tree and in
the worst case h equals n in the best
case is H equals log n right H equals
log n in the best cases why is that look
in Balance financially there are seven
nodes right seven notes and the height
is only three so it's locked to seven
which approximately equals three okay
this is how we get the Old Log edge here
so what have you learned today
how can we solve it
back by the tree and
um
we we have Target yeah so what are we
trying to do with the target
doing the Sun
so what are we trying to do trying to
find out what
if we do any leaf
the sun will add up to with tea we're
done and then I work now we're using
today we have a certain difference
is this a deficit your professor yeah
see
from the rich people
leave we even
add or subtract and so that adds so you
just add the numbers as you don't know
and then see if we can add up to tick
and and then all but Contracting a bit
is
um you you get tea and subtract the
number as you go on along the Earth kind
of thing okay what's the time come next
week what is n
the N is the number of the notes in the
tree what's that space complexity what's
this look following recursion needs to
go that deep o h h is the height right
in the balance tree The Edge is the
roughly equals to the login right okay
that's it for today bye bye-bye
nice let's take a look at these two
approaches those are recursion deficit
let's take a look at this the one on the
left so we calling this step a search
function with the target the end is to
subtract node values from the targets
until you reach the leaf nodes this is
to check if it's a leaf node and if the
sum has become zero then it will turn
true if it's a leaf now we need to check
if the sum becomes zero otherwise we'll
recursively check in the left tree and
the right tree right and the one on the
right is slightly different we we are
calling and beginning with the Lord when
we saturated sum remaining sum from the
target so instead of subtracting
at the beginning of location we put it
we delayed it we delayed it when we are
calling the recursion right so
4K in left and right so it has two kids
then if K if the left tree or right tree
is not empty it's not new now we're
calling the recursion with the remaining
sum if any of those
we found the path then we return to
otherwise return before okay so this is
static difference updating the sum
happens when calling the recursion
function and this one is not updating
the sum happens at the beginning of the
recursion we can accumulate some instead
of minors we can accumulate some and
check if s equals to the Target in both
cases a few moments later hello Ryan I
okay so look at these this is the final
tree right find another tree we are also
given a Target so can you find the pass
from the loot to the leaf that the sum
of the notes that equal to the Target
and look these are the leaf notes which
does not have any kids this one a salute
which does not have an appearance okay
yeah the beef nose allows without any
kit and this is the pantry each now has
almost two kids
all right we're given a Target P equals
nine can you find out if there is a such
pass from the loot to the leaves that
the sum equals the target
yeah exactly one plus two plus six okay
yeah yeah yeah yeah now you get it there
okay
okay so this question let me rephrase it
again so we're given the binary right
and each planetary each node contains uh
integer uh positive negative doesn't
matter and we also given a Target the
task is that we want to find out if it's
possible to travel from the root to the
any eighth note
let the notes the sum of the the notes
that we visited equals to the Target
am I so remind me what kind of the
agreement can we apply in the final tree
how do we travel as a binary usually
level by level what do you call it
breakfast
PFS and BFF okay in PFS what kind of
order is this one two four five six
seven well done so it's never by level
we use the Q DQ double and the Q yeah
you'll remember that all right we talk
about lots of these three algorithm
right and the default search if we are
going deepest yeah deep is
six foot seven yeah yeah we're done
that's one particular type of search
contains a lot of orders so if we visit
the node first and let's write or visit
the left note right or visit the
this one right or sometimes we have this
reverse in order so this is pre-order
because look look at this
look at the now the visit if we order in
order close order right and then what
you said is but basically the pre-order
meaning we reach the due to know first
and then we visit the left tree left
tree this part and then we visit the
right way so it's one
two five six four seven okay and
sometimes we have a reverse in order so
reverse in order will be I don't know
maybe R and a right something like that
reversing order or reverse because or
the reverse per order today we're going
to talk about the deficit to do this and
then in the next lesson we're going to
talk about professors so this deficit
preferences you have the two most
important aegon that we can apply on the
trees and graphs Etc because the binary
is a graph it's a dag do you still
remember what's the AG
um
black tag yes directed a cyclic graph
directly means that there's a direction
basically I don't draw the direction
here from the parents to the kids right
so usually you given the note you can
only visit the kit from parents but you
cannot call vice versa so directly a
cycle a cycle there's no cycle graph a
tree is a graph okay given this attack
and we can apply the deficit to find out
if let's pass from the root of the leaf
right previously you said okay there was
a past one plus two plus six equals the
nine so how did you find this it just
looked right
that's right yeah so we just look at it
but this is a very tiny planetary right
if it's a big one how would you do it I
mean if like lots of notes right so
for every person you have to recalculate
or something for example in this case
here this path is one plus two plus five
and here this past is one plus two plus
six so you should notice anything in
common one plus two plus five one plus
two plus six anything in common let's
have one plus two plus
so what does it mean so as long as we
travel down the tree we can carry the
Sun from the loo to the current right
all right so look at here is one plus
two here is one plus four and here is
one plus two plus five here is one plus
two plus six here is one plus four plus
seven so we do remember this so it means
that we don't have to every time we
don't have to go back to the loot to
calculate the sum so we just traveled
the tree using depth search and then we
can accumulate some right and the other
way is the opposite so look here we have
one plus two plus five one plus two plus
six and we check if it equals to the
nine another way is we take one out from
nine five eight eight minus two
I'm six minus six zero and they need to
be zero when it reaches they're leaving
away there are two ways right it's
similar right yeah okay so let's do this
type of search as long as we carrying
the sum accumulate some or we keep
subtracting the value of current root
from the sum remaining sum okay
Define that for such root the current
sum right so if not load
or if loot is empty then we return two
of us if the note is empty with the
tension of us
first let's try yes first
otherwise we first of all S Plus equal
if we accumulate X Plus equal root of
value right
we added the value the sum this is
accumulation we added this value right
we added one plus two and then we have
to check if s equals equal equal T if we
get this T but we also have to check if
n
and do top left
is none how do you check if a node is a
leaf node how do you check if you know
this is a leaf note
we check if I have any kids if the sun
with your time is Target and then if
this node is additional will return true
right
so look we have accumulated some Target
and then this node is a leaf node now we
listen true otherwise we have two
recursive check in the left three and
the right tree right yep so return
left
s and therefore search through the right
F okay so can you tell me here
whether I should put a n or should I put
an O which one
now I have to check if let's pass on the
left tree or even letter pass on the
right tree
so is this n or
I have to check because we on the left
tree or on the right tree so it's this
error oh obviously I just said it right
I just say it's all right so it's all we
accumulate the sum and we pass it down
because we have done it here so we can
pass the sum
here to the left tree we're not visiting
the left tree and the right tree we just
have to basically check if laser path
on the left tree or if you let the
surprise on the right tree and we pass
down the accumulation right the other
way the opposite way is to take the sum
taking the value out of the topic
something right yeah nine take one out
which is a
k for R which is four take seven out
which is not zero right
so
I just have to change this to minus
and then I have to change this to zero
so if it's accumulating something we can
just say return that first search blue
start with the zero
if we are taking that value out of the
remaining sum then we have to call it as
def as such low the target okay
the time till next day oh if they are
unknowns in the financial what's the
time let's see
oh
and well because we are visiting each no
exactly one right now we have
accumulated some we have this update is
done remaining some are accumulation it
doesn't matter okay the space complexity
oh and and yes in the worst case it's
Owen but precisely oh
H is the height of the binary tree right
so because the recursion this is
recursion in a recursion calling step
calling depth yes the edge in the worst
case is n you know the when the tree is
like that right you know
when each note of the tree has only one
kit
why look there are three nodes and the
height is three all right yeah
okay so in the best cases when a tree is
balanced so there are seven nodes
and is seven height is approximately
lock lock 7 which is three okay
approximately three okay
am I right does it make sense you know
why the login yeah the final research
each time we cut in half right so when
we go to the left we abandon the right
tree when we go to the right we abandon
the left tree so let every time we cut
it in half let's lock in well that's
where the login is for in the best cases
when the tree is balanced balance means
the height the absolute High difference
is smaller than equal than one between
the left and the right that's a Delta H
is the high difference okay so what have
you learned today and that's it Ryan
what have you learned today what's the
problem and what what eggline are we
using today
we we have we have a tree we have binary
specifically and what are we trying to
find out t what's the
number yeah what are we trying to find
out here
can you say a whole sentence
add number
equals
we want to find out if there's a pass
from the loot to the leaf node let the
sum of the notes we have visited equals
to the Target right am I so there are
two ways of uh solving it
yeah and for deficitors we can do it
like two ways
yeah it's easier so next one we're going
to talk about purposes for the 10th
research we can uh pass down the value
that accumulate some line it could be
accumulation or it could be a dimension
okay that's it for today bye-bye bye bye