hello Mr Eric I right
so let's take a look at this advice so
we talk about the concept of sub-array
sub array
or sub-list before right and we also
talk about subsequently do you still
remember what's the difference
what's the difference between Subway
Surface or algorithm is continuous and
others we can just pick out numbers
that's right so which one is continuous
no it's the opposite okay but it doesn't
matter actually it doesn't matter but as
long as you understand the one is
continuous one is not right this is just
the different names we're calling it
right okay stop away and sublist that
continues
subsequence is obtained by removing
zero or more elements from array so for
example if I can remove these two remove
this one and the remaining is ten five
ten right this is the subsequent the
subtle array is continued service right
10 20. 20 30 20 35 okay some array if a
problem is a Subway then usually we can
do it in o n Square time right o n
Square sub array continues so it means
that if we have a
left and if we have a right then we can
determine a sub array right so many
different sub arrays if there are ends
elements in Array they are how many so
each individual element is a sub array
right so it is cn1
and choice we pick one and animal we
pick one or if the sub array contains
more than one element is C and two all
right there are n numbers we pick one
one single number is a separate way it's
also a subsequent Subway is a subsequent
but no devices all right and this one
picking two what does it mean by picking
two you will pick this one and pick
another one pick two numbers out of the
array and then use it as the leftmost or
right mode right for example if we pick
ten and five and then we have a sub
array which is 10 20 35. if we pick 20
and we pick 50 it means we have a sub
array 20 35 10.50 races okay subsequence
usually it's uh you know the naive
solution the proof of solution is O2 to
the power n
subsequent each element we have two
choice we pick on our Peak right two
the second element we have two choice
pick on a pick right like an element so
two times two times two times two times
n times two to the power of n okay okay
so let's coming back to this question so
we want to find out
the separate way right containing the
max possible sum
however
there's only one requirement which is it
has to be ascending can you tell me
which sub arrays here in this one is
ascending containing ascending numbers
so increasing right 18 20 30. yeah yeah
and 5 10 50. okay so we have two right
so which one has the most Sun
okay so the question needs to be
answered 65. ascending ascending
this is quite similar to uh longest
increasing subsequent not unnecessary
continuous so long is increasing
subsequence we use the dynamic
programming and greedy prime minister we
talked about a long time ago right but
today we are focusing on sub array which
is the maximum increasing stock array
sum okay
is there gonna be negative numbers
that's a very good question you
you get
even get the same
person yeah okay the most naive solution
which will be I just said Ln square
right
we do this right four I in
in range
and the left yeah for J in red
we start from the I uh start from I
right to n
and then the sub array is what some
array is number a r r i to J plus one
right to J plus one meaning inclusive J
okay so then we have to check if s is
increasing and strictly increasing right
if it's strictly increasing then answer
at the beginning zero answer equals
maximum of answer and then sum of s
right yeah
so return answer
so what's the time complexity if you're
looking at this naive solution yeah
oh and
always Square this is to check if the
array is strictly increasing that's our
n
so here o n o n o n o n o n o n
and here is our Empire this is in the
same so linear time here right I'm not
so oh and cubic a naive solution is over
and give you do we have a better
solution
okay
10 30 60
oh this is too small
so I start five
fifteen sixty five
so what did I do hmm
[Music]
do we start when it's too small it's
yeah it's perfect this is like a a land
and then if it's too small it means
there's a river
so we're basically finding the size
maximum size of the length and you can
think of a river and then we jump when
we jump to the next one then we have to
restart reset the counter right okay so
we have a answer at the beginning zero
and we have a carbon sum which is zero
okay look 10
10. yeah
the answer is the maximum of these
current answer like 10.
class 20 right this is still increasing
plus 20 so plus 20 here plus 30
plus 30 kilo F okay so so the next one
is smaller
right so we have to reset it to
five right
now look 5 compared to the answer is
smaller so we just ignore it right pi
plus the next one is increasing plus 10
all right 15 is smaller than the maximum
we have seen so far we're just ignoring
and now five plus ten plus 50.
right what's the sum 65 65 is larger
than 100 best we update the current
price to 65.
make sense
which one is better which one is quicker
this one is quicker because we're just
going to once but for this one I have to
go through this and then for each eye we
have to go to J and then again to
calculate sum of the sub array right and
for this one the time complexity oh n
times o n times this one checking if
it's in strictly increasing this is
taking another o n times so o n cube
right the sum we can do this accumulate
sum so for this one it doesn't next we
take or when we can optimize this b201
but still because overall time
complexity is o n times o n times o n
which is o n q b okay for this one okay
so let's implement this a little bit
okay think about it what have you
learned okay I'm gonna ask you a
question later
Define this is the max
increasing sub array
sum okay
all right
n equals the length we first of all get
the lens how many elements in Array if
not n if it's an empty array you just
written zero right it will give me
nothing then simply answer zero answer
equals carbon current sum equals the
first number is arr0
then four I invent
one to n so look 10 20 35 10 50 right so
we start with this number second number
by comparing to the previous one right
so look if a r r i is bigger than the
previous one which is a r r i minus one
right so look we are here AI it is this
one number is bigger than the previous
one so it's increasing right so
increasing man carbon this is the
current sum current sum plus equals a r
r i right because current at the
beginning is set to the uh the first
number right now we have 20. so 20 is
bigger than the previous number so the
sum is 30 all right
else okay you tell me what's this if
it's not strictly bigger what should we
do if AR if this number is not bigger
than the previous number so what should
we do here this number is bigger than
the previous one so the sum is 30. if
this number is like 5
is like five
so what's the sum of this current land
five so comma equals this is a r r i
this is a r r i minus one okay
what's current current means the sum of
the current increasing sub array so if
this number is bigger than the previous
one
so the current increasing sum the sum of
current increasing salary plus 20 am I
right
now look if this is five or six smaller
than the previous number the current
increasing sum should be set to which
number
should be set to which number because we
are restarting with counting anyway I
currently I okay now current sum we have
this current we have foreign sum which
is the sum of the current increasing
Subway so here we need to update it
check the Maxima answer equals Max
current
and the second parameter yeah
every time the answer stores in maximum
currently I will return return
answer
what's else
the numbers
n is the numbers does it make sense
what's n the number
what numbers
in that number
and okay so n is one number yeah
nice
oh and what's m and means
what numbers
so what are but what about those numbers
is it a particular number or what we are
given an array what's m hooray array
it's is it a number
yes
what nose number it's a single number or
inside oh and what do I talk about array
yeah
yeah what do you understand what's on
it's the
you need to take the amount of
those numbers
okay so look o and n is the number of
elements in the array so what's Owen O N
means that when the size look if this is
five uh this is six elements
if this array contains 600
right so what happened
the time complexity so it's a linear
Nina yeah this is n this is T time so
it's linear o n right it describes how
the complexity scale with the size of
the problem the N is the size of the
program which is the lump of the numbers
the number of the numbers make sense
is a number yeah but it's not very clear
when you describe it we make it 10 times
more of the size the size becomes 10
times more the tongue spending the comes
next to spending will be 10 times more
that's om right right but look o n
Square will be like that right oh log n
would be like that right so it describes
the complexity so which one is better
obviously login right and increases the
scale the size the scale of the time
complexity
does not increase so much as linear or
quadratic we call it this quadratic yeah
face complexity are we using any
one a one we are using constant space Oh
that means that we are using constant
space look n here
answer current these are only three
variables and possibly here yeah four
variables one two three four four
variables when the size of the array
gets to a minion how many variables do
we need
uh fool when this size of the element
gets to a trillion a billion whatever
how many variables four that's right a
one constant what a one yeah
look this is X this is y right one is
here so when the N increases the value
doesn't change right that's why it means
a one okay what have you learned today
[Music]
about numbers and you're gonna add
find the
sub the
this this the greatest sum of the
celebrate and it's it's ending summary
and yeah
that's the problem and how are we doing
it we are doing it by
we have two solutions and that one is
the one when you go through the the
numbers of the numbers and and you
e plus the numbers on the way and and if
you have a drop to a smaller number you
restart and and restarts the current and
an nvnd
give a fine give the greatest look for
the greatest comment and and then that's
the answer we're done perfect let me
repeat okay to sum up so today we
describe a problem we want to find out
the maximum sum of the increasing sub
array right and we can use the proof of
the most straightforward solution most
intuitive solution which is to iterate
overload some arrays and we can do this
in o n Square to go over those actual
summaries but again when we get a
summary we need to check if it's a
strictly increasing and that takes our
end time if it is strictly increasing we
calculate sum which could be accumulated
right it doesn't have to be linear to
calculate the sum of the sub array so
that takes o and QB that's too slow way
too slow the way we're proposing here
yeah is that we keep tracking of two
variables one is the global maximum the
other one is the current sum of the
increasing sub array right so we check
if currently if we have this increase in
salary if it is then we updated the
current sum and we update the global
maximum otherwise but not even the next
number
yeah if we meet a new number which is
decreasing or it's equal then we have to
reset the current sum all right we have
to reset the current time yeah so this
is our end time because we just simply
go to the array once the space
complexity is a one constant and we're
using constantial space okay that's it
for today bye
hello Ryan
look uh we have given this array of
numbers positive numbers yeah for
Simplicity so we want to find out the
maximum possible sum of a sub array
which is ascending so summary and all
sublets right we talk about the concept
array service and subsequence do you
still remember what's the difference
which one is continuous which one is not
array is continuous continuous
sequence is not right subsequent is
obtained by removing zero or more
element from the original race for
example I can remove any possible
combination of the arrays and the
remaining is the subsequent subarray is
continuous so basically you have the
left and right and everything continues
that's a salary right convenience so we
want to find out the possible maximum
sum of sub array right continuous and
the only requirement is that the subway
consists the ascending numbers so it has
to be ascending right that's the one
problem we used to look at which is the
longest increasing subsequent right and
we use the two ways one is the dynamic
programming the other one is the 3D
original balance search for that right
so given this what's the maximum sum of
sub-array
which has the increasing numbers can you
find it so we want to find out the
maximum Max sum
of sub array which is increasing right
so for number 10 20 30. this is the
summary it's increasing right so the sum
is 60. there's what 10 20 35 10 and 5.
okay yes so this one yeah and this one
so which one has the largest sum no the
the second one doesn't include the last
five
is only 5 10. uh oh okay yeah you're
right actually this is 50. okay the
second one second one that's 65 okay
you're right yeah 65
yeah one number right for the second
example what's the maximum sum of uh
increasing salary
I'm 10 25
yeah everything yeah because it's
increasing okay and how about the third
one
we're done 10 11 12. this is bigger than
that right
how do you find out the second one is
the the increasing how do you know it's
increasing just look at it
and then it's all increasing in
syncreasing and how about this one
yeah
but now
so what happened when the next number is
smaller it's not increasing anymore yeah
we start with restart here right yes
yes okay so yes you're right yes so
let's look at this we keep checking of
the sum of the current surface if we
break it somehow if we move to a smaller
Lumber which is our equal number which
is not increasing anymore then we reset
the sum all right we will say the sum
and we accumulate again and then in the
meanwhile we have to keep tracking of a
global maximum all right
common sum equals zero and the maximum
equals yellow first of all we start with
the first one so current sum is 10
maximum is 10 right because every single
number is increasing seven right
the next one is bigger so the current
sum plus 20 all right it's bigger the
maximum sum
10 and 30 which is
30 people all right
and then plus 30 60 60. and 60 and Max
30 60 is bigger so we updated 60. okay
what happened here five we don't add the
five right
so instead we change it to Five Sixty
and Five Sixty we keep 60.
10.
11 15 right
15 and 60. we keep 60. and then next one
65 65 and 60. we keep 65 right that's
why we find the 60 okay let's try this
example okay
a current sum equals 12 which is
defaulted to the first number the
maximum sum which is 12 as well okay 12
and 70 plus 70. obviously this is Theta
next one is smaller to listen to 15 okay
15 and this one this one is bigger
the next one is smaller so we reset it
to 13. nothing is smaller than that
right
and the next one
is smaller than 13 so we reset it to 10
and this one is bigger 10 the next one
is 11. 10 plus 11 right
10 plus u time and smaller than this one
we keep this one and the next one
is part of the increasing service with
plus 12. so this one is bigger right
this one is bigger than that so we will
place the global sum with 10 plus 11
plus
all right and then that equals five
three yeah so this way okay so for the
second example we always increment this
current sum because there's no breakage
right there's no breakage so if
everything is increasing okay
defy with the style function declaration
using Define the
maximum
sub list
increasing sum okay
all right
if not array if we are given the empty
array we can zeros and equal the length
of the array the current sum equals the
first number AR 0 and then the answer
equals the first number as well we go
through the second number to the end for
I in range
1 to the end
all right look if this number well if
this number is bigger than the previous
one if a r r i is bigger than a r r i
minus one right if this number these
numbers Ari
is bigger than the previous number which
is a r i minus one
then C S plus equals a r r i right
as we reset it to CS equals a r r i all
right look at the difference
if this number is bigger than previous
one then we accumulate it if not we
start a new Subway right yeah and then
here we need to keep tracking of the
maximum Max
answer which value is it
can you tell me which value which value
I should put here
um we're done
okay so what's the problem what have you
learned what's the takeaway today we
have
an away we have a array of numbers and
I'm trying to try to say small things
come on try to say in you know remember
later you want to teach daddy right
[Music]
okay put down the maximum plus person
open it is 17 ascending separate Subway
okay so we want to find out the maximum
possible sum of Subway which is
increasing uh which is ascending okay
strictly ascending do you have CS CS
which stands for our current sum and
then we have the answer here so every
time we check and if it's
hey girl you added yeah add it to the
currency if it's smaller you start new
one start new one by resetting to
resetting to the number right yeah look
this if this speaker is part of the
increasing we accumulate otherwise we
start a new Subway which is the current
number am I look one two three ten nine
eight ten okay look one two three one
two
one two look one one two one two three
okay one two three ten
okay now it's decreasing right so we
just abandoned the previous one we start
a new one we say nine
a which is decreasing so we abandon this
we start a new one a 10 a 10 right makes
sense
bigger yeah yeah okay
the time collects the oh and right we're
just going once the entire array oh and
it's the number of numbers in the array
let's face complex three or one we are
not using any linear space we're only
using constant space okay that's it for
today bye bye bye bye bye
[Music]
foreign