all right okay so look at these there
are two positive numbers we're given two
positive number we want to find out the
number of common factor common factors
what's common factor look these are one
two three six these four numbers both
divides 12 and 6. so therefore right can
you find more
okay how about 25 and 30. how many
common factors uh one
this one no I said there's a common
factor of one yeah of course
five and five anymore
[Music]
um
no yeah no just okay so given two
numbers A and B positive numbers we want
to find out the comment the number of
common factors for A and B the common
factor is the number that divides both
positive integers given least 25 and 30
how do we know it's two how do you check
these two right you said to prove us
that's a good idea but how do we prove
us we check every time tables every time
table so we check from two two yeah
because one is there right one is a is a
common factor for any two numbers all
right what's the biggest number we have
to check
the
the biggest number is off yeah huh
we can do more than that how is a good
guess half of what
half of the smallest number half of a
smallest number that's a good guess but
we can even do better so 25 30.
do we need to go to 12 or 12.5 12 right
do we need to no no that's right because
we have another number so what's this
gcp do you still remember
Places come divisor create this comment
divisor 25 and 30. what's the greatest
common divisor five five so we need just
need to go to five am I right so what's
the definition of greatest common
divisor is the greatest
divisor between two numbers right so
there's no such thing divisor that goes
beyond the greatest common device am I
right yeah another example
14 and 21.
yeah and then how many factors common
factors
hmm
okay two yes two okay and animal okay uh
another example yes four and
six
two
which is one two eh okay I need to come
up with an example with more than two
okay let's say
126. 6 16 and
123 and 64 and
24.24 and 4096. one one two two
yes
um
what's the name a yes anymore no that's
it all right okay so 16 and 24 hours of
the greatest common divisor eight eight
we just have to check from two right two
three four five six
seven eight these numbers if they can
divide both numbers then we incrementize
them right yeah so create this common
devices CCT the python provides this
function but do you still remember how
we're doing this uh greatest common
device for example 25 and 30. how do we
know it's five we use this right look
25 divided by 30. the remaining 25 right
so we just move here
okay so that's 30 and 25. 30 and 25
divided by 25 remaining 5.
right move here that's 25 five 25
divided by 5 remaining
0.0 this is the common divisor okay
let's try another example 14 and 21.
right 14 divided by 21 remaining 14
right we move this we shift here 21 14.
so basically when a is more than b we
just swap it around 21 divided by 14
remaining
seven
yeah 14 divided device uh this is 14 7.
14 divided by seven remaining
zero right so when it's zero we present
this seven right correct correct is
common devices we use to touch algorithm
right so I'm just going to quickly like
that Define g c d a b y p is not equal
right a b equals p a modulus B and then
return return a right the simple as that
this is a simple implementation of the
common device and we can use the
application as well so if B then return
g g d uh B A modulus B otherwise 310 AI
okay okay coming back to that question
so x equals g c d a b and then answer
equal at the beginning set it to one
because one is always the common divisor
right and for
I in when we start from the second
number up to X Plus One X inclusive if x
modulus I equal equals zero then answer
plus equal one return answer right this
can be found in one line return sum
right some one for I in 2 to the X plus
one if x modulus I equals zero okay the
time complexity for the gcd is log
minimum of A and B okay you don't need
to go into the details but this is
roughly the counter black State there's
a mathematics analytics uh on getting
this Samsung Galaxy we're not going to
go into deeper today okay so time to
next is this one the most time consuming
times infinity loop okay so what have
you learned today and that's it
you go first
so what's the problem and how are you
show me it okay
we are using decorative
[Music]
and you have two numbers and you want to
try to find
the the numbers that play with the
number of common factors right yeah the
common factors is the number that
devices we just need to prove us from
two to Let's create this common devices
okay so we so semi we we're trying to
figure out like how many number of
common factors there and we're using
them
the greatest common divisor and so and
say
and so uh solution is is
getting dividing both of them and
getting the remainder and then keep
doing both of them and then do and then
and then and then repeating and
repeating until you get the remainder of
zero and the divisor you divide to give
a reminder is is the greatest common
divisor well done good job okay that's
it for today bye-bye bye-bye