hello hello hello hello hello mr
aeropolo mr wright today we're going to
talk about yeah yeah okay
[Music]
hello sit down please hello hello hello
guys
so today we'll talk about uh we're still
talking about a link list remember we
have talked about reading business
what's the link list
on this part but it's consists of notes
connecting to each other right
yes yes and now we have a head head
head can you sit down please
the most important thing about english
is that it does not support
the random access it means if i want to
take a visit this
note yeah you have to follow it from my
head yeah work one by one okay
yes one by one
okay so how about giving you a head
and okay so this cake
is smaller than all equal than the
length of the link list okay
it's for sure linguist
and what i want you to do is to
return the k last note for example if k
equals
what if k equals 2 then i want you to
return this now if k
is 3 i wanted to return this stuff
so do you understand what i'm talking
about if k is one i want to start from
the
end no but you can't access the n you
can only
you're only given the head yeah
so think about it is it easy to do
the thing is you only give it ahead yeah
and the head starts at the beginning
yes start with the beginning remember we
talk about the
middle of the linkage remember how do we
do it we have a fast
point and a slow pointer the first trend
was twice as fast
as first slot so can we
wait can we do something similar
look we wanted to return the case
remember you propose the first solution
when we talk about the middle
of the link the first of all is to
travel the linked list
and then find out how many notes
right so we can compute the language
yeah yeah yeah
right first you need to count how many
notes are there
minus k minus k so for example like two
four five five five notes and then
the minus two is three so that's one
two three um
one two three wait is the first one zero
oh yeah yeah of course yellow if this is
zero that's one that's two
three four so it depends if if k
is two so then i want it to return this
three right so zero there are five
five notes minus two is three
so look it's three so one
two three this one means no yeah yeah
yeah yeah
yeah so generally you travel this once
and then you
you compute the the how many nodes and
then you
[Music]
you can uh compute what's the number
what's the
what's the which no is it this case
note from the last right yeah can we do
better only travel at once
can we do better i need traveling once
yes
uh
look how about if i give you a note
which travel two step at a time two step
so one two so now i'm here yeah
yeah so and i have another note now
starts with this
and then the post travels some distance
you see do you get it this one is out
yeah yeah oh when this is out then this
snow will be there
why is that why is this working
look what when this when the first note
when the first
travels k step right and the second note
second pointer starts so what's the
distance between them
two two yeah oh yeah yes i wouldn't eat
the first one which is the end
and what's the second distance what's
the second pointer
or b cave right because they are they
are distancing
their distance
yeah does it make sense yeah yeah very
good
okay
[Music]
okay so now let's do this coding first
so yeah
so look we need a k parameter yeah okay
so so c equals hat
now it's remaining four i in
redwater
you're not guessing range k come on
what's the range function range k will
be
zero okay okay again p
equals p dot next
right yeah now with key now and then i
have
another one so y
y p is still valid then p equals p
dot next and head
equals one head
equals head downward
they're moving the same right hand next
right yeah
and after when this p is the end and
what what's the
case note return what return
head yes where the return head
okay so let's see what's the complexity
[Music]
so yeah so we uh
we talk so we can compute remember we
can compute
the the the nodes
the length of the nodes define out
length
of the of the note yeah of the notes so
how can we
how can we compute the the length look
yeah lens let's say answer equals
but let's do it equal one
y head
right yeah answer plus equals one
that will be zero okay and then head
equals one
yeah this is how your calculator length
or you
also can do this look you can also do it
recursively
if head is none
return one none
why long nothing is yellow come on
zero return number two
[Music]
one plus what lens
head or next right yes do you see this
how this works look this is the link
list okay
okay so the length equals what the
length equals one
plus the length of this speed right all
right
yes so what's the length of this is the
length of the one
one plus this and this lens is
the one plus this right do you get it
yeah do you see i'm seeing it okay
good so this is the one you know if you
want to use the better you propose
you need to calculate the length right
and that's the way you calculate the
lens
right yes got
yeah oh let's that's perfect that's very
clear oh no perfect
oh that's very clear
can you please sit down please i need to
uh can you sit there please i i can you
see that this i
i don't want to shake the skin can you
sit on the chair
lecture okay so i can do this
okay so look it's not shaking right hi
so we still have this note right yeah
remember at least the
we still have this uh i can't see the
this bit let me do this you're blocking
the way
[Music]
wait wait wait
i think this is okay this is okay
perfect
okay so look okay can you see yeah
yeah no so this is number one to turn so
we have uh
we we have a cycle this one yeah so we
don't need a cycle
we print the list remove the no we don't
need it
clean the linked list we can leave this
and then we don't need this uh
23 to what dddi
online okay so please print the link
list
uh twinkling list
so now we
the english link list is
okay so now
let's print it first okay let's print it
first
so the link is one to nine okay so let's
let's say i want to get the number eight
which is the second to last right
yeah okay so let's do this
define uh case
head okay right remember what we talk
about for
p equals hat for i in
range k okay yes
p equals p dot next now
now we have we got that uh p then we
have the head right y
t p was peter
next node head equals head
on next now right and then now we return
paste return head
let's try this work okay look
uh okay we need to print it we have the
[Music]
beginning we have this already so that
case let's say
okay now okay k equals case head
two so you should print and then let's
print
uh take second
second last note is
is what s t r
k dot value
you should play the a right yes
yes you see putting the okay now okay
how about let's try
try the opposite we can print it
opposite way so how can we do this
let's say uh
look for i in range
a how many notes are there nine notes
yeah
yeah then k
k equals k hat uh
we should print the i plus i i okay
i
uh let's do it one two
ten and then we can print
between case of value
okay queen let's put the empty line
you see nine eight seven six five four
three two one so what am i doing here
so look what am i doing here so is that
i
get the notes from the last from i to
i item one to nine right so you
basically will print the link this in
reverse order okay and
yes yes and then look we can implement
that
computer english defined length
right head can you implement this for me
answer equals what you know
why what hey
what
[Music]
okay so and another one define lens two
head if head
is numb ryan it has in line what should
we return
zero one zero yeah we're done
and we otherwise we return one plus
because if it look
length two dot what
happened next you know okay
so now let's see print
let's print this number okay print
length is
star lens head
okay and then let's using this function
to print this
lens is star lens 2
head you should print the
twice uh which is 10 right
left or nine nine notes that's it's nine
yes you got it yeah
once you once you have the length then
you can substitute
subject with k and then you can follow
the link at least with
k times right now k times that uh
dense minus k times all right yeah okay
so
that's your approach yeah it's also very
good yeah
yes cat yeah always
yeah this is the code we are using today
with another
another then let's do it uh let's
release the
uh case this is most important uh code
to take away
is 23 line 23 to 30
okay so get ahead we
first of all we launch a pointer which
works first
uh after the first pointer was k step
and we launched the second pointer
yeah so the second pointer the distance
between the second point and the first
pointer is what
what's the distance between the first
pointer and the second pointer
uh two okay okay
yeah and then one they also work at the
same speed
so when the first pointer reaches the
end where's the second pointer
uh k is the k to the last yeah from the
left okay
good job today good job today good job
that's it
that's it let's see today
say bye bye say bye bye
[Music]
bye bye bye bye bye