hello okay hello Mysterio right
yeah today we're going to look at this
uh cloud and safe from
cow and say
so let's start with the first number one
right so when n equals one when given is
the integer n we need to say is one
right that's the base cases so how do
you say well how do you count and how
many ones are there in this one
uh one so it's one one okay so one one
10 into 1 1. so how do you say this
no cow then say how many ones
two ones so two ones
all right so it becomes two one click so
how do you come and say this one like
that one two one more
well done so one two
one one so it becomes one two
one one okay and how do you say this
three one one two uh okay that's a good
point so you count and say from the left
so you're not merging them together it's
one one
two two one okay
so one one
two two one that becomes one one one two
two one okay
so that's n equals two n equals three n
equals four n equals five
for example if you want to solved n
equals 5 so what information do we need
to get before we solving n equals 5. so
before we get this this string right we
need to return a string before we return
this we need to attend what kind of
information how do we get this number
n equals 4 what do we need to do
a nickel three exactly and then coming
back to n equals one so what kind of
algorithm coming to your mind like FN
let's say F1 Returns the answer we need
to get this F at minus one and then f n
minus 2 and f i minus 3 and here F1
which is we already know is one right so
what kind of Agron is this
FN we need to call FNL minus one to get
the answer what is this in general if we
have a function FN and then we need to
call the FN minus one and in f n minus
one it needs to call F and minus two so
what is this the one with stars are
calling is what do you call it
recursion yes
thank you Ryan okay
done okay so
Supply application on it right so the
the thing is that we need to count and
say for example like that so we need to
count how many ones look how many ones
are we and how many tools are we so we
can use a function called Rule but we
talk about that right Global E2 is
called glue back so first of all let's
start with f Define FN so for any
recursion we need to define the base
case right so we have to tell it's a
computer at some point how do we solve
the very basic problem last Fibonacci
number F1 equals one right if we don't
have the computer
F1 equals what if we just say Okay FN
equals f n minus 1 plus f n minus so
what happened the computer with because
we're calling itself but it doesn't know
how to solve the very basic case
so the problem with the curse itself
into minus infinity which means the
problem never gets solved so if and
equal equal one return
one okay now this is the base case so we
are telling computer okay when in n
equals one we don't need to recurse
anymore we know the answer which is one
okay otherwise
we put this answer into a list okay
and four i j in Theta towards the group
by previous answer is a so a equals F
and minus one here look this is
recursion calling the previous number
right because you said you want to solve
FL
the previous answer is f n minus one
look
so we need to go out for a equals one
one one one two one okay so we need to
go by this answer this is the previous
result so we grew by this we grew by
using the group by function and then you
Group by continuously groups so that's
two one so you return a key and a group
points to the group two and here is the
two two and here's one one okay I
will be the keys J will be the iterator
so we need to convert this iterator to a
list and then get the lens get the lens
uh let's one one okay answer the append
first of all we want to append the count
how many of them which is here right so
how many of them is first of all we
convert to at least let's do this and
then we get a length right
okay or we can merge these here I answer
the pen star somebody to at least
converting or getting the lens
converting a string plus the I and then
return
this answer is the least how do we
convert this to a string which function
we're using join where that so we joined
by empty string join answer and now beat
right we don't need to put a cache here
right why is that the cash is optional
right because FN only depends on f n
minus one so FN for example f n any FN
is only used once
makes sense that F3
in order to calculate F3 we need to know
F2 in order to know F2 we need to call
F1
line F1 we know this answer is one and
we come back right we're going back
right back so any FM we only use once so
we don't need to put a question
Fibonacci number we need to put the cash
why look F4 equals F3 plus F2 right F3
equals F2 plus F1 so do you see why do
we need to put a cash yeah F2 here F2
here
right so it means that we need to put a
cache otherwise F2 might be calculated
over and over again all right but here
look it's just single branch
S2 only calculate ones so we don't need
to pull the cash
the key thing today take away here is
goodbye yeah goodbye what does goodbye
to give us 1 1 2 2 3 3. if you go by
this then you tell us one which is a
group of one one right two
all string only two two
and three
three
we can implement the group by ourselves
but this is the very convenient method
one two three so the keys will be the
unique element in that group continuous
and the values
will be an iterator
iterator
to let at your group okay
okay please tell this uh group to
convert to a list and now we get the
length so we know how many we this is
the part of count
and say count and say the element is
this yeah the element is the group in
that okay I know we do cursively calling
the previous one until we got a F1 okay
okay what have you done today so the
countdown today is like you basically
saying like
like when the num the number and
the num the number and how many of the
numbers so like for example one one one
two two one there's three ones
um so and two twos
and then one one hmm
it says to be three one two two
what kind of eggplant can we use to
apply to solve this one really buy and
what's the algorithm called
solving a smaller size a problem and
then what's that recursion recursion
yeah the cursing basically we saw this
smaller size here all right look a
equals F of minus one so because we need
the F and minus 1 results to call and
say it and these F minus one because if
we call in F A minus two f n minus three
until we reach F1 right okay suppose we
are given this n is positive okay if we
give at least negative number it doesn't
make any sense so we can just say we can
put here if and smaller equal than zero
then we tend nothing okay just return
nothing just to avoid this uh functions
those errors all right yeah look if we
don't have this if we call it f minus
two what happened
if we don't uh tell the computer to
check the N if it's negative f minus two
all right now you will call F and minus
three right
FN minus 3 calling f n minus 12 minus 12
minus 5 minus six minus 7 minus infinity
because the the computer coding is
without solving any kind of problem so
that's why the N needs to be positive
another way we can just put a sub
I said here we just make this double
check L is bigger than or equal than one
okay a third and bigger and equal to one
the complexity this is a bit complicated
this is all uh 4 to the power of n
divided by three okay we are not going
to details today here because it's uh
too complicated so S S Plus T equals FS
plus ft if the last digit of s is not
the same as the first digit of T makes
sense right so look f
one two three plus okay
four five six right you count and say
this one two three four five six it's
the same as f one two three call and say
one two three plus F four five six one
easier easy to understand right if the
last digit of s is not the same as the
first digit of t make sense yeah so from
that point we'll be able to understand a
little bit more up on the term and space
complexity okay that's it for today bye
bye
nice hello Mr Ryan all right
So today we're going to look at these
numbers when n equals one
we set one right okay so how would you
say one how many ones one okay so it's
one
one okay so we turn that into one one
says
so that's n equals to how do you say
this how do you say this T1 two ones two
once
to one right
how do you say this you count and say
how many twos one two one two one one
right so one two one one so that becomes
one two one one
and equals four okay n equals five
so how do you call and say this one
one one
two two one yeah one one one two one one
one one two
and two ones one one one one two two one
right and then these keep going right so
given n
we need to return the string on the
right hand side
yes what's groova so basically we need
to grow by the numbers and then count
all right yeah we want to find out n
equals five so what's the result depend
on so before we figure out what's the
answer of n equals five what do we need
to get
right
it depends on n equals to so what kind
of algorithm coming to your mind uh FN
right we need to find out f n minus one
and then we need to find out F and minus
two so what's this
we want to find out FN and then FN
depends on f n minus one f n minus 20
times F minus two so what kind of the
equivalent can we apply here we want to
find out FN and then FN minus 1 f n
minus two so what's this until we reach
FN which we need to know is one because
you're calling itself yes because
I forgot how to say it right okay
location okay so we can use that
recursion right so the thing is that we
get this from the F and minus one and
then we count and save from the FN minus
one right so Define f and
is n equal equal one this is the base
case Louis 10
one right this is the base case right
when n equals one will return one single
one this is a string now we get the
previous which is f and minus one right
this is how we recursively solve the
problem with n minus one smallest
problem so when we have this a right so
we need to call it for example
one two x this is if a is going to then
we need to count this string right all
right so how do we call it the idea is
to group by right we can Implement a
group by ourselves but we have this Glue
by function so we Group by the same
for example like that the same digit so
Group by this right so once we Group by
we know how many two one there are one
there are two ones and there's three
twos
okay
so for
for
i j in Google is from itatura group by
Group by a right and before that we put
the answer into a list
so if Group by if we apply the group by
In This suppose this group by a a is
this one right this is the previous
result if you could buy the I would be
it's the iterator yeah I would be one
the the element the unique element in
that group and the values would be uh
iterator to uh
to the to each group so it's one one
something like that but this is the
iterator so two
two two two right so let's go back so
now we want to find out how many of them
right so we can apply the lens function
to the list of the iterator so there's
two ones and that's three tooth and the
unique element we know right answer dot
a pen
right how many ones comes from here so
we first of all converted star lens
list
J
uh uh yeah so what this means this J
converting this into a list a length
which it gives the two and we convert it
to a string plus plus this one right so
we just have to put an i here
now this is how we count
and say count call the numbers and say
it out right and then return
how do we convert a
this to a string
how do we convert this look one two
three into one two three well which
function is it we talk about like how do
we convert US array array to a string
what's the opposite of split
yeah so return empty string dot join
this is a separator join answer
so f l depends on f n minus one so we
don't need to put the cash here right we
don't need to put the cash because it's
it's not reusing any other results if
you want to get the FN you have to
calculate from F1 F2 F3 until F1
this is the question right in order to
calculate FM we need to the result for f
minus one right the FN minus one
suppose it's something like that and
then we have to group by Group by this
the string at a f a minus one is a
string then we could I will use the
group by to count there are two ones and
three twos the reason we use the array
to store the each component store each
each group is that when we join it it
will be more efficient instead because
the string continuation is inefficient
and it's better we put the string into a
list and then we use the join join is
the reverse operation of split the join
a string The Joint the separator is
nothing so it means we put it together
if we put a plus here then that will
become one plus two plus three something
like that right if we put an empty
string then it'll be one two three
okay the terminal space complexity I
mean it's very complex right it's uh
we're not going to sew into details it's
uh around this right the time and space
complexity it depends only the FN
function we know FS plus T equals FS
plus ft is the last digit of s is not
the same as the first digit of T then we
have least then we can continue analyze
it but it's a very complex we're not
going to go into details but this is
roughly the time and space complexity
okay okay so what have you learned today
and then that's it
um number one is
and you lose one the other one one
because you need because
there's the number one and we
and
and there's only one of it yeah and then
we called and say it out and forming a
new string am I right so what's the egg
room we're using today
could we buy and split join no no what's
the algorithm we're using recursion
what's the recursion
yeah Colleen said why do we need a
recursion here if we want to capture F
and why do we need to call FN minus one
if we want to count FN it depends on F
and minus one right so let's recursion
FN depends on FN minus one s n minus one
depends on F and minus antia F1 we which
we know is one that's the base cases so
recursion we have to define a terminal
case which is the base case if we don't
have this what happened can you tell me
if we don't end here what happened it'll
keep going live again and you will never
end right because look F1 and then if
you don't tell what to solve if there's
nothing to solve you because into s0 F
minus one F minus two F minus three F to
Infinity
which the computer don't know how to
solve at some point the communication at
some point you have to let the computer
to solve the very basic thing all right
this is what the recursion is right for
example the factory one factorial is one
two factorial is two three five three is
six right and for Clear equals n times n
minus one factorial all right look so f
n equals n times F and minus one right
for example we have to left computer now
F1 equals one right if we don't have
computer F1 equals one then computers
don't know what's F1 and you will need
to recurse into F0 F minus one F minus
so I'm right
yeah
then this problem never gets soft F1
equals one right look f n then it needs
the FN minus one F minus two and then
gets to F1 okay the computer knows F1
equals one and come back to F2 equals
two
okay two times F1 3 times F2 four times
F3 okay
yeah and then until it gets the value F1
foreign