foreign
16a 16 divided by a remaining zero one
is remaining zero this is the greatest
common division 24 and 32 what's the
greatest common divisor uh is it um
eight eight yes how to do it 24 divided
by 32 remaining 24 move it here 50 32
24. so basically when a is smaller than
b we just swap it around 32 divided by
24 remaining eight right look 34 8
24 divided by a remaining zero what is
the remaining zeros this is eight okay
this is the way we calculate the
greatest common divisor and do you still
remember this and SCM
please comment multiples okay what's the
least common multiple of uh 16 and 24.
so you basically
a million no no 32 144 48 million what
40a am I so it's 48 am I 48 is because
how do we get it for the a so 16 times
24 divided by the greatest common
divisor of both
this is a right so look so it's 16 times
24 divided by 8 so that's 48 that's how
we get the least common multiple so
basically this common multiple of two
number A B can be calculated as a times
B divided by g c d a b so y uh B is not
equal zero a b equals B A modulus B okay
and then return
return a okay at least can be done in a
recursion so Define gcp a b if B
okay if B return
gcp B A modulus B
otherwise return a okay so that's the
recursion that's the iterative coming
back to today's problem so we're given
an array we are given an array right
array
we want to find out the minimum splits
of these numbers so we want to split the
numbers into continuous groups start
away subtle right we talk about sub
array and sub list right Subaru and
subjects are continuous subsequence is
not continuous so in some ways of
continuous so we want to split the
array into sub arrays each number
belongs to one Subway only and then each
group each group The GCB the greatest
common divisor of all of it
is is more than one if two numbers the
GCB A and B if we equal equal one right
for example like three and seven the gcd
of three and seven is one
then we can say that three and seven are
Co Prime co Prime
pillow plant because their greatest
common devices is one okay so coming
back to this question so we want to find
out the minimum split minimum means
split of separate
other ways so that the greatest common
divisor of the numbers in each group is
more than one twelve six three what's
the greatest common divisor of this
three yeah three it's more than one
what's the common divisor of this
two right so yeah bigger than one bigger
than one if 14 in the first group what's
the greatest common divisor of of these
these four numbers one yeah so it is not
satisfy the requirement all right so we
want to find out the minimum speed the
subway is continuous so we can do this
uh greatly right what's the idea what's
the what's the idea we can apply in the
greedy agreement if we can include the
next number in the sub array
or include it right
bless you again okay
so look prayer we can do this book 12.
the greatest common divisor 12 right 6
12 and 6 squared is common divisor which
is six am I
it's still bigger than one one three
question divided by three so look when
we are at 12 and 6 the next number is
three
all right but including the next number
our greatest common divisor of current
group is still bigger than one still
means the requirements so we can just
take it all right because when we take
it it does not compromise the global the
optimal solution because we are looking
for the Minimus break if we can include
the next number in the current group we
do not compromise the global Optima does
it make sense yeah because we are
looking for a Minimus break minimum
spray what does it mean minimum speed so
we want to include as many numbers as
possible in the current group make sense
so this is uh this is the green thing so
we want to find out the minimum split
minimum split right so we want to
minimum speed that means that we want to
have as many numbers as possible in the
current group as long as it does satisfy
the requirement right so look 12.6 my
current group is 12 and 6. so by
including the next number
which brings the GCT to three it stays
good so we want to take it right am I
right it's better we take it if we not
take it we leave it to the next group
things may get worse I mean right let's
create it okay what's great strategy is
that you always make a decision and in
the best of your entry at the coloring
point right you'll have a bananas 10
bananas you can have six bananas now and
four later or you can have four bananas
now or six later on the greedy strategy
you always pick them the best strategy
at your point which is six right Ryan
you'll pick six now right
Define mean spirit
okay so at the beginning answer equals
yellow carbon gcd and let's send it to
one okay we can go through the numbers
what does it mean in numerate
or doesn't like cheese and values so for
example like uh a b c okay if we
enumerate it it will become zero a
that's a Tapper okay and one b
two c okay so the key is here this is
the template okay actually it's no keys
but it's the first element in a couple
is the index the second value uh in the
table is the actual value okay so we go
to i j in enumerate
uh array okay
all away
so now we have to check we have to apply
the current current equals gcd carbon
and J J right and if carbon if the gcd
is one if electricity is what means that
this number needs to be in the next
group not this group because the
greatest common divisor of all the
numbers up to now this group is one so
we can't include this number
and index I right so we have to
increment the answer we need one more
group one more split and the current we
need to set it to this new number J here
right and at the end we do 10 and 12 6 3
and then 14 uh seven right I think this
this was the example okay so look answer
equals zero and gcd equals one the
current equals one
12 plus 1 and 12 gcd is one so we need
to increment the answer
and gcd set to 12 the current set to 12.
12 and 6 the greatest common divisor
becomes six
right becomes 6 is not equals one then
we continue six and six and three the
greatest common divisor becomes three
is three bigger than one okay now three
and fourteen look quantities common
divisor becomes one right becomes one so
what happened we plus one here answer
plus one right and then we set the
greatest common divisor here to 14.
right 14.
make sense
what's the
that's a good guess this is our an
obviously but here
gcp we talk about ggd the complexity of
gcd
uh AP is block the minimum of a b okay
okay so this is kind of that we have to
take it into consideration that o n
times gcd leaves or n Times login maybe
11 times
block but okay
okay
this is the upper bound okay in practice
speaking Yeah they come to the next
thing this is very fast okay but we have
these numbers yeah and we go
flip them into groups yes and then the
requirement of each group is is
the greatest common divisor of them is
it must be strictly greater than one
what's the key word today what's the
strategy pretty yes we saw yeah okay so
how how do we interpret this query they
think
so if the next number yeah even the next
number we can include it in the current
group we might just take it okay well
space complexity is a one constant right
this strategy is uh very popular it's
one of the classic algorithm in computer
science so it means that you always
choose yeah best choice at that point
you don't consider somehow in the future
they have six banana and four bananas in
front of you you don't care what
happened next you just pick the best LED
Point that's greedy okay yeah
okay that's it for today bye bye
[Music]