bye-bye hello Mr Remy said I know right
no okay you know the time right how will
you present the time like you know one
o'clock zero one
twenty right so the format is our and a
minute the hour from zero to to 12. the
other one is uh 0 to 24 right 24
actually not including 24. all right
is zero to twenty three because it
includes zero yeah yeah and but to the
12-hour clock doesn't include zero okay
okay so so yeah
yeah you're right you're right so look
sometimes this is if this is the
afternoon then we probably can represent
it as 13 20 right or 0 1 20 p.m
sometimes right okay so today we're
looking at least 20 24-hour
representation time representation right
so given the time right 23 56 this is a
very time right yeah it's Lisa by the
time uh no why is that
because you are a 24 yeah 24. okay so
you know it's
okay so the hour needs to be bigger than
zero or equal than zero and 23 yeah okay
and the meaning needs to be 59 and
bigger than zero right okay so let's say
we have a string of these terms and but
if I erase one of it and replace those
question mark how many valid time can
you represent using this three one
dollars uh zero one two zero one two
okay that's good and how about you
if I replace this with question mark how
many times
how many how many valid terms can you
represent using this three one zero one
two three no why is it only three and
how about this one look this is zero one
two two right and three three okay and
how about this one zero one zero one two
three four five six seven eight nine
okay so how many of loans zero why
it's fun look combination what is it for
eight
eight six twenty six very close how many
possibilities here
four times ten okay combination do you
get enough yeah
yeah
we have four Choice here we have 10
choice so for each choice here we have
ten so that's four times ten okay make
sense no but it's only zero to nine not
zero to ten zero to nine
zero yeah look zero to deny how many
digits how many possibilities ten right
ten and I have four Choice here left
hand choices here so combination that's
four times ten okay we talk about
multiplication do okay these these ten
how many choice
um
this is very simple look what's how many
Choice 24 good another one
how many shots
uh 59 no 60 66
but this is quite tricky how about how
about
two
what you don't need zero or one zero and
one but not two right okay you've got it
oh yeah well they're nothing that's 29.
that's right okay how about that's not
that tricky no that's okay good 99
[Music]
how many
zero zero yeah because the this is not
the time right uh okay how many uh four
here is zero one two three zero one two
three okay yeah what do you mean
this one
um
ten
ten yeah
that's good so let's go uh so how do we
solve this problem
we use our brain so we give a string of
this uh
it depends on which digit am I right
yeah so how would you do it what did you
do I mean when we try to find our
Solutions I'm just one
like
keep going this like the time can be
because like like I know the time and
and I know like 60 minutes and blah blah
blah blah blah yeah 24 hours blah blah
and I kiss you back
okay like oh let's let's use Let's Do It
um let's do
let's let's do like two question mark
column zero zero and they're like I
let's see zero one two three I can't do
four because I know they're 24 hours and
they include in 24 hours clock is
include zero so we then clicked 24 as a
consequence I don't know okay we first
yes but but here we are not actually in
proof I think we are actually counting
right we're actually counting so counter
so it's like a pattern matching yeah
look so given a time right I I said 13
20 something right so if this is
question mark definitely we have 10
digits 10 possibilities right oh yeah if
this is question mark we can't answer
answer at the beginning equals one with
times answer 10. okay
yeah if this is question mark what
happened
how many possibilities
six six possibilities okay I'm just
times times six here right so he's 60.
all right yeah if these two are both
question mark how many possibilities
if these two the the least the first two
digits yeah if these two uh the first
two digits are question mark it times 24
okay so the typical part is that one of
them is question mark right
one on the next question man and we have
to check the different situation for
example if the first one is question
mark right the first digit is question
mark Len okay so let's add our our mini
mini
if the first digit is question mark we
have to check this one all right
so if this digit is
is 0 1 2
three so how many possibilities here
three because we can have yellow one two
one two right if it's a four if it's a
four five six to your night how many
possibilities two because we only have
zero one right we can't put the two here
right yeah that's the first digit how
about the second digit if the the second
digit is question mark if the second
digit is question mark so we have to
check this first one zero one two okay
we have for the second digits zero one
two three four five six seven eight nine
four zero and one but if it's yeah
zero one two three oh yeah yeah sorry
yeah yeah yeah if it's still on one
that's nine uh that's ten choice right
if there's two
one two three
make sense answer answer equals one and
if we check the last digit if the last
digit if last digit is question mark we
answer time equals ten if the second
last digit answer
uh times six right if the first two uh
both question mark answer times 24 all
right and then this we have to check the
different situations if the first digit
is still one the second digit could be
ten choice if the first digit is two the
second digit have four choice right this
times ten this is times four uh times
four and then the opposite if left
second digit is zero one two three the
first digit is three three choice if the
second digit is four five to nine the
first digit have two choice
okay another way we know this right yeah
we can just prove us for H in range
24 0 to 23. for a minute
in French
60. we prove us the hour a minute and we
just have to check if the check if the F
function h m at the time
we just checked it with the matches with
plus equal one and return answer
so let's think here is that how do we
implement this F function
we just have to construct a time using
the H and M right and then we just
compare two string two string this time
is s so we can just return
or
s i equal equal t i o t i right
oti equals question mark
for I in range five right because there
are only five five characters zero one
two three four five okay five characters
zero one two three four five five
characters
we have to check if each character
equals or
the target time the given time contains
this question mark then it matches look
I'm complexity what's the time
complexity
um what's the time next day here look
uh Square
what's time obviously 2460 what are
those
oh one constant they are all one
constant term okay and at least so the
first approach is a one constant because
you're just checking we just do this
mesh right okay so what have you learned
to
about the time
on with
um
yeah
but the possibilities of the valley yeah
the digi the digi over unknown unknown
values difficulties
and the approach is that on the left
side it's up and we we're seeing that
the hours so so if if the hour if if the
tens hour is zero one two the second and
the
um the first digit
is zero one it can be
it can be zero one two oh sorry um
listen the second idiot is this is a big
confusion this is the opposite actually
but okay so but if a first digit is zero
and one or one and if the second digit
is a unknown digit and the first digit
and the first digit is zero and or one
and the unknown digit has 10
possibilities and if uh you know if the
first digit is two of the unknown the
second digit is zero one can be zero one
two or three
um
and and and if and if the first digit is
unknown and and so and so
it can be if
the second digit if the second digit is
there a one two three it could be zero
one two but if it four five six seven
eight nine and it only can be zero and
or one okay and how about I said this
the third digit is is
if
is
is six no matter what but if both of the
minutes are are unknown it can hit 60.
yeah this is six this is ten so sixty
right yeah and then the second choice is
to iterate over electron we construct
the possible time and check if the time
matches right the given time a time and
a question mark in it okay so what are
we trying to do here we're trying to
count how much possibilities can the
question mark be to
be very time yeah so what's the approach
[Music]
um
it will be 60 because there's because
the last minute
so it's
it is the 10 and this and the first
minute the the six and six times 60.
okay how about the hours yeah no
possibilities but if one of the minutes
yeah is question mark if it's the second
one is only ten okay and if it's the
first one's only six yeah if the hours
both of them it's 24. that's right but
if
the first one is question mark but the
second one isn't
you what you need if the if the second
one is zero to three it could be there's
it could be screamed that the answer is
three because they could be free but if
it's fourteen four to nine it only can
be zero or one
but if the second one is only it
uh the question what about the first one
isn't
It could only be zero two three which is
which is four
but if it's
but if it's one or zero it could it
could only be it could be zero to nine
because it's three because it's free
oh you're talking about this right yeah
okay okay that's it for today bye-bye