you have two meetings today right like
uh from uh today yeah from one to one
o'clock you didn't really have a meeting
two o'clock okay and then I have another
meeting like say I have another meeting
once uh to three o'clock so are these
two meetings having a comfort so you
have to do two at a time so you want to
cook so one o'clock
ah okay okay so the question is that
even though two times two events we want
to find out if they have this conflict
the conflict saying that at the moment
that we need to attend the
United needs to attend to meetings so in
other words we're asking if there's an
intersection between these two terms
if we go a multitask
okay so yes yes look beef with product
on the timeline timeline yeah right look
one o'clock here one o'clock
to two o'clock
and 130 is here 130
to 3 o'clock
okay so look
the first bit is this bit the second
event is here all right so we have a
overlap
so we have an overlap
then it means that
we have uh conflicts okay
okay so the question is simple given to
Time Event
uh yeah well
even zero for example
and zero two zero zero star and and E1
even one is zero one two three
o'clock man will return yes there is a
conflict otherwise uh we return sauce
so another special case is that the if
the second event is from two to three we
still think it has conflict right
because at two o'clock at the moment of
two o'clock there are two events
inclusive am I right
okay so what's your thoughts
um
the later one and the the start of the
later one
which is one the star of the later one
is which is 130 if if it's before the
end of the first one it's it's dead
overlap but not necessarily okay that's
a very good stuff okay how about look
how about you see this is uh is before
this yeah all right but how about you
for the entire thing moves like
basically it's still before that
but there's no overlap
it doesn't make sense yeah so how I mean
[Music]
today change it to the early one
if you remove a hole in shift to the
beginning that makes it the early one
nobody okay yeah that's another thing
okay
so you're seeing the later one so so
first of all the later one what's the
later one so let's start
needs to be bigger than this right
the Earth
so what how do you define the later one
what's uh what's later what uh it's the
one
the one with
uh
what do you know which one is later what
how do you know which one is better one
is bigger than that right and this is
smaller than that right then then yes
yes and and you need to do the opposite
as well right because there are two
cases
if this is the later one
so if this is bigger than that and
smaller than that right yeah that could
work okay
yeah that's good okay so how about that
if we think differently like what's the
opposite what's the opposite of overlap
let's conflict what's the opposite
okay so look look
if you look what's the opposite how many
situations of our left look yeah this is
a right and then another one B so it
could be something like that right
this is one case and what's the other
case
this is a what's the other case not
overlapping
uh the B to the right okay
okay
so this is the second this is the first
event this is the second if the second
event
if the end of the second event before
the start of the first season oh
oh evil star of the second event right
is bigger than the end of the first
event then we don't have the overlap
right please cover us all the cases when
the two events no not overlapping not
having a conflict and the opposite
not
or not
not overlapping so what's this
not not of anything that becomes
overlapping yeah okay so yeah very
simple okay and given the time we can
just do Lisa so uh if a b equals uh easy
to give at least time two times uh
uh A1 A2 okay and then B1 B2 okay E1 and
then we can say so this is the A1 this
is A2 this is P1 this is P2 A1 A2 B1 B2
then we can say
uh return not okay parenthesis B2
smaller than A1
or
P1 bigger than A2 right and that's it
right so this is one wave and then your
waist is good another way another way is
that we can compare if the maximum look
if the maximum of the starting point
right if the maximum of starting point
is lower than uh
if the maximum of a starting point right
starting point is A1 B1
okay is smaller or equal and the minimum
of the ending point which is A2 B2 okay
yeah look nice yeah look at these two
the starting the maximum of a starting
point is this one
but
minimum of ending point is this one so
this is smaller than that it has that
overlap okay let's look at the not
overlapping
the maximum of starting point is least
one the minimum number ending point is
here so it doesn't satisfy so let's not
overlapping another one
the maximum of starting point is this
one the minimum ending point is this one
so starting form is bigger than the
ending point so let's not overlapping
but if the maximum of starting point is
smaller than the minimum of the smaller
equivalent minimum and important we have
overlay okay think the opposite okay
let's look at this another new problem
okay given to a rectangle
yeah look given to two rectangular just
horizontal rectangle
how do we know if laser overlap come on
look we you know there are four
coordinates you know love coordinates
yeah you know each coordinate how do we
know
one of the coordinates must be like in
if like
in in the upper rectangle yeah but how
like many many situations look this is
also you know overlapping this is also
uh overlapping there are many many
situations but how do we know how do we
approve us all kinds of situations that
we are sure the two rectangles
overlapping you know just horizontal
right horizontal if they hear another
rectangle yeah how how do we check what
did I just say
what's the opposite
what's the opposite of tool and tankers
overlapping two rectangles
[Music]
so what's the opposite so look look
what's the opposite two squares look
here
so this is the first first rectangle
right that's it and what's the second
rectangle that is not overlapping
so what could be you could be here
it could be here okay can you click here
it could be here it could be on Jupiter
okay
there are only 400 situations when they
are not overlapping why look it's a path
at the top so it's it's uh it's
somewhere here right it's somewhere here
so it could be somewhere here right you
know
could be here
yeah yeah it could be here right
and then below below the bottom bottom
uh border so you could be here right and
then on the right of the Whiteboard
right yeah so these are the fourth
situation the covers all the cases that
the second rectangle
overlaps the first one right
no no no no no I'm saying overlapping
with this one these are just some
examples okay
all right so what's the opposite then
it's overlapping right so we just have
to check because this is easier to check
right I can just check and look at this
this is the y-axis is lower than the
length of up above the left the excess
is on the left or on the right it's
easier to check if these two rectangles
if they don't overlap then the opposite
then that will be overlapping okay yeah
so today's question the two events two
interval yeah this is basically asking
if two interval time overlapping and I
think we covered that slightly in the
previous lessons right so I'm not even
like two intervals overlapping so the
easiest way would be to check if they
are not overlapping because it's quite
easy to check if you're not overlapping
they're just two cases right so one is
the second one is totally on the left or
totally on the right and we just have to
be negat let's check then we'll be
overlapping them right okay so back to
you what have you learned today and
that's it oh I learned about oh uh
determining how two events have conflict
if if they if two like
um meetings meetings like overlap and so
you have the multitask or movies yeah
okay oh yeah
and so
the way we do it is for example like
my way is like
um
the beginning of uh later one I was like
two um uh to uh no believe one is let's
start over
approach
[Music]
you approaches like using the
coordinates like the olive that is over
there and that is over there and if
that's over the that one then it's a
month overlap the opposite of not
overlapping okay and it's the same thing
as checking if two like tenders
overlapping so sometimes uh today's key
takeaways sometimes it's easier to check
the opposite
that we can get we can make it Opposite
then double negative means positive all
right right not not overlapping is
overlapping okay Ryan what's your
favorite place
um so you have this event yeah it could
be anything yeah like eating apples and
watching movies okay
um
Ryan please
so what while we're trying to find out
there
is
overlapping intercession okay and then
how are we doing it how do we check it
what's
um
yeah so can you be more specific if they
pass the rectangle
no I'm talking about the events the the
interviews
how do you check if there are two
intervals on the line overlapping not at
least two universe
highlight overlapping if they talk to
each other yeah but how
what's the opposite of not overlapping
what's the opposite of overlapping so
this is not overlapping this is not
overlapping the only two right
so we can check if they are not
overlapping and we make the opposite
then that's overlapping all right
because there are more situations of
more scenarios of of
overlapping right what's that okay a
caterpillar
okay that's it for today bye bye