up hello
so you know the triangle right we're
triangle three point
yes triangle
so that's not a drawing girl it's wonky
okay okay so given three points in 2D
space right I put us I randomly put the
three points can you tell me what are
the criteria for for them to become a
triangle if I you know connect the lines
between dots
I can put three dots on the space so for
the three dots to be a triangle what
kind of requirement do you have yeah
this
this is my triangle right they're on the
same line right so it does not become a
train
so what are the requirements
um
[Music]
it's two must be like on the same line
and it on the same line and
everyone
unless unless it's on the same line as a
young team two points on the center and
two points we can have a line between
them as long as they are not the same
right yeah so in other words these three
dots three points
conform uh trying as long as these three
are not on the same line if two points
here leave three dots are on the same
line so it does not form a triangle
[Music]
total distance of any two sides are
bigger than the third one how do we do
this this side A plus b is bigger than c
y how can we prove this because a equals
11 b equals
so you're all connected and C C is a
line and the other two are two two lines
and if you split them apart like that it
the A and B is like that and the C is
like that it's easy to spot it but it's
hard to prove right I mean it's very
obvious mathematics sometimes it's very
easy to see but yeah
you need to explain stuff like
what happened
a plus b equals c what happens
so a will be in this line right if the
point is Allah it's not on the line then
a plus b bigger than C because this is
the straight line yeah that's the
straight distance if you want to go from
P to C this is the shortest distance
right any other point this is bigger
right okay we got that okay okay so now
today question simple given a few
integers
five okay so for example
parameters so what parameter a plus b
plus C foreign
to form a triangle to form a triangle
and we want to maximize the parameters
okay so for example at least two three
one five can you pick three integers to
form three integers as a side of each
triangle right then to maximize the
parameters
okay so this is a bit tricky five three
two
you're very close can we have a child
easily three numbers no why is that
because five and three so look five
three two so this is five this is two
this two three plus two is it bigger
than five no so no okay so how about if
I put this uh four what the fuck what's
the maximal parameters triangle we can
have by picking three integers as a side
of each child
okay give it what's the one before
that's good question okay if I pull up
five what's three three
um one two and five one two three right
if we pick a five
we can't find any other two sides is
bigger than five so we don't use five no
three two one no three two one three
plus two plus
four plus two degrees there has to be
because then a or b i I see so there's
no answer here that's another answer
okay yeah you're right that's yeah okay
so yeah my mistake so three two maybe
zero no no no no maybe two okay so two
plus two is bigger than three I need two
sides okay come on any two sides a plus
b equals c yeah so look one plus two is
equal and three it's not bigger than
three thousand we can't have a triangle
like that right another question ten
nine seven
Seven Ten nine six one four five okay
what's the maximum parameters we can
have by picking three points here seven
four ten seven four ten C four C four C
four dead four therefore
C next to ten
that's nine
that's four
okay Seven Ten nine okay
yeah okay okay so what's your thought so
if I give you the numbers what's your
song what's your strategy
obviously you better Die slow
fast
yes we can prove us that
each number here for I for I
in wrench
n right and N is the number of elements
for J in range size for K in range J we
pick three different numbers and then we
check if it forms the triangle right so
let's open cubic okay
something that's good why do we need to
stop if we thought what happened we if
we thought then we have this 10 9
okay so once we have this increasing
order so how do we check we do the top
three
very close we do the top three oh okay
so we check this one
bro
it works it was how do we check it
bigger than ten right bigger than 10.
that's good if we can form a triangle
using these three numbers we just return
it why can we return it closed
captioning not available
it has to be least requirement has to be
satisfied for any A and B in the
Triangle okay if the smallest two
numbers are bigger than the
so we we come from a time that usually
what do we do yeah move back and then
now what do we do now we check
nine is bigger than seven why not nice
the peak is the side you know triangle
five plus
seven seven bigger than nine then it
forms a triangle and we return at least
the sum of these three okay
yeah
one two two three five okay so look
we sold it right so two three five can
we form a triangle
um
okay we move back two plus two can we
find yes yes
okay that's it yeah so so the numbers if
it's a okay
the times n is the number of elements in
the array okay this is sorting increase
in order okay then we can solve the
reverse order so for I in range
n minus 3 minus y minus one so we start
from there we start from this
to this I start from uh the third to the
last
going back to the first and then we
check if a i this one plus a i plus one
this one is bigger than a i plus two
right then we return return the sum of
of these three okay otherwise will
return 0 at the end right the time
complexity oh and okay because this is
dominating this is o n oh and again o n
log n plus n
why this is bigger than this so we
ignore the trivia part right our login
is more dominating okay
so why do we need to check only if the
smallest two numbers the sum of the
smallest two numbers added together if
it's bigger than a bigger one
I we just
need plus nine is is it bigger than the
third number if this is because because
no matter what it is
it's still if it isn't that means it's
not but if it is too
yeah but if it is that means the way it
is that's right yeah because look these
two are smallest if the two smallest
number add it together then the third
one
then every island pairs means this
requirement because these two are the
smallest right look seven plus now you
bigger than ten obviously seven plus ten
is bigger than nine right because look
seven plus nine ten is bigger than nine
right so I choose a bigger one and these
become smaller so on the left side is
increasing on the right side is
decreasing so obviously it works right
yeah
yeah okay what have you learned today
come on that's it
um perimeter of the triangle can you
describe a little bit more and then you
have a list of numbers yeah we have at
least some integers positive integers as
the size of each triangle and then what
are we trying to do and we want to try
to find out the maximum
right okay so how do we solve somebody
so we started yeah we saw it and then
increase in order
so that's the thing is that we continue
so we created to try the largest three
numbers
right and here we find the valley
triangle okay so one question
can use this why don't we don't need to
check any pairs on the left hand side
because they're smaller they're smaller
exactly because we're sorting it seven
plus nine
and ten
this is the valid triangle the largest
we have seen so far there is no point to
check one plus five five plus seven
right because five plus seven is smaller
than seven plus nine all right yes yes
okay there we go two come on parameter
and the largest parameter of the
triangle and so
so we have cheese three three and five
and we we are we have a list of numbers
and we have to
put bananas label label the size
size
um
how long live and and so so first we
smoked it and
and we are gonna what TV
oh my God
three maximum
because because there's no points doing
this one before
but because they're too because they're
they're smaller obviously smaller than
the ones at the end after you saw them
unless if you're unless you thought it
wrong
but and so if you if it doesn't add
up bigger than the third number then we
backwards yeah then we backwards
yeah move it move the window the window
of the size three move it to the back
yeah yeah yeah and until you find it and
if you can't find it then the
thank you that's it for today bye bye