right
yeah
Okay so
we talk about a gene right the human
body Gene
basis to uh determine like the color of
your hair right the height yeah
something like that the color of your
eyes brown there are only four types of
gin a c g t like do you still remember
no a pair with the c a t um eight pairs
T right C pairs with juice yes
because C looks like DNA looks like t a
t c g yeah so look it comes with these
pairs DNA blood yeah your DNA so it's
it's like the two you know uh a pair so
if this is a and it pairs with t and if
this is T this pairs with a
so if this is C pairs with G if this is
G pair with C okay so what's the
advantage of this pair
can you think of one advantage if we
know if this is G and then we definitely
no the other side is C
yeah if you have one like if you have a
hole
and and you still have one side you
can't you can't you can still know if
you can say oh oh do you put pairs with
cs so we have a very lucky yeah yeah
yeah so look if this is broken yeah so
we know we can repair it
yeah so your human body DNA knows how to
repair itself if one of it is broken
right so it's low passed does it make
sense you can figure out on the other
side okay yeah that's the other okay I'm
not extra on this biology just some
Quick Knowledge okay so we're given a
gene type like a a c c g g t t okay you
know size of a this is one gene type
okay and this is the star we call a
mutation what's mutation
immutable
can you change huh what's mutable
change okay so mutation
yeah mutation is that if we can change
one gene to the other for example like
any you can pick any right you see pick
this one and change it to some other
type like G so this is called one
mutation of of the original Gene Okay so
each step we can apply one mutation and
then we want to find out the minimal
step to the Target destination mutation
for example like the N the end is
a a c g
g t t Okay so from here from star to the
end
how many mutations do we need aacc ggt
to a a c g g t from star to the end how
many mutations do we need one because we
just pick this Gene and change it to G
okay and how about the N is
is T here how many mutations do we need
aiccgt2 a a c g g t t two
two yes because we change this to G and
change this to T okay so another
requirement is that we can only apply
mutation if this mutation is in a bank
in the bank so it's in uh a list of the
allowed Gene type okay it's a it's a
list okay
and then we want to find out the minimum
number of mutations from travel from
star to the end I understand the
mutation needs to be in the bank okay so
any idea how do we solve this problem I
mean what kind of it's like like if a
star has eight letters and the end has
an seven how about breakfast that's a
good yeah okay one one at a time okay
that's a very good point yes the the
size of the star and end is the same and
the mutation is the same so yeah if it's
different sizes there's no way you just
return uh you know Infinity okay size of
the tune is fixed and you'll say the
pressure what's the good thing about
breakfast search we want to find out the
minimum number
moves so we want to find out the
shortest distance right the five percent
is good if we want to find out the
shortest path in uh in an unweighty
graph right remember in the analytical
one mutation cost one all right so it's
unweighted so we can visualize this as a
graph program so each one is the gene
right so for example is star and then
the edge is a mutation this is the
mutation right mutation so another Gene
to another mutation Gene and then we can
apply this
and until we find
and here we find what if this is n here
if this is the topic we're looking for
the distance is the shortest because
when we apply the prefer search we can
guarantee
we have the shortest distance it's the
shortest to last root
as long as the graph is animated make
sense Professor yes it starts okay put
it here
apply this that's a search but it's not
very effective this answer may be here
right the Shorty's past maybe here but
whatever certifies this first hello
everyone this is not a correct answer
because it's not a shortage all right
but we talk about the iterated deepening
search for if we want to apply the
deficit to get the shortest path we can
do it two ways first one is that we do a
exotic search on using the data search
or to visit every node in a tree that's
going to take a lot of time right if the
tree is big
if because if we prove us all the tasks
then we know which one is associated or
we apply the iterated deepening search
so at the beginning we limit the tabs to
one we do the test as such if we can't
find any destination node we increase
the depth to two we do a def as such and
we increase the test to three so that's
equals one wire that's smaller than the
maximum then we do a lot of stuff and
such if that's massage with the maximum
T we found it then we return the answer
right otherwise t plus equal one okay so
this is the iterative difference search
and the ideas of iterative differences
is that we incremented this
set the limit and then we perform a
deficit search that's limit search we
perform a depth name research okay to be
exact that's limit search it means that
when the depth is bigger than the
special than the maximum test then we
just return okay
answer the message we use the professor
level by level and as long as we found
the destination it's the shortest okay
and in order to find the shortest path
we have to remember that notes we have
visited so we don't want to coming back
and follow us for example the a change
to T and then NT change it to a we don't
want that right because we have visited
this a and t so we need to keep it in a
hash set in a set right
this allows our one Constantine it's a
live notebook right notebook to look up
the notes you have visited you put it
down on a notebook so the next time you
first check if we have visited this Gene
with stick this note first if it's the
pin visited we just skip it we don't put
it down again right now two let's turn
15 into uh to visit the same time again
and again okay so how do we implementage
easy double-ended
yeah
means that we can apply the push and pop
operation on both sides it's both one
constant timeline compared to this
simple uh list in Python right because
that if this is released
if it is at least in Python usually the
operation on the left side is all ending
your time and on the right side is a one
so this is perfect for stack right stack
first thing last up but for the first
things first off
in on the right side
out on the left side we need a DQ PQ
okay the perfect size how does it work
look look this is the binary right this
is how do we perform the professor one
two three four five six seven yeah so
first of all we initialize the Q is the
loot right we take it out we push it as
a kid which is two and three
we take one hour to push it to kick is
four and five
okay
Define minimum mutation
Bank okay Bank of genes we specifies the
allowed mutation where you can travel
okay Q equals TQ at the beginning we
pushula
star and the couple all right the type
of we push your Tuple into the queue the
current note and the current step is the
current distance to the root is zero
[Music]
may not be in a bank
and the distance we kill the path left
right we take one from the left hand
side so if carbon
if we have seen the destination will
return distance right look
we take a note
a note contains the current node and the
distance
and then we if we compare We compare to
the destination we have visited in
another with the tender distance
otherwise we have to check the neighbor
the mutations yeah we have checked my
mutations all right so how do we check
the mutation for I so look a a c c
what's the possible mutation of this
Gene how do we improve acccc how do we
prove false if we're given the type of
Gene how do we prove us the mutation we
check every possibilities yes what's up
every possibilities so we check the
first one first one there are four
choice right and but not including the
current one so the first one we have
four three the second yeah three the
second one we have three the fourth one
we have three like the third one
or every post everything has three times
three more times all right yeah but you
said that okay first one has three the
second one have read the full form has
four okay the fourth one has three okay
every because look eight I could replace
a with c g t yeah
nothing
good point no mutation has to change
something okay yeah you need to change
something you don't have to change all
of it
you can change nothing yeah it looks
good point yeah we have to check that on
we pick so what's mutation we pick one
and we can change it that's it yes we're
not picking magnet until we just pick
one and then chain so the next one could
be cacc okay or the next one will be a g
c c okay but not but not ggcc okay
because look these two change
so that's only one chain okay so for I
in range
we want to tell students each character
this is the index the length and then
the next one K in
a c g t this is only four possibility
and we want to replace the index I to K
so the new will be the carbon up to I
plus K plus carbon from I plus 1 to n
okay
and then if and in Bank well this
neighbor has to be in a bank and also
and not in scene we haven't seen this
before and seen dot add
and right I learned Q dot append we push
it back to the cube
the next one will be n and it is ten
plus one right and then if we can't find
it we ten minus 100 what's this the most
important thing is this one this is the
mutation so look a a c c g g it will
take this one look we want to mutate
this C right we want to mutate this C so
what do we do the new Gene is
constructed by using the character
before right and then using the
character after at least one we can have
four possibilities right it doesn't
matter if we repeat this Gene it doesn't
matter because we we can have uh I mean
we have listen okay we have released the
hashtag to remember the numbers so we
replace this one with what with a c g t
am I and then it has to be in the bank
right this is in a bank
this is Bank
and then it's not being seen first thing
if we haven't written the note the first
thing is to put it down on a notebook so
next time we don't do it again this is
to put it down on the notebook and then
push it to the queue okay the time
complexity oh n right
you only push the note back to the queue
as long as it's in the bank all right if
it's not in a bank then we don't push it
okay
yeah definitely I will be
about the jeans okay so come on come on
more sentence please
come on you're not saying one tea was
mommy don't understand this
okay
some
jeans yeah and then what do we do
yeah and
so what's the problem just one step at a
time what is the problem we are trying
to solve today
and the second is the what kind of
approach and then that's it
[Music]
yes
um
find out mutation
final mutations what
everything you want to keep it going
[Music]
we have
we have so we have a star and the end
and this we have the see like how much
can you like mutate to to to change it
to the end and and the proof is we have
uh here we have a few and
yeah oh yeah we have this hash
cable thing so we don't do it so you
don't do it so you didn't change it to
it again
and what's up what's the diagram we can
talk about all about that yeah okay so
let me repeat okay the problem is that
we want to find out a minimum right the
shot is distance to transform to mutate
from a gene a starch into a destination
engine and one additional requirement is
that
the mutation has to be in the bank which
is defined allowed to move right so we
can visualize this as a graph problem
yeah yeah uh a graph problem which is
the
directed or and directly actually is
undirected right what is that because
you can change a to T and T to anyone so
it's undirected animated graph and
waiting means that the all the cost the
mutations is uniform is one right so you
it costs one step to mutate from one
gene to another all right yes
so this is the quad problem which is
undirected annuity graph then we can
apply the preferences to find out the
shortest path
now prefer search we can use the
preferences to compute the shortest path
between two nodes in a graph when we
talk about that we can use the data
search but def research is not very
effective
we can use the deficit if we install all
the exhaust ordered paths and that's
going to take a while let's prove us on
the path down five dollar minimum
distance from two nodes or we can use
the iterative different search so the
way we apply the iterative difference
search is that every time at the
beginning we set the maximum test to one
if we don't find we will perform at the
differences if we don't find it we
increment the depth to two and we
perform a deficit on you know with the
max limit too if we don't find it we
increment to three increment to four so
every time we increment the depth we
perform a depth as such yeah that
guarantees that uh when we find the no
it's the shortest distance to the loot
the most intuitive way is to use the
prefaces to apply the prefer search we
need to use the DQ double ndq first
inverse out and now we need to type a
patch set to remember the nodes we have
visited because if we don't have at The
Notebook a mutates to T
T mutates to a a mutates to t t mutates
a demands it's going to spin the wire
while you know ongoing right it will
spin one and one and one it will never
end when we still have the notes in the
Q we get it out and we check if we have
seen the destination if we've seen it
with the tender distance otherwise we
pushes negative so this is the mutation
with each mutation is that we can pick
any one any finger Gene in a chain
string index I and then we can prove us
all other types acgt right this is HTT
and then we we check if not in the bank
and not in the scene okay so but here we
can make a small slide uh optimization
is that if this end this n could be the
same as the current right as you said
if we do nothing is that a mutation
okay so here here less possibility let N
equal equal but it doesn't matter if we
don't check if it's an equal I'm still
okay because it's finding the certain
parts but we can avoid pushing this the
same current back to the cube by putting
another chip if uh and not equal the
current okay and then we'll push you
back okay and that's a very good point
okay that's it I'll be right because
then the B defines the way it moves yeah
the bank because everything pushed back
to the tube needs to be in the bank okay
and that's it for today bye bye bye