right
yeah what did we talked about yesterday
about minimum genetic mutation yeah
minimum genetic mutations we use the
breakfast search to solve this problem
right so the problem is that we given
these genes right gin strings the chin
string there are four types acgt A
pair with d c parent with G right I
would also talk about why why the gene
is like that right so look it's a double
strand Right double strand so look if
this is side is a and the other side is
T if this side is G the other side is C
right so DNA is small robust meaning
that if one of them is missing your body
knows how to repair it all right so this
your DNA carries information right
calories information it's a double
strange right and each one has four type
of Gene it's like finally but it's four
the equivalent is the information and
DNA needs to copy copy and this is more
like the checksum all right so when you
copies he knows he knows if this
information is correct or not okay and
we're given this Gene right and then
we've also given a list of the very Gene
in a bank so we call it Bank of Gene
right Bank of gin
so we want to fry it out from the start
starting right starting may not appear
in the bench of June but it's very
charging and when we apply the mutation
how many steps the minimum number of
steps to reach to the engine right and
then all the mutation needs to be in the
bank of Gene so one mutation for example
acct mutation one mutation we talk about
one mutation mutation the opposite of
immutable right immutable content
mutation means change so we pick one
Gene and then we can change to other
three types for example we pick this C
if we pick this C
right so we have G
a p so we can change the second Gene to
all three other types okay and we use
the first message uh because the perfect
search is suitable to find the minimum
Steps From the Source to a destination
in the undirected or I directed I'm
waiting it has to be unwritical and
waiting means that the cost between the
notes the edges having the same weight
because that each mutation costs one
step it's all the same so this is
perfect search and because they are only
a limited number of genes in the bank so
the time complexity for the prefer
search is OB right because for each
mutation it has to be in the bank right
this is about it about the preferences
so what's the other search algorithm you
know not perfect that's a search okay so
we can apply the deficit in this case
right because it's more trickier yes
it's more chicken
you might go to a different end okay
you know that we use the double English
to level by level right level by level
so when we find it
the first note we find it which is the
target is the guarantees the shortest
distance right right because you're just
searching basically level by level the
first note the talking note you find is
the answer the optimal right if it's the
defa search it does not guarantee the
shortest
look if the destination is here and
possibly another one here right look
when you perform a text message you go
least here here here here you find it
right this is now you find it but this
is not the optimum this is not your test
here this is the shortest so in order to
calculate guarantee the shortest
um
such is the distance we can do approvals
using the deficiency so basically we
exhaust the search we can exhaust all
the paths right what we find is what you
should remain by but we are not
returning because we haven't finished
the whole tree right we just continue
searching searching and here we update
the optimum right so basically the first
search in this case is more like a blue
Force because we have to extort all the
paths but the way you're searching like
that if it does not
that's that's yeah yeah that was such
the thing here is that when we perform a
differences usually we return right but
here we're not returning because we are
not sure if this is the optimum
am I right yeah so we can apply the
default search in this case right
because the there's number of The
Limited uh genes in the bank
if there is no such limit this uh to
exhort all a paths industry might take
uh longer right ideally ideally this is
not a very good approach but we just uh
showing you here today okay to give you
an idea so in the next lesson we're
going to revisit this using the
iterative deepening search which is the
combined who is the death limit such
incrementally
set the max depth for the temperature
why did you write IDF iterative
deepening such it's like that okay so
let's start with the Step Zero the
maximum
depth is the distance is zero so we stop
here and then okay we don't find it so
let's increment the math step to one so
we do a default
we're not going because the test is too
maximum two and we'll go back so def's
limit search what's Steph's name is such
we perform at that first search with a
maximum depth okay theft limit search is
that first search
plus please
limit okay that's what it is okay so
okay so we go to implement the type of
search so definite search usually we can
use the recursion and non-recursion
right the recursion is more easier to
implement all right yeah because the
computer maintenance that class okay
first of all uh set the answer to
Infinity right we haven't found it
infinitive Define therefore such we want
to have a star we have n and current
distance current steps and we need to
have a
paper has table to remember the notes we
have visited right yeah because mutation
if a change to t t might change to a
again right a changes to C C my change
to a again we don't want left right we
don't want that if we don't remember the
notes we have seen what could happen if
we're not remembering this explanation
then we're working out with same thing
yeah
take forever the problem will never end
right because you just walk here walk
down pause and backwards okay so we need
to remember for example we need to
remember this remember this then we're
not coming back okay we're not coming
back we're not coming back if
visited the destination n right so we
need to remember the current distance
which is save the answer we want to get
the minimum right and then distance and
then return okay you can return true to
say okay to say we will record it and
then okay if not if the current node is
in the scene
why yeah if we we have seen this before
then we'll return first right return
first this is the pattern right every
time we check if the thing is in the
headset if it's a visited before then we
do 10 you look at the things in the
notebook if it's not there
what do you want to do next of course
out mark it down okay so I put one here
because I have visited enough right so
he allowed look scene dot add
F right and then I'm going to
come to do the next one the mutation
right mutation mute
in there are four types
mutations stencil or mutation okay I'm
just lazy mutton okay amazing what's my
turn in a sheep oh the meat the mutton
okay yeah
yeah they're only four times right so we
talk about how to do limitations at Ace
GCT so we can check every uh we can
mutate every Gene right so for I in
range
the length of uh current this is going
to the index and the next one the need
label right we want to mutate this
position now we take all the characters
all the genes before and the origin
after and then we need to mutate right
so all the genes before is s up to I
plus current Gene will mutated mu mat
plus s i plus 1 to the end
okay and of course this neon can't be
the same as s right because if it's the
same thing
if it's the same thing there is no
mutation right look we're just iterating
look acct for example I want to mutate
the second one so the second one has
four Choice AC
GT the original one is C right so we
don't want to continue doing this right
because it's the same so we cross our
right one so a g c p a g t okay and if
not equals the original if there's a no
mutation and then we need to Def as such
that first search now
and distance plus one right we're doing
one more mutation and then scene at the
end we need to remove it from remove
remove the S voice so because the
deficit search yeah we have seen this
before we have seen this before but when
we visit this this another path we we
haven't seen this now before so we have
to unmark it for the default search if
you mark it you know if you're traveling
the past traveling the tree using the
deathless search if you mark it you have
to unmark it somewhere okay and also we
have to check if the neighbor is in a
bank this is most important I forgot
this yeah because the neighbor has to be
that the mutation has to be in effect
this is one more criteria and then we're
doing the third research and therefore
such against okay now time complexity
and space complexity for this one is a
lot trickier because we can't is that uh
Bank of Gene criteria if we don't have
this criteria what happened how do we
analyze the time complexity of deficit
we just check look even this note how
many kids
how many kids have it or if there are
two
for example if it's a buying a tree
what's the time complexity of deficit
surgery on the binary tree so is is o p
t okay so we use this notation B is the
branching Factor D is the depth okay
prompting Factor look to function Factor
two
death okay yeah because for each note
you have two choice right there's always
two to the power of C right this is more
General kind of the analyze of the
deficit on the tree but for this one the
three right another three how many
possibilities
if the size if the size of gene is n
right so for n if a gene is n size A C C
T for example if there are n characters
here n characters here so how many
possibilities for each one for how many
mutations so I can pick n of them well I
can pick n on them each one has three
choice right
each one has three Choice make sense so
it's three times n right three times n
so this is the function Factor function
factor and the T the test test is length
of B right the length of B so so love
bank so is O3 times n
to the power of a bank right
this is branching Factor branching
factor three three to the power of n
three times n right or n right we drop a
constant maybe n to the power of b b is
not the branching factor or anything
it's the length of the genes in the bank
right because it gives the you the valid
move value mutation okay yeah for that
first search the space complexity is the
maximum depth of the tree if the
distance the maximum density and the
space complexity is already for the
deficit okay but for breakfast search is
determined by because we have to use the
Q
okay yes
okay so what have you learned today
what's the problem what have you learned
today and that's it I mean you go first
[Music]
yesterday but it deficit yeah so can you
tell more about this deficit search I
mean why
why we
well you have this notebook and and so
we don't really do the same thing so so
whenever yeah we and every so often we
market so we don't do it again yeah and
market and don't do it again yeah Market
unmark it right the first search we
checked with marketing people if it's
visited we can close right yeah and if
we find this then we update the shortest
path
shortest distance this is kind of brute
force in a text message manner okay so
it only works in this kind of particular
problem if this tree is unbounded then
this will take forever the ultimate
solution is breakfast such we talked
about yesterday never by level because
it guarantees the minimum distance as
long as we find it right the first note
we find it impressive search is the
ultimate in uh in an animated graph it
doesn't matter if it's directly or
animated okay it has to be unweighted
okay you can be directly or undirected
but it has to be unweighted okay make
sense can you tell me what have you
learned today and I'm just saying
what's the same thing
okay so what's the problem and what how
do we solve it
Stefan search
yes going deeper as we can yes
okay and how we usually implement the
depth as such
please
use a light blue forcing what's what's
up calling yourself yeah yeah
because your hair looks Eric yeah yeah
okay yeah that's it for today bye-bye
bye bye