why
I keep your balance
so I'll have this date
and what else date adjustment
and a balance right
so for example someday and you deposit
a hundred pounds and their balance will
be 100.
as I promise you I will give you the
interest
every month
am I yeah so three percent remember or
four percent yeah if you promise that
it's a fixed you're not withdrawing any
money from the bank from that is for the
next 30 days then the interest rate will
be four percent right so after a month
how much money you get so I'll be
kicking it
100 no balance
four percent
that's the interest for a year right for
a year
divided by 2f
12 months
right so after 30 days you'll get these
as an interest have you thought about
what happened because next 30 days what
happened the next 30 days
[Music]
um
so look this is
going to earn Ed in 30 days right
so I don't know what number is it a okay
so in the next 30 days these entries
will be part of your principle right we
call it principal at the beginning your
principle is a hundred so in this next
30 day will be 100 plus a all right this
is your principle
yeah and then times the interest rate
for 30 days four percent
divided by 12. right
okay
yeah
so what does it mean it means that your
inches you earn become the principal
okay yeah so have you thought about if I
give you the interest like
every six months every two months every
week or every day which one is better
every day you can discuss feeling right
okay I go for every
Okay so let's make it simplified
suppose you one pound on delis one pound
right
that's your money yeah one time and I
promise you a hundred percent interest
rate 100 meaning that if I calculate
your interest once a year in 12 months
what do you get so like look this is
your principle once yearly so how much
money you get a hundred percent uh one
yeah so one plus one that's two that's
your principle that's your interest
there but we calculate it once a year so
we've got two how about every
six months
every six months one plus
so how do we calculate every six months
in six months five
five in six months so you have one
hundred percent right one hundred
percent
divided by two because every six months
it means that there are two two periods
in a year right look right to the power
of two yeah this is the total money
you'll get in a year if we split the
period into two every six months you
know what you need a squad that's a good
question how do we get this okay so look
here this is six months this is six
months this is a year right so this is
at the beginning the first month
right one plus one equals two you
understand this part right this is easy
right why is that look it's one plus a
hundred percent
divided by one that's only one period
right makes sense yes six months one
plus
a hundred percent divided by a hundred
percent you're not getting a hundred
percent in six months you're getting
half of a hundred percent yeah so you
divided by two this is the total money
you will get in
six months right but in the six months
as I said this whole thing becomes the
principle again right what do you get
here look this one in six months so it's
times a hundred percent divided by two
right 100 divided by two but also plus
one plus times one plus but why time
look this is the principle so basically
the interest rate is p times I
one plus I okay one plus I
interested
one plus I this is the total number of
money you get all right so this is the p
P times one plus I this is interest rate
right inches like a hundred percent okay
make sense
this is the total number of money you
get a mile equals P times one plus I do
understand this D is the number
principle the money you have got now the
money you put in the bank one plus I I
is the interest rate now I equals one
one 100 percent okay
so why why this every six months so it's
look at six months we get one plus
100 divided by two so that becomes a new
principle that's p and then you times
and the second half
because the interest rate you end
in from the month 7 to month 12. this
bit
this is on P which is which equals one
plus 100 divided by two right this P
here is just one yes
makes sense
okay so how about if I keep splitting
you know if I calculate the interest so
every season is every fourth season so
actually this is divided by four and
12th I learned here is 12. so do you
notice the pattern yeah
yeah so it actually means that
is one plus one hundred percent divided
by n
and and if n equals two it means that
the whole year you divide into two if n
equals four you divide it into four if n
equals 12 you divide by 12. if n equals
if n equals 365 we calculate the
interest every day right yes and then if
360 5 times 24 every hour
times 60 every minute
times 60 every seconds
nice
how about every milliseconds okay then
you keep timing so and
and you can increase that so what's the
value so the thing is that you said
every day is better than every every
month right
yeah because again
so look
we can define a python functions to do
it that's a very simplified F so we just
have to pass the N here right so return
one plus
one divided by n to the power of n right
to the power n
to the power and we talk about that last
double star means the to the power or we
use the power function right power
function x to the power n yeah
so if we calculate light so what do we
have
one two four
six twelve 365 365 times 24
365 times 24 times 60. and then 365
times 24 times 60 times 60. so what do
we have with these values n equals one
anyway yes that's two
yeah is it increasing
52 weeks 2.692
2.714
2.718 2.7182
okay
so what have you noticed here from these
values here I just particularly at least
values using this function
um it's increasing right but it has a
limit am I right yes
yeah
even I calculate the interest every
second
it's still not going to Infinity
right because based on this function
yeah one plus one divided by n to the
power of n this function has a limit
so look 2.718 this converge this value
converge to to this
2.71 a to a something okay
this number irrational
there are unlimited numbers of digits
Behind These numbers it's like Pi you
know Pi yeah the circle yeah so
irrational number you know the
irrational number irrational
so this is the mathematic constant a
magic number we call it e okay this is
the most important thing to take away
today e
okay
yeah
e is counting how many zeros right
now e is the nature and
nature
in the natural constant e okay okay
so what does it mean look so
limit
when n approaches Infinity all right so
we want to calculate this Infinity
one plus where do you copy the numbers
from
this is not e this is not easy this one
the easy this one how much is it VCC
okay
look one plus one divided by n to the
power of n okay so the most important
thing to take away here look this one to
understand this
when n
approaches infinity look you'll
understand this yeah this is infinity
here
Infinity
what is it what does this infinity mean
it means carry it going on yeah when n
approaches Infinity this this value
one plus one divided by n to the power
of n what is this value e e that's what
I just said e okay be loud okay so
what's e
e is that number
but this is never end yeah this never
ends this goes repeat and repeat the
number and it's like PI what's pi what's
the value of pi
three three
and
two three
okay this is like the numbers I can
remember okay remember I put these uh on
the fridge
but you know
pi and E those are very special
mathematic constant Never End irrational
number
like one two
zero point five okay
the end
this is the number of
the number of the interest paid out
right so one is that you pay our
interest in one year two is they pay out
twice
inches so it's payout four interest
six
inches 12 12 inches right so this is
monthly this every two months this is
uh every three months every six months
every 12 months we increase the number
of payouts
365 means that we calculate the interest
every day and then the a this is the
number of money we can get in one year
is it better
to calculate the interest rate daily or
monthly
n is how much yeah interested
in Daily
this one is every second
every minute every hour
every day
every week every month every two months
every three months every six months
every year every year look one two
yeah remember you've got one one pound
the interest rate is 100 in 12 months in
a year you've got two pounds right one
is interest rate if we split it into two
you got 2.25 and girls larger the egg
the number of money gets larger but if
there's a limit it's not Infinity right
that's what it is here so when n
approaches Infinity yeah look this end
approach Infinity yeah
you're not getting infinity money you're
only getting the E you converts to e
which is this number of money so it
means that you have one dollar the
interest rate is 100 percent
the maximum you can get
from the bank
is this Lambda e okay
2.718 you only have to remember these
three digits
yeah this is the number you need to do
the rest we don't care okay two points
of one eight two eight one seven seven
eight four six eight nine
yeah and I look the person is good yeah
one plus one divided by n times n this
is to the power okay
we have the bank and and so we we're
doing the interest and it we're going
like
um like daily
daily we're doing daily
um second minute uh
the monthly
um
everything around
every three months
every six months and every year and
and sober
so the result is like um it's easier to
calculate every year because
because uh like every
second you uh see because uh
the bottomans has more numbers to it a
equals P to times one plus I what what's
P
uh yeah so after a month what happened
to p
increases after 30 days the T includes
the interest you end on the first month
all right
yeah so that's why the more
of n the more of the a because P
increases
make sense
okay that's it for today bye bye