hello Miss Mary Mr Rhino right
Okay so we've given this uh four digit
number and our test is to split the
number into two we can use the digit
this is these four digit so we want to
split the digit into two and now we want
to minimize the sum for example like
this one if we split these into one two
and three four and by the way you can
rearrange these numbers right you can be
2 1 or 43 and we want to minimize some
so the sum is 46 can you find the
smaller one yes what is this 13 and 24
13 plus 24 Max
37 that's smaller and anymore
14 and 23
14 and 23 that's it's 47. is it the same
answer this one yeah okay anymore
okay so basically we can prove off right
do we have to try splitting the number
into three digits and one digit no
yes because of no matter which three
digit is at least three digits right
there will be a hundreds right maybe
hundreds
good question one zero zero one okay two
two yeah we can have bleeding yellows
bleeding zeros so like obviously this is
four units you know one plus zero one
right it's two okay how about this one
do one plus zero zero thirty four one
two five four and two sorry what did you
say one two three four one two five four
one two three four and two one plus zero
zero one okay okay yes yes we'll add two
very special case
this is 27
. okay so how do you know this is the
smallest
yeah we can try I mean obviously this is
just four digits we can prove us right
four digit we can prove ourselves as we
said that we don't want to try the three
teachers thing right so how many
possibilities so four digit we just pick
two as the first number right and this
is the normal way of picking the
two-digit and now we need to times two
right this is the overall proof of if we
don't try three digit thing right so
what's this number four Apple speaking
to Apples right there for that five plus
we just have to pick two apples as the
first number and then how many ways so
this is basically
p
four apples picking two apples but with
sequence right so it's four times
3 12 waves right this is just 12 12
different ways we have to prove us three
different ways right okay
so this one if I saw this number
okay if I saw this number this is the
small list this is the biggest
so obviously this this big is number
where do we want to keep this biggest
number
[Music]
the biggest digit we want it to be hands
or we only repeat it once
we only be once obviously right so we
want to be two ones here
okay so here there are two numbers put
us together this is the ones how about
this number this is the smallest put it
before before yeah so this is I wanted
to obviously I want to put it here right
so yeah and then these two which one is
bigger so it's bigger so the bigger one
we want to put it in right in the ones
right yeah in a while
so this is the smallest 27 one two three
four so four I want to put it you know
once
one and put it in a tens and then two
three seven okay this is just common
sense right the big digit I want it to
be in uh once that's not the digit we
can put it in the tens okay if we're
given these four digits how do we
extract each digit well we can convert
it to a string right one way or because
this is four digits if this is n all
right how do we convert it to each
Studio first of all we convert it to a
string all right convert to a string and
then we
split we convert it to an array of
digits and then we have to map it as
method as integer right
okay I know we need to sort it
salt it right so look this is two three
four one if this is two three four one
Str will put a cloth that's the string
least if we do this list you'll become
two three
four
one right this is the list we map it to
integer so that will become two three
four one all right I know we sort it now
become one two three four okay that's
basically what it is right and then we
just have to return
this number
this number times 10 plus
and then plus this number times 10
right because it's in the tens Plus
this number okay and now okay okay
another way I'll do three four one if we
want to get it into each number so this
if this is n and modulus 10 that will
give us one right and then we need to
divide this number into ten now become
two three four and then
we keep doing this right we remove the
last digit that the ones a number like
one two three four how do we get this
how to get the digit only once
yeah modular scent right
yeah and then how do we remove that last
digit we just divided by 10 right
divided by 10 it will be one two three
point four but we converted to the
integer so one one two three okay one
two three
123 models ten divided by 10 remaining
three okay yeah make sense
yeah one two three six is the same yeah
so one two three six six six equals one
two three six modulus ten and then
one two three equals one two three six
divided by divided ten right in Python
okay in Python right modulus divided
yeah you see six I want to get this last
the lowermost digit I'm not understand I
want to remove the rightmost digit I
divided by 10. double divide means to
divide by 10 and only keep the integer
part forget about the fraction okay okay
so what have you learned today and
that's it I learned about numbers
there's a full digit number and split it
and we split it and to get to like the
lower sum okay so do we have to try the
three digit and one digit right okay why
because it'll be big it will be big
right three digit you guaranteed it's a
three digit thing once we did this thing
you guarantee there's a hundred right a
hundred
this problem is founded there are only
12. if we try to expect four numbers
four digits into uh two digits Plato
digit so it's it's basically the same
thing like four iPods speaking to apples
with sequence that's that's p
two apple five for picking two apples is
equals let's pick two apples out of four
apples and then permutate it permutated
okay permutated first of all we pick
like two a plus
and then we can rearrange these two
apples that's basically the way it is
okay that's it for today bye