is let it go hello hello hello okay
hello
hello my hello eric hello teacher hello
mr eric
sit down please so
today we talk about these the how do we
calculate this the
power you know mathematic power
x to the power of n yeah if i tell you x
is some any number 14 numbers
1.5 to negative
3.5 maybe you know and
it's an integer it could be negative as
well
remember okay so when it's positive so
when it's positive yeah for example like
2 to the power of 3
okay so it means that
3 times of 2 together yeah 2 times 2
there are three
there are three yeah okay
how about 2 to the power -3
do you understand no it means that you
can convert it in
you can because it's negative so this
you put one
away yeah yes oh yeah and then
three times and this negative and then
what does it equal
one one and eight two to the power three
one and eight yeah
because one to the power of three is one
two to the power three is eight okay
yes how about
one two three four five to the power of
zero
how about zero to the power of one two
three four
five uh
because zero i mean a mean and zero
multiplied together is zero right yeah
yeah okay
how about one to the power of one two
three four five
um
one two three four five one to the power
of one two three four five one times
time one equals one
one and one times a minimum times equals
what one yeah one
okay so these are three special cases
yeah and this
is you these cases you need you can turn
the negative power
into the positive power right yes okay
so if there are
n n x how do you calculate these
and x x and x to the power of n
define power
x comma and what's missing here
okay so when we write the we write the
spatial case yeah if x equals
one right yeah all n
equals zero
return
zero no no no one one
one
if if
n smaller than zero okay
so now remember x equals
x and n x will become 1.0 divided by x
right yeah remember that 2 to the power
3.
x will become these right and these will
become
these yeah it's the same thing yeah yeah
so
actually become this n will become what
the negative becomes positive minus
n right yeah n is minus three and then
minus minus two equals three right
okay so these last cases so now
how do you how do we implement this x
and
the very simple way you just terms x
n times yeah okay so how do we do it we
got the answer
beginning will be one right yeah
then for anything you know
you can use understood score if you're
not using the value
in range what
range x and
times times y times
what times x return
later on we're done you see this is
exactly this is the very simple case yes
yeah easy
to get the problem but look if
if x is an even number
now that's all number right like two to
the power of three
these three is order yeah yeah
effect otd yeah odd number yeah
so e equals 2
times 2 to the power of 2 right
yeah because there are 3 2's then i i
take 1 2 out
and times it will be 2 to the power of 2
right yes
look this is a this is 2 times 4 is a
right
okay let's do another example
3 to the power of 4 this is even number
now right
even number yeah yes what does it equal
does it equal what's this number
81 right 3 times 3 times 3 times 3
81 so does it equal 3 to the power of 2
and times 3 to the power of 2 right
yeah this is like this is not yeah so
so what what this four i can divide it
so
basically when this is even number i can
do this i can reduce it to half
and then i can square it right i can
square it
yes yeah so
this time you need to do three times
right
four times yeah three times three times
three times three
right yeah yeah three times three
times three times actually three times
as well
uh at least three times
you need to do three multiplication here
how about this
three times three one time
square it one time
so that's two times uh two times yeah so
you see this is faster
yeah okay so if
if like let's say 3 to 100 power 2 to
the power 100
you turn 3 to get 100 times this is oh
what complexity over i
if this is an over
because yes you are right because you
need to multiply three
a hundred ten times yes how about
if i do this i can for to take a release
i can calculate this becomes three power
of
fifty and then i can square it right
yes and in order to take your lease
i can do this 3 to the power of 25
square
squared right yes and the 3 to the power
is even odd number size is equals 3
times
3 to the power 24 right and this thing
3 to the power of 12 squared
you see so what's the complexity
uh logan wow brilliant
that's what i'm looking for exactly very
clever oh my god you
you follow that is big brain yeah
okay that's good so you understand this
okay so we can implement
this so look we this we can use it yeah
because this we can
use it yeah okay we can reuse this bit
but
but now we're going to remove this
look then look if
n is odd number so it's all number we
can use this yeah
or number equals one right yeah all you
can do is
remember in binary the odd number the
last bit is one right
yes the binary zero one two that's one
zero one
uh one or zero that's five right
this is always one the least small least
significant bit we call it
this sniffing provider least
significant bit in binary is the right
mode so you can do it you can also write
this n if n n is in binary
n one then do this equals one okay and
then
what if it's all number so
we can do it recursively return
x times
times y n no no no
x times power
x and minus one right yeah yeah
look we take one x and then we have n
minus one x left
if it's an even number let's do it y
equals
power and you tell me what what's legs
okay x
and divided by two half remember
and then written one remember the square
thing
thing three to a hundred equals 350
square okay so where's your player
yeah y times y y squared yeah y times
y or y squared or power y okay
okay this is this one is we call it
recursion yeah
look this is the question calling itself
calling itself
and we can do it iteratively
so this is the last iterator so y
and smaller than or equal to one right
we've got the answer here answer equals
one if
n is odd number answer
times x right and then we need to x
times excel right x becomes
x x becomes x times x
so x times x okay and then n
will reduce to half so n divided by two
right so n equals n divided by two
divided by two all you can do is this
shifting look
double equal this means double
crochet this this means what for example
this is shifting rook binary
one zero one zero doing this if n is
this n is what
four plus two this is six in binary
right yeah
this is this is six
okay so doing this if i shift one
position to the right where it becomes
i shift it shift it with the shifted so
you become
zero one zero one okay so this one the
yellow is gone
right it's gone it's 15 and then they'll
become
what six again
no that'll be three you see so it means
divided by half
okay so if because it's binary if i
if i put a zero at the end it means the
shifting
to the left then you'll be the value
will be double
right if i am shifting to the right i
get rid of one zero at the end
now being divided by twelve ah two right
okay so this is the the same as the same
as
n equals n divided by two okay it's the
same thing okay
okay so now let's do recording
can you sit there please i reckon
yeah it's very clear that's it i need to
use this computer
okay good we are very good
it's very clear can you check thank you
okay
okay let's do it call
okay power so oh yes
so let's let's do the first first uh
first version okay first version
x n so you tell me if
x equals one
or n equals zero what should we return
we turn one yeah if x
equals zero what's we determine because
zero
okay then if n smaller than zero then we
need to
do x and equals one
1.0 divided by x and what
minus n we are negative okay then let's
do the very
first version let's put it uh in the
answer answer equals one
for uh in range range renoir
range and then
answer equals answer times what
what are we multiplying x yes
and we can
what are we calculating here
okay let's do check some value first
okay
power one two to the power of ten yeah
three power one two to the power of
minus 3 okay
okay 1 to
a 100 1
between power 1 uh
uh
yes okay this is great okay let's do the
uh second version okay
so second version
define power to
xn so these will be the same yeah x
equals one
or n equals zero uh return
one if x equals zero
returns zero if smaller than zero then
we
do this x n equals one
divided by x minus n and then we do this
if uh if
and this is odd number then it return
power to
x n minus 1
and times x y
yes otherwise i return otherwise i need
to
save this value power to x and divide by
two right
yeah and then return y times y or y
you can do this as well okay yeah okay
so let's see
let's change this to
[Music]
very powerful so you should give me the
same result right
yeah it's giving the same result okay
all right let's do this
version
yeah yeah
define power three x n so basically
let's do it
return one if x
equals zero return zero
if x n smaller than zero
x n equals one i x and minus
n and i look answer equals one
okay so y n is bigger than one
then we do this if n is odd number
answer times x and then x
times itself and then n will become
become
uh half right and you can answer
and that's the third version okay
it's a bit low that's okay stays it
doesn't
matter let's do this
yes it's the same yeah yeah okay so
actually there's a false version
really because we are inventing
this is how we calculate it but already
the computer already know how to do it
or already defined it so we can just do
this
it's already supported by python right
you can do this
double star yeah
this is the same thing okay
so we don't need my powerful
which one is better do you think
which one do you think which one do you
like the better do you like the first
version
it's easy to understand look it's just
times times expected to
is it the phartest or the notice
i think it's
like yes no because you need to times if
n is armenian you need to times
n a million times right but this is on
the power 2 and power
3 oh this is all log n right
so it's much smaller yeah in the times
it's always reducing look the important
thing is that when it's
all when it's even number the end will
become
half right so it's going to be three
yeah yeah it would be reduced to
100 becomes 50 50 will become 25. you
see
so it's it needs three times to reduce
from 100 to
25 but it takes 75 times to reduce from
125 right you see the difference
yeah yeah okay good job today good job
good job
good job good job today
say bye bye see you tomorrow