hello Mr Mr Rider right
okay so what's maze Amaze is a thing
where we're dead and the end
not like that okay let's say this is
the end okay and then it could be any
right there's only one part at least but
one pass okay or maybe not right okay so
maybe
so what is that okay so yeah I'm going
to draw a maze but yeah I can do it but
there's squares yeah then that's Square
I can do it so how do you do it
um there's no video you haven't finished
that yeah yeah let me try it and then
you understand what I meant okay okay
so amazed I understand the main the
normal maze is something like that right
so you have a different you know
different parts
that's just a picture look that's a
picture okay okay
another parrot
oh okay okay
this is amazing
like that that's a funny picture
like
panda
yeah I understand that but how does the
computer store the maze right so it's in
a great Elementary right I can draw a
mate here right for example like if I'm
saying right this is the entrance entry
the engine and axes are on the border
right so this could be uh exit and this
could be another exit and then I could
have uh you know a war right this is a
war
okay a war
okay so look this is the entrance right
if I'm saying this is the engine there
there are two exits okay so what's the
shortest what's the nearest exit what's
the nearest I think uh there is no
mirrors they're both the same the Bowser
Center one two three four
okay another two more to this two more
three yeah you're right and how about if
I rock it with the wall you can't even
go with that yeah you can't even go
there the nearest exit is this way right
I'm just too distract you yeah yeah okay
okay yeah but what if
yeah I know I know okay
what is
um
[Music]
then we need to return minus one why so
we're given this kind of maze we're
given this entrance which is on the
border one and we also given well we
don't know we need to find out we need
to find out the axis the X's are the
empty cells On the Border okay there is
no
language written minus one that's good
well if there is an exit
that is
actually do you get it yes
okay so what's your Source how do we
solve this problem
[Music]
that's a good thinking okay so how about
that massage can we use the deposition
really no reason why the professor she's
okay yeah it's good
we usually use the prefer search to find
the shortest path right level by level
you know I'm waiting Club okay we talk
about that right so we start from this
one when we start from this one and then
we do this level by level search as long
as we find the first exit which is on
the border a noun empty okay by the way
are you saying that we check in no no
that's a good point look we visualize
here we're at this point right we are at
this point which is the this step this
step one here
okay so that we expand what's the next
step here is two here three here is two
here three okay uh suppose to be here
and then what's next two two this the
next step of two is four all right
okay and then three in the next step is
five
we visualize the search we visualize the
path finding in a tree right in the tree
it's a search tree we visualize it and
we can do level by level right like now
this is six suppose we don't block it
okay we don't block it so seven
okay
9 10 11 12. okay so what's next look we
take three and a five
which one is no one you're not knowing
this one
this is what so one is what we don't
push it back to the queue all right with
the first thing first round remember so
look we take the four out
do we need to push two and three back
no because we have seen it we use the
headset right so now we take this out
for four hours and then uh and then
what's next in a Q5 right we take a five
out
what's the kit three and six plus three
we have seen this before so we put the
six what's the kit of six
seven right
what's the kid of seven and eleven all
right are you an 11. what's next eight
okay nine
when we see this nine right we find it
actually no actually we will take the
eleven out right let's watch his kid
seven and twelve but we've seen the
seven before so 12. what's the next to
take out nine
9 is the exit
then we find it so this is the shortest
right and when we expand the tree we
remember the distance
so when we push the kit back to the
queue we have this distance increment by
one all right
so perfect search and wait here we talk
about and waiting always it means that
the one step one step equals one it's
the same it's the same it goes to left
those the right goes to the up close the
bottom as long as empty cell right and
waited
and directly meaning that so we can go
to five five can double to three and we
need to solve this problem by using the
hash set am I right okay that's my
search my work or may not work because
that's my search we're just going deep
as as deep as we can and when we find
the first exit it may not be the nearest
make sense unless
unless we extort proof of us all the
paths and then we can find the nearest
path all right if we search if we find
all possibilities then we know which
path leads to the shortest but it's not
very efficient last week we talked about
minimum gene mutation and two
to find the nearest path we can also use
iterated dependencies right but in this
case prefer search is the way to go
right it's the way to go okay then let's
implement it and that's it so
we start with the engine right exit is
not the entry right we have to make sure
that the axis is not the same engine can
you tell me what are the other way of
doing it it's again the perfect search
but we can think of the opposite what's
the opposite
[Music]
yes but there could be many exit right
we can just push this axis into the
queue and then once he finds the engine
it's the same right it's both way right
yeah I'm right okay let's do one thing
at a time first of all we need to Define
this axis right it's exit
and we Define this R and see if if I
equal equals zero or C equals zero or r
equal rows minus one or c equal to a
column minus one right it's in here it's
in in the border right if it's in the
Border also we have to check the maze it
has to be a empty cell right empty cell
we can use the top okay empty set
otherwise we'll return first right this
is simple
simple function right the exit has to be
in the Border here here here here and it
has to be empty there no rewards we can
use the plus to represent Awards okay
this is the X equality and then we use
the Q Q equals c q
DQ EQ awakened Hybrid engine right
entrance so we push this entering and
train
and then at the beginning the step is
the yellow okay and then wire Q
of course we have to keep all the
visited cell in the scene hashtag
hashtag it's a notebook when we visit
the number seven we'll put it down so we
don't put this 75 in the queue okay one
question why do we need to remember the
the position we have seen so you don't
go back
you'll never
why is that look look one I push this
one I take it out I push it to two and
three back to the key okay so two
what's the kit one and four one and four
I push it one and four okay three take
it out what's the kick one four five
five one four five one what's the keep
two and three you see do you see the
problem
do you see the problem here
yeah we have seen this before and then
we keep pushing back to the kill and
that never ends so we need to have a
hatchback a notebook to remember the the
says the position we've seen okay yq we
take it out
ah C and the distance equals Q dot pop
left right here double ndq top left
foreign we take it out from the left
hand side okay if I see if not equals to
if it's not equal the entering we have
to compare to the entry if it's not
entering because the exit is not entered
right if the current position is not
entering and also it's an exit
right so we are basically saying that if
it's exit and it's also known the
entrance right we don't go back to the
engine
land will return the distance right
otherwise we go to the fourth Direction
Dr
PC in four Direction Four Direction up
down left right okay up down one zero
zero one
minus one zero zero minus one one zero
zero one minus one zero zero minus one
what are those
n r and C equals the t r plus r
and C right so okay I'm not going to
write it here two two squeeze it here
okay if n r n c is less than red
that easy to win the range and if it's
not seen before and I can see not insane
land
okay so if and R and c not in scene we
haven't visited this before and the N
are bigger than zero smaller than Rose
bigger than zero and
Zillow and C is smaller than columns
like we push it to the cube a pen
and then otherwise if we can find the
PATH using the blood pressure to return
minus one right you ask this question
this is to push the entrance to the kill
and what Eric you mentioned that we can
push back backwards we can push the exit
look around to exit so we go to La made
we find out the exit which are not the
entry okay and then we push all our exit
to the queue we initialize the Q here
this is to initialize the
kill when you start entering right so
only
opposite will be first of all go through
the maze find out or exit which you are
known as entering kill the append to to
push the exit to the kill and do this
then if RC is equal equal entry we just
need to check if it is entering we don't
need this right we don't need this you
want to find the path in the Maze you
can start with the engine or you can
start with the exit
but the thing is that there could be
many exit but that's okay for breakfast
we can push
all the axes to the cube so start with
all the exit right there could be many X
here
we see this engine we find the surface
path it's the same thing all right we
have to check if the next cell if the
next cell is empty it's not a wall then
we can push it back to the queue so here
what it's missing is that we have to
check if n
maze
n r and C
it's not a war right it's not a wall and
then we can push it back to the kill
okay the other thing about using this a
headset right it's not insane right so
we are marking down the cells the
positions that we have visited uh in a
queue right the other way of doing it is
that when we push it back to the queue
uh we directly change this the a cell
for example if it's an empty cell we
change this to wall right so we change
it to war then the next time with this
check same cell is not pushed back to
the queue again instead of using a scene
table headset to remember the fixes that
we have uh push we have visited we
directly change the maze yeah from empty
cell to wall so it's not being pushed
back again in the future so this is
another way okay so the time conducts
tea
this is textbook okay
okay so the next lesson we're going to
use the deficitors to prove us to see
just give an idea yeah just like last
time we have been talking about the mean
gym program the lesson after next we're
going to talk about the iterative
dependent session right so increment
increment the limit and into the default
okay what have you learned today it's
amazing more sentence you have a some
books
I don't want to find a shooting and I
haven't even breakfast search why can we
use the birth massage
because it's do you normally useful
finding the shortest path yeah because
we can visualize these in using the
graph it's a graph problem right it's a
shortage glass problem in uh weighted or
unweighted
waited on waited
okay is it directed
why is it directly just
just
and there's a star and and we don't want
to go back and and could be any
more of everything and so we want to
find the shortest of the shortest amount
of
um but
the closest exit then you're real estate
and then how do we solve this problem
okay and what other algorithm can we
apply to this problem
okay yeah
which one is the most efficient
purposes deficiency is inefficient right
just give you an idea
that's what TV