okay so we have uh different ways of
cutting a circle like if you can imagine
that's a pizza right these are the two
Valley cards so you can cut directly
through into that diameter okay
or you can do this half cut one touches
the edge of the pizza and the other one
touches the center of the pizza at least
it's not a very cut right so the
question is that we want to cut this
piece up this circle into an equal
slices equal slices right you can do it
this way cut into two half or you can do
this half cut right but this is not
cutting into two slices this is just two
half cup okay so the question is that we
want to do the minimum cut that cut into
the N slices equal slices all right so
for example yeah as you can see we draw
here right if n equals the one so we do
zero card right and n equals 1 so that
means zero cut right n equals two
okay this is n equals two you do this
one cut right into two so n equals two
we need to do one cut and equal three
yeah you do this yeah because it depends
n equals three so you do
three
half cut so that's three
all right n equals four which one is
that initial for this one yeah this one
so two four cuts
n equals five which one is that equals
five which one
two three four five okay
I equals six
this one so how many cards of this
okay right three three okay and then
equals seven
I'm gonna cut
seven seven
yeah do you see the strategy
so what's the strategies you can use it
is that from one is that from one yeah
it's kind of different to the other side
yeah special cases this is the even
number you can it's Heaven yeah and and
if it's the old number it's just that's
right yes you are right very good
observation so if it's a look if n
equals six n equals six so it will be
so we can do this uh half right so n
equals six is this this way right yeah
so look look at this half
so that's three three slices
but with the three slices look we can
extend this to that so it's it just
requires half of it all right yeah we
cut half on a circle half our pizza into
slide uh three slices just you know this
this is three slices but we can map it
so and honestly it's like this so if
this is n equals six right so it's even
number we can uh half and it half and
half a cut
right but if it's a odd number how would
you do it
you just do this on one server right to
130 just equally
equally space right okay and n equals
one is a special case
so be fine uh F if n if n equals one
return zero special case if n is odd
right n one or modulus two if n n one or
if if n modulus 2 equal equal one
land three ten and right if it's all
number written n otherwise return and
divide divide divided by two heavily
okay common space complexity
[Music]
exactly look just mess space or one
right okay so what have you learned
today about cut okay so if you want to
describe this to Mommy or how would you
say come on we have a cool Pizza yeah
you have a pizza that we need to eat
and we need to cut it
and
try the minimum equal slices yeah yeah
so what's the strategy we just
we just have any even numbers
uh to the minimum and then the other
okay
so we have a circle and we we only can
do the cuts of of straight through or or
a half cup
a a half car and so so if you want to
cut it into n equal slices and so it's
just like a pizza and the strategy is
if it's an even number you can just it's
haha because because you can you can do
two
two hot two half cuts which makes one
just like two half Cuts makes one street
Cuts so it has and and the odd number is
just it but but the N equals one is
special as as you can see here oh so you
don't need to zero but
well that's good that's it for today
bye-bye bye bye bye