why
okay so a few days ago we talked about
this maze program right we're going to
find the nearest exit
yeah in the Maze okay so the exit and
entrance are the empty cells On the
Border these borders and their four
borders right
and
engine is not the exit so for example if
you're given this entry and you can't
just go back to this right obviously
it's just not exit you have to find a
ways to other axes in the Border okay
I'd only talk about a breakfast search
right because these actually this is the
unweighted graph I'm waiting I'm
directly graph right we're finding with
the shortest part I think the one
Newton Corner yeah so yeah so for
example like we call this cross this is
represent uh see what you're doing a
wall a wall no okay so the shot is
passed if we give them this entry shot
is passed to the exit would be nice
it'll be this one right yeah but but
before when the moon won that it was
that one which is different made if
there are exits you return the shortest
part the distance so one two three four
five six you return six right and if
they are not exists or if there is no
ways I have no way is to the x is 0 to
10 minus one makes sense well you can
break the word no we don't this is the
entry one two three four five six seven
eight nine ten eleven twelve thirteen
okay so we don't Mark the walls because
there's no point to push the positions
of the walls into the queue because we
you know we don't go there basically
right we go to this empty cell so the
perfect search first thing first all
right so at the beginning will push to
the entrance one okay we DQ DQ means to
take the element from the Q in the left
top left yeah
which means that we push the kit off of
the you know the children to on the
right hand side okay so we take you out
what's the keep of wine what's the next
two right only two okay so put it two so
two we take it off what's the kit of two
one and three but one we have visited
before right we need to have at least a
scene table hashtag to remember the
petition we have visited so we take a
two out we take a two hour the kid is
three okay three we take it out what's
the kit for
oh we take it out what's the kid three
and five or three we have seen it before
so five
five we take it out what's the Kid of
Five
four nine eight right but we have seen
four before so nine and eight
okay what's the kit of nine take it out
and six ten and five right but we have
seen five before so
what's six and five one and five
children is six okay okay
ah five five so what is it five six here
right is it so now we six take it off
what's the kit five we've seen it before
seven right seven
when you push the kids to the kill you
push on the right hand side when you
take it out you take it on the level
inside so now what's the kit of a take
it out what's the key level eight five
and seven we've seen five before seven
we we have seen it right 13.
13 to the 13 right okay
and what's the kit of 10. now we have
seen it before what's the Creed of seven
hey we have seen it before oh yeah yeah
you never know yeah okay okay and then
we take the 30 now okay 13. this is the
exit so we know the distance okay so
when we push the kid back to the queue
we know the distance right so for
example at the beginning we're pushing
the one and zero right I only push the
two we know the current distance is zero
so we press one so it'd be two one right
so every time we push the kick back to
the cube or you can store the distance
in a couple the first element is the
position the second element in the table
is the distance so when we find the axis
we know the distance the shortest
distance that's the purpose we talk
about two ways of professors starting
searching from the entrain okay find any
of the exit or we push all the axis back
to the kill we put a 12 0 and 13 zero
right and then we do this perfect search
from the axis until we find the entrance
this is one way okay
and we also talk about a hash set right
so we don't need to use the hash set
can you think about a way that we get
rid of the headset when we're about to
push it back to the queue we change the
cell to walls does it make sense we take
one out yeah we push it to keep two
right so two now is an empty cell right
so if we push it to the Q we change
immediately to walk
huh we just change it so the next time
this cell is not visited again right
make sense
yeah it doesn't make sense yeah because
we're only visiting once oh no you're
about to push the fair
position to the queue we mark it as War
so the next time it's not visited again
simple right perfect it's ultimate to
find a shortage path because Never by
never that's very straightforward so
look if there are two axes right if
there are two x's if this is exit this
is exit only to the person search level
by level when we find that exit this is
the shortest path because it's anointed
but if it's deficit it's not right when
we find it we might find this first
right but this is not the shortest this
is the shortest unless we exalt all the
parts I think we talk about that yeah
unless we
use the deficit to find all the paths to
the exit when we perform the temperature
we find this exit we don't stop here
because we haven't finished setting the
whole tree yet
and we finish this trip I know we found
two axis and we can compare the distance
obviously if we know Leia two axes and
then we use the different search
definite search and recursion usually we
talk about implementing the data as
usual recursion again we set up a search
we can use a headset or we can mark the
empty cell walls as long as we visit it
if I that was such a common position
rows column and then we have a distance
current distance and we can have a scene
table a scene headset right headset if
is exit
ah C and if currently is RC and RC is
not equal to the entry right entry is a
total okay then we remember save the
answer at the beginning is infinity
save the answer
equals the mean when we find the exit We
compare with the minimum we attend the
minimum right saved answer
and then distance and then return okay
return true if we find it okay okay and
then now we have to check if RC in scene
well
this is very important in an unweighted
undirected graph in the binary tree we
don't usually worry about visiting again
finally three you visit two from one
right you don't go back one to two we
don't go back it's a directive but here
this is not because look three visit
four four can visit three three four
you're F4 right you can go to three and
you can come back so if I don't have a
headset or if I don't remember the notes
I have visited what happened you just
keep walking here or there and you never
get job done right this is the point of
using the headset and then the first
thing to to put it into the headset okay
and then we just need to go through the
neighbors for
brtc in four neighbors one zero zero one
minus one zero zero minus one and then n
r n c equals t r plus r d c plus c
please look for coordinates four tuples
is just means that four positions up
down left right okay and then obviously
if n r this has to be in the range
bigger than zero smaller than rows and
zero smaller than NC smaller than
columns okay this is the interesting
part okay so if that
and if maze nrnc
is not what
then we do this step and such step as
such a n r and C now because you know
this is Bluetooth and I can see D plus
one and then sing sing don't remove we
need to remove it we need to recover
this is very important why is that look
oh this is the path after we finish this
route we have to unset otherwise other
route might be affected this is very
important in terms as such when we
visited we mark it as visited and after
we install all the paths here we have to
unset it and look at that message we
perform a data search we are not saying
terminal here if I say if
if two then that's going to be a problem
because we are not actually stopping
once we find the exit right we want to
excel the paths right we talk about this
scene table right we don't need to use
it instead we can set it to maze RC
equal
what we change it to war and then we
unset it to Maze and R and C equals
empty set the first thing is that the
visited we have to mark it as visited
before and then we have to restore after
we can Mark a visit is there a war
instead of using a headset before we
recursive recording itself better search
we have to check if it's an empty cell
right if it's a wall we don't do that
basically you say well you you basically
can't go into the war right so there's
no point to calling right yeah you have
it mine in jail
what's that a drill a tree okay okay
there's a roof
I know there isn't
fine what if you have
a cannon why we need to restore it I
feel this speed a little bit complicated
to understand okay when we visit day
five we go to the left we go to the left
we have to mark it as this is visited
right so it doesn't go back right yeah
however
easy however if we finish the loot this
way right we have to unmark it a market
because there may be other rules that
will go go to this position
right make sense if we don't a market
what happened we probably can't go there
anymore but there's actually a path to
that
does it make sense uh
that's a good question okay that's a
good question let me draw something
spend a little bit longer and then put
one under so then you have to go
there that's right okay so look if this
is empty sale right and if this is a
task yeah so it might go this way right
right however we should definitely
search you might go this way first right
but you'll be about a market what
happened
immediately this is why you mark it as a
really really recently but if you talk
about Market what happened this moon is
blocked makes sense yeah that's why we
finish it we have to unmark it here okay
it's a common mistake that people do
this deficits you may make okay so like
that's a search is easy to understand
but there's many many people when we
implement it the time convection
obviously this is much complicated and
breakfast because the perfect search
when we find the exit we stop but never
search for this one
in order to guarantee the minimum
shortage pass we have to exalt all those
parts okay next lesson what are we going
to talk about
we perform a deficit we set the depth to
two to form a deficit that's the three
we perform the density
zero we don't find it we increment the
depth to one we still don't find it we
implement the depth to two we find it
look we do the deficit we find this why
we don't find this one
why do we don't care about this one
because this one when we set depth
equals three
we have the high limit can't stop here
so you don't find this one right so you
find this one instead okay yeah
okay so yeah let's iteration different
research okay that's it for today bye
bye bye bye yo