hello Mr Mr Ryan all right
that's a few lessons we talk about the
maze program right amazed
so basically we want to find out the
nearest exit to the engine in the Maze
okay and the entrance could be anywhere
actually it doesn't actually have to be
on the border but let's to simplify the
engine is the empty cell On the Border
and the axes are empty cells on the
border right the empty sets for example
these two okay
so obviously the entrance is not the
exit if we put the people here little
people here and we can't go back to
where the the same engine right it's not
counted as an exit we talk about the
first massage
and we'll talk about the deficit search
right so these two are the popular past
finding algorithm in the in a graph we
want to find out the shortest path in
this unweighted graph the anointed
because each step right so if we are
here so we have four directions to go
and each time we move one position it
costs one step this is animated okay
yeah it has to be animated because if
it's a weighted then
Massachusetts is not working right it
has to be animated so perfect search
level by level we use the DQ level by
level these are perfect search argument
guarantees that as soon as we find the
exit is the shortest right so for
example like in this graph it could be
two axis right it could be one actually
here one that says here but if we
perform the processors level by level
this axis is the shortest but not the
deficit
Dash we perform the default search
because as deep as we can and then the
first action we find is this one this
one is clearly not the ultimate the
ultimate is this one right okay but we
can apply the deficits to find the
shortest class if we explore all the
paths right if we just pull Force the
graph and then we know they have to
access and obviously we know this one is
the shortest it's the ultimate buffer
search Q DQ first in first sound will
push the note into the queue and then we
take it out from the left hand side
let's pop left
and I will push its next step back to
the queue this is in queue when we push
the kids back to the queue we have to
make sure this note is not visited
before so we use the headset or
alternatively we can mark the visitors
say walls right okay so look because
each cell we can only visit it once
so as long as we put it into the queue
we can mark it as a wall right so it's
not pick up again and for that massage
the same thing okay but for def research
we have to mark and unmark and we talk
about this problem right look if this is
exit this here is exit
so the deficit it could be somewhere
here right here right we found the path
but this is not Optima this is Optimum
right but if we're not unmarking this
picture
so this picture is taken so obviously
you can go through these parts again
yeah and that's why I was going to leave
the first search we have to unmark it a
market Mark and a market and we use the
recursion right we talk about that last
lesson right okay so Ryan you said this
lesson we're going to talk about what
kind of addresses
different search okay iterated
dependencies it's simple but to do this
iterative differences we have to find
out how do we do this test
let me search
okay let me search what steps limited
it's actually that first search
but with the limit right with the limit
PFS so FD research is actually that
first search plus limit which limit okay
look at this uh tree we're gonna find
the tree or it doesn't have to be
managed actually it's a coach tree right
what's called
q u a d means four right what is it for
each cell a mouse has four kids right
you can move to the neighboring for kids
so it could be four four feet is this
means for in English
so this is not the axis we stop
we increment the limit to one
okay so when we increment the limit to
one so basically we're seeing this
simplified code tree so we perform a
double search we don't fight it we
increment the limit okay so we perform a
deficit look and I found the exit right
and then this is the settings
good question well that means that this
is the exit secret what are sequence to
finding this exit the iterative
difference
has been on some black men and red and
red mixed with the black okay
let's do the prefer search professors
order
easy one
okay we found it this is the shortest
okay what's the type of search on it
right
okay we find this this is not the
optimum right so we need to continue
three seven tenants
okay and then we'll find this and this
is uh okay what's the iterating
difference we set the tabs to zero
what's the order now one right yeah this
is the limit basically I want to say
that to Yellow it means that we only see
these three we only see these three okay
this is one okay
[Laughter]
so what do we see yeah
we increment
okay what's the temperature one two four
two four five six three seven eight
sorry okay we found it yeah at the
beginning
so the maximum D given is maze this is
the columns C and this is r
can you imagine what's the longest
what's in Siri what's the longest uh
path for entering to the exit
[Music]
what's the longest you can imagine
the longest I'm not talking about
shortage longest so in what cases you
can get a long distance
you never go to the exit or place an
axis what's the axis
look yeah no you can't Loop that's
actually a very good point okay if we
can move but there is no longest right
you can just go round and round okay how
about you can Loop a myth a very long
way from top left to bottom left that's
right yeah the entrance is here right
the exit will be here you could be back
there right
um
okay this is long exactly so that's our
time to see right I can't see you Siri
right in series okay so why are T is
smaller than because we start with zero
it's smaller than three right like if we
perform this step we may search with the
currency and an entry yeah the entrance
and then obviously we need to have a
headset or marking the position visit
the position walls and I Market okay
let's use the headset first scene table
so we put a set headset a notebook right
if we find it let me turn T right
okay so one question can you tell me why
if we find that node and it guarantees
the circus so how to use true it's a
shortage if we I just visually look at
it yeah I know I mean the definitely
message while we do this iterative
differences you know because it's
because
you can go like level by level you're
basically yeah it basically like
foreign
that's the difference right we find
definitely research D the entering right
the current position okay position
and scene table if if the partition is
exit is Exit okay I'm writing this and
also position is not entering
then we find it right we finally exit
then we turn two okay and then if this
position already seen before return
false we don't go back otherwise the
first thing is to put it in a notebook
right and then we have to check look if
T is smaller than zero
and otherwise you know what to do right
for a drbc in four direction right in
four Direction indones in four Direction
one zero zero one one uh one zero zero
one
this is the direction of set okay fourth
Direction zero minus one minus one zero
and then n r and C equals the d r plus r
d c plus c okay RC is actually from
partition R C equals position okay
and then if we need to check n r is uh
is within the range
and
NC is also with the range and also
if the Maze and I and C it's not a word
right it's not what we don't go to the
wall right if it's a wall we don't go in
there there's no point we can't pass
through the wall if that's B Mister
that's the question this is basically a
recession which is the T minus one right
with the T minus one that's the search
this T is incrementing and I definitely
message we can do it uh opposite which
is incrementing we decrement the
positivity
because here is passing the positive D
we decrement The anti-e Falls below zero
or below or equals zero okay and then we
turn through y the position nine T the
scene table and then return four okay so
look here we add it so we have to unmark
it remove right remove our RC okay look
at this is pretty much like the deficit
the only difference
the only difference is one look uh this
this one
what's this
if T is smaller or equal than zero
written first what's what's this mean
why are we adding this Criterion one
question because it's
like yeah basically we perform a
definitely massage yeah if we set the
limit to here then we don't go to the
deeper one we leave it to the Future
right this is what it means yeah all the
rest similar to deficit okay so this
actually guarantees the shot is passed
right and then it's more efficient than
deficit obviously but it's not as
efficient as professors right but why do
we need this uh iterated differences
that first search right this is not a
good player here right this is not
Optimum
why do we need to use the iterative
differences and why do we need to use
preferences in some cases
Okay so
these two first okay but first search
because we have a queue right we have a
Q we have a Q
so this has this larger space use right
the iterative differences is basically
you know recursion so it has a oh look
when you set the harmony to T right it
has an OD space using right because look
the only store current pass which is
three now right yeah
if this is this you only install the
path the space uses you only store this
past right but from The Breakfast search
for search you need to store all the
nodes in the current level which could
be very big so the space uses in terms
of space uses this is efficient and
processor iterative research is also has
the same space uses in the deficitors
yeah that's such
okay so okay so what have you learned
today about may I do need to resin
iterated deepening step
okay so I mean more details please
whatever you go first okay so I'll do my
integrated 15 minutes
yeah and it's basically for the search
and you have a limit for your depth and
then you search for the exit and then if
there's another x that you increase your
limit
one step further and then and on and
then so on until you get you get finally
exit and which is the cutest exit and
also
I learned
um
it's written they didn't remember even
more like it's not it's more like use it
it has less use of space than both
search as as if Jesse perfect
really touch just chalk super nurse in
the queue and well iterating different
definitely search
just only
uses like the only like one light bar
yeah yeah we're done good job good job
okay
finding the nearest exit to the engine
in the Maze we have so far cover three
aggro that's
iterated differences okay so these three
are the parts find in a in a graph right
basically we can visualize it in the
graph find the tree you know try three
quarter tree a graph and directed graph
waiting I'm waiting graph it has to be
unweighted okay because if it's weighted
then we can apply the professor we have
to use the decade straw remember we
talked about the shortest part decostra
yeah yeah for your washer yeah the
Castro
b-i-k J D Construction
okay
a uniform causes yeah we cover that in
about 100 day 200 days of the Unison
yeah okay that's it for today bye
bye