what's a pivot
[Music]
uh pivot in what is it like the sports
thing like how you pivot like your
netball yeah kind of pivot it's what's
this word in English
it's funny right remember when we talk
about a quick shot all the result is a
Lumbers a quick sauce
pivot well first of all we choose the
pivot index let's make it five okay
let's choose the last element that's the
pivot integer so what do we do with the
pixel
okay just five okay for now so how do we
use the quick saw remember five what
numbers are smaller than five here one
two and three okay so three two one okay
this is on the left hand side here what
numbers are bigger than five nine on
seven nine and seven we can solve this
two recursively there what's the PV
number let's pick one okay I'll pick two
you know pick your number does not have
to be a particular index so you can
randomly pick any Index right or we pick
these two so we pick these two what's
the number smaller than two one what's
the number the pigments two three each
individual number is 35 and then five
okay so now we six seven what's the
number bigger than seven nine what's the
number smallerness and nothing wait and
now look it's solid right yeah this is
quick so remember we went and we choose
the integer
yeah that's a duplicate right it's the
same so the idea of the quick saw
remember we talk about it in early days
we pick a number and we find out the
numbers they're smaller than it and we
find out the numbers bigger than they
only recursive we saw the left and right
part okay this is the one that pivot is
wrong okay so not today keep it it's
different you can see that look one two
three four five six and here and and
it's the integer number okay
so let's say tier a okay n equals a so
we want to find this integer pivot
integer X so one plus two plus three
plus two D to the x equals X Plus X plus
one plus X plus two here n okay for
example eight so what number why the X
Plus X plus one this is the next number
so we want to find out for example you
said one plus two plus three plus equals
tier x what look
one two three four five six seven eight
okay so n equals what's the difference
that's a good point we want to find out
the X if laser X look n equals a right
so can you find a x between if x equals
at least so one plus two plus three plus
four equals ten right
four plus five plus six plus seven plus
a it's not equal ten right so we want to
move this x to the left or to the right
so let with X is n good point there's
only one cases One X equals n and it
satisfied this okay so basically n
equals one then look there's only one
number so the left part and the right
part equals one okay this one if we move
the X look this is a cursor right
okay we can move left or right let's
move it to the right
here here
One X is here so one plus two plus three
plus four plus five plus six equals one
how do you know if one plus two plus
three plus four is ten
you tell me how do we know one plus two
plus three plus four equals ten you know
how to solve it right yeah
yeah okay okay and then why doesn't
come here tonight then that's a good
point you'll tell me later okay do you
understand this question so far
yeah okay so when x equals six what's
the sum of this one
what's the sum
21 okay
what's the sum of this part
six of seven six of seven twenty one
twenty one okay so we found it x equals
six it's satisfied okay but if n equals
four one two three four can we find such
number X so it's satisfied the left part
and the right part look this x is
counted as boundary okay you don't have
to use
it doesn't matter because you can just
see one plus three plus three plus four
plus five and and is equal to ten plus
eight that's a good observation yes
that's a good observation yes you're
right okay because they all plus this
one number okay yeah that's a trick a
trick okay so coming back to this one
one plus two plus three plus four can we
find such number X that the left part
the sum of the left side equals the sum
all right no right no right okay so
basically this is the question today
any sauce I mean this is very simple
question beautiful how do we Brew false
we just checked we just check X right
yeah because look you're given this n
right you don't give at least n how many
possibilities we need to check and and
obviously because they are only n Choice
all right okay so I'm losing right now
the proof Force you tell me the time
complexity and how do we improve it okay
okay what's today's
oh you understand this question pretty
well all right one n equals one the
answer is one right one nine equals one
obviously that's one number so x equals
one so the left part is one the right
part is one okay so how do we profiles
four I in range
start from one to n plus one to n
inclusive okay the left part okay let's
call it a the sum of the left side will
use the sum function right sum the left
are range
start with one two I plus one the right
part some Rand
start from where I right I includes it
to n plus one right and then if a equal
equal B return
I otherwise to return minus one right
look
simple proofers am I right simple easy
so easy exactly okay so how can we
improve it I mean by the way these can
be written in one line using the next
function return next
I
for I in range one to your I plus one if
some of this speed equals some of this
speed right and the pi default is minus
one right if we can't find it okay why
aren't you writing the I part sorry
which one why aren't you writing the
icon yeah you're too squishy but look
next function remember we talked about
next one this is the iterator we're
going to find the first element in the
iterator I for I in range one till n
plus one and inclusive if a equals B if
sum of the first bit less power equal to
sum the right bit right if we can't find
it the minus one is the default value if
this iterator is empty okay okay so
what's the problem of this one what's
the time complexity is this is o n five
what's this space
o n square right look this is our n
this is o n why there's a loop inside
there are two Loops these two o n right
o n inside the loop is o n square right
oh it's good that's too slow
so you're saying you're saying one plus
two plus three plus four plus
and do we know how to solve this
like the sum and when n equals
okay when n equals a hundred what's the
sum uh is it fifty fifty fifty fifty
okay so we know that mathematics
equations to solve that right okay
before coming to this we can also use
the prefix sum we can calculate the
total sum here right total sum
sum of everything right some from one to
the end and plus one right and then we
can have a prefix on the left part A
equals zero a plus equal I okay so I'm
telling you okay this total sum
is
total the left sum is a what's the sum
of the right part this sum is a
two look this is I right this is I yeah
a
look because look we talk about eyes
inclusive in both leopard and right part
right so this left part is a so the
right bit the green bit is total minus a
plus I right yes yes okay so look this
is O and if we do this o n
and then we can do this a plus equals I
this is accumulate quick exam and then
we can use the simple math to calculate
the sum of B so instead of b equals
right we use this right
yeah and instead of this one we use a
plus equal sign every time we accumulate
this sum so what's the time table let's
say after this Improvement oh and
exactly this is l n and this is of one
okay we're done okay
next time here we can use the prefix sum
like this where all we can do is
accumulate right it's the same thing
yeah accumulative function we talked
about like a cumulate right uh it's the
same okay this is a great Improvement we
can do better binary research you
remember we pick lamida if I can
calculate the last bit and if the lepid
the sum of leopard is smaller than a
rapid so how do we move it if the sum of
a if the sum of a is smaller than sum of
B is the sum of the left part is smaller
than the sum of the right power so what
do we move to
you know we cut into half right and this
is the I this is the left boundary R
boundary then this is the meter and I'm
telling you okay now the sum of a this
bit
this bit a is smaller than the speed B
so where do we move move the Middle
where do we cut into the half to to
solve remember the binary search
I have a number in my mind from zero to
a hundred right
oh it's cutting the middle okay so now
look this is
[Music]
right obviously right to increase the
level and then and the opposite if it's
too big now we move to the left remember
the mathematic
mathematic we talked about that in the
early days using the mathematics
induction mathematic induction okay so
one plus two plus three plus two n
what's the sum of it
some of it right some I equals 1 to n i
this is some I look equals
the first item
the first item plus the last item
times how many items are there and items
divided by two okay yeah this is the
equation right and we know this equation
obviously we can change this we don't
need to accumulate some no we don't need
the prefix and we can replace this a
equals B and then P equals we can
directly calculate it am I right okay so
what's the sum of three four five six
seven eight nine okay what's the sum of
these you do improve us yeah four and
five and six I mean one easy way three
plus nine
yeah it has to be continued three plus
nine the first item plus the last item
times how many items are there two four
six seven
divided by two okay
nine equals
um twelve twelve and twelve divided by
two is six six times seven forty two
yeah
can we verify this three plus four seven
twelve eighteen twenty five thirty three
forty two okay yeah you know this
equation the first item plus the last
item times how many items are there
divided by two okay so how do we
interpret this this plus this
these plus n minus one and how many of
them divided by two look remember one
plus two plus three till a hundred how
do we know it's 50 50. one plus a
hundred is a hundred and one two plus
ninety nine
is a hundred and one How many pairs of
that fifty pairs of that so 50 times 101
is 50 50. that's why we got it okay make
sense
yeah okay okay so we know these tricks
to compute the sum of you know of
continuous the left part and right part
we can do this uh final research okay
final research
and tell me that you think about a time
complexity the last is ah the right is n
right
wire left probably small
yeah yeah yeah this one okay left is the
you know because one two here and right
right the left part of the way at the
beginning the right boundary the meter
is a plus r divided by two or six
through sixty one right these two
calculated first the left path what's
the sum
1 plus M right times how many n divided
by two all right the right part we know
the sum right
M plus n right there's a problem here
because difficulty
we got a problem look this is one this
is n okay this is the middle so when we
calculate this meter yeah this meter is
just a place to representative we
calculate sum so we're not calculating
this speed of sound we calculating the
whole bit okay so let's one
one plus n times n divided by two and N
plus n times how many numbers between n
to n how many numbers
[Music]
and
minus n plus one right you forgot the
plus one y look three to four how many
numbers two so how do we get a two four
minus three that's one we need to plus
one here
so we need to move it to the right right
move it to the right so
the left equals mid plus one okay so you
tell me what's next if a is bigger than
b so what do we do here move it
um
yeah how do we move it to the right
minus
one yeah and otherwise we can't find it
minus one okay the term for next what's
final result
yeah because every time you cut in half
yeah you cut in half
there are a hundred numbers and every
time you cut in half how many car
maximum how many times up to 25
oh look it's Locker two to the power 100
right so right this is the number of
times every time you cut in the half in
the search space it's never down Okay oh
okay
we can do better
so this is a great Improvement okay so
how can we do better
yeah we can look
is one plus x times x divided by 2y
this is a right this is a this is X here
all right yeah and what's the sum of
this bit
what's the summer is it equals the sum
of everything minus B right
all right yeah so the sum minus this
should be plus X okay so the sum sum of
everything is n times n plus 1 divided
by two minus the left field right minus
left it one plus x times x divided by 2
plus x what
this is one
this is n and we want to find if there's
an X here right so the left bit the sum
of a rapid this is the sum of 11. the
sum of everything is this one right the
sum of everything
minus that this bit this bit minus this
bit is this bit right
five to plus X here plus X here right
plus X here right
okay so let's solve this problem okay so
look this one one plus x times x divided
by two let's move to the left plus one
plus X
yeah
and then minus x equals n and plus one
divided by two right
look these two added together look half
of this plus half of this equals what
half of least plus half of this equals
what
this one yeah so one plus x times x
minus X
because this this bit is the total sum
right total sum okay so what's this do
you know how to kick it at least yeah
yeah
so X Plus x squared minus x equals X
l so x squared equals x so what's x x
equals square root of x and we just have
to check if this is a whole integer so s
equals n times n plus 1 divided by 2.
okay and then square root
so x equals square root
of s if x dot is integer if it's an
integer right
then return
integer part of X otherwise return minus
one
what's the time probability
you know this answer a one yes a one
what
if this function this is amortized
what's this word amortize
amortize 201 right because in modern
computers the processor the CPU computer
what's CPU I talked about this before
CPU this is the brain of Computer
Central Processing Unit the brand of
computer in Grain of computer knows how
to deal with this sqrt square root he
knows how to calculate the square root
of any number very efficiently so we
treat it as this function as amortized
or one right but mathematics
we just try to compute this so which one
is the fastest
yeah obviously this one yeah and there's
no loop I just calculate the square root
right how to get this we just prove it
right okay so to sum up the beginning we
talked about the book first I'm just
checking every possibility but let's
avoid the square and we made a slight
Improvement because we don't need to
calculate the sum of the left part and
right part using the for Loop we can use
the accumulate prefix sum right and then
we can follow improve it by using the
mathematic equation right
to calculate the sum of any consecutive
numbers right and further we improve it
using binary search let's bring down the
complexity to our login and then we try
to solve this equation and basically
we'll try to find out this using
mathematics equations and we'll find out
x equals square root of x
and then we just calculate it okay what
have you learned that's it
yes
what's the problem and what kind of
eggplant have we learned before what's
the problem first of all what's the
problem
numbers what's the what's the distance
come on say mom please
um we have numbers anyway what numbers
normal numbers what's a normal number
can you give me an example like what are
we trying to do three four five eight
seven yeah yeah what do you call these
numbers nature numbers right
yeah we have these natural numbers
natural natural numbers natural is
normal
naturally is a synonym for mention
numbers natural positive integer right
one two three four five here and find
out if laser pivot yeah if you like a
pivot integer that the sum of the left
part inclusive X is equals the sum of
the right path inclusive X right
and what kind of way have you learned
today
[Music]
mass and
one more let me see numbers
one you divide into two what do you call
it binary binary search every time we
cut it in half right and the last one is
we start with using the pure mathematics
all right yeah and the most efficient
solution is using mathematics all right
and the first three the first three
approach are computer algorithm the last
one is more like mathematic thinking
okay
yes okay that's it for today bye bye