so we are given a sentence a string
right uh separated by a white space so
we have a list of words right and we
want to find out if this is the circular
sentence no sentence
they don't have a full stop good
question okay how about we ignore that
okay
you can't say this this suit was this
okay okay dirty circular what's the
circular it's not cool what is the verb
a circle and so in this case and and
dirty is adjective you don't actually
need the adjective well you need a
subject and a verb subject and an object
okay this is not a English method okay
coming back to this okay what's uh
so look so the last letter of the first
word equals the
first letter of next word and then the
last letter of the last word
so let's just assume it's all lowercase
so for example another one a b b c c d e
f a this is the circular right because
look
this is the same this is the same uh
this is not okay this is the same all
right and then the last one right at
least it's not right hello
what this is not
okay and how about the finger word
sentence how about hello is it a is it a
circular sentence no no this is it it's
only one word yeah but h e l h this is a
circular but what's that word no I just
made it okay
what's a solution here
um we
um what's the solution what kind of
problem is this
because you may work here but we don't
need it right look we just go through
the water we just check all right
basically we just
yeah yeah we just checked right this is
simulation right it's least
next at the beginning of the next one I
will stop and we turn fast if we found
this match right do it split okay so the
first thing to this is a string to
together words we need to split right
Define if this is checked okay check
circulars okay check circular s array
first of all array equals s dot split
right
by the meter but if we don't give it a
delimiter it will split our y space okay
we can give a delimiter right here right
if
listen through okay let's make it true
right because the empty empty thing is
the circulation that's that's just that
assume that okay okay so now uh n equal
at least is the length of the walls
right because it was
four I for I in range
two and
right if
a r r i the one the current word last
letter right minus one right if it is
not equal the next block what's the next
one
return four
okay that's a slight problem here can
you tell me and otherwise if we're
passing all the Checkmate entry right
that's the problem because the a a b
C okay so for example last three words
index from I here to this one well I
plus one right this is the next one I
plus one there's nothing here so we want
to rewind it to to the beginning right
look when I is here
I plus one
what's I plus one yeah I the last law
was I plus one you should go back to the
first first of all right
otherwise array I plus one that would be
out of index the index ARR is only valid
from zero to n minus one right but but
you're telling me eight I plus one this
is out of index it should be pointing
back to the first row right so how do we
fix this sorry does it have to do that
yeah the last one we have to check the
password if it matches if
so how do we do this how do we wind it
remember we need to use if
we can do it but we can do better
um all right we can do you know this
remember we how do we calculate what's
this
modules yes and modulus and it becomes
zero right all right so we just have to
model us here modules and like and then
you make it back to the first one
another way is how do we fix it another
way
how about I push a here
okay and then we just keep looping the
index at the beginning I put that extra
I copy the extra the first element
back to the other way right am I
make sense okay so these three lines
like look what's this kind of pattern
okay we are checking the violation here
right if we find a mismatch we do 10
fast am I right yeah
does it make sense if we don't find any
violation we return true make sense we
can use the all keyword right return or
or
means everything here needs to be need
to be there two need to be true any
what's the difference between all and
any kinectomy
any of them but all
so anyway
it can be at least one and all it has to
be everything that's right yes so return
or
this thing and all this thing here four
comes here right right so we can say
return or ar I minus one this is the
last letter of the world but we have to
neglect oh this is the opposite it needs
to be
equal or everything needs to be equal
for I in range n right because look this
is checking the violation but obviously
we have to check the operative which is
that each wall connects to the next word
okay return any this is just checking if
any of them
satisfy everything okay the Time come
back stay if there are n-words
and each word has the length a what's
the type of next thing
times eight okay I have three Choice o n
o a no o and a okay
this is a simple question so what have
you learned today what's the most
important takeaway the sentence and we
use split to split the sentence string
into a list of words and now we just
have to go through n times and we are
suppose they are inwards and then check
for the violation if the coverage was
the last letter minus one is if it's not
equals to the beginning of the next row
I plus one then we return first
otherwise we'll retention and then the
place of paper is that the last word
last one is to chip be checked against
the first row and we can use the modulus
MRI erase yes yes yes okay let's see for
the day bye-bye
[Music]
foreign