right okay so today we'll talk about
this question how many matches are
played during the World Cup we know that
they are 32 teams right 32 teams how
many groups are there eight eight so a a
b c d e f g right four teams one two
three four five six seven eight they are
eight groups
so in the group how many matches I
played six yeah how do we get the six we
have four teams right so for each team
to play against
realities right so One play with two
you know for one place with two is the
same as two players one right
and one plays with three what I'm
playing with four two three two four
three four right plus six look level we
are picking two without considering the
order the sequence does not matter what
do we call this
contract
combination combination so we use this
symbols C for forever picking two right
so eight groups so times a right this is
the matches we need to play here in the
group stages so how many teams qualified
to the you know to the next round
half of them right so only the first two
in in Groom stage okay so half women
qualified so how many teams are there
16 right 16 teams so now into the next
stage which is knockout right how many
matches play in the next
so put it this way if we play one match
during this knockout how many teams are
eliminated one so in order to get the
champion how many teams need to be
unlimited yeah 15 so we need to plus 15
right but there's one more match which
is happening in the semi-finals right in
the same in the finals there are four
teams right and The Losers of each team
for example this one and this one needs
to play against each other to decide who
is going to be the third one right third
place or fourth place and I still
request one so how many are they so how
do we get this number foreign
[Music]
first of all we need to find out the
ways to pick two apples without sequence
right and once we have two apples we can
permutate do a four permutation which is
the n Factor right yeah so c n n CNN
C and zero equals one right picking
nothing One Way c n n apples kicking and
nipples how many ways one one way yeah
okay
CNN equals c n n minus n right
other interpolarities they are forever
I want to pick one apples how many were
picking one letters four episodes I want
to pick one of those how many ways
how many ways picking three letters four
yeah look if I pick one of us and there
are three efforts in pair right picking
least if we pick these
you play this and that gives another
option of picking Vehicles okay so this
is what it is CNN equals n factorial
divided by n factorial n minus n
factorial right and P and and
bacteria n minus n factorial
all right so P and M equals C and M
times M factorial right yeah so is it
is it true so this one comes n factorial
is this one okay one one one one two one
one three three one what's this one
oh yes so look at this number any number
this number this number equals the sum
of this this number equals the sum of
this right F all right so c n m equals c
n
minus one n plus c n minus 1 and minus
all right
yeah so look
this one this number equals the shoulder
the sum of the shoulder so how do we
integrate this we talk about this okay
and Airport
and apples
they are NFL we want to Pick n apples
right so for this one how many ways we
can pick it we pick or we skip right
if we pick
if we pick we have n minus one apples
but we have to pick a minus one if we
don't pick
we have n minus one but we still have n
apples to Big all right is it simple to
understand this this equation
right yeah we want to pick another let's
look at this apple first
and of course I want to Pick n apples
but for this one the first Apple how
many ways I I can make a choice I pick
it or I skip it right if I pick it
how many apples I need to pick n minus
one but from n minus one right here is
Amazon if we don't pick it how many
apples we still have to take
because I don't pick this one I haven't
make a choice right so it's an apple but
what's left n minus one ever okay this
is what it is okay so with this equation
we can implement this using this
recursion or iterative now with the
recursion we can just easily write the
something like that Define C and M and
then Define the boundary if and equal
equals zero will be ten one
if m equal equal n we turn one right or
if n equals zero or m equal and we can
one then return
see
n minus 1 M plus C and minus 1 and -1 we
can remember the intermediate values by
minimization putting up cash
AI you catch this reason we use cash
from function tools import AIU cache Max
size equals nine this is the
minimization top-down dynamic
programming the other way to implement
it is to use the iterative functions so
we can initialize the two dimensional
arrays and then we go through this row
by row it's basically to clearly with a
pascal triangle so from math we can
import com function which calculates
this value column
for two it will give us 6 and another
similar function which actually Returns
the combination itself is from ether to
a
import
combination okay combinations so how do
we use it so combinations
combinations
the first one is the iterator right so
we can pass it one two three four a
second is the number of items to choose
basically says that give us the solution
of picking two items from this iterator
so it will return a list of combinations
so it will be one two
one three
one four two two three two four three
four okay
we can compute this value right this
value using mathematics this one right
this is also okay and we can calculate
this value based on this function based
on this formula instead of this formula
okay so this is the combination okay so
you know in the next World Cup instead
of 32 teams there's going to be 60 40
18s 16 more so 48 teams
let how many girls how many goals 48 if
each group has four teams how many
groups 40 18 12 yeah 12 12. so okay so
applying this
right so we just have to change this to
12 12.
but after group stage how many teams are
left 24 right
so we need to play 23 more
to eliminate right and plus one right so
it's uh 48 plus 33 plus one right so
what's this 72 plus 23 Plus 1.
what's this 75 and 95 95 96 96 okay if
my math is correct if the next workout
has 48 teams and there are 12 groups
right and 12 times 6 equals 72. this is
the number of match that play in the
group stage and after that you know each
knockout match eliminates one so it
needs the 23 to animate
23 teams right and then we have one more
to decide who is going to be the third
place all right
I mean matches they are C two four about
how many matches are in the World Cup
okay so what's the answer 64. 64. okay
so how do we get a 64. so we see two
four times the number of
[Music]
um
and in The Knockout stages
one we play a match we eliminate one
right and there's one X or more which is
to decide who is going to be the third
person okay so it's around about how
like the World Cup actually works like
how it matches oh how to do that and how
much matches they are
if there's 32 teams
if there's 32 well kind of countries
playing then then there will be 64.
each one is split into groups and then
the groups and then we do the
combination two out of four
like I said there and then how much
groups there are and then we have half
of it minus one plus that and then Plus
One will go to combine a bit further
than before
yes
okay that's it for today bye bye bye