okay so we are given an array of digits
one single digit like
uh two one three okay let's just take
this one three digits each number in the
alert is one digit so
the question is that we want to find out
all the three digit number
three digit number okay
and it has to be even so three digit
even number
that's impossible
you hear me out okay okay um
unless you have zeros like two times
three three digit even number and no
leading zeros oh that is impossible and
also the numbers could be duplicate in
the original race you need to
concatenate concatenation of the digits
for example here I can do two one three
right this is a three digit but yeah but
it's not even I'm about I can do three
one two do you just have to order them
that's right yes but it could be money
right it could be another zero we need
to return all these three digits so four
numbers we want to keep
zeros
two two one three zero three digits
three one three zero yes
three one
two one two yes one two three one three
two one three two three one zero two
three zero uh-huh
what else ten zero two one zero
is that it anymore three two zero
I think that's it
and we need to return this in assorted
right we need to solve this number so
from a small list
okay so I'm not going to do uh what are
your approaches so I give you a few uh
integers how do we prove it one two zero
okay one two zero that's good one zero
zero three zero zero two zero zero one
zero so that's gonna be money so what's
your sauce so we want to find out the
three digit so here obviously that could
be more than three digit and each digit
could be duplicated it could be a
duplicate uh digit so what's your
approach here uh just have a lot of so I
just look for the even numbers
even number sorry
two one three there there's two zero
zero Advent even number
but how do you know is it even lower we
check we divided by two I just know it
three Force wow we check every numbers
we check every possible three digit
numbers check every
three digit number huh
what do you mean by check every three
digit number so what do you mean here
make all the three digit numbers you can
make from here right yeah yeah that's
one way what's the most easier way to do
that you will fight close to that check
every no no starting is the last step
check every three digit number okay I'm
going to read it several times until you
figure out every three digit number
every three digit number
every three digit number how many three
digit number how many students
how do we prove Max yeah it's messed but
okay so can you give me a few three
teaching numbers six four two okay
one zero two one zero two four six three
okay so how many three digit numbers 899
how do you get it because 999 and a
hundred
nine nine nine and 100. I'm Gonna Leave
it okay check every three digit number
and then just do one zero zero one zero
one and do it check every three digit
number let two ways huh one way is that
true false they are n digit here I pick
three digits out of it so this
permutation right commutation pn3
permutation with the sequence right
[Music]
good point yes let your mentioned you're
mentioning a very good point no just uh
this is unique right but it has to be
started there are two ways one way is oh
typing into the input to do this
permutation and digit and digit picking
three digit dollar permutation we know
how to permutate right
foreign
we mentioned that ether to a stop
permutation right communication that
will give us the actual communication
once we have a permutation land we just
haven't checked is
zero and if it's an even number if it's
even number we add it to the answer and
we sort it that's one way the other way
is there are limited number of three
digit numbers so we just go through this
from 100 to 999 step two and once we
have for example like a hundred we just
check this 100 if it can be made from
this input
makes sense so here we just have to
check how many even numbers 999 minus a
hundred all right divided by two roughly
this number right
899 yeah am I right 899 divided by two
okay okay so just add a ground which one
is more efficient which method is more
efficient the one over there this one is
okay why
any any thoughts yes this one is more
efficient why
um because
it's limited so yeah it's limited and
then when we're checking is the because
it's so big easy yeah two approach right
oh yeah the full permutation yeah okay
so I'm going to write it okay and then
you tell me the complexity
Define of death five
okay so this is the array of digits okay
so digit we want to count how many
digits per digit right how many
frequency the frequency per digit so we
use the counter right okay so C equals
counter or can you tell me what's this
counter mean counter digit is that
dictionary the Additionally the keys
will be teaching the value will be there
the value will be how many times they
appear right okay so now look for I in
range we start from 100 right this is
the smallest the mean three digit the
last digit will be
999 and we step two right actually we
step two right okay so 100 102 104 this
is what you mean let's start
okay now this eye what do we do so last
three digits like three two one how do
we get this number how do we get things
from how do we get this number I equals
three to one how do we get one how do we
get two how do we get three 321 is
okay so this one is
321 more than 10.
10 10 yes what 10 right modular ten that
would be equal one okay so how about
this one hundred
is it Mother Earth
321 divided by 100 that give us three
okay and how about this one two how do
you get it how about we can read number
one
how do we can do the one shift but if
this is not binary this is the base ten
and
focal point yeah we can shift it in base
ten
divided by 10 okay so we divided by 10
here
and how do we get these two
we subtract 30. it's a fair 10.
yeah
we are looking for a 10 a hundred this
is because the number system we're using
is base time right am I right it's based
on a decimal right this is what we call
a decimal
because it is base 10 binary phase two
okay and we also talk about phase 16
what's that
hexic hexic
okay what's this mean Phase 10 0 1 2 3 4
5 6 7 8 9 and what's next
based her base 16 a b c d e f okay
16. okay so for example let's ask what's
this number in base 16.
look f is 15 right 10 11 12 13 14 15 15
and 15. so what's this this is base 16
16. times 16. plus 15. so what's this
number
one times
10 to the power of 2 plus 2 times 10 to
the power 1 plus 3 times 10 to the power
zero so it's one hundred twenty three
okay so here 15 times 6 base 16 right by
16.
to the power one plus
you get that from here wow we're done
255 yes because why why this is equals
to 100 but in base 16 minus one right
base 16. all right because look if I
adding one here
you carry it over right F becomes yellow
f plus one becomes zero carry over 100
100 what's this in space 16 1 times 16
to the power of 2 256 minus 1 255. okay
this is all connected right okay so we
go through these numbers all right so
now let's read things so the if this
activity number is ABC okay look this is
teaching I put a horizontal line above
it it means that ABC
in this is a times 100 plus b times ten
plus C okay ABC I put a horizontal line
above it even slide so a equals I
divided by a hundred right b equals I
divided by ten
modulus 10 right C equals I mod equals
10. I only go to the three digit ABC
we want to find out if these three
digits can be made from the digit right
so we use the color we can do this if
counter
a b c e smaller or equal length BC right
look at this is a very important look if
this counter if the three digits the
frequency is smaller or equal than the
DC then we answer with answer answer
here okay answer always answer dot of
hand
okay
and then return answer
okay so can you tell me why we don't
need to sort the array here so the
numbers because we're going 100 to 19.
well done okay you're listening yes okay
the second question is why do we don't
check if it's an even number here it
says two two yeah step two so it's a
hundred a hundred two a hundred four it
skips the odd number right okay so
that's very good the times if we ignore
this one right if we ignore this one
if we don't consider this one what's the
tangent brexit
Owen I won oh one yeah oh and because
this is a constant Loop
and then
then Concepts this one
we treat it as constant right because
comparing this is the limited right and
this is uh given as uh we just don't
consider that but if we consider this
one this is not a one language because
the digit could be n right there could
be end this is when we need to go
through this n digit
another way I as I was saying before yes
this is going to be the checking this
background right and if we given this
number digit
so we actually need to permutate
all right tell me if you like n digits
per me like three digit out of n what
C and three cn3 picking two airports out
of an apple without orders this is with
order so this is equal C and three times
p33 okay
so how do we permutate we can deficit
profession but I leave it to the next
few lessons but another way is to use
the function tool from ether to us
ing power
commutation right permutation one two
there are two letters how many ways do
we permutated
one two three how many ways to
determines I did one two three two six
yeah yeah this is full permutation right
one two three one three two two one
three two three one three one two three
two one right and of course the first
one has 10 Choice second one has M minus
one choice the third one has a minus two
Choice the last one has one choice
what's this
n times n minus one times n minus so
three times two one
what's this
bacteria bacteria
okay
so we we use this function right
now then we can do this four a b c
commutative three digits right the
hundreds the tens the ones in
permutation
digit all right I want the
pick three digits out of the digits a b
c three digit and then I just have to
check look if a is not equal to zero
right we don't have a leading zero here
right and if C
and one is still so this means that if
it's an even number answer because it
could contain the duplicate so answer we
need to put it as a set so answer dot
add
what a times a hundred plus b times ten
plus C right and then return
salty we sorted the answer okay
what's the time complexity
um
[Music]
number of permutation space complexity
again why because each number could be a
even number right 246 then how many
possibilities two four six if the given
numbers are 246. how many
six yeah because look you can do any
communication and it says so now in the
worst case the phase complexity is this
the time complexity is this okay and
also don't forget we have to sort it the
time complexity is pn3 plus sorting if
like an animal we want to sort it how
what's the time the black stick
this is n Times log
p and three okay so this is the time
complexity okay yeah okay so what have
you learned today about
finding three digits
three digit uh
we are given a list of digits we want to
find out a three or the three digit even
numbers no leaving zeros the result has
to be in uh increasing order so okay
right and how many ways we can do it
odd numbers so it's and it's already
sorted as we're going up so if you go
100 100 102 up to 998 and then we find
out the ABC so we teach it and we check
if these three digits can be made from
the original digital then we use the
counter right we can directly compare
two counter to see if a counter is
included in another account right
smaller or equal and C if it's a smaller
in currency it means that the original
fitted
we can use the original digit to make
this uh I this I digit okay with the I
predicted ABC okay that's it for today
bye bye bye bye
[Music]