[Music]
so we are given a list of the integers
uh a list of single digits like one two
you know we could have a duplication
so our task is to find all okay
or three digit number
which is also even right and it does not
have relieving zeros okay I do not have
a living kilos for example
one two two three zero
so what we can have is one two two
zero right and one three one two one
zero three one two three yeah yeah so
all these three digit even numbers do
not have leading zeros and has to be
sorted in the uh distance in a returned
array okay yes and then we talk about
two masters one method is to
basically this is just to permutate
three digits out of this end we
permutate this pn3 picking three out of
n digits and then once we have this
commutation we need to check if the even
number it does not have a leading zero
and then we need to add it to the set
right
okay so why do we need the set do you
remember
so you don't want the duplicate right so
that's why we use the set okay so why
are you using set because we don't want
to install the duplicates uh we only
want that you need the numbers and then
before we return we need to sort it
right the time connects to your sorting
is over and again and that permutation
is pn3 this is the time complexity and
the space and complexity obviously if
all the numbers if all the numbers are
unique and even digits for example if we
have an array of 2 4 6A right
and then the full permutation every
possibility every commutation of three
digits is a good answer and we need to
add it to the results and that takes pm3
space
but this is not efficient right one
efficient way the more efficient way is
to get to iterate cancer
yeah
so we want to prove us because they are
limited number of three digits right so
we proof of we try each even number we
seen this ring we try basically we are
saying that we try every three digit
even number and to see if it can be made
from the given digits right and how do
we determine if it can be made out of
this given array of digits we just use
the counter we count the number of the
appearance for each digit and then we
compare two counters
if the counter of these digits the even
number three digit even number is
smaller than the given counter then we
say it's possible to make these three
digit even number using those digits
right and this is more efficient because
look this is a constant Loop we just
have to iterate how many times you know
how many even numbers of three digits
minus 100 divided by two
I need to plus one this is the number of
the three digit even numbers this is a
constant number so this is a constant
Loop
constant time complexity if this is not
considered okay if we are not
considering the
time complexity of turning the digit
into account least bit we're just
talking about this this bit as this
constant of we talk about this we don't
use this from ether tools import
permutation right and at least gives us
a nice uh easy to use tool to to do this
permutation
of three digit and this is the iterated
but basically we're saying that
we want to find a permutation of three
digits based on these digits given right
and then we check if it doesn't have a
leading zero if it's an even number last
digit is the even number then we add it
a this is 100 P this is the 10 see this
is once I learned
answer is a set this is to prevent the
duplicate numbers and then at the end we
need to sort it all right sorry this is
om log m n is pn3 so okay so the time
for next is pn3 this bit
plus right plus plus
p uh N3 Times log p and z Oh this is the
n log n right and as I said n equals p
and three I mentioned the paper search
prefer search we can solve this using
type of search and in the next lesson we
are solving this using professors okay
what's the difference between defenses
and Professor anybody
searching good level by level but
deficit you go deep as you can that's
right and how do we get there
uses stack and breakfast at Jesus key
good man okay so
what are we trying to do with the
deficit here right we are trying to
implement this communication right we
want three digits even number and this
is from the mathematics perspective we
want to find out the three digit
communication using the deficit
suppose we have this digit right how do
we do this switch patient anybody what
are those possible Communications
um one two one two two and one two three
one two three no no no yeah yeah one two
three yeah that's okay forget about it
even number I'm just saying the three
digit permutation how to do it one two
three okay it's enough one two zero here
right so that long right we want to find
out a three-digit permutation using the
number of digits given right so we can
do this step as such and how do we use
the default search let's do this deficit
first of all we need to counter I
counted the digits right we need to
obviously notice the frequency C equals
counter
counter digit
okay and then Define self massage let's
say the current number is X right and if
X is bigger than 99 or bigger or equal
than 100 it means that it's a three
digit number right if x and y equal
equal if it's an even number right
answer equals that we just put it in a
set answer dot add X
right and then we ten if we have already
three digits if it's an even number we
add it to the answer if not we'll do 10
okay and then for I in range
10 right we're going through each digit
0 1 2 3 4 5 up to nine and then we check
if
this c c i if we have enough digit of I
this is the counting how many digits of
the features we are given right if it's
bigger than zero let me do this step
massage
okay so I'm gonna put it here and then
if it's bigger than Seattle
but I have to c i minus equals one and
then c i
plus equal one right and then here this
is the sun return sorting
sorted answer one thing is missing here
this one
that's a search
we have this x this is the traveling
number right it could be one it could be
two at the beginning is zero okay we
don't have enough digits here so we go
to here and we try each
digits from 0 to 9.
look if c i is bigger than zero it means
that original number we have enough
digit from zero to nine right zero to
nine times zero
so zero this is turning it into counter
is zero one time one one time two two
times three one time right okay so zero
we have one time that's good
it's bigger than zero we're using this
ZL right so we take it we take it take
this material and we turn it into zero
right and then with that first search
current number X so x times ten
class I
so what does it mean means that look if
his current number is one two right and
I'm taking another three right one two
so I'm taking the digit three I equals
three so what's X
one two times ten plus three it becomes
one two three okay yeah and after we do
this recursion we have to
give it back give the teacher back I get
back right make sense do we talk about
the maze problem remember we mark it and
we need to unmark it
okay we follow the digit I here look at
we are checking the digit from zero zero
one two three two up to nine then we say
okay if we have enough digit C remember
C is the counter of original if we have
enough digit of I
then we follow it c i minus equal one we
follow it and we do the test as such
after we do the research we do we turn
it we give it back right so how do we do
the deficiency this is the location
current number is X Y for example is X
is 12. and we want to
follow the digit three right so what
happened to the number I have 12. and I
want to put a three on the right what
happened to this x so now X is 12 right
I've tried two digits now I need one
more digit the three I have enough three
so I can put a three on the right hand
side of the one two so what happened to
this x it becomes old
yeah I know but you know when the X
passing here if you go to real because
it's bigger than 99 it's 36 right so
here so what happened if x equals 12
and then I borrow a number three digit
three put it put it on on the right so
what happened to this X
it's very obvious one two and what
happened
um if it gets free it becomes 120 yeah
so it means that look at 12 times 10
here right times that means 12 times 10
it means that I I put I want to put one
digit on the right and then plus three
okay
search
make sense yep
so we need to give you back right if we
don't give it back then the digital will
be running out and then there's some
solution will be missing okay yeah which
line of code says is commutation of
three digits
from where you can see it's a three
digit permutation
[Music]
99 means the the only is three digits
and it's three digit here there will be
a return
so that maximum digit is three digit
it's not possible to get four digits
using this right because after three
digits we do ten we don't do the
recursion anymore right this is the
terminal case right and at the beginning
we call that first search you know at
the beginning we have nothing and then
you will try each digit okay
and which part of code says that it's an
even number
um
if x is
which part of code says uh is less
notification
is accepted yeah okay
okay unique digit for example a equals
set
by a DOT add one okay so a DOT at
two a DOT add
three okay one
a is one right contains one a DOT add
two so one two so a DOT S three one two
three okay so how about eight dot add
three what happens a is a set of one two
three right one two three I want to add
one more three into the set what
happened
set Only Stores unique numbers and if I
have one two three already in a set and
I want to add one more three to the set
nothing will happen you can add as many
numbers in it but you only stores one
two three and that's it right okay this
is the one that set is okay
and which part of curve guarantees the
answer is sorted
um yeah that's an easy one right okay so
what have you learned today about the
same as yesterday fighting finding three
digit even numbers what what's the new
today we use that for such yes what's
the time complexity uh
yeah this is the permutation this means
picking three digits out of entity
what's the difference between pm3 and
cn3 okay one last question anybody pm3
is like it's like picking three apples
out and apples and what's the difference
between p and C and C and C okay let's
say p three two and C32 what's the
difference right so yeah plus one two
three okay one two three
is one of them kind of like
[Music]
give us
so yeah for picking two what are those
what are those
see the way you see is um
whatever is a bacteria and C is she is
like how much possibilities he can pick
from the bottom one and and the third
one is how much okay
you can pick and and you just need to um
see how much possibilities
I'm trying to understand what it says
[Music]
it got me confused
is
like
instead of like the picking it is
putting the numbers like
but I didn't remember like one two one
three
Okay so
yeah
and obviously obviously one is how much
how much is the popularity and and two
is it how much you have
I have to pick basically they're pretty
similar instead of seeds doesn't really
care about the numbers and and you can
use anything like apples or apples or
bananas and yum no PNG numbers
it says like one three one two one
million
okay see see combination for picking two
apples how many ways how many ways yeah
how many ways
c one two is the same as two one right
but P one two is different than two one
okay that's what's the difference C is
this speed p is both ended up together
okay
there was a p32 is one two two one one
three three one two three three two c is
one two one three two three right
combination without considering the
order all the order doesn't matter P
commutation full permutation yeah one
two three one three two this is
permutation right two one three two
three one three one two three two one
look full formulation and exact earlier
yeah we talk about that okay yep
everyone you talk about it too that I
would say listen to you for like five
minutes before I figure out your kind of
like jumping right good job okay see you
later bye bye bye
foreign