numbers
[Music]
what's my list
so we're given an array of digits single
digit and they could be a duplicate
right it could be duplicate yes
yes and we want to find all three digits
and no leadings uniforms no leading
zeros okay
so we can't have like zero one two this
is not a good number right but we could
have one to zero to one zero and since
there are two two so we only keep one
copy of that which is two one zero Okay
so
we talk about it both of us yeah
how do you pull fast we talk about
permutation try to
try to check everything
and I and then start from my
skip every odd number and check if it
can be even numbers and if it can be
made from the array excellent yes so
there are two ways of proof of one way
is because it's a three digit right so
we approvals try every even number from
100 to 998 yeah skip two so for I in
range 100 here 999 step two and once we
have this number for example one zero
two we come back to check if one zero
two can be made from a given digit at
least it's more efficient because there
are limited number of the three digit
numbers and we can just do this in
constant term
the other way our profile so it's using
the permutation because we have permuted
actually permutating three digits out of
these and digit okay we can prove us
these the whole number or we can prove
was each single digit right so let's say
ABC left this is the three digit number
so we can do this for a in range no
readings you know right because there's
no living zero so it's always one up to
ten right no readings you know
in French
the second digit it could be any from 0
to 9 right
for C in range the third number okay so
what's the third number the third number
has to be even digit
right because it has to be even number
so the third number would be from 0 to
10 step two right so zero two four six
eight this is what it means and then
once we have this IDC we check if
counter ABC is smaller than the this
counter
then we don't need to check a leading
dealer right because a cannot be it's
yellow well you don't need to check for
even numbers right because C
with step two right and then after that
then we can push this to the answer
which is eight times a hundred
eight times a hundred plus b times ten
plus
C okay do we need to solve this using
this uh kind of for Loop do we need to
solve these numbers not really because a
is one to ten yeah look at when the
numbers generated so a from the smallest
to the thickest B for the smallest to
the ticket C from the smallest to the
biggest right so this number generated
is also from the smallest to the
previous this is the same thing like
this for Loop for 100 to 998 step two
IPM free
picking three out of and with the
sequence cn3 is
taking three out of n with a the order
does not matter so pn3 is actually C and
three times the p33 okay this is the
full communication we're using the
default last lesson left as such and we
can use the pressure search but because
we are only picking three
all right well because we're only
picking three so we can also do this not
looping over the numbers we're looking
over the index if not n so we can say
for the first index is range and right
the second index for J in range n
Force the third index is also from when
uh we have to check if I equal equal J
then we continue we don't want a
duplicate Index right because each index
can only be picked once if I equal K or
J equal k then we continue we ignore it
right so and once we have the i j k we
can test if this number is an even
number without a leaving zero and then
if it is they will push it back to the
result but after this we need to solve
it right because we are just picking the
index
okay so definitely such I will use the
recursion and then once we pick it we
pick this number we follow it and we
need to keep it back right
now how do we implement the perfect
search
anybody perfect okay
first search because yeah
if and it's bigger than equal to 99. we
need to check if n is
uh even number and if it's a even number
we push this answer a pen
uh append answer copious is a set okay
success answer for ADD
and another 10.
I know we need to go to each digit for I
in range
10 right and then if this frequency IF
frequency I is bigger than yellow
lands we follow it right we have enough
digit of I
we follow it
I minus equals one and then f as such so
current number is n so n times 10 plus I
okay after recursion we need to give it
back frequency
I plus equal one
and therefore such at the beginning we
start with zero and then return
sorted
salted answer right okay so this is the
ever such at the beginning the frequency
it needs to
be computed using this counter widget
this is deficit that stories
you said you use a q first in first
element okay first inverter so we push
the kids every time we take you we take
one from the left hand side pushes the
kid back to the cube okay so the clever
such level by level that was such as
steep as we can
which method current is that the first
solution we get is the optimum if we are
looking for the shortest purposes okay
but in this case it doesn't matter
because we are finding all the three
digits right we actually finding all the
three Institute even numbers so it
doesn't matter differences you
preferences we have to perform the
entire search using the default search
different order okay at the beginning
why we're using the set anybody
because we need to store London
we don't want that duplicates yeah okay
set the unique things the numbers that's
right unique numbers so it doesn't store
duplicate like for example if it's
answer is at least it's a list of this
is this right answer the door open one
answer to open one another one right you
store three elements but answer if it's
a set answer dot append one
nothing changed because one is already
in the set nothing changed okay this is
the major difference
we can do this uh push and pop on both
sides PQ
we need to store the current number and
the digits right we need to install the
current number in the digit so the color
number is zero the digit is counter
count uh AR okay so this is a couple and
then wire Q
so n f equal Q dot Pub left
taking from the left hand side kill the
problem and this is the current number f
is the remaining digit okay so here if n
is bigger or equal if bigger than 99
okay actually there okay so it's bigger
than 99 not equal okay three digit
figure 99 or bigger or equal to 100.
well if n is
odd number then answer add answer dot
add and
we tell here otherwise we need to go
through each digit for I in range
fan
so now we need to make a copy of the
counter right counter is the object so
counter let's say C equals copy dot d
copy
copy this is a package deep copy what's
the difference between deep copy and
Cheryl coffee
deep copies
what kind of deep is it I I think you
call it something like aliens
did copy what's the tip is clone okay a
equals one two three okay if I said P
equals a this is not deep copy because
if I said P zero I want to change it to
four so what happened here B will be
equal the first element to four right
four two three a is also changes to four
to three because b equals a b is just an
alias pointing to the same yeah yeah
that's called Shadow copy this is
channel copy but it's p equals copy dot
d copy a then b and a is a separate it's
like everything I want to make a column
of Eric and another separate average is
here
yeah I touched this area it doesn't mean
I touch Diana Eric right this is a
separate coffee
the D copy we can also do this syntax P
equals a
and then put the
what's this yeah
[Music]
instead of
them so this is two tops yeah this is
least comprehension it's also means a
deep copy okay and we copy this and then
if you see I is bigger than zero right
if we still have enough digit of I then
we can make a copy and then push it back
to the cube Q dot append so what's the
next next is current digit is n minus n
times 10 plus I and then did copy which
is a c here
okay and then we turn we need to solve
it right again we need to solve the
answer
here we don't need to give it back okay
so if CI bigger then we copy it and then
we see I minus equals one right we need
to decrement because we're using one
more digit of I but we don't need to
give it back because we're making a deep
copy okay it's different than
deaf as such because this frequency is
the is kind of global
is is modifying this uh counter so once
we decrement we follow the digit I we
need to give it back does it make sense
okay here we don't because we make a big
copy we push it to the queue the note in
the queue
has a number and a counter so it's a
different counter right different
counter so it doesn't matter you don't
need to change it change it back okay so
by looking at this both uh approach the
definite search Professor you know the
same time complexity in this case
because we need to find all the three
digit even numbers we are actually prove
something using different uh travels and
order but that's as such space usage is
because professors we need to store all
the nodes in that field right for that
massage
we don't make sense
last time we talked about iterative
difference
in the space usage okay
about finding free
even three digit numbers from an array
I'm using deficit
this is deficit we are not talking about
differences what's it is
okay so this is not new today this is
what we talked about last time okay just
different ways of solving this problem
okay
um
the three digit uh
so we don't have to borrow it because in
something like yeah probably what
channel it doesn't do both kind of like
it's like a mirror and so like what do
you do to one it does two hours it's
kind of like a mirror
so so you do something to be you have to
do it to a that you don't want to do a
so so you put a back so again and so
that's why you think
okay one last question what do we store
in the notes of the prefer search like
in the queue it's a tablet so what's
what's zero what's counter what's this
what's the first number what's this
what's f
kill the problem look we're taking the
note from the Q so what do we store in a
note
the common number
n is the value is current number we
improved something that three digits
right this is calculum f is the
remaining digit we can put on the right
hand side of the current number now you
get it right so that's why we check if c
i bigger than zero we have sphere have
remaining digit of I then we can put it
on the right hand side n times 10 plus I
but for example if n equals 12
times 10 is 120 plus 3 is 1 2 3.
and then remaining
remaining digit is C we made a deep copy
of the current remaining digits and we
decrease by one okay okay that's it bye
[Music]