[Music]
yes today we talk about
metric transport uh magic transpose
i didn't know that because i wasn't
there pantry
magics what is magic i don't know
because
oh that is what you sleep on
you can think of it as a two dimensional
array
so look this is a metric
okay so numbers like one two three
that's basically four
five six seven eight nine so there are
nine numbers
okay so in in python you can do it this
way you can have this
yeah this is a list but it's a
two-dimensional list yeah four
dimensional list it's three times three
metric because it's three rows three
columns
oh i know i know yeah
this is a whole bed there's six
okay okay think of learn as well okay
look and how about this one look
one two three and
four five six and then you can do a
uh impression you can do this yeah this
is a style with a list yeah
it's at least two lists a whole is
conceived
consists of two lists one is it consists
of three elements so
this is also a magic it is two times
three
match because it's two rows three
columns okay
so this is three columns zeros okay so
now we are transposing uh
transpose transpose what's this meaning
transpose
can you guess okay sorry
i write it and then you tell me what it
is okay okay
okay so it's this uh okay so it's the
same okay
but i will have this one five nine okay
and then two four three seven
six eight oh yeah okay so can you tell
me what's transpose
one two three four five six seven eight
nine
i guess then you basically go down
what do you mean go down so how do okay
so you
for this one it's it's less but how
about this
you go this way that way like
a b c d e
f and then
[Music]
a b c
y okay so i tell you why so it becomes a
b
no no no no it becomes a b
[Music]
uh
tennis eye left yeah like turn it the
other way
yeah turn it like that you should be in
here but it's still on the left
yeah like that
okay you have something close we have
something good i need a drink of water
okay
oh i know you turn it like that then
pretend it's not 2d and you just flip it
over
okay one zero so
so this is one zero uh so it will become
zero one can you open this yeah
okay look at it yes
this is original coordinate is one
two right out one two right
so it should be the same as in the
new new metric it should be 2 1 so 0 1
2 1 2 2 1 so it should be c sorry
1 0 1 2 2 1 is
so for this one if the side if the rows
and the columns are the same yeah if the
rows
of columns if the size of the rows
and the column if it's a square okay if
it's a square metric
this is diagonal yeah you never change
yeah
oh yeah you never change and you just
swap it
so look two becomes small four becomes
two yeah yeah i'm saying that
if this is a square metric you just swap
it look
two and four swap three and seven swap
six and i swap
okay swap along these do you get it
okay yeah yeah yeah
for this one for any any of others
if it's not a square you can think of
this one so first of all if
these are two rows and three columns
and the target metric will be three
dollars and two columns
right right the size will be swapped
yeah
yeah it will be first of all you return
this way yeah yeah
and turn this way but if this if this
original here is it is one two
if it's a one two location and then it
should be in the new metric
it should be in the two one location got
it
yeah yeah okay okay okay so
how do we write this code
transport of magic how do we write it
define transpose
that looks like let's do it like a a is
the magic okay
and then we return b okay
okay let's call it r and c will be
original
size which is the what
lens a study computer
that's okay then a0 okay so that's the
original yeah
i like we need to create a new metric
which let's call it b
okay okay t
equals t yeah attack it or transfer so
let's do it
original let's go along
long time how many how many how many
elements of the
rows how many elements of the columns
should be c columns yes yes
no r columns are columns yeah
i is the rows it should be the columns
now and then
for for i
in range
[Music]
this means that i create a new matrix
with the field with the noun
but it's the accolades and c rows okay
so you don't need the
i you just put the underscore and then
for i for r small r in
range row column
for c in range
c right and then t
look this is transfer c r
equals what a what can you tell me
what's this what's your
favorite ci equals anyone
bc what's b next
c r c rc so you see this is
of course we are doing this you can
guess okay so look
this is a bit tricky this is to create
the original size is a
column and time thing now this could be
is create a
metric with c co c zeros and our columns
and then we go through each row each
each column in the original array
of magic which is rc but in the new
metric it should be cr what's the
time compensating
no you're just kissing
using the r and c because when you say
log n when you say
n n means something i see
so what's c meaning here there's no c
minor here yeah
there is only r and c so what's the
complexity
because we need to go through r times
rho and c times r do you get it
you're not guessing you're not saying n
and what what
you can say o o n
square right if n is a size of a square
metric if
this is n yes very much
when you say oh something that's
something you need to mean it
you need to tell me what it is that i'm
right do i make that
okay so what's the space complexity
because you need to allocate the new
basically you this is the metric you
you transpose it you rotate it you still
it still takes that much amount of space
am i right yeah we're done let's do the
coating
can you turn on light please
wait i need to take this off okay
and then i need a little bit blurry
no now the picture's super blurry
well i forgot my password you can go
your father
oh yeah yeah it's one two five six eight
nine
you think one one three four zero three
right
is that all right is that alright
oh my god i need to see i need to check
okay that's it no don't don't touch it
i think this is all right very clear
yeah
i'm right myself
that's okay
[Music]
okay good so let's do the transpose okay
transpose ui
i wasn't here yesterday yeah that's okay
i i i so let's do this original metric
okay
so we can do this so it equals
one two three okay and then
column four five six
let's do a square metric and not square
metric right
and b equals
one two three
four five six okay and then that's it
one two three let's let's put in the uh
let's print this queen queen print the
magic okay
print the battery a so we just do this
for
r in
but we can just do this a and then print
up okay print the r
so if i think yeah yeah let's do this
let's try metric a and put printer
matrix
b let's see if it works okay
transpose okay one two three okay
i probably need to uh
they're all in random just add them
together no i what i mean
is this i need to print the uh uh
magic a okay
[Music]
syntax highlighting magic b
how does it why does it make it red it
means
it's a string with the others yes
okay so let's clear yeah yeah
now we need to transpose it right
transpose it transpose
i don't know it means rotate maybe maybe
transpose a okay remember we talked
about rc
equals length a that's the number of
rows
and then a0 let's number currents right
t equals now
times times r times c
times t
for in range
c right yes
for i for r in range
r for c in range
c then what
t r
[Music]
i already gave you the answer okay
now now let's do this okay
and then a then let's do this a equals
transpose a okay and print
transpose
okay then we can say print metric
metric a again and then the same thing
for this
so print a print
after transpose
and then b equals transpose
b yeah and print
magic
[Music]
okay let's open the
for the best okay uh-oh uh-oh
index out of range that's interesting
so the first one is okay but for the
second one there's a problem okay
for the second one so not r let's should
be
c uh wait
r c i is the length look that's catapult
but this
is let's let's okay let's okay let's
okay that's okay
ah no
there's a mistake this cl
c ah equals rc right because rc is the
original coordinate ci is the new
right yeah
okay so does it make sense look one two
three four five six
eight nine seven transpose it will be
swap
will be swapped along the diagonal right
match b one two three four five six then
it will be one two three
four five six all right
yeah does it make sense wait actually
in python you can do this okay you can
do this
person right now i have list
a equals 1 2 3 yeah
4 5 6 right
if i put in the a you release yeah if i
transpose i can do this look magic okay
i transfer it into b
i can do this list make it a list and
then
zip a this is a magic
i i tell you in the last lesson and
let's print the b okay
you see is it transpose yeah
one two three four five six yeah it
becomes three rows and two columns
yeah yeah okay
this is the python because we already
know how to
how to do it in python and it's quite
useful so that's why computer already
provides this
so we don't have to reinvent the wheel
you know we invent the wheel
you know the phase we invented we are if
it means something that has been
invented we don't need to
invent it again i'm right yeah
i'm right hello
yeah that's the last okay good job today
good job good job very well done today
both everybody