right
so we given a list of words like Eric
rice
my Ryan
and and a
h
why okay just some random words right
okay
n-n-a-r-y is not a word and my name
needs a capital letter I'll buy the
small word
so all these words are in lowercase if
there are two words contains the same
characters okay some characters and we
call it similar Y and and these are
similar even though this has not end
right the lens is different because they
they are made
something I made up okay
and everything lies obviously what do
you call it
it is
I remember last time you tall chocolate
and it was and you gave the example like
listening and listen and silence yes
what do you call it I forgot something
within his a antonym anagram anagram yes
anagram yes good job
okay so anyway how do we compare to
string S1 S2 is Alucard that's a few
ways right we can say we can encounter
counter S1 e if it's equal to counter s
to Y because counter counts the
character and the frequency if there are
two counters the same then it's a it's
an angle another way is we'll sort it
right we can say we can sort it
so to S1 is equals to sorted as 2X
yeah for example Eric that's when we
started you become c e i r and this life
we solve it you become c e i r okay I
said sorry it's elegant when we started
this if the string is that is n then the
term lesson oh and okay but if we use
the counter that stays complexity and
time complexity is over okay so this is
in terms of the term complexity this
method is faster than less sorting
because o and
is better than o and again right
and the space complexity this one is
aligned because we're using the counter
but this one um told me to use the
additional space that's our one right so
in terms of space usage the o n is
worse than a one right when we compare
if the two strings are similar we don't
actually compare the frequency r one
times n one times a one times y
one time and this one
and two times a when times r one times y
one times right because we only compare
these it uses the characters n r a y and
r a y then we say these two words are
similar even this is two times the N the
only one time here make sense Okay so
given this a list of words we want to
find out the number of
pairs of the similar strings
e r i c r i c this is one path
r y a n and n a r y this is another one
so there are two pairs if we have
another one like e c i r okay and then
how many more pairs do we have
if we have one more string e c i r we
could have e i c
easy ir and I see
e-c-i-r okay
okay so the first question how do we
compare if two strings are similar
so there's different ways like you can
sort alphabetically
so and and if it's something like an
anagram it it should be
I it should be identical to each other
so so you know so um that's that's a
pair and and also one way is kind of
like
um is it value
is it something like was it called
okay so you mentioned about the Sorting
right so look at these two because it's
different than the underground yeah yeah
uh is something like a memory serious
like you list it like
I think it's a neat enumerate okay
enumerate yes
and so if they contain the same letters
then they should be the same even if
they if even if they have different okay
different frequencies okay so look this
is S1 this is S2 actually we can do this
we can use a set filter all the
duplicate characters right and then we
can sort it right sort it the set land
if it's equal then it's similar right
because when we use the set we remove
the duplicate numbers and we only
compare the unique characters and once
we do this set we can actually use the
method that we use to check if the two
strings are endocrine so there's
actually one more step just to filter
the duplicate numbers all right
duplicate characters make sense yeah
Okay so
approvals yeah obviously we can prove
also am I right so we're gonna prove us
look answer equals yellow for if n
equals the length of uh right for I in
range
and
for J in range
I right so we are checking now we need
to check this area
so if
if these Aria and arj are similar so we
can say if set a r r i
actually we can just directly compare
with the set yeah set a uh J right then
answer plus equal one
fixes
that's it return answer this is the
address
here is the average length is M okay so
the time connects to be o n times O N
squared times M look why is that here is
n here is Ed
and here we're converting we're
converting each one the length will be n
right
to a set that takes a long time a length
of square comes in okay
makes sense easier
look at the index this is index J is up
to index I
okay because that's every rice is a pair
but we don't count the duplicate which
is why it's every we only count once
right okay okay so that's why the J
index looping up to I so when I is zero
this Loop is skipped when I is one when
I is one okay the zlo J we don't have
any J when I is one the J up to zero
right one I is two
zero one two one I is four
J is zero one two three okay so the
index of J is always from zero up to the
index of I
Okay so
this is uh okay you know because this is
very straightforward but we can do
better if I want you to come up with a
way to identify unique identify like ID
a word based the similarity if we played
out a way to compute the ID the score or
you know identity of a word if two words
have the same ID then they are similar
the amount of letters were the same
let
it is like Eric has four letters yeah
yeah but this is also for letters but
obviously the ID of these should be
different right yeah and so I think it
should be like the same like letters
some letters as just some letters okay
so we can just do this right so if this
is Ash right so we can just do this set
yes right and then sort it
we sought it and then we just join right
join it
so this is the function to compute the
ID of each one if two words
have the same ID that are similar right
let's join
are you doing it
okay but whatever you put in the thingy
I see look at this one okay let's do
this using this one set the first
operation is set so you become and a uh
y right this is the unique right remove
the One X or n okay sort it
when we started you become a and uh y
okay only join
right and it will become a and now okay
so this is the ID of that
okay so we try another one side like
every variant okay
so what do we have
is that duplicate numbers yeah I look
one way so okay so what first of all we
can't do vowels yeah we use the set so
but what do we have e r i c
y a n okay and then we started
a c
e i
and ah why all right
enjoy just put it so this is the idea of
everyone okay so we can have found that
like a equals counter
and we go through this word okay so if
this is the thing yeah
if we have this function identify this
ID function this is the S we turn this
right return this x equals ID w
IDW answer okay answer pivot zero answer
plus equal a x Ln a X Plus equal one
okay this is very uh interesting here
return a look at return answer
these four we have uh two pairs right
okay look at this example we have two
pairs
we calculate its ID right yeah I see and
yeah I see the ID would be C
e i r okay c e i r answer plus a c i r
see there is no entry C IR in that so
answer plus equals zero answer still
zero a c i r plus u one so c e i r we
have one entry here one okay okay I see
what I see is the ID
let's say right x equals c i r answer
plus a c i r e equals one right so one
pair because originally we meet Eric
before so answer would be one now now
cir
increment one so I need to change this
to two Okay how I and what's the id a n
r y right answer plus a a and now y
there's nothing here so zero but this
Loop we need to change it to one so A
and R Y plus y okay this one looks the
same yeah plus equals one and then two
days two please two okay so we have two
pairs got it yeah yeah look why this is
okay I'll show you one example Okay so
this a the counter stores the IV
previous number of times of these the
same similar string right
okay if this is e I see here and this is
also yeah I see here if release is here
okay so now a e r i c that's three times
right now okay
if I had one more year I see how many
pairs I already tell you there are three
errors and I have one more array so how
many new pairs can you make the similar
strings I think in title you have two
typical pears is two and four divided by
two is two four divided by two y because
you said pairs pairs means two and so
okay okay look this is one pair okay
this is one pair yeah yes yeah those are
two
I see no no I'm saying one pair
yeah one pair is like
a pair of shoes oh okay okay so it's not
so yummy fruit
yes a pair of pears
okay come on do you understand this
question at least
and I have one more area coming how many
new pairs of the similar string can we
get I have one more Eric so this area
can pair with this one compared with
this one compared with this one How many
pairs three so eighty three yeah
okay and then Eric there are four Eric
now I have another area coming how many
new players can we have okay for plus
this number right look this is what it
is look answer plus already and we
incremented
makes sense but it makes sense now
yeah this is ideal okay so which one is
simpler The Messer which one is simpler
this one you understand this and the
previous one is the profile
they are n words how many pairs you know
without considering the similarity they
are n apples How many pairs can you make
without consistently sequence picking
two out of n look picking two out of n
what's this cn2 this is equals n times n
minus 1 divided by two
four How many pairs four times three
divided by two let's
um six four is one two three four right
so you pick two one two one three one
four two three two four three four five
this is the sixth C and two picking two
out of ten okay so proof of the console
is the answer okay the last uh method I
want to mention is based on this this is
ID right not ID function uh ID we use
this function to calculate and if it's
only lowercase if it's lowercase we can
change this IV to a better one because
the ID is uh
he's a lowercase character and we could
talk about the ASCII right aaci let's
ask it for the a
o r b a what do we have anybody remember
the magic number
the lowercase a and the bigger case a
do you still remember asking asei
American
um I don't know exchange information
so lowercase 65. uppercase is 97. right
that's that's the location yeah yeah
okay and then you said uh is
[Music]
48 okay
and the space
okay okay you're not lucky there's an
Enter key right Enter key
I'm lucky this is 13 and then it's a
space key
space this is 32 okay
the mapping from the keys yeah a lot is
to calculate this number from the
character and the opposite would be c h
r so if we say chr97 you give us a
little bit eight but I think it's all
lower case then we can use the feed mask
asking master so we can think of a big
integer and
if this is hey hey this is zero okay P
then is one C is two t is three e is
four right so if it's an integer right
if it's an integer
finally remember integer this is a this
is B this is C this is C this is e okay
so if we have e then we set this to one
okay if we have this R we set this to
one
if we have I we set the I to one okay
simple as that c set to one okay and
then we are transforming the words into
a number
that's what we are doing okay so now we
can do this uh one shift shifter
ORD W minus 97 5 and then four W in what
but we have to reduce this function okay
W in words word actually in word okay
so this is I'm talking about this work
okay well
I know we can use this reduce function
reduce
uh oh ah like that okay so the reduce
function basically you're saying that I
want to apply at least the first
function which is all
in the second iterator okay we don't
need to go into details here but
basically this is a complete the ideal
of Ln for R for w in the word and two
lists uh IB equals ID or
least speed 150 50. a lot if it's a then
we shift the zero position if it is Z
then we shift to 25 to the left okay
this is more fancy syntax because it
allow us to transform the the word using
the bit bit masking
mask then we have a transform basically
we'll choose among the lowercase
characters uh into a big integer and
then we can compare two integer if the
two integers are the same and we say
these two words are similar okay and
it's basically a based on this one and
the time complexity let's analyze this a
little bit okay so this is n right o n
let's face complexity o n this function
is W so o n times n right and that's it
look
because that's easy to come up with and
we talk about the Improvement look this
is our one right and the ID function is
omo right so earn times n the space
complex division the counter okay let's
see okay what have you learned today
[Music]
we have a
similar like letters in them and you
call them similar
yeah okay so which method can you
explain to me how many messages do we
have to talk about three
yes to be exactly happy but the third
one is based on the second one just the
ID function we improve it okay four
apples picking two letters how many ways
yeah six pairs right two right so we can
prove us yeah we can prove us and then
we check if the two words are similar
right how do we check if two words as
middle uh we just converted to set and
that's it right because that only stores
the unique numbers that do not care how
many times they appear right okay let's
say for the day bye-bye bye