right
okay so we given this maze which only
contains zero or ones and originally
okay zeros and one okay originally
you're at top left corner okay so yeah
here there we go and Ryan yeah you are
here
and for each move you can move right
one position to the right or move one
position to the top so you can only move
to the east
oh
South okay one position
and the destination obviously you can't
cross borders
this is your destination
so I'm just asking can you find a path
can you find the route that uh write
down write down right and then listen
can you find the look is there such a
task that you when you cross the path
you know when you walk through the dude
you meet equal numbers of ones and
dealers
okay so equal numbers of 1 and 0.
equal ones yeah and equals what Ryan
just said what was that right down right
down right yeah right now right right
down right okay so how many ones three
how many zeros three okay another one
write down down right right okay okay so
this is a small base we obviously we can
look at it but if it's a very big one so
what's your thought uh one hint is that
it you can only move two direction it's
not like four directions it's just two
direction it can only work to the right
or walk to the downs we have been
talking about similar program before
right we are trying to find out how many
ways we can
chills from the top left to the right
bottom
and also we mentioned if we want to
bypass if this root needs to bypass one
certain point right we talked about a
long time ago we use the combination so
for example here
there are three rows here they are four
columns right to sum up you need to make
three pounds
and four
right in order to get to this point
right so this is kind of like
combination problem all right let's to
calculate the number of ways from the
top left to the right button but this
this problem is slightly different we
want to find out if there's a such pass
that when we can work on it we have this
equal numbers of zeros and ones
so any idea earlier just random Source
any idea
[Music]
but tell me how do you prove us
how do we check every possibility
so if I'm here with how many
possibilities do we have at each point
how many possibilities at each single
cell how many possibilities yeah two so
for each one we have two right so let's
say we have a function that's a search
right that's a search you remember what
you want to references
[Music]
okay so by thinking about that which
method is suited research says
look we are trying to find out if such
paths exists therefore such we just you
know just walk down a loot until we find
one right so that's as such okay let's
coordinate ah C
and B can you guess what are these
values
what's this okay something what's this
yes Rose columns this is this means life
look okay so I'm saying this function
returns that between
okay
that's that's as such I'm saying this
function I'm defining a function that
can tell me if like the past then wait
this function returns true or false
right it tells me it tells me
it tells me no Killers listen it tells
me if I can find a pass from RC from
this location to to the right bottom
right as if you if yeah that's a good
guess it's rows column which which
partition right B over if I say it's
balanced can you tell me what does he
means
it's equal
parents how about if I say okay if I can
see violence means you
know it is here it's like the same value
parents what's better
it's it's kind of it's kind
of like it's it's equal and yeah it's
equal yes one
and also honestly it has the same value
okay so in order to find the PATH so
this balance needs to be oh you can
balance them okay come on yeah yeah
listen oh
[Music]
you were full of okay so both yeah
parents okay so what's this this is
better okay so in order to find the past
this balance needs to be equal and
what's the usual value we will present
your balance is equal what should I put
here what should I put here well what am
I looking for come on it's a balance
so okay so this is once how many ones
how many zeros okay how many zeros how
many ones okay so in order to find the
pass we need these patterns to be yeah
right balance maybe here this is yellow
right so how about yellow then I said
five minus one because it's it's zero
okay minus one we said
this is uh positive yeah positive this
is negative if we meet one zero we
decrement the balance
by one if we meet one once we increment
the balance by one and the number of
equal zeros and ones it means that the
balance will be zero right look plus one
plus one plus one
one one there are three zero zero zero
minus three three plus minus three zero
makes sense so here you don't use
[Music]
good point yeah but I'm trying to say
look yeah that's a very good point yeah
look I'm trying to say at this point
we are here tfs00 and the balance will
be
the balance will be minus one right the
dependence will be
zero the balance will be
one the balance will be zero the balance
will be one the parents will be zero
when we reach respond we check if this
balance is zero right if it's zero it
means that we have equal number of ones
and zero makes sense yes so to sum up
when we meet zeros we decrease the
balance by one when we meet one we
increment the balance time one okay
okay so that this is okay and we can
solve this using Professor which I'm
going to talk about in the next next
time okay
yeah which is tomorrow next year come
online okay so that's uh look at this
and then you can improve it later okay
this is quite similar to some problems
we have talked about before right
balance
balance plus equal one if this makes
maze RC
is one right is one as we need to minus
one right okay so this means that if the
maze current position is one
we increment the parents by one
otherwise we decrement right so we can
also do this P plus equal because it has
only two values minus one one and then
Maze We can do this RC because this is a
Topper cutter contains two values couple
zero is minus one table one is one right
so I will use it this couple and we use
the value of the maze to retrieve the
value of the minus one or one and then
if B plus equal and then we leave a
check if r equal equal rows minus one if
it's the uh the last row and if the
columns C equals equal columns minus one
if it's the destination then we need to
return return if b equal equals zero
right
okay now look I'm at this point right
that's a search RCB right I'm moving
down so what's this that's a search R
plus one C
B right
I'm moving right
this is what that's a search
ah C plus one B am I the only two
position right yeah but we have to check
the boundary if ah smaller than Rose
and
that's my search R plus one
c d level between two and similarly if C
plus one uh R plus one okay R plus one
smaller if C plus one is smaller than
columns and
therefore such r c plus one b
then return true
okay otherwise will be 10 false right
look does it make sense here
look we are at this point recursion
right I'm at this point position
I'm here I'm here so I have two choice
I can go down or I can go right I can go
down or I can go right all right go
right
so if I can go down
if I can go down and call this deficit
if I can go down I find the past then I
limited return true I don't need to try
the other route right make sense because
the question I was asking is there such
a path do I need to proof of all of us
and if
by walking down I have a path I know
there's a path not return true
okay if there is no pass I need to try
working why right I need to try working
right okay so this balance thing is
updated here right at the beginning of
recursion right instead of updating here
okay
so is there a problem with this approach
yes what's that yes it just keeps going
Rock sorry does it just keep on going by
don't just keep going down there are two
yeah each partition I can have two parts
but
this is a
look this is a performance
putting your cash this is the top down
dynamic programming why there's a
duplication we need to remember
okay
let's Okay okay let's look at this point
so how many ways from here to here learn
a lot right so here here
here
supposedly I know laser path well
there's a path I already calculate this
when the balance is one I can't find the
PATH but the thing is that there are
many times that this point is passed you
know we need to cross this point
we need to cross this point therefore
says RC Balance so the first time we
cross this point for example this value
RC Balance we know there is no path
there is no such path
the second time we cross it with the
same RC Balance do we need to do this
again
suppose this is huge this is a very huge
area it takes like an hour to calculate
RCB okay so we're done right
we don't because we already know there's
no path
okay
if when I surpass will return in meters
we don't need to catch it actually but
if it's a false if there's no path we
don't want to spend time calculating it
again because we already know we tried
last time there's no pass we remember
there's no point to keep trying
I might say yeah this point there are
lots of ways
eventually will come to this point right
okay okay
the first time we calculate the result
remember it so look the time came back
stay we allow the cash this is
explanation right right it's
relationship because each point would be
computed many many times it's
exponential but with least cache the
number of total States we calculate it
is
Rose
times columns right look because look
each position when we calculate it we
saw it how many numbers in this maze
R times C right
but we need to remember the third one is
the balance
companies in RC transparents okay this
is the range this is the range okay
let's face complexity obviously
the same yeah we need a
array to study this is top down we're
using a cache the computer does the job
first the computer maintains a notebook
for us but we can do this in photo app
dynamic programming as well the opposite
photo app is non-trivial to right to
implement top down is easier
compound is easier because we just put
in the cash this is the magic keyword to
turn these proofers into uh top Cloud
anime programming by the numbering this
is quite similar and Fibonacci number
Fibonacci number F and equal f f n minus
1 plus f n minus two
yeah look quite similar look in order to
calculate FN we need to two recursive
call with a smaller problem right with a
smaller phone
yeah this is quite similar look at each
location
we need to solve two recursive functions
if it's flowing to two we need to
remember but if it's flowing to one we
may not need to remember another example
why we may not need to remember the
factorial f n equals n times f n minus 1
right
do we need to pull the cash here no
probably no right cover now because each
F value is only calculate once if you
want to calculate F4 you need to
calculate F3 in order to calculate F3
you need F2 in order to pack your F2 you
need to take the F1 which we know is one
right so when we get the one we come
back to calculate F2 come back to take
the S3 F1 but when we calculate F4 F3 F2
F1 it's only calculated once am I right
but here here why is it pregnant more
than one
F4 equals F3
plus F2 F3 equals
F2 plus F1 you see the problem
F2 here F2 here
okay
so we need to calculate because
otherwise we spend time
recalculating it F2 equals F1 plus F0
okay look F1 again okay so what have you
learned today
and about a maze
problem so what are we trying to do what
kind of solution we have and that's it
the numbers like what one zero ones or
zeros or ones and zeros and so we were
we gonna
we're gonna reached the top left is the
star and the top and bottom right into
the destination and so
and so
we wanted to have a we want a part of my
hat must I have we want to know if if is
there any possible part that the pub
contains the same number of zeros and
ones we can do three four seven candy
top down okay let me tell them yeah
dynamic programming what's dynamic
programming
yeah the key thing is remembering and
using an intermediate results okay this
is solving the smallest size problem
okay another thing is that look we're
working from the top left to the bottom
line and we all can also do the opposite
walking from the bottom right to the Top
Line it's the same right we talk about
finding the nearest exit in the maze
we can start from the engine to find the
exit or we can start from any exit to
find the entry this is bi-directional
right
okay that's it for today happy New Year
happy New Year bye