right
Okay so yesterday we talked about this
maze problem so to sum up we're given
this maze uh filled with zeros and ones
okay and then we are placed initially
placed on the top left corner and on
each move we can go to the right and we
go to the bottom two directions right
and down
and we want to find out if there's a
task that when we cross it the number of
zeros is equal to the number of ones
right and the destination is on the
bottom icon there's a maze like a three
times three is there a path no no why
because number what odd number three by
three equals nine three plus three
equals okay so look precisely speaking
right look this three times three we
need to work five three yeah five so
it's uh three plus three minus one
that's an odd number so it's impossible
to spread into equal numbers of ones and
zeros okay and yesterday we talk about
profiles which is Step as such and by
putting the cash we make it top down
dynamic programming so tfsrc coordinate
this is the position RC clothing Rose
columns and a b is the balance which
means that the number of ones
between the ones and zero by meeting a
one with plus one to the parents by
meeting a zero in minus one with
decrement the balance right so if we
have an equal number of ones and zeros
then the balance needs to be zero
four plus three plus three minus one
thing yeah it is plus three you do three
plus three because besides right
yeah it's three plus three
and a minus one this is the number of
steps from the top left to the bottom
right
three plus three doesn't it like always
be oh it's like four plus four minus one
it could be
like that three times well so how many
steps one two three four five six that's
six steps so like three plus four minus
one okay so it doesn't have to be a
square Matrix Square mix
okay
good point yes if it's a square then
it's odd right so we can find it because
n plus n minus one this is even a minus
one that's all we talk about the unique
parts right so it's quite similar so we
are finding a unique parts from this
position top left to the bottom right if
this is dimension is M this is n if this
is M this is n the number total number
of steps to move down is M minus one the
total number of steps to moving right is
M minus one so this is the number of
steps for us to move from top left to
the right but it needs this step and
this is the number of a step and we need
to pick
n minus one step to go to the right all
equally we pick M minus one step to go
to the bottom so the number of steps is
c m plus n minus 2 and minus one five
this is the number of steps
number of unique Parts if we want to
travel from this
top left corner to the bottom right
corner if we can only go to the right or
go to the bottom and we can go back okay
make sense simple example okay so how
many ways
from the top left to the other right how
look here this is three this is three
okay how many ways
how do you call for one
two
three
four five so how do we get five look how
many steps look at this is three yeah so
how many steps to go to the uh the
bottom right so you need a two
two to go to the town yeah you need to
move two steps down and two steps to the
right so two plus two this is four you
need the fourth step and then in this
first step you need to pick two of them
to go to the right or go to the bottom
picking two apples after four
okay so let's how many four times three
divided by two actually this is six so
last six ways so one way is missing
always missing
okay
one two
three four
five and what's that what's what's the
one that I haven't counted I lost track
okay one
two
three
down right four
five
six okay so six yeah you don't want to
do the same top no which one this this
this twice no no no here this one and
this one that's different
okay let's try again that's why I can
come up let's try again
one
two yeah
three all right I need more coming from
here now right
four
five
[Applause]
six right yeah
this is the oven that's why I calculate
it right there are four steps from the
top left to the bottom right and I need
to pick two of them to go to the right
or go to the bottom so this is C4 to
picking two out of four today
PFS prefer search level by level EQ we
use the TQ yesterday
recursion and we're putting the cash to
make it dynamic programming and
Professor is the same but
in order to solve this problem because
the duplication we need to use a set to
remember the state not exactly the
position we need to remember the state
which is RC Balance we need to remember
this state
that could be many many times that many
paths cross a point okay so you know
given the size of me you know how many
ways to travel from top left to the
bottom line right I just told you if
this is M this is n so it's c m plus n
minus two and minus one this is the
total number of Parts but if I say if we
must cross this point we must cross this
point so how many ways you don't need to
tell me the exact number but just you
know how do we solve this problem
so if I say okay there could be many
many parts but let's count how many ways
passing this point interesting right so
how do we do it this can be broken down
into two steps first of all we count how
many ways from this point to hit this
one yeah
yeah this is let's say a like how many
times from this point to this point and
we know how to solve this B so what's
the answer a times B that's the number
of parts that from top left to the right
but the crossing this term must be
Crossing at this point am I right so we
separate it we make it smaller this is
smaller maze two smaller Maze and when
we can use these to count how many parts
from this point to this one A to B and
how many parts from B to C and then the
number so the number will pass
from a to c Crossing B is a b this is
answer a b c this is B right yeah
interesting this is mathematics
you may appear in your exam paper okay
graphic search I'm just going to write
it okay okay I'm going to write a
question
and try to find out the mistake okay if
there's any uh Define
normally means you're gonna put some
mistakes no I don't know we're just
writing the code because you don't know
but you know
I may know okay writing the code on the
Whiteboard is not easy sometimes you may
mistake you're not aware of I just write
the code there's no computer to check my
code if I write that code using the
keyboard when I click the submit
the computer will check the code right
and then we'll tell me if there's a
mistake but if I write it on here so who
is on the chat YouTube
okay okay Define okay this is uh what's
this problem find
and then we given the maze Q equals DQ
yellow zero and then let's define a
function f 0 0 so I tell you what's this
function for so seeing
equals set this F function we talked
about yesterday
this is the return the value of the of
that maze but if it's one returns one if
this is passive saying if r m r c equals
1 then we do ten One S with 10 minus one
right if it's zero with a minus one and
we all we can write it in one number we
turn one if M R C equals one s minus one
or return we can write it this way
return a cutter minus one one and then
mace
maze RC okay
okay this m is global okay
then wire Q
r c p equals Q dot pop work
a q we want to take it from our other
side yeah top left if we don't specify
the left
taking from the right hand side okay you
know that
and if
Rose minus one
and C equals minus one so this means
that if it's in
destination now we need to check if B
equals zero return true and we need to
continue here anyway
all right and then select two locations
we need to go right then we just check
if R plus one is smaller than those
a pen
R plus one C uh and then this is f on
your f plus one C
is C plus one smaller than columns if we
can go to the right to the append
r c plus one f r c plus one okay okay so
now we need to use this scene okay so as
I said we need to remember the states
this is okay this is true false this is
the Brute Force version of breakfast
search remember the death research
recursion the Full Source version of the
different search but we couldn't attach
here right remember we're gonna catch to
make it top down the element programming
so here we need to implement this cache
here this is the cache this scene
remember that
the state which is RC RC Balance so
here we just said if r c balance in
scene right you calculated this before
then we just need to
continue right continue then otherwise C
dot add RCB okay okay this is okay
because if we found this we immediately
exit okay so we don't need to remember
this actual value of a state RCP right
because this is just saying that okay
when we cross this from RC and with the
balance we already push this into the
queue so we don't need to push it back
to the queue again
this is to enqueue right if we can go to
the bottom then we push its key kit R
plus one see the next location with the
balance with the new band ah okay so
there's actually one mistake
this is the pattern right this is better
so it needs to be plastic right current
balance is B plus this and the new cell
the new set is it plus one or minus one
right okay make sense
okay so look we are checking the
duplication here so actually this can be
moved
when we
pushing the new kids back to the queue
right or we can do it when we actually
dequeuing pulling the kids out of the
cube layer two ways both okay there's a
slight difference one is to check for
duplication to see if this node has been
visited when we're actually pulling
pulling the note
pulling a note okay so putting the note
from that queue so we check if it's a
duplication that's one way the other way
is that when we try to push we take this
note out we try to push it to kids right
we're not about to push the kid back to
the queue we check if the purification
checking duplication could happen here
or here but for professors usually
checking the duplication when we're
about to push it back to the queue it's
better okay but you know this is also
okay
uh the time complexity also similar to
the default search with the cache
top-down dynamic programming okay so
it's actually similar why is that
similar
to be the similar thing just different
ways of visiting the nodes the time and
space complex is quite similar right the
only difference about the space
complexity is that the preference search
will use the queue so every time we need
to maintain a list of the notes in the
current step but for that first search
look for the depth as such we only
maintain
the path current path right we don't
store the nose in the same level okay so
what have you learned today
we use the perfect search how do we
implement the perfect
in Python how do we Define a queue
what's the e means
what does double ending mean two sides
two sides we can push and pop from the
both sides so what's the alternative of
DQ if we don't use the DQ we can just
use a simple list right but the problem
of the simplest is that the operation
the problem of the simplest is that the
operation on the left hand side is
costing is O and linear okay so another
thing is that this size right uh rows
equals lens M and columns equal this is
the size of dimension of the maze
and then we can say if both plus columns
minus one and one if this is the all
number one we just immediately return
false right so we just checked as I said
right if the dimension if the rows plus
columns minus one if it's an odd number
then we don't need to perform the prefer
search or definite search am I right
this is an improvement right because
you've given me a maze I don't need to
perform a breakfast socio Professor so I
can tell you there's no pass
okay so we put this chip at the
beginning of the algorithm okay that's
it for today bye
bye bye