right
so guess what
well irregular circles something eggs
eggs okay eggs
okay so okay these are actually balloons
okay they don't look anything like
balloons okay I'll get eggs okay eggs
so we are giving this eggs on the wall
suppose that you just put the eggs
attach the eggs
Friday
Okay okay something like that yes let's
say how about the balloons you know
balloons are simple yeah but they don't
like anything like balloons they look
like so you only know the extraordinate
left and right right you only know but
you don't know the Y coordinates okay so
that doesn't matter so yeah accordingly
so
coordinate okay look at these
coordinates
so if we should
if we have this error right
okay if we have this error
you know vertical errors
so last time we have a vertical Arrow
here then if this error goes forever
right from bottom to the top and then
you will burst the balloons right so
look first up again but if I have
another arrow here you'll pass this
balloon so the question is
it that's good yeah that's good
observation yeah so the question is how
many we want to find out the minimum
number of errors that can burst all the
balloons one two three
one two three yes okay got it yeah so
let's say we have a unlimited number of
uh errors and then we are given a list
of balloons right but we don't know why
coordinates actually we don't need to
know the wild thing is we just need to
know the X boundary of the balloon and
they are regular Circle okay they are
regular Circle like this
that one doesn't look nice
that's okay but all we need to know is
that the balloon of our place yeah a
place on the wall right
and then we want to find out the minimum
number of the arrows that could burst
all the balloons right and
and you're saying that three how do you
know history because like it's my plane
I checked the ones above it
yeah so what's your strategy here so you
know I'm just giving you so what's your
strategy how do we know it's uh you know
one two three I I just eat my big smart
the balloon will be bursted if look if
this x i x
smaller than equal than this uh right
okay right and bigger than equal is left
okay if it is the balloon X
catching the left boundary or right
boundary you count it as a bursting okay
and it could fall into any values
between this range okay so yeah we've
given that this stuff to be like zero
and one can be like 0.5 it doesn't
matter because we are not we are not
finding when we should put the error
right we just want to know how many
right so but that's a good question like
we can just put it any one but only one
is enough right
yeah so we don't care which one where
exactly you just need one Arrow why
no just place this the error Circle uh
look Arrow now if Queen no it doesn't
redirect okay okay that's okay it
doesn't look that right okay it doesn't
change the directions it's just uh going
straight up forever forever it could
burst as many balloons
as they can along the direction vertical
up
okay so what's your strategy here
any idea any idea well if they're no
balloons
no balloon just returns yellow good
question that's a common case yeah no
balloons given nothing can you get
deceiving fault do you get this
no we just want to find out the minimum
number so minimum
number
of Errors to First
oh balloon
okay this is the question why I'll lose
you you are very clear right so we just
launched a vertical errors and balloons
so when it touches like the side of the
blue new bus let's try yes yeah
so
this is the kind of question remember we
talk about the interval thing right is
this kind of similar question in the
verse finding the intersection of
intervals right so we can visualize this
right this is one interval this is
another interval this is another
interval right
and then another interval
another interview right so we visualized
as these there are five intervals look
one two three four five so we want to
find out
how many right connected how many
components how many groups so obviously
by looking at it we know that one two
three right so three arrowser all right
yeah okay to solve interval questions
one usual way is to solve them to solve
all the coordinates solar intervals okay
so once we started we can go through
this right so we can sort the intervals
by the end point
okay so why do we need to solve the
intervals by the endpoint not the
starting point this is the question you
need to think about okay so look yeah
zero one right here
two three
and then
three four this is five seven and five
six right so we put the
five six here and then five seven okay
okay zero one two three four five this
is six this is seven okay
so now let's just take the first
interval this is current n which is
equal one right and obviously we need at
least one error to first the first
balloon right so answer equals one right
we check this one
we check if the
but if this is smaller than that if the
N is smaller than the beginning of the
next experiment right so we need one
more error right all right yeah because
it is
okay forget about
[Music]
it okay but and anyway just imagine this
is a different example okay so look
and it's smaller than the at least the
start of this panel so look visually
they are separated so we need to plus
one
all right
and as long as we press one we need to
change this end to here because this
covers up to this point so the end of
these three
if 3 is smaller than 3. no right if it's
not smaller than three if it's smaller
than three we need one more error to
burst this one but it's not smaller than
three it means the current error
converts this one okay
next okay so what's left
this balloon five and six is three less
than five yes this Arrow cannot pass
this column so we need to plus one and
then we change this end to counter n
which is six
okay so now we change the six now we
check this one it's six
smaller than five no no so it means that
the last error first this person
makes sense
yeah if it's smaller look if this this
is n right and this is the next one a
this is one situation if n is smaller
than a we need one more error to pass
this balloon and then once we turn left
we need to move this end
to here because that indicates the next
error can cover up to this point and
then we just iterated to the check if
and is not smaller than a so look this
is n
is not smaller than
you hit this way right look this is n is
a and it's not smaller than a
so what does it mean let's have an error
can pass this balloon
so we don't need one more error right we
can just jump to next one make sense
this is kind of usual way we solve the
interval pressure solar intervals and
then going from the left to the right we
need to sort by the end point so look
the input means this one
these
comes before life right another example
is yeah okay so which comes first which
comes first look this is the one
interval this is another interval we
need to compare we need to put the
interval the endpoint right the end
point smaller that's the coordinate the
balloon with the smaller right
before so right
okay
because we are checking we are checking
we need to move to a smaller right
and instead of the Pickled right and
balloon
dot salt what's the time complexity for
this one if they are endurance oh and
again okay all right okay the space
complexity usually oh and again as well
okay so now
the N equals the first balloon
the first one zero the end point right
zero one zero means the first one the
index the one means the end point the
the right boundary okay so we have to
also check if not balloon then we return
zero right if we are given zero values
then we just return
look the answer
at least we need one error right for a b
in burnt we start from the second
problem to the end right
e n is smaller than a
if we need one more error if the current
error does not burst the next balloon
then answer plus equal one
okay and then what's next if left n is
smaller than a the current error does
not pass the next balloon we plus the
answer we need one more errors and and
equals B right we jump to the right
boundary of the next element right and
then that's it right hand
answer this is the angular simple the
key thing here is
balloons dot sword is to sort it using a
quick salt right usually clicks off and
then this is the right battery of the
first person and then answer equals one
and then we go through the tolerance for
the second one to the end we can just go
through from a star we don't need this
and it still works why why is that
because the end is the n right boundary
of first room on the first iteration
this never gets executed it just weighs
one cycle because n equals a and the
next one so the key idea is that we saw
the balloons we saw the balloons by the
right boundary okay by the right
boundary thought here we need to sort by
the right boundary look by a b sort by
this one so k equals Lambda x x one okay
this is very important okay we sorting
let alone by the right boundary not the
left boundary and then we just have to
check what's the first distance
let the current error come first
the end which is indicated by n if n is
smaller than a right it means the
current error cannot reach the next
balloon we need one more barrel and then
we move that current
error to the right of the
next person so the terms of let's say
dominating and login and this is just o
n so it's o n log n plus n but it's
dominating by this one so we drop the
trivial part okay okay so what have you
learned today
[Music]
so if it is kind of like you you have
balloons and you have an arrow
is that you have balloons and you have
like a banana
and you gotta travel
balloons
so if it's kind of like if a balloon is
behind it another balloon you can burst
more than one and so and so for this we
use kind of like an intervals so so it
kind of looks like there's
um the kind of bubbles kind of thing and
then for the more previous one like that
one so you get this end and this
beginning if the end is smaller than a
we need two
if but if it ended bigger or or equal we
can bust two balloons at once that's
right yes yes exactly okay okay that's
it for the day bye
bye