right okay so we're given the numbers
array array of integers positive
negative and zero zeros are neither
positive nor negative right yeah so we
want to find out the maximum count of
the positive number of negative so
taking this uh for example like how many
positive numbers here
how many positive numbers
um
no I I was just saying that zeros are
not positive and are not negative okay
two okay so how many negative numbers
three okay so you need to tell me is
sweet is that easy it's very trivial
okay okay another example numbers equals
is a limit
negative
[Music]
we have to count the negative and
positive number and compare which one is
bigger basically this is what it is am I
right
you have to say negative or positive
yeah positive or negative we count yeah
we just count yeah how do we count
counter
uh we don't need them no the counter is
more like uh
now the counter is more like you want to
know how many times the number appears
right but here we just want to know how
many times a positive any positive
numbers or any negative numbers here oh
we can just go from the left to the
right
yeah should come right negative two
negative three negative okay three
negative
yellow zero we ignore positive positive
to annually compare why are you always
writing numbers which are sorted
that's a very good observation okay so
this is the proof of us right I didn't
tell you that it's salty right
that's very good very good yes I need
your eyes on this that's very good
actually if it's not salty if it's
unsalted that's the only way we can do
right it's a random the only way we can
check is go into all the numbers and
then just classify them right if it's a
positive just imagine there's a two
bucket if it's a positive plus one if
it's a negative a plus one if it's zero
so right away at the end we just compare
these two numbers right this is the case
when the level does yes the numbers are
unsorted right okay so let's quickly
write it it should be very easy right
okay and then think about how we can
improve it when it's sorted okay so look
positive equals zero negative equals
zero four I in numbers look
if p is positive
if I is positive P plus equal one L if L
if this is s if plus short for L if okay
and if I is smaller than zero negative
plus equal one and after we're going
through the all the numbers we just
return depend maximum if it's a p bigger
or and bigger this is Trivial right it
should be understand this in you know a
second a Time complexity
leave without a number what's the
temperature
oh well obviously we have to
finish seconding right that's today's
complexity a one right because we just
need a constant space okay excuse me to
sort it if I tell you these numbers
sorted in non-decreasing order so in
other words it's ascending
non-decreasing right
yellow yes why we look for geolog
because
that's good so what is sorted how we can
improve this uh we just I just we I just
can't go before go from beginning until
it's until it's positive or zero
and he is positive or zero which one the
country is you have to have zero
yes that could be zeros in there no but
do you have to what do you mean do you
have to yeah yeah because I have to have
is it right it doesn't have to have a
zero or can it notice if I'm negatives
it could be having a jealous you can't
make assumptions
when the negative ends it comes to zero
or another positive so if we delete
those two zeros with us we'll count
oh
if you let us know the ganza is the sin
and that's why I said that yellow is not
positive not negative yeah yeah
but the thing is um my point
is
do we have to have a zero in it
do we have had to chill in the uh
you can say yes
so we have to if it hasn't then then it
will turn to positive yeah of course but
the answer is still the same
yeah I know yeah but you're you're
thinking about the answer changing but
what I'm talking about is how when we're
negative
and it either stops at zero or another
positive okay so yes I understand your
point now but so you need to tell me a
way that works for both cases if the
zeros in there or if the deals are not
in there so if the array is sorted if
numbers are sorted if we meet the
positive we just stop can we because we
don't need to continue so with scan scan
scan we check check check okay it's a
positive
we don't need to count the rest we don't
need to continue suppose look yeah minus
one zero one two three
up to a minute
I mean how many zeros okay okay so here
this is a very extreme cases okay so now
now I'm telling you
okay okay thank you for correction okay
thank you so look the number of the
numbers in the array is a million and
two right very specific Facebook okay
this is the total number assume you can
get this number you know how many
numbers in the number in the array right
this is the number okay so do I need to
finish counting tier list no look
negative negative number
one
zero ignore
one it's positive so how do we calculate
the number of positive numbers
I know I already visit two numbers so so
for it's just like forever was it called
like the maze thing like you plus one
and the one time you tell us like plus
one minus one so for the negative we may
be minus one and and then for the
positively plus one
uh okay
because look let's say you have those
yeah you you have a negative yeah
whatever and a positive so when you have
something like I don't know
this and so when you mean minus one you
minus one
and then when you
um okay so so you start with zero as
always and then and then you minus one
two minus one and and then and then and
then you meet a zero and when you meet a
zero it's it's still the same and then
the next must be positive and then it
makes it a zero and then another
positive is one and you don't need to
count there because because you know all
the rest are going to be positive so
look I already counted two
right and then now I have a positive
number
I already counted two which is like are
not positive number and I know total
numbers how many positive numbers
there are two numbers which you are not
positive and I told the numbers in the
array so how many different numbers
simple math a million that's right a
million and two minus two right this is
what I'm saying right so because look
I've counted this and then I made the
first positive I don't need to continue
to the end this is a huge I can just do
a simple mess as long as we know this
number and normally this number is a one
we get this number one right
but some problem in language don't
provide these in order to know the
number of elements in the array you know
possibly what they do is that they count
it until the end that's very stupid way
right you can't imagine how stupid this
computer is now
you know if it has to count each number
to know how many numbers right normally
this is not the case normally there will
be a counter somewhere saying okay how
many uh how many numbers in the array
and then if we add one more number we'll
just add the this counter or we take a
number out there with decremental
counter so this is uh one simple way so
we can just improve this right so uh
negative equals zero total equals the
length of the array right negative
equals zero right now positive let's say
at the beginning we said to nine four I
in
numbers right if I is smaller than zero
the negative plus equal one right here
if
if I is bigger than zero if we meet the
first positive number so in this case
the positive equals what the total
right okay so we need to know the index
right so I V in illuminate right you
know this function right you numer like
illuminated function and then we need to
change this to V
V the I is the indexes of zero this is
the zero this is one Index this is two
so we need to minus this one right so P
equals total minus I this is Index right
and then we need to break we don't need
to continue here this is the the
optimization we need to break right we
need to play and return this is the same
return maximum p and v okay the time
comma x t come on this is a tricky one
we have a third Improvement the time
from next day when we talk about the
time complexity we always talk about in
the worst case so what's the times I'm
listing
oh
be brave say it out
[Music]
in worst case what could be in the worst
case
no in in the worst
in the worst case
these optimization slight optimization
is not useful at all when
they know positive number right if there
is no positive number it's the same as
the previous one so the time complexity
is
oh and oh and because in the worst case
you still have to go through each
numbers when there is no positive number
right okay so this optimization may not
work please optimization works if like
there are lots of the
positive numbers
right like this we just count two and
then we can exit oh we're given is
sorted arrays one algorithm we can think
of is what kind of ignorant we need to
think you know one we're given something
sorted we need to think one algorithm
which is like Ryan you talk about
finding zero zero is a very important
part so look
this number right minus five minus four
minus 3 0 1 100 a million
so we want to find the zeros here these
are very exotic so how do we find it
because it's sorted
sorry we can
binary
gas
spinosis yes exactly yeah yeah if we can
finally search we can reduce the
complexity from o n to O log n guessing
the number not example I've given you
many many times I have a number in my
head
and I can't tell you you get the number
what's your story is it 50 okay the
number in my head is smaller 25 okay
you're not a strategy you're always cut
in half when look so I have a number a
zero to a hundred and then you guess the
in the meter right if it's a
figure
you guess from 51 to 100 if it's smaller
it gets from zero to 49 right every time
you walk you abandon half of it you
don't need to check any numbers here
right your abundant half of it so let's
improve the speed right like cut the
search space into half right so we can
finally search right and we can find and
search the zero this is very important
but we need to understand how to win
final research the zero we talked about
five seconds five seconds left and
biceps right right we talked about that
probably 200 days ago
okay
one example okay five seven left
five set
right find the search okay we can
Implement search but the python function
is this one when the item we are looking
for in a sorted array does not exist
these two function Returns the same
thing when it's not exist okay so look
zero one two two two two three I have
lots of tools right so if I'm saying
that I want to buy set that the numbers
right this is numbers
okay numbers
okay and I want to find the two where is
the two
okay look I want to find the two
but I said left and right works on the
salty the lumbars needs to be sorted and
then you're looking for two looking for
two so five and left you will return
this position this is five set left
it means that this is the position that
you can put the new another tool to make
it salty right
is here look here this is the difference
so first advice is that when you put
this partition here
why is salted okay this is a new index
okay
yeah
so
minus five minus four minus three zero
zero zero one two three okay so look
we're looking for pi set left
is here please position price and right
is this one okay so look
if we do divisor left faster than how
many negative numbers
yeah all right
how many positive numbers
how many positive numbers this bit but
we know this Index right we know it is
index so we know how many total numbers
the minus the spices right and then
that's it okay makes sense so simple
right this end is this total total
equals the length of the numbers
okay the negative number equals five set
left the numbers
zero this is the number of negative
numbers and positive number equals total
minus 5 set
right
numbers
zero and then we can
maximum
negative positive this speed is the same
okay one two three four four lines of
code
and the time complexity oh look n plus o
log n two
login oh login plus o login equals o log
n times two we drop the constant so it's
O log n okay the first approach oh n the
second approach is n the third position
which one is better which one is faster
okay
the first approach you know some people
might write it as one return in a
maximum all right you can say some I
smaller than zero for I in numbers all
right this is to count how many negative
numbers and some I bigger than zero for
IE numbers right but the problem of this
is that the max function requires two
parameters here we need to go through
the array twice right so you go to one
array once to find out how many are
negative numbers you go through another
time to find out the positive number so
it's actually o n plus n which is o2n we
drop the constant even the time
complexity is still on the performance
is worse than the first as you remember
we just go through it away and we have
counter to count how many are negative
numbers how many are positive number
right it's just single person all right
okay so what have you learned
these numbers and there's a range of
negative and positive numbers but then
we're supposed to counter the negative
and positive numbers and then the most
popular
positive or negative number we we return
the clarity of positive or negative
number and also zero zero doesn't count
so we can just program a bin
okay good so what kind of equivalent can
we use here
the only if the numbers are in order
yeah even they are not in order we can
prove us from the left to the right
right yes okay right on your turn
to learn about that there's like
it's even negative
yes and sometimes somebody arrives yes I
know you want to find out the biggest
number we want to find out if there are
more positive numbers or negative
numbers right okay so if the numbers are
sorted what what can we do with it we
can basically
can't use that bicep thing and also we
could count the negative numbers and
then these quick maths that's true and
the pie set is finally first yeah so we
are buying a research of what
we want to find this but basically what
are we trying to do with the binaries
bicep thing we want to look for the
zeros right the left zeros and the light
zeros and based on the index but because
spacer left retains the index python
right it also Returns the index so we
can paste on the index to do the math
because bicep is by research takes a
long end time it's faster and the bicep
left and python right basically the same
if the element if the element is not
existent in a way right for example if
I'm looking for 0.5
if I are looking for serum for Thai uh
using python level right basically will
tell me it's here you don't need to make
a difference if the element is in the
array okay that's it for today bye bye
[Music]