hello hello
okay so we're giving this number integer
positive integer uh
and we want to find out
why am I right we want to find out if we
can find any non-negative integers
let the sum of it and its reverse equals
the N for example like if we're given it
for three and a search number one seven
two which is non-negative and it's
reverse it's revised 271 plus a together
equals 400. 140 the reverse zero four
one okay we can have leaving zero so
plus it together equals 181 okay 63 we
don't find such integer like
non-negative integer plus it's reverse
yes
can the original number yeah have a
leading theorem
the original right you mean this one
I mean I mean this number like this yeah
yeah of course don't look
look zero four one this is the same as
zero four one plus one forty five
oh yeah yeah so we're given this end we
want to find out if they are a plus b
right equals n okay I'm not asking you
to find out the which number right I'm
just asking if there's such integer and
it's reverse okay make sense and then we
could have a leaving zero so A and B so
a this is the reverse of B okay reverse
the integer reverse so this comes with
impairs does it make sense
okay so what's the first solution coming
to my
if we were given this n and we want to
find out if they are long negative
negative
yeah non-negative A and B plus together
is is n and a and b needs to be uh
reverse is a symmetric right symmetric
how do you spell symmetric
symmetric right what's symmetric
both sides are the same exactly the same
symmetrical but that's not symmetrical
well this is symmetrical no it's not uh
I'm trying to okay symmetrical
[Music]
because on one on the right it's a
wobbly one but one other left but your
left hand and right hand symmetrical
okay no they're not what is that
I remember uh so basically it means that
kind of mean all right no they're not
no my left hand is doubled my family the
double jointed by my other one okay okay
I know sorry this one is cleaner than
this one okay okay yeah yeah forget
about the details but I'm just saying
that you understand
teacher before I go my Vine teacher
right now
her pinky is he is low her right one
pinky is longer than her left pinky okay
now let's uh focus on this uh problem so
what's your solution what's uh what's
the thing in your mind so you've given
this end so what we can do
what we can do
so how many possibilities we can check
what is the solution that we have to
check each possibilities
stupid way right given this 443 how many
possibilities we have to check we check
from zero okay two four four three so
they are four four four numbers to check
what I'm saying they were given n so we
just need to check from 0 to n inclusive
right
of course the N could be anything
so but the thing is that we have to
check out to end right for I in range
from 0 to n right to n plus one
and now we just have to check if I plus
it's reverse I equal equal n right
and then we do 10 true
otherwise return false all right this is
the proof of 310 we can write it using
any return any I plus reverse I equal
equal n
for I in range and plus one right and
this reverse function let's write it how
do we reverse this one if we say one two
three how do we get the three to one
[Music]
which we round
we just switch it around
we can there are two ways
one way is that if we convert it to
string right
if we convert it to string that will
become one two three how do we reverse
this bit
three two one yeah how do we make three
to one we use the okay what's this
latest column column
but this is the string now we need to
convert it back to integer right so we
just put it integer
okay this is one way another way one two
three how do we get a three
we talked about that
modulus 10 right and then we get rid of
three by divided by ten right and then
we keep doing this right extract the
rightmost digit we extract the ones and
then we remove it
okay so one two three four we extract
the first Stitch four
we extract the three so where do we put
the three
and now I'm taking three out what should
I put it right yes okay now I'm taking
two where should I put it
right and I'm taking one where's here
today
yeah you see
Define reverse and
we want to reverse this individual the
answer would be answer at the beginning
of this yellow wire n is bigger than
zero right then we take the last digit
so the last digit will be
x y x equals n more details 10. this is
four right and then
answer equals answer answer times 10
plus X then n divided equal to 10 return
answer I want to put a 1 on the right so
I need to multiply this by 10 right so
it becomes 4 3 to 0 and then plus one
make sense look I take the one the digit
and one here I multiply 10 means that I
put a 0 on the right hand side
and then plus X right from the X here
and then the original number needs to be
taking out the one digit so we divide by
10 okay this is the three four solution
so do we have to check every number no
why so for example like four first three
so we have to check from 0 to 443 can we
do better than this how
look we are looking for two numbers A
and B symmetric but add it together to
443 so do we have to check every number
for a true false all the possibilities
of a right
so I'm saying A and B are symmetric so
one seven two two seven one is metric
right
symmetrical okay so these two numbers
are symmetrical so does it matter that
which one is which
it doesn't matter right they're not
symmetrical that seventh line is one
seven two one seven two I mean reverse
t-shirt okay there's symmetrical okay no
that one has been rubbed out a little
bit okay symmetrical is like adapters
not opposite
symmetrical is like a mirror yeah so if
I did one seven two it'll be like this
one seven ah okay okay okay okay
that's the confusion here but the one on
the right side is the two is slightly
okay let's forget about this uh what I'm
saying the 172 and two seven one this is
symmetrical okay forget about the shit
okay no no no it's not symmetrical it's
reverse
ah okay that makes no sense okay but
what I'm saying is that this AMD can be
interchangeable all right so do we
actually have to go through this
can we just do half that's what I meant
we checked from The Middle
does it make sense yeah because we only
have to check half of it and the other
one we just use the mess does it make
sense okay so which is which half the
first half from zero to that meter or
the meter to them this is the one
question for you
okay you're listening yeah I am
listening okay so from what's the half
of forward three
spider
it is uh two two let's say two two one
or two one or two to one point five okay
do we check numbers from zero to two to
one or from two to one two four four
three we check this number so we go
through this number and then we reverse
it and we add it together to see if it
adds about two four three which one do
you think it's better left left one
because it
it's obviously going to be bigger
now let's have a tricky one because
because
well either way I think it's I think
they're the same way but are you sure
how about I give you a hint leading
zeros which part does not consider the
leading zeros
to the right
left heart does not consider leaving his
wife because like zero one two three in
Reverse list you never get leading zero
am I right
the social
yeah so for example like you you because
here no no what I'm saying
what if you do 180 yeah
yeah that's true what I meant is that uh
look this is yellow one knife we don't
zero right so we instead we check from
this side we check from this side
because when we eat away over this range
right we are missing we're missing this
for example if it's three digit we're
missing this is yellow here
all right yeah so we're going to reverse
this 19 will become a 91.
if we reverse if we check the integer
from 9 1 0 and then it reverse will be
0.19 okay so we're gonna be leaving zero
in this case make sense
so the Improvement is that we start from
the middle middle and this so we start
from a meters integer and now we close
to all the half numbers and then we
check its reverse
and then we add it together and we
change if it's a 443 if it's a given and
if it is then we return to otherwise
written Force the time come next to each
layer n right so this is all
divided by half right times
the reverse function takes o
takes Ln right let's say m m is the
digit right one two three so it needs
the three iterations to get to the
digits so m is roughly log base 10
uh n y so it's o n Times log 10 Place n
over 2 is the same as n when we talk
about time complexity because this 2 is
the constant we drop the constant okay
make sense
layer better approach like mathematics
and also binary search which are too
complicated for you okay so we're not
going to talk about that today okay so
what have you learned today
and we learned about the calculation
over like reversity numbers added so we
have a number and and we want to we want
the sum to add up to that so we have
reversed so so we have it so we like
so we try to see if there's a possible
to
possible to like
um uh reverse for numbers and add were
some together
okay we just use the profiles yeah so
the key thing to take away is that we
start from the half
from meter to the to end
just to iterate half of the numbers
and then you know how to reverse a
number how many ways we can reverse a
number
so okay can you just say one of it
yeah we convert to a string we use the
column column minus one to reverse the
string and then we need to convert it
back using the in function okay let's
see for today bye bye