right
okay so you've known the maze right the
maze yeah
yeah we talk about the main problem many
times finding leaves past shot his paths
from the engine to any exit right or we
can use the professor to use the deficit
so that problem we are given the maze
the maze won't change and we're given
this exit here and then entering here
right entering exit
yeah but there's no exit
executed yeah yeah but you can't get
there because because the door was
blocked okay in front of the image okay
all advice that I feel and then that's
literally a super easy maze yeah I know
because they know their dance okay so
here yeah
and then
[Music]
a kind of maze it's a different type of
Maze and for example this one you put a
gap there and they get there yeah and
then you can you see
like that and then and how I would do
whoops like that and then I'll put some
some different ways
so so it's not only one so for example I
might put that
um I might put
um
[Music]
like that okay
but also you need to fill in that energy
so yeah
yeah I see I see okay okay let's see
interesting okay he's done and accurate
to generate a maze okay so this is the
ambiguous question can it be like this
can be like this
oh this is simply it's a mess okay yeah
it's amazing yeah so that's a good
question that's good so in a in a box
yeah I know we want to design a maze
this is an ambiguous question so we need
to ask the questions why do you keep
saying ambiguous because I just said
design and icon I didn't say how right
you know what what is the requirement
and we need to ask a lot of these
questions okay what kind of question
would you ask you need to know before
you design the maze design Ackerman that
could generally amaze what kind of
precious what type of mates does it have
to be that's a good question what type
of maze yes this could be the one with
just squares and the ones with parts
squares
yeah this is square everything is
squares no
one like this
okay that's good okay yeah yeah okay so
actually these two are convertible right
are convertible okay so let's focus on
this one yeah it's a square and okay to
simplify if it's one if it's a you know
two dimensional array right metric if
it's one it means that it's a war if
it's zero it means that empty okay you
can work okay okay so let's design a
square maze with one which is more zero
is empty cell and
what's next
so just type them randomly you just put
it randomly like pick or not pick pick a
nappy yes but pick up nothing you could
be a very random picture right random
Square how do you know if it's a maze
uh we we try
to try our knife
possible okay so your solution is that
randomly General y one and then we check
if it's nice huh that could be one way
right so we generate so we generally
random you know whatever it could be
amazed or could be not amazing and I
will check if it's amazing if it's
amazing right yeah next one was about
doing them thing is not guaranteed to be
amazed and it could be you generate like
a thousand times and it's still not
amazing what would you do we delete some
how do you do this
we use Hulk smash okay so you're saying
that we generate the Maze We generally a
random square if it's not made some some
words yeah oh that could work right okay
this is one way okay is that an easy way
to do it it's a square maze along we
want the dimension right the rows and
columns right we obviously need to know
how big is the mate all right we need to
know how many valid cars yeah that could
be one hour parameters Valley path
sometimes a maze does not have any valid
path right that could be still a maze so
can we think the opposite Instagram
randomly generating right which by the
way is a good thinking right very fast
so can we think of these the opposite
way so you think of a pop yeah okay so
we first draw the path yes let's say we
drove a path like like we can draw a
path like that and then and then add
some add some other stuff to it
as as some Alistar what other stuff like
Wolves yeah it's water so many times
remember we are given this for example
if you want to generate a maze with only
one part then we learned that they
generate this path okay here all right
this part okay
this is the path okay and then that's it
we just feel the rest please move
was and okay so this is a simple maze
but how do we make it like the maze we
put some other parts like
like
we put some other lights yeah we can
turn we can put another path to the end
or per dead end
good point okay so how about this way
it's a similar idea okay so within the
past but you are only asking for one
very pass okay let's generate a few more
to spare you know it could cross right
but for each other value pass I put
Awards randomly somehow to block it
and then that will work
is there a problem with this solution
think
Sly yeah it could be but it's efficient
and this one right because you don't
know this one you just say why
true okay I promise not to write the
code but this is unit okay and then
generate you know the maze
generate generate okay Maze and then if
maze is valid
then we do 10 right we can make
otherwise we keep doing this okay okay
so this one remember what did I talk
about so we generally a path right we
General path
and then we generate a few other parts
for broke it broke it when I broke it I
broke the meter block the same route of
the original value path that color
problem so when we broke it we don't
broken the Cross Point okay makes sense
yeah then that will work all right the
idea is that we generate a very fast
first and then we generate a few other
paths which will block it right
depending on how many Value parts you
want okay we could have two then we
generate two Valley paths
okay and then we generate a few other
parts which will eventually we're going
to block it okay and okay so how do we
generate a value path right this is the
whole picture and come back to this
question how do we generate a path
yeah amazed how do we generate a value
class we put entrance and exit yes they
enter in the exit on the border right
remember the a few days that's what we
talked about that engine here
right we learned a lot of generality
right so I could just say the entry is
on the top
all right if you want the engine to be
here here let's find a generate here and
I will take the magic
like says I know the trader Matrix let's
say the engine is on the top and the
exit could be somewhere on the border
okay why do we need the engine to the
top I can say okay every time I can only
walk down
I can only walk down walk left or work
right until it hits the boundary right
so randomly cross a coin with three
possibilities face up face down or
neutral huh so down left right if random
pick an a direction you go go okay when
it hits the boundary this is a very fast
another way we could be like that right
and hits this boundary that's a very
fast
okay his part he's found another task
like that's one way
this this is the entrance that's the
exit no no we don't Define the exit here
we just let it dry hit the boundary
which is the exit we're asked to
generate a path we don't care we are not
saying okay
after here let me become complicated
because you are trying to find a path
from A to B actually that will work but
it's complicated we want to simplify it
so we don't care where is the exit as
long as it's on the boundary as always
doesn't hit the boundary
you can prove it always look on the top
every time you'll need to work down work
left of work right you you don't go up
so every time you move and move the
first time it has to go down okay it
can't go left or right otherwise it will
be on the top right that doesn't make
like any sense right the first move has
to move down and after that
you can move left or right or down right
you try this many times you will
eventually hit the left boundary right
boundary of bottom button am I right but
what if the main just keeps on going in
a loop what do you mean
the loop a loop and it never ends you
mean here just because no it never
happens in this case because it never
goes bad all right
but you can keep on going right left
right left right yeah that's good
spotting yeah that's what you mean right
yeah good point Okay so
we can just use the hash
the hash table to remember the pictures
we visited am I
yeah okay so
go down go left this piece that we are
visiting we can't go back we can't go
back and then only give you two choices
all right
yeah I saw you were talking about these
go you know like that you never have
satisfied but to be fair we can add four
directions
as long as we have a headset right so if
we have this uh headset scene table
which feature we have seen we can add a
pointing up Direction but it depends on
how you like the path to look like right
it could be very curly right if you add
in the top you could be very curly in
the country this way right level work
right
yeah okay so to sum up what happened
today
learned about
how to generate a maze a general an
Amaze what kind of parameter we need to
fit the computer first the more kind of
the parameters how big is the maze yeah
how many Value parts you want it to be
right these are the most important
parameters and then how do we generate a
maze what kind of Agron ever you
mentioned the point the randomly General
Maze and then check if it's available
but the thing is how do you check if
it's a very nice
so if you got a headset and and you can
go up yeah what happens if you go like
if you go like this yeah
ah then then you can't go anywhere good
point that's a very good that's a corner
case right there's no parts right so
okay that's good as you can think of
that that's very very good yeah that's
one situation it could happen but maybe
unlikely to happen because every time
you pick you know this is the public
busy piece right that was saying before
what if you don't hit a boundary that's
true yeah yeah very good okay so let's
get rid of this app right and just uh
down left or right and you will have
about it all right
yeah your hair powder right that's very
good okay I didn't think of that very
good very clever okay
that was gonna be a good job okay and
you said this one how do we check if the
metric is amazed you give it a square
with the one and zero how do we how do
we determine if it's a maze first of all
if I if they are entrance or axes in the
border right entrance engine yeah and
then you try to find
finding the nearest exit to the engine
you can use the aggram
question
remember we are given this Maze We
equivalent is entering right and we want
to find out the nearest exit
to the engine in the Maze right we talk
about these Professor Stephenson the
only difference is that we are not sure
which entry we can just pull forth these
uh pictures these are places on the maze
to see if it's an entry and then we just
apply an accident so this one is
breakfast search or deficit generator
makes
pick or not pick right you're saying
each Pizza has two zero and one two
Choice it's just quickly random
generated I don't know how efficient is
that because the maze could be very big
and then you're randomly populating that
and then you try to listen that's a very
good solution very good thinking and the
other way is the opposite we generally
the very pass and then after that we
just populate the rest right
and that's it right okay so have you
learned something today yes good okay
let's see for today bye-bye
bye bye