okay so what's uh Sudoku
it's like a 9x9 square and it's filled
with numbers not all of them but and
there's nine squares with nine squares
inside and nine columns each okay like
that all right so each one is nine times
nine right and then what are the rules
for that
so you try to fill the numbers with one
to nine right and also the rows and
columns did one to nine okay and they
all have to eat and they all have to
equal
one day one day and then also one there
right yeah yeah so like I I
and they will have to equal up I see I
see yeah
tonight well um well I'm not sure it's
after number actually so yeah to sum up
yeah we put the numbers one to nine
we put the numbers one to nine in each
box little box there are nine of them
and the numbers
each number can only appear once in each
row each column and obviously in its own
sale okay when we talk about this
we talk about you know how to complete
how to solve it with some numbers in
that but some numbers we need to
determine right so we use the
backtracking
so how do we backtracking I show you
it's very easy yeah basically that's a
search so if this number is missing then
we try to determine right and then we
can try you know we can try one two
three four up to nine and if it violates
the existing rule we just try the next
one if it doesn't violence for example
if I can put a 4 here right so I move to
the next one
I move the next empty cell and I keep
trying step as such backtracking the
idea is very simple definitely go deep
as deeper as you can right so if we can
put a number four then we move to the
next one if we can put the number four
here we try number five if we running
out of Digit up to nine then we go back
to the previous solution previous uh
empty cell for example the previous one
is uh three and then we increment this
to five this is the backtracking to
solve this problem okay so today
expression similar like yesterday we
designed the maze so the question is we
want to design that again like design
it doesn't have to be so when you say
designers Sudoku so we want to return a
fully solved
that's a very good question so I just
said design uh Sudoku and that's it you
need to ask a lot of questions before we
actually go into the details okay so
these are questions to clarify the
requirement okay so you're saying does
it have to be fully solvable right do
you have to return a solved certificate
no your playlist game right all numbers
are filled in we don't play right it's
already layer so the question is that
design uh Sudoku that returns partially
right so it can be played we can play on
it right and that's a very good question
so is uh partially right it has to be
partially filled
all parts of the completed the second
one is any more questions
any more questions we can ask any more
questions when you play this Dooku
it's solvable that's a good question
yeah obviously it has to be solvable if
it's not solvable the worst case I can
just put random numbers in there and you
can find the solution right for example
I return a Sudoku and with two ones here
no matter what the rest it's not
solvable because one and one is eight
right okay so it has to be solvable and
any more questions
it had to have nine by nine squares
obviously Sudoku is nine by nine okay so
when you play the game you can choose
something to play you can set the level
of who is that when you play the game
usually you can set the level of what
level of what
easy yeah yeah yeah what is it called
yeah difficulty right the level of
difficulties yeah all right that could
be one of that level of difficulty
and another one is
how many solutions
okay because some Sudoku could have many
solutions right if you're saying okay
there's only one unique Solutions yeah
okay maybe one unique solution right so
there's only one way right
obviously if you are given uh empty
empty stuku there are how many
these two numbers huh
6.679 times 10 to the power of 21 so 10
this number followed by
21-0 this is a huge number so this is
the number of total Sudoku Valley States
right but if we do move the duplications
duplication like you know some states
may be the same if you transform uh if
you rotate it nearly right and it brings
down the number to 5.4 times 10 to the
power of 9 very solvable States okay
yeah make sense
okay so we're saying that if we return
an empty cell and then obviously this is
not unique okay okay so these are not
requirements all right we want to return
a partially field State and it has to be
solvable if it's not soluble there's no
point right and then the level of
difficulty this is optional we need to
consider the number of different usually
okay so how do you know if it's easy
easy to do how do you know it's hard
by looking at our numbers
the the number how I mean how do we know
it's an easy how do we know it's a
difficult
by giving you two how do you tell which
one is easy to solve one of these is
let's try yes because the more numbers
more clues right so it's easy to solve
last number you have to try right all
right yeah then it's a more difficult to
solve that's exactly what I thought
about the numbers the number of numbers
yes yes I understand good job numbers
okay okay so how can we design that
I think we have to get a Sudoku
um and and fill all of it and then and
then delete a load of them very good
very good so first of all we need to
find
a complete complete it Sudoku right
and then remove numbers and then we move
the numbers
remove a teacher at one right step two
I remove a digit and that will return a
valid solvable state right these two
steps satisfy this one and this one how
about level of difficulties
yeah okay so we can simply remove a
certain amount yeah yeah so we can
simply repeat the step two to make it
this one but how about this one how many
solutions if we want to make sure it's
only one
how do we make sure if it's only one
um that's that's basically the first
time we are finding a complete let's
start right complete and then he has
stupid random right yeah we don't want
to we want we don't want to return the
same uh every time it has to be rendered
okay we come back to the step one later
remove a digit right and then we need to
check if it is solvable right and
obviously it's solvable and
check if it's over and only one solution
right if it is solvable and if we have
removed a number certain number of
digits right this could be a parameter
like if we want to remove n digit so for
example if we remove the one digit one
if we removed one to ten digits then we
say it's easy okay
if we do more 10 to 20 digit 11 to 20
this will say medium okay for example if
we know 21 to
upwards it will be hard okay okay this
is just example of configuration of the
game if we remove the up to 10 digit
it's easy okay remove one digit at the
time if we go back to check if the
Sudoku can be solved and contains only
one solution right we can use the
backtracking right to count how many
solutions
if we already remove ntg then that's it
right if it not okay what happened if we
leave digit we do it move these two many
solutions then we have to pull a digit
back right because if we remove the
digit for example if we do more or less
and then we found out there are two
solutions right then we have to put the
number nine back right make sense okay
so the first one find the completed
random Sudoku how do we find we can just
simply do the backtracking all right but
with some random randomness so we try
for example we can try instead of trying
from one to nine we can randomly select
the number we can Shuffle the selections
right the next number we could Shuffle
so for example the next one is empty
self right empty set then we can
randomly pick an integer from one to
nine instead of trying from one two
three up to nine right previously when
we do the backtracking to find
a solution we always try from one right
so but we want to return some Randomness
then we can choose the random integer
layer and once we complete uh find a
Sudoku State we remove a digit and we we
check if these Sudoku is solvable and
only one solution right only one
solution and if it is we keep removing
until n digit right make sense
yes
okay so what have you learned today
so to make a Sudoku yeah okay
I mean obviously
The Brute Force way is I just randomly
generate number I put the numbers there
and I randomly take it out and I check
if it is
solvable but that's going to take more
time right yeah because when you run
then you put the numbers in you cannot
guarantee that
this one yeah yeah that's what I meant
right because
yeah I know I know this way is a it's a
very very inefficient it's not
practically uh useful right when you
randomly generate the numbers so when
you run the Nintendo numbers it could be
anything and it could already be
unsolvable and no matter what numbers
you've taken out it's still unsolvable
and you have to check you can do this
repeat you generate a random blending uh
sudo check if it's a solver if it's
solver then break otherwise to repeat
but this is not very good okay that's
what I said one better way here is that
we use the backtracking algorithm to to
find uh come completed Sudoku with some
random yeah we want to we want this uh
stucco to be random and after that we
remove a digit at the time all right we
can remove any random digit at the time
and if after we're doing the moving
around that digit if it has more than
one solution we put it back we put the
digit back we'll try the next one right
if it's uh only one
solution now we can keep removing it
until ended it and this is n digit this
is the level of difficulty okay does it
make sense
okay that's it for the day bye-bye