what's this
the tree and
a tree with numbers okay so what is a
tree it's a tree finally three yeah is
it oh yeah because the h l has at most
two kids and also a tree is uh a tree is
a diagram a graph a graph yes a tree and
also we can that's great that's great
yeah pH okay wow okay also it's uh we
can say a tree is a t a g right
because it has a direction and it
doesn't have uh Cycles a cyclic directed
directly okay a cyclic
means no cycle okay
what's that
that's a great but yes a grave is a
graph okay
and then you can think of it as a tree
as well okay okay so we want to count
how many nodes right how many
how many cores the sum of its uh
descendants descendants what's
descendant means
bottom you send them basically I mean
their children right children right yeah
okay so what's that descendant what's
the kids are all the kids of ten three
I ended up together 10
because of that okay anymore
three is two one that's right so we
defend two four is zero
good point if the note has no children
the sum of The Descendant is zero we
want to count how many notes right how
many notes equals the sum of its
descendants for example it's 10 the
descendants of ten is three four two one
all the kids together can be zero all of
them can be zero and all of them will
have it
ah you mentioned you're saying that zero
zero
zero yeah yeah that's good yes yeah
exactly because everything is zero okay
okay so the kids of three this sentence
is two and one two plus one equals six
yeah I think in 490 days or something we
talk about a similar program which is
the counting the number of nodes which
equals the average average of it okay so
for example like 10 of this substrate
right ten three four two one this is 20
20 divided by one two three four five
average is four okay and if this is now
is four then we count it right it's
similar right it's similar instead of
counting the average we are counting the
sum okay so on that day we use the data
search we use the recursion deficit to
retain the number of uh notes and then
the sum of it okay so each deficit score
returns a couple number of nodes and the
sum so for this case we just need to
return the summer we want to return the
sum how do we check if time equals all
this okay so now I'm telling you that
some of this path is six you know
without looking into the details that
some of the left tree is six the sum of
a right tree is four how do you know if
it's do you have to work to work it out
good point we're using a recursion
that's a search right so look this is
four without looking at the details I'm
telling you the sum of its or the left
note is six some of all that right now
is four and then you can check right six
plus four equals 10 we increment account
of one easier this is the big picture
but how do we get this recursion we talk
about the recursion uh defines to go
through the left three right tree
accordingly right and then we can return
the number of the nodes or we can return
the sum of it how do we count how many
nodes in here very simple right Define
that first search loot
uh if not root
we just returns yellow right otherwise
return
def as such how many notes in the last
three here plus how many notes in the
right tree right plus one note of itself
recursion right recursion that's the
search
if we are given an nothing return zero
how many notes in the left three how
many notes in the right tree plus one
now okay so if we want to transform this
function to return the sum of all the
nodes in the tree
which numbers should we change let's
continue this function recursion
function Returns the number of nodes but
if we want to change it to return the
sum of the nodes we just have to change
two place
actually no we just have to change one
place we just change it to
um
value right yeah
to solve
yeah do you need to call this bit here
because yeah okay we have this function
to return the sum of it and then how do
we do it that first search Define
search loot right
if not load
returns yellow right the sum of empty
now is zero the left sum
equals that's as such
Blue Dot left right this bit this is a s
a s
yeah please wait the RS right sum equals
seven search what
Blue Dot right right in this video
because eventually this application code
will call itself right otherwise we need
to return
the left sum plus the Y sum plus the
loser value right but here we need to
check
if
air sum plus us as if the sum of a left
3 plus the sum of the right tree equal
the answer is defined here answer equals
zero and if we want to increment this
answer we put a number right now to q1
okay and then we turn
answer
that's a search root
okay so basically just there for such
we're just adding this check and that's
it okay so this function without this
bit
it's just calculating the summer we want
to calculate the sum of this entire tree
we need to know three things
the value of this note which is 10 we
can get it and the sum of that tree the
sum of the right tree which can be done
recursively right because the deficits
recursively
okay
and then return the sum of the left tree
plus the sum of the right tree plus the
null itself okay
yes and I'll just have to add this okay
if the sum of the left tree plus the sum
of the right tree six plus four
if it's equals to 10
if it's equal to 10 then
we increment the answer that's it that's
an easy question okay
this is kind of like a photo of the
photo up but here this is top this is
button from the leaf when we visit the
leaf node
When I visit the leaf now the sum of it
is two and then here sum of these two
plus one plus three okay and then we go
in this because
the time complexity is o n because each
note is visited only once okay make
sense the space complexity is all
usually for the recursion definitions oh
H is the height of the final Tree in a
worst case h equals n can you tell me
why in which case h equals equals n
roughly equals to n in wordscape the
final three it could be just degraded
into a single line or you know it
doesn't have to be a single line
right as long as each node has only one
kid right it could be zigzag right
height is n right am I right
that makes sense yeah all this right
okay okay so what have you learned today
[Music]
the problem is we figure we trying to
have uh but how much noise have the sum
of the descendants to the parents yeah
to the parents and what the Agron are we
using we're using this precaution to
find out the left right and the root
and then when we never left
you can see if they're adult and and
then we can just add one yeah otherwise
we won't do the check this is actually
the same as a similar idea to counting
the average right checking which you
know is the average of each entire
subtree we're using recursion deficit
and we can also incrementally using the
iterated deficit okay which I'm going to
tell you know next lesson properly okay
it's trivial to implement a deaf as such
Fusion recursion looks so easy right I
just call itself left and right and do
this like recursion is very easy to to
understand and we usually use the
deficit to illustrate the the idea we
can implement this using the iterated
deficit iterative fashion okay can we
use the prefer search to solve this I'm
not quite sure maybe it's not very easy
to do this in first message okay but
defenses is the way to go because we are
calling this supporter up right when we
call it location
we go to the leaf node at the leaf notes
we know
right at the leaf nodes
here too
and then you close it left and right
right left and right which is zero two
so that if now the sum of this now
is The Descendant is zero but itself is
two right so and it goes the other way
around to uh from about half okay
definitely search calling the trees left
and right recursively people as we can
right and then we will reach the least
notes we go back okay that's the idea of
the depth search okay and then that's as
you as you know we have different
traversal order we order in all the pose
or the reverse pose or the reversing
order okay just a quick one
one two three four five six seven okay
and then here eight what's the prefer
search order for this binary tree one
two three four five six seven eight yeah
we use a q yeah what's the the first
search bar is last note
left no right no so this is in order
which is the left three first note and
right
left three first two two seven left
three first so okay so left three is
four
that looks like a seven four five six
and right
two five eight one three six seven
no look at left no one one no no no no
no no no two two
four sorry four eight four okay four two
five four two
A5
1 6 3 7. okay and then if we want to
visit the note left off so that's the
note that now this is pre-order so it's
one two four five eight three six seven
yeah you'll get it yeah that's so much
easier than Eleanor yeah this is
miniature okay I want to fit to the left
three first and then now and the right
trick so left three of one is this big I
want to visit this tree and then again
for this tree I want to beat it this bit
right so it's four and then two and then
this is the right video I want to visit
the a the last three first so for each
subtree we always go for the left tree
and then the no and the right to record
it it's a recursion it's a recursive
manner okay so the final three trees
those kind of thing is recursive and the
answer we can use an application right
by default okay so it's very good okay
that's it for today bye-bye