[Music]
yeah two arrays of integers and we want
to find the smallest the minimum common
value so put it otherwise uh we want to
find the the smallest value if it is
that appearing imposed arrays yeah in
this case Zero okay
what's your source and if we can find
such numbers minus one
minus one yes
if we can't find any return minus one
okay
foreign
any idea
um so we thought both of them and then
just walk along good job thought right
okay so I didn't tell you it started
okay so we started okay but if it's
salty we don't need to sort it so how do
we work through it these two are already
salty right let's check how do it works
too
and if like so that so the B one is
smaller so we just moved to the right
now the A1 is smaller than the B one so
we move the right it's still smaller and
uh which one is here yeah and still
okay
if I put one Whatever
B yeah let me see if I one moves to two
two moves to a hundred five means see a
thousand and and then and then a hundred
and you see nothing and that one is
nothing with the 10 by this one that's a
good job okay that's very good we are
given to sort it already let's say we
give it to solve it array already okay
so if we want to solve them if this is
uh the length is n then the time from X
is our login right okay so if we are
given already two sorted array and if
the then is n the length is M what's the
time complexity how many steps maximum
together two pointers yeah I know what's
the time
and and what should I put here
plus yes because at most you are working
M plus M right okay so this is the
temperature if the arrays are not sorted
we can use the set right so we just
convert it to set so set
a by converting these to set and set b n
right intersection right look remember
this is a a
this is B this is a this is B A and B is
here right the common part and then we
need to sort it right a common part we
sorted sort it then we converted the
list and then return the first one if we
didn't say anyway if less any if not we
determine minus one so we set a answer B
if N is a b we put it as C C equals n c
b and then if C we sort it and return
the first one the term complexity for
this one is look if they are n
elements M elements right and if they uh
pulls the same right if both arrays are
the same so n let's say n the times of x
t is O and Logan
okay if a and b are exactly the same so
the intersection is itself right and
then we need to solve it it's our login
and then get the first one if there's
any this is the case that when the two
arrays are not sorted first solution is
oh and now can I when
login which is using the set a space
complexity so well the second approach
is O uh o n plus n and the space
complexity is 101 right because we don't
use any other space before we go into
the third approach let's just quickly
implement the second approach which is
the two pointer the length of a equals
the length of a the length of b equals
the length of B and then the left equals
right equals zero f 2.0 left and right
wire
less smaller than air a and
Y is smaller than a of B right when we
haven't reached the n
is a air equals equal equal p r then we
return
Al right it's the same with the calories
otherwise L if if
this is as if if a air smaller than PR
[Music]
um
air plus equal one yes
and then if we don't find anything after
the loop when we reach the end the
conditions do not meet at any moment we
return minus one here right
let me take minus okay so this is the
two points I think the third approach is
that look because two arrays are already
sorted we combine the research right so
we go through this each number minus
three now we finally search this number
in this sorted array right four I in a
and we go through each number and then
you tell me the terminal and then we
need to bicep right five set left
remember the bicep left and bison right
the bind research yeah okay so look
twice enough
Zillow one two two three
then if we fight that look every time I
talk about bison left I will talk about
this example if I said left which array
is a okay a let's find two
five two then you will return this
position but if a pi said right A2 you
will return this position okay this is
the difference so it basically depends
that this position where to put the
new too you could still sort it right
it's a level right so we we find it if
the element is not in the array
then it retains the partition where we
can put that element in right so how do
we use the python left to check if the
element is in a sorted array we can do
this right x equals bicep
left percent
e-i-s-e-t
left
P we want to find element I in Array 30
B right and if x is smaller than the
length of B and also we come back to
check if b x equal equal I right look
this is to check if we found the element
I in the array B like if it is then we
turn
I otherwise only 10 minus one so we are
going through the numbers in Array a and
we check if the numbers can be found in
the second array and like because the
second array is sorted right so we can
use the binary search if it's not sorted
in the worst case is how do we check it
we just go through the first number
second number third number right and the
time complexity for that one is wrong oh
n times n right the proof of o n times M
okay this is another approach 11 times
o n times n go into the first number
already in the first moment check if the
second array has six but the thing is
that this m this second array is sorted
so we can use the binary search the
linear search linear search is om and
when we binary search is all log M right
we print out the complexity of Logan so
the temperature is before this one is
all n Times log and move right so
because this is a sorted array so how do
we find such element in the solid array
we use the bicep Left Right bicep left
so remember the numbers you think zero
to 100 cut in a minute 50 cut in a meter
25 all right twelve six
okay
we find the inside position and if it's
uh in within the
if it's a wish in the range right
because it possibly will be here right
now the temperature will be here we want
it to be the instant Position will be
here right here and also if in the
position the value that we come back to
check if the value equals I then it
means that the number in Array right so
look at it two it retains this position
then we come back to the chair a 2
equals 2 then okay so we have two here
how about if we want to find 2.5 2.5 you
will return the position here right here
but when we come back to check it there
is no 2.5 in this array so if it's not
there right makes sense okay so look
there are two arrays we can go through
the second array finally search it in
the first survey which one is better two
arrays I didn't say it's the same lens
right
okay these approach I was just saying
finally we go through the numbers in the
first array find the research the second
one or we can go through the arrays in
the second one final research is the
number you know first one which one is
better I mean so basically look this is
a this is a the first approach is go to
the numbers in the first one and check
if the number appears from there and I
the second approach is that I go through
that number in the second one and check
if the numbers appear in the first one
using the binary search if it's a proof
of o n times m equals o m times n right
because n times m equals n times n right
this is simple right but with the final
search it's different right binary
surgery is what n Times log m
and N Times log n right
okay so which one is better said that
that day it doesn't you can't it does
not always like the same size yeah so we
need to check if n is so big and bigger
than ammo right if n is this is this is
big
we want to make it binary search right
all right if N is a million if N is a
million a million okay so it it's better
I put it locked in right because look
remember the lock-end thing is this this
right so it brings out that complexity
so if you want to put an end and it's so
big so you might want to consider this
one pretty clear to bring down the
complexities right so when n is bigger
than M we choose the second one when n
is smaller than m is bigger then we
choose the first one make sense
does it make sense yes yeah
okay
first of all prove us as actually the
proof of n times MF we go through each
number and then we just prove us to
check if it appears on the second one
the second approach
using the headset right we're using a
headset so we turn this a into a
secondary speed into the set we use the
intersection n right and then when we
have the intersection we still have to
sort it in the worst case A and B is the
same that all the elements are the same
so we convert it to the set is O times n
plus and we need to do the Sorting right
so the Sorting is our login right okay
and let's face complexity obviously okay
the second the third approach every by
the way very well done is two points I
think this is actually quite similar and
merging merging to sorted language
remember we merge it right to array two
arrays zero two four six ten another way
one three five seven nine yeah how do we
merge it bye 2.9 the same idea right
smaller
smaller use this one move it smaller
move this one use it okay this is
actually exactly the same exact letter
we are looking for the common uh element
instead of merging them together and the
time table let's say om plus M let's
make on let's say oh one right and the
fourth approach is a binary search so
because
both are very assaulted we can go to one
array and then find research in another
way so the time convex is this one all n
times o and which one is better look at
least one big better than or n plus m
which is which one is better o n Times
log M or om plus n
um which one is bigger which one is
smaller okay I'm saying oh n plus n
or n Times log m
which one is smaller if N is a minion
then there is going through two million
times and here is a minion
a million times
again this is bigger than two right so
back this is better tuning your skin is
better than this one okay
yeah because luck Armenia is obviously
bigger than two
okay and then this is just two okay so
everything your approach is the optimum
it's the the best okay because you just
just tuning your skin and this one the
problem of this one is that you have to
go through each number and then for each
number you have to find a research in
the second array in the other way so it
takes more time am I right yeah yeah the
problem we want to solve is we have two
arrays with the numbers in them and we
want to find the the nice uh smallest
number that appears in both of them
if if it's if there isn't any we return
minus one
mm-hmm
so one approach is you before you one
approach is uh you scan um
you do two point I think uh one that one
and a one and B
or or whatever you can call it right
left and and so and so if one is smaller
smaller than the other then we just move
it and and then if one of them is bigger
than the other we need we just move the
smaller one and and then it it it it
goes on until until you reach the end or
or you find a matching pair yeah well
done good job
yeah two pointer okay and the proof of
the obviously I'm buying a search okay
okay and then using a set intersection
of two sets okay bye-bye bye