hello hello hello mr eric mr ryan
hi mr
t mr junior
welcome okay so how about today i give
you a very
big list and let's say
these these the list is consists of
zeros yes
and once but once it becomes one
and then you'll be all ones okay yeah so
you'll be separate
between zero and once but the thing is
you don't know
you don't know so this is the first
index one okay let's say one okay and
this is
n you know the size is one and n all
right
yeah and then you can have a function to
call it like
check checklist
check if given an integer a then if
it's you will return the value of zero
and one okay given
if you check locally check one
is zero okay okay
check two three four five five
is one okay so your task is to use this
check function
to find first first
one i understand yeah so in this
three four case yeah yeah because this
is the first
time it becomes one okay
i don't want you to give me the four
because it's zero i don't want you to
give me six because
it's the second one i want you to give
me five
any idea how do i so we just draw a list
and then check which
number define let's say
uh first first
first bet okay bad breath
bad and now let's call it m okay
we are given this n right yeah
yeah okay so now normally what would you
do
normally what would you do i
just count it from one
so you just say okay if this is one if
this is one
this is one if this is one if this is
one return yeah
yeah yeah so how would you do that four
i in range
one m plus one okay you know what is n
plus one
well you go one each time n plus one
means the the top the test
the final version final thing we want to
check is x right
it's always minus one of this number and
now what do we do
if check
check what if we check a
there's no a come on i i yeah we're
what's the time capacity i went i won
oh and yes i went because
worst case look we're talking about
another two in the worst case and
and not only the last last uh the first
bet that would be the last one yeah then
you'll need to check it you need to
check how many times
10 times right because lower zero can we
do something better
can we do something better this is all
this is too slow if you
plot this this is
n right the time time is like that right
yeah this is because n is a minion and
you need to check
in the worst case a million times which
is too slow
yeah can we do can we use the binary
section
exercise can we use the final research
sorry stretching exercise
can we use the final research
yes look and
so this is the left first of all we have
a left wing on the right
okay now what's the meter meter is
somewhere here yeah
somewhere so if the meter
is zero what does it mean in the check
meter is zero
what does it mean so where should i go
to look
if check middle is zero yes
what's the answer what where is the
answer is it in the left part or in the
right part
if it's zero check meter is zero the
answer is in
left and right
if it is yellow of course it's in the
right half right because it's
yellow yeah so what is if
the answer is one where's the answer
because we are not sure if it's the
first first one right
because all others will be be the
ones yeah
so when when check meter is one
then what we do
we do this uh right will become
minus one right if it's the second meter
is zero so it's
in the right in the right hand side
right so left will become one
become right me the plus one okay come
on
no just guessing okay okay let's do this
coding
here right define first bet
okay
[Music]
y left smaller or equals right
meat equals one
[Music]
mid equals left left black
left times right divided by two left
plus y
divided by two okay yeah yeah
i like how if now here if you tell me
okay if check
mid is one
what do i do here what should i do here
and return return one
okay there's three things you need to
feel it
yeah here and here
if the middle is one so which lines are
going to be
in the left left hand side so what
then we need to set the right part
to the middle minus one right yeah
this is okay i know what's here if it's
in the right hand side if
this is yellow equals
is not no longer smaller than right so
where is the answer
return that right yeah okay okay so
that's it
[Music]
can you see it please i need to i mean
we don't need a chance i know i just i
just need to
okay yeah
yes okay
so this is this seems very clear let me
check the video just make sure
everything is all right
don't check if you're shaking i can see
the screen is shaking which is
very blurry so we don't we don't want
that right yeah we're going to just sit
quietly
and then let's do the coating okay let's
do this one first bed
fat white bad apple okay let's say bad
apple
bad apple why is it called bad
because a bad boy i don't know let's
so look if let's do this first version
okay
let's do a check function right
checklist
uh let's do this let's define your phone
what what happened i didn't turn it off
you are doing this that's why it's
turning off
come on can you be good boy
sorry about that just give me a second
to
put it on okay
that was unbelievable
i know please communicate every time
you're here
everything's strange happening yeah okay
luckily we are back
yeah okay good still good still good
yeah still good let me check anyone can
see me
no no no uh i can
okay now it's better now it's better
define check okay then given
okay and then look then we return
apples and okay uh
actually it will be n minus one because
we the index starts on zero and then we
are given
from i yeah okay so let's see
okay so let's see can you
yes please can you not find
bet one version one okay why is it bad
yeah i don't know whatever you want
let's do it
so let's for i in range
one let's see how many how many of these
two
fours two four
a 10 right so let's do it 10
part 11 oh yeah
and then if check
i equals one
it means to check okay it's not a sign
one way you want to check is double
equal okay
let's see find the bad one
so it should give me one one two three
four five six
right i i hope you will give me a
six yes
and then let's do this the final version
back two okay
divide five back two
so left right equals one
and then the the the upper bound is ten
right because there are ten elements in
there
yeah two four six and ten when you think
bad
[Music]
bad okay look at me
equals
[Music]
yeah if check mid
is one so where is the answer
left hand side
okay left yeah left so then what
um no
no left it's in the left hand side so
we need to change the left or right
boundary
uh right right father equals one
see
i see you should you should give me
[Music]
please give me one twelve oh no six six
we're done yeah then next one must be
six or six
yeah so do you see it this is the
program right
what's the complexity of the second
version find
back two i won
[Music]
and again no i won
you're just guessing why is r1 obviously
it's not a wall
[Music]
well every time you cut into half one is
finally searched when we talk about
binary research
the complexity is what left plus white
we cut into a half uh
[Music]
we cut into half every time we cut into
half like
this yeah every time we divided
no come on come on there's no
there's only one n there's no left or
right
left or right and
no no one is the first one divided by
two
when we cut into half look remember if
there are ten
eight elements we needed three times to
search it because
eight divided by two is four four
divided by two is two
so it's at most three times oh what
remember the power function power
function is the same complexity as the
power function a to the power of b
remember remember we're talking about
multiply the exponential timing
is a hundred times but we need only
needs to times it
four or five times remember
it's fast much faster come on give me
binary when we talk about binary
research we talk about the complexity
usually it's in o
log n come on how high is it look do you
understand now
yeah don't make a guess don't make
okay good job today turn on the lights
and then you can do a little bit dancing