hello hello
okay so let's take a look at this what's
this a tree
a binary tree
yeah
yeah yeah
okay so this is the final trees anything
special about this final tree they have
duplicate numbers
okay and
oh I'm sorry actually
what's uh so special about anything yeah
when mirrored it's the same mirror okay
so another one what do we mean right
so this is a sensor is also sit
symmetrical then it's not symmetrical
it's not symmetrical because that tree
needs to be upstairs
why is it not symmetrical this is Mexico
no it's not
these socks have to be exactly the same
you need to flip the numbers around you
need to clean it so it's exactly so
which food is North symmetrical a little
bit huh a little bit that's symmetrical
it's symmetrical right nine four four
three three two two that's the
definition of symmetrical no it's not
symmetrical is something that is the
same look this is dirty that's not that
one needs to be like this and like
something like that okay
okay
forget about the shapes we are talking
just the values and that's it okay so
this is symmetrical okay in early days
we talk about how to check this uh a
tree if it's symmetrical using the
cushion remember yeah and today we're
going to implement it using the just
iterated approach okay yeah we Define
check F function A and B right A and B
are two two trees two trees okay so if a
is now
and
p is none okay we want to compare if
these two trees A and B are symmetrical
right so we're given at the beginning
we're given these two trees we want to
check this is actually a hyper function
to check if a and b are symmetrical A3
and B3 are symmetrical okay so it
requires two parameters but how how do
we apply this function to to the finger
finger tree so we are passing these
three twice okay so that's what it means
okay so A and B if a is now B is none
both are empty then we'll return true
right we turn two mt3 is the same
symmetrical
a is now
or B is num right
then we do 10
fast and all right at this point
because those trees are now is check
here both are empty then we return true
if one of them is empty we return first
obviously and E3 and something is is not
symmetrical
then we have to check right now we can
just return return
value
it has to be equal to Beta value right
so look at the value needs to be equals
to be the value all right
I have another identical tree
this value needs to be the same as this
value right so we turn a the value
equals beta value and
f a DOT left we're looking for B to the
right right here
and
f a DOT y
B dot left okay so we swap we swap so
how do we interpret this how to
interpret this so f a DOT left a DOT
left is this bit and B dot right
be the right is this
right so lead speed and this speed needs
to be symmetrical and then this speed
and then this speed needs to be
symmetrical right this makes sense
okay look at this
this is a this is p okay
okay so we need to call this recursive
function if a is not B is now both trees
are empty then obviously it's a
symmetrical right if one number line is
empty
if one dollar is empty we'll return for
us right otherwise we want to check if
these two trees are symmetrical
basically these three we want to check
these three is the Mexican so we
duplicate this right so in a the value
needs to be equals to Beta value also
the eight on left is this bit needs to
be symmetrical to this speed right B dot
right right look two three four two four
three needs to be symmetric a DOT rise
this bit needs to be symmetrical to be
the left okay this is what it is and
then you just need 10.
that's the way it is
okay so look at this one
if we don't swap around what happened if
look I'm saying that if we swap those
eight or left Beetle right eight or
right Peter left right this is to check
if the tree is symmetrical but if I
don't swap around then what does it do
one question for you if I'm just say
pretend
what does it do
if I change it to
f a DOT left
be the left
and f a DOT right so what does it do so
left and the right three would be would
be the same exactly that's true if I'm
changing to eight dollars we're just
checking it yeah the two trees are the
same right yeah okay okay so that's very
good actually we talk about that when we
talk about uh recursion to check if two
trees are identical we use the iterative
right and it's the same so I can
Implement that using the iterative and a
little bit okay
uh so let me
let me erase this pic
so Define f a b let's compare if those
trees are identical right so we use a q
or stack right we use a cube V Cube
we can perform this using data search
preferences right level by level
one two three and then we want to check
if two threes are the same we just just
perform this
both level by level okay BQ I like at
the beginning we'll push your topper A
and B
right and then wire Q
Wireless anime in the queue we get it a
a b b equals Q dot per left okay we're
taking out from the left hand side we're
taking out the elements then
I was I was almost using this to erase
it okay I learned right so we just put
this put this here right come here if AI
actually we need to change the a right
so uh so if a a is nine and PB is none a
a is none
and PP is now
we need to continue right if we need to
continue
instead of return right this is
recursion with returning but but for the
perfect stepper search we need to
continue to checking the next right so
air if
a a is none what's added else if oh yes
Phoebe is not and then we can false
right because if one of the notes is
empty one of node is not then it's not a
identical tree right
as as what do we do at least as
now we need to check and actually we ask
L if okay we still have to have to check
if a a down value is not equal to P beta
value
then we'll return first right we found
one of the nodes do not match each other
if this here is one here is two it's not
the same
then as
we need to push it back to the q i q dot
a pen
okay okay I'm gonna either left
speed down left
killed a pen a Double Y
come on you don't like so if you want to
make it make it chicken if the tree is
symmetrical which line of code we need
to check this is just iterated this is
the iterative version of the left hand
side right actually where something
needs to be changed it to match exactly
the same so which line of curve yeah so
a to left B so right and a DOT right B
to left left okay so look well done
either left pizza left that's checking
if the trees are the same yeah we have
to check the left tree that's the same
right trees are the same right this is
to check if two trees are set to check
if to check if a tree is a symmetrical
we just have to check if the left tree
is symmetrical to the if the right way
and the right tree is the next level to
the left chain that's the symmetrical
right yeah yeah okay so this is the
iterative look we are using the DQ here
can we change it to stack yeah can we
change us there
yes because the order of checking
accounts do not matter right here this
is 2 3 right so one two three four five
six seven right we want to check if two
trees are the same
all right two tricks I understand
then order of checking each note no
matter right does it make sense yeah I
can check this I can check level by
level look I can check level by level
so this is the iterative and the
question will be visible the two
problems so one is the chicken if two
trees are the same
if we check uh the tree is symmetrical
right symmetrical so when we talk about
chicken the tree symmetrical we also
talk about an animal cell one two
two
three four four
five I'll fall asleep so we also talk
about how do we do it
this is a tree right we inverted
we talk about that inverting the tree
so you become this
right this is original tree and then we
invert inverted
right we got these three and we just
have to check this tree if it's the same
as this one is the same it's symmetrical
right this is ideal right this is how do
we invert the tree are you using the
recursion as well left equals uh inverse
through the left right right
equals invert do the right and I will
just say low down left equals right
right the left tree will assign it to
the right I know that right equals left
and then return Loop
and then if if
not
if what if not load then we'll just
return right yes yes
so
do don't laugh
I want to email this tree so left needs
to be invert version of the right tree
and the right will be invert version and
we keep recursively doing that okay this
is actually the interview question of
Google okay yeah just a few lines of
confusing recursion okay okay and yeah
so you see how we do it right so it's
quite similar using recursion and using
the iterator we can use a skill or stay
it doesn't matter okay stack we're just
using a list to do it and it's the same
okay so what have you learned today
silks
about a binary submit to cool we wanted
to find out if a tree if a binary tree
is symmetrical so how can we do it we
can use recording or we can use the
integrative yeah we talk about these a
long long time ago in the early days
maybe in in 63 64 days
talks about uh you should you should see
day 40. okay foreign
[Music]
as long as each kid has only one uh one
uh one kid the number of notes equals
the height okay
yeah okay okay that's it for today bye
bye bye bye