okay so we're given the integer I want
to transform that to something on the
right so basically we extract each digit
and you see five two three five minus
two plus three equals six three two one
zero three minus two plus one minus zero
one just one one two three one minus two
plus three equals two it doesn't have to
be minus plus
that's right yes so the leftmost we call
it the most uh significant digit okay
most significant digit on the left right
because this is the most significant at
least one is this one on the right hand
side this is one right these are the
least significant digits
okay so we start with most significant
digit always with plus one and the next
and the next digit is -1 and the next
digit is plus one again so alternative
sine digit okay so we just want to know
the sum what's your thoughts about it
are you given the number on the left
yeah I will not get this number on the
right you only have like one choice like
minus plus minus plus yeah one choice
yes yeah yeah and so you're giving given
the one the number on the left and
you're trying to give the number on the
right that's right yes okay I feel
confess it and then so what's your sauce
okay
I think we're done
so it's easy
easy it's simulation it's basically
doing what you're told right so you're
basically
okay
how do we extract each digit so you
start with the first first number which
you said is the most significant digit
and then for every two numbers every two
numbers leave every two digits you
subtract that digit okay and then for
others we add it yeah okay okay so my
question was more like how do you get
the five how do you get the two how do
you get the three and then there are two
ways right you can start from the left
to the right or you can start from right
to the left right which one is better
from the left to the right I think it's
tiver it depends on what or or what the
number is like moderate I think yes but
I'm saying that okay so five two three
you start from the left to the right or
you start from the right to the left
that's what I'm saying left you right
left to the right end
he says we're left I think it I think
left to right is how you do it because
English you like read it like that way
but and also you said it's the most
significant yeah yeah
right yeah okay so that's what I want to
know yeah because five two three yeah
always start with the positive right so
you know intuitively yeah five two three
we start from the left to the right
there are only two choice if it's even
number of digits or if it's the odd
number of these right you don't know
which one is it
all right so you can still do it from
left to the right as long as we come
release into
string
so with the string then I can cut each
digit we can also do it from right to
the left but the problem with the right
to the left is that you don't know which
one you know if you five two three these
three this is one this is plus one and
this is past right but if it's five two
three four this will be minus right plus
minus
plus minus MRI if you start from the
right to the left but you're not sure
which one is the least significant digit
right but why do we need to care about
starting from right to the left because
it's easy to do the math modulus right
look five two three four how do we get
the four
models by 10. multiply 10 and then
divided by 10. how do we get a three
modules by ten
divided by 10 modules by 10 divided by
10. let's do this uh the first approach
using the converting to the string as
equal if the number is uh defined okay f
n okay and then this needs to return
integer Type S equals Str we convert it
to a string answer equals elevation zero
sine
plus one minus one right so at the
beginning is plus one yeah
for I in s
answer
plus equal and the plus equal I I this
is the string we cover T2 integer
converted to integer yeah times
sign
okay yeah I learned I need to make plus
one two minus one how do I neglect The
Sign Plus make it minus if it's minus I
want to make a plus how do I do this
sign equals what
uh equals minus minus sign
oh sign
equals sine times equal minus one one
times minus one
is minus one and minus one times minus
one is one and then we turn
and look if the number n has n digit and
digit the time complexity we're going
through each one so o n
phase complexity we need to convert it
to a string and this is O and Y if n is
the number of digits okay number of
digits
yeah so n is the number of digits then
it's block 10 face the N right look
because block one two three four how
many digits four digits so one two three
four is the inner scale of log ten one
two three four okay
n is the number of digits and log 10
base 10. block 10 100 what's this number
10 to the what power equals a hundred
two two not ten a hundred equals two
okay mixes okay the other way we're
going through the number from the right
to the left okay okay so that's a trick
to do this
that's a trick with tourists okay
previously I was talking about that we
are not sure that this significant digit
if it's the plus or minus right yeah
yeah yeah okay how about let's try with
minus one one two three four okay yeah
minus four plus three minus two plus one
and if I add another digit minus five
plus four minus three plus two minus one
minus one plus one minus one plus one so
plus one and the last one minus one plus
one minus one plus one minus one this is
one two three four yeah the answer
should be one minus two plus three minus
four this is equals to minus two okay
this is the answer this is correct and
the sign is plus one one minus two okay
I'm confused
one minus two plus three two two and
five one two three four five seven seven
minus one seven minus two this is seven
why is it seven hundred
this is one this is one one so this is
three okay I know what we get from here
seven minus one minus one minus three
plus two minus one that's minus four
minus two minus three okay
okay so look if we are always starting
with the minus one on the least
significant digit for the odd number of
digit number
we need to we need to negate this right
so but it's okay because at the end the
sign is minus one we just need to fix
the Sun by times the sun okay does it
make sense yeah
yeah okay let me repeat okay this is a
little bit tricky tricky let's have a
little strategy okay let's start with
minus one from the right to the left so
this equals to minus two plus one
okay
this is minus one if we have another
value with the three digit one two three
this is minus three plus two minus one
this is minus two
okay
but the answer for this one should be
one minus two plus three this would be
two all right but we get minus two
but that's okay
we want to change the minus two to two
we need just need to fix the sign by
times the other side sine look
minus one plus one minus one times sun
when you turn this okay and how about
this one minus one
plus one when you still need to fix the
Sun but it's okay because minus one
times one equals one so we times percent
okay
so the strategy is that we start from
the least significant digit from right
to the left and we keep tracking of the
sun sun star is minus one plus one minus
one plus one and at the end we just have
to fix the sign by multiplying the
answer to the side does it make sense
we can do this uh look from right to the
left okay F and N is a digit it needs to
return the integer I answer equals zero
so at the beginning we set it one but we
immediately times it to minus one wire
and it's bigger than zero answer plus
equal
sign okay I need to change the sign sine
equals minus sign right
at the beginning is one and we are
starting from right to the left so you
immediately become minus one okay
sign
times N I want to get this n number one
two three I want to get this three how
do we get it us more do you understand
and then we need to get rid of sweet how
do we get rid of it
divided by 10 and then okay now we get
this now this answer we need to
return
answer times sine right okay this is the
last step to fix the sign okay this is
from right to the left yeah
time complexity
oh
and space come back to be first
uh one a one okay or one because there's
no arrays you know we're given n we just
have a few variables or one the time
till next day it's hard
at least not so what are we doing with
this end look at one two three four five
what's and look we just get rid of this
video get rid of this did you get rid of
this the end digit right so it's o n is
it simple
but you need to tell me what's the end
if we did and usually itself is well one
when you say oh one you don't need to
say and because there's no letter but
when you say o n you need to tell me
what n is n could be anything
n is n okay and N is the number of
digits in decimal format of of this
number for example one two three four
and N is four
because what are we doing here is
get the least significant digit get rid
of it you don't need to explain because
they all you need to know is o n
now use o n when you say o n it's just
50 percent when I ask you what's the
time complexity you say o n but I don't
know what n is you need to tell me what
n is n is the number of Digit I think
you know what n is because you written
no I could be anything okay okay
this is oh and it's the number of days
required okay so he said it is the
number of digits yes
divided by 10 okay
or you don't convert it to string this
is all mathematics right all numbers all
numbers numbers numbers
number we get the digit by modulus so
it's all numbers the thing here is we
need to multiply the sign as I said this
is a tricky way from right to the left
but from the left to the right we can
convert it to a string and get each
digit right and then we convert it to a
string and then we need to convert it
back using the in in I block two is
usually for binary 15. in binary is one
one one right you know that right and if
we want to go through the digit in
binary format is one one one and the
time conversation usually in this case
is
locked
n and log base 2 and N is the number is
15. log base n now this four in binary
one one one okay every time we get one
we shift it make sense yeah yeah what
have you learned today numbers and we're
doing some stuff sounds
plus minus plus minus
antique on all the digits and and then
we're getting the sound we're done and
then how can we do it uh usually how
many ways we learned how to do it today
what are those uh from left to right and
right to it yeah and which one you think
is better that's right
it's easy to implement but which one is
more efficient in terms of space
why because
complexity for the left to the right
oh
oh we need to convert it to a string so
our end what's the space n is the number
of digits okay what's the space
complexity for right to the left one so
which one is better
right left because the one is better
than om right both uh time complexity is
o n the L is the number of digits in the
in the taximal format of n okay let's
see for today bye-bye goodbye hello bye
bye
foreign