bye-bye hello Mr Mr right now right yeah
okay
okay so we're given an array of integer
and the size of the array is Power of
Two
one minus 1 0 4 2 3 8.
there are eight numbers a is power of
two okay so why do we need the power two
I'll tell you
so we want to visualize it as like the
leaves of the trees you know in another
tree span actually here so look these
two and these two these two and this two
these children need to release to him
okay we group
consecutive two numbers right and I want
to get this this is in the magic I want
to get the mean here we want to get the
maximum here we have to get the mean
here we want to get a maximum here
so the minimum of two one is one one
maximum zero
four
I mean oh yeah two two eight okay so how
many numbers we eliminated half of it
right so we have four okay so now we can
clue two
total number of numbers at the beginning
is an odd number
part of two the size of the array yeah
but what they're the same number the
same numbers and then return any of it
so what do you mean the odd number so
oh yeah
boy for you like you have men yeah if
the if the first number two yeah with
the one okay so you say one one the
minimum of one and one is one the
maximum of one and one is one
okay the larger one right even they are
equal you can still get the minimum of
the maximum all right yes okay so now
look we have reduce
half size with this
oh yeah yeah so we did use half of it
and then we continue this process the
mean always start with the mean the left
Mouse is
yellow Max
hey okay and then get them in which is
zero once we have only one number we'll
return this number which is together
okay any questions so far for this
problem what's the first power of two
power of two what number is pi of two
one one is power of two which is two to
the power zero two two to the power one
four two to the power of two a yeah this
goes on where okay
what if you have one number one number
yeah so we just return it this is the
terminal cases okay
okay
good point yeah it doesn't matter why
because the cutting the minimum and the
maximum of two number it doesn't have to
be integer but yeah too far
simplistically we just use the integers
right to sum up we're given this uh
array which is size 12 and we want to
continue this process group each two
numbers and then from that to the right
mean Max mean Max this is a three right
this is the root
okay so this is the loot zero
and then
yeah yeah zero eight right and then one
zero
and then you see this is a tree actually
we are given the leaves if the height is
H the notes is 2 to the power of H minus
one n equals that right this is a
complete final three right I think it's
perfect perfect financially okay I
forgot the details so that's good
completed is that balance oh your
balance is the other story perfect
complete and full okay
okay balances is the any trees the left
and the right and the data type data
height is smaller or equal than one okay
so this is the balance tree right
but this is not
right this is not I mean we're given
this what's your Source about this
I think
[Music]
I think I think it's it's kind of like
the other day it's kind of like math you
you you do the same thing but maybe
you're just presenting it differently
forwards backwards video just do math
good job yeah because this is kind of
thing that you do what it says right
you're told what to do you just follow
it if the steps this is just called
simulation right so that's good this is
kind of implementation uh problem so we
just Implement what we are told it's
similar like yesterday yeah do you still
remember what are we talking about
yesterday what have we talked about
yesterday
we were talking about numbers
foreign
what's the problem we have to talk about
yesterday I think
I think thank you for reminding me yeah
okay so this is kind of thing simulation
okay we can use the recursion right so
if the array has only one number then we
just return it right otherwise we reduce
it to half but defined F array okay and
equal we get the size
if n equal equal one if there is only
one number in Array we return the first
element otherwise look the new array
right let's say new array equals that so
we do this for
I in range we start from the zero up to
n with step two right every time we step
two the first one is minimum the next
one is maximum right array dot a pen
I
a uh uh I plus one right now look at
this G
at the beginning g equals minimum right
at the beginning it's minimal the
leftmost the left Mouse is minimum mean
the next one is Max the next one is mean
so what do we call this mess mean Max
mean Max mean Max mean mix so now it's
mean now I need to change it to Max so I
can say g equals Max this is a function
I assign it to a variable equals max if
current g equals
the next one has to be Max otherwise is
mean right so this is actually the same
as if G equal Max as D equals mean okay
and then
recursion what are we doing here this is
terminal cases
but if array has only one element we
return we know how to solve it right if
it only has one element we written is
the first element yeah otherwise I'm
just doing this group two numbers
I need two numbers yeah so look a is the
half of the array right so this one this
one this one this one I put all these
numbers into a
okay into a and then this Gene at the
beginning is mean and after iteration
you become Max so mean Max mean Max
right so this is mean this is Max mean
Max this is G Okay g will be mean Max
mean Max and after I got the a
the size of the half of the array right
can anybody explain to me what's this
what's this bit
a is the half of it so why do we need to
call the F function again why do we need
to call it as a hundred again because
you don't same thing same thing with the
hover size until it reaches one animal
right this indication right calling
recursion to solve a smaller size
opponent but we have to define the base
cases all right good job so this is
using the recursion the time complexity
and space from next thing okay let's
face complexity obviously we need to use
the a new array to store the new element
half size element again right the time
complexity how many steps if layer and
element how many steps to reduce to one
there are eight eight elements how many
steps to reduce to one element three
yeah
okay
128 how many steps to reduce to one
six okay so is it six no
one two three four five six yeah you're
all right so yeah yeah yeah so it's lock
phase two no no I'm not correct if eight
two one is three then I'm not correct ah
okay okay because four eight you count
for one yeah not base two n right yeah
this is the log two function everything
reduce
four two one and you were two people of
32 16 8 4 2
4 2. okay and that's six but but you
didn't count from one so so it must be
seven yeah good points uh details okay
that's good we're just changing mean Max
mean Max and we can use another function
called cycle what's cycle mean from
ether tools you go on the bike and cycle
what does this one mean circle is like
going over like going in a process that
that leads over again again like recycle
it goes it it recycles to something new
and and then it like recycles and Cycles
the wheels go round and yeah
okay so look at this cycle so we can
change this uh g equals we can say it's
a cycle cycle I mean Max right because
look there are only two elements
basically just like okay I want to mean
and I look at the max right it's a cycle
right okay so this returns an iterator
currently it's mean the next one is Max
and the next one is mean the next one is
Max right instead of doing this I don't
need this anymore a 10 G I can say next
G
okay next to you will give me the next
if it's a mean then the next will be Max
and min max okay so this is the fancy
syntax using the cycle to make the code
clean easy to understand the other way
we can use the Q to do it so we just
turn the numbers into the Q and then
every time we pop two elements we pop
two elements right and then we push it
back to the cube Define f a r r q equals
DQ you turn the array into the Q
and wire
the length of a queue is bigger than
what should I put here zero one
one yeah because if it has more than one
element then we need to pop two elements
at a time right but we need to get the
lens first so now I'm saying there are n
elements in a way so how many times we
need to pop two elements now there are
eight elements yeah yeah I'm saying each
time I pop two I take two so how many
times I need to take four yeah four
times okay so four I in range
the groups the groups that is like that
there's five groups and then you need to
and then you like me and my
no that's not possible because I said
sub Power of Two
yeah three numbers in one okay means
that you can always divide half half
half until you get one right okay a b a
comma b equals
so I take two they are a here right
yeah here so I take two I take two I
take two I take two I take four times or
two and again I the G function here
right so I can say Q dot a pen
a pen G function G function a b i Pop I
use the G function which is mean or Max
and
and push it back to the queue right and
then at the end just return q0 right
okay so this G function the same thing
here G I can do this D cycle thing or I
can use the g equals max if g equals
mean as mean right G cycle thing so I
can just say g equals the only here and
then instead of G I will say next G okay
okay yeah Akil this is the same thing
right and this is basically like this
instead instead we use the cube so this
is the Q right this is a q four four
four four oh so I pop four times I take
two at a time and I do this the mess me
Max and I push it back to the cube so
this is I push it back to the queue yeah
I push it back to the kill here push
back to the Q here push back here and
then there are four right and I again do
these two two at a time until it only
has one element and I return it right
make sense yeah yeah okay so so far
these two approach use additional space
right a queue can we do it in place can
we do it in place for example like we
have array
we have array here
one two three four just these four
numbers can we do it in place
previously these two methods I need to
allocate another array which is the mean
this is One Max is this one this is
another way another two is
okay but instead of allocating already
this is using a curious see you in the
recursion and an additional array we can
save this variable in place
one two three four five six seven eight
okay
so every time I cut in half right after
the first iteration there are only four
left
so look
this one
so one
one two this is one
okay and the second element is three
four
okay look at look at what I did look at
what I did
this is Speaker four this is what
smaller five this is bigger
hey got it do you see this I can
override this I can override
I can overlay okay look one and four
four
one
five and a
eight eight
okay so every time I can override this
variable I need to cut in half this n
equals a at the beginning the second
iteration a equals four and then two by
one because I'm writing the values and I
don't care what happened here but in
order to get these if I'm iterating over
this index one I need to get the element
two times I this is two times I this is
two times I plus one right
okay make sense I just noticed if you
have a numbers sorted the answer is the
smallest number
how can you prove I don't know but it
looks like it right it looks like it
because look because you because you
because you always end up end up having
like women
and the and the first number the
smallest numbers ever beginning and and
that's where the minimum is going
minimum Max minimum Max and it starts at
the minimum so the most minimum goes
down and then the most minimum because
it's always ever start so and it always
starts at minimum so it's always
Obviously good path and then eventually
eventually it's going to go to minimum
and then good job good job excellent
that's a weird uh Discovery yes yes
you're right it won't improve it if it's
increasing this is always uh winning
right it's always winning because the
leftmost is always you know meaning okay
that's very good okay so I can use the
index I can override this variable or is
its index 2 times I plus one and two
times I okay that's the last message and
then think about which one is the best
Define f a r r okay we are overwriting
this uh what's in place
what's the implant in place means that I
don't want to allocate additional array
I just want to change the original array
this is this is an original right you
can change it let's call in place I am
in place
so I'm multiplying the input in place so
I don't need to allocate other places
and equals length ARR
okay wire n is bigger than one
for I in range n over over 2 right
divided by two and then a ah look a r i
I'm changing this variable now I'm
changing the input equals g function
Okay g function is listening ARR
2 times I okay this is 2 times I and a r
2 times I plus 1 right
yes look
here here
this is I right this number is 2 times I
this number is 2 times I plus one
okay this is I this is 2 times I this is
2 times I plus one okay makes sense yes
okay and after this
and divided by divided by two what's
this mean it means it's divided by two
yeah why do we need to divide by two
and then we get one and so that's half
and you end up having half of a original
yeah yeah so every time we do this one
iteration we deduce the size to half
right so n divided by by two is the same
as n shift is Shifty equal one right we
shift the N to the one partition all
right and then
310. a r ZL right
okay and I think that would be it right
eighth element four pairs
16 elements a pairs right this is what
it does eight divided by two so one this
original value one needs to take care of
one and two these two needs to take care
to three and four these three needs to
take care five and six this four needs
to take care of seven and eight okay
let's see the time the next thing is the
same log n
the space complexity or one we are
modifying the original value Okay so to
sum up the first one recursion the
second one using the queue the third one
modifying our original array the three
approach the time complexity or uh log n
because it takes log n step to reduce
the size of n to one the space
complexity the first one when the second
one you know
um a one right the third one a one so
which one is the best the size one yeah
is
very good okay so what have you learned
today nothing
okay should we do it okay
okay what have we learned today okay I
have learned about the numbers no so we
have
um
total amount of digits have to be uh in
the towel too because you're halfing up
which are numbers which which
we can hop until it's one yes
left we uh yeah okay so what are the
approaches yeah we have recursion yeah
we have a Q yes
um
and we have uh
yeah okay so because this is modifying
yeah so okay before I forgot yeah this G
function this G is the same yeah cycle
yes cycle you learn this new function
from meter to an import cycle right and
it's basically it Returns the iterator
so you can do this next one is next is
mean the next one will be Max it's an
indefinite indefinite iterator right you
can call it called the next function on
the G function as long as you define G
cycle mean Max okay
okay that's it for today bye-bye bye bye