yes
and you mentioned what's title Circle
decorations like the wheels on the bus
go round
he said we all know the and we like put
the milk powder I'll I'll
smile look at this one
out though we learned you to call them
one two one two three okay so in eat a
two US python provides this eater to us
it has a one cycle function okay so what
does it do g equals psycho
one two three yeah and then I can do
this why uh two
wire two means that in definitely do
enter this Loop and I can say point
next
G
okay so guess what happened after
executing this piece of code three line
okay what happened LD operate one two
three one two three one two three four
two three yes exactly look g equals
cycle you know a parameter one two three
and Y true white room is integration
Point keep going so basically this is
the busy dupe uh keep going it never
ends next G because G is an iterator
next move to the next year next will be
one next will be two three and then
you go back to one two three okay so
without this cycle if we change it to
iterator and this will stop after three
iteration because one two three the next
one is
no elements when you stop we can use the
second parameter next iterator right
this is iterator and then by default
for example minus one so if we went out
of elements from the iterator if there
is no such next element we pretend the
default okay so without that it will
stop it will stop it will just say that
it will stop so that cycle makes it end
this iterator so in other words cycle
look cycle
cycle one two three is basically means
this one so one two three one two three
one two three keep going keep going keep
going okay
iterator iterator
makes it possible
to point to uh and the list list okay so
there's no such thing as and delete
please and right and this list
in computer because what's endless what
does it mean it never stops but you were
talking about this this is the concrete
thing it's impossible to put endless
element in the computer
am I right if you're asking for Endless
list give me a endless list
so the computer can do it why is that
because computer can put endless element
in the list and okay so this is endless
with all elements here we go the
computer can do it right okay but with
the iterator computer can do it okay
computer say Okay imagine just imagine I
have an endless list but I can't give
you at once
all right instead you ask me using next
I give you one you ask me again I give
you two you ask me again I give you
three you ask me again one two three
just imagine this is the end of this
list but I can't give you all at once
all right that's the difference between
list and iterator
okay so with the iterator you can do it
this way so with the internet how do I
give you one when you ask what's the
word sound with why
you'd Yeah well yeah yeah means give it
okay so that's what it means okay okay
so how do we implement this uh Exciter
how do we implement
so usually
I'm giving the one two three this is not
how can I turn this into an endless
iterator now let me Define this title
title X okay so look X is one two three
if you ask me three times and I will run
out of it
so after I'd ran out of it what happened
you asked me the fourth time I don't
have element for you when we go through
the anime we need to save copy of it
right save I have a saved which is an
empty this now so for if you ask me for
it I in X Y this is iterator I hear the
first I give you the element first and
now what's next I need to put this in
here okay
save
got a pen
all right okay so what does it mean look
if you hear to me if you give me you've
asked me three times I'll give you one
two three but after that that's fine one
two three I put it in safe and yield it
right so wire safe why we have any minus
eight four I in saved yeah
I this is how we implement the cycle
this is actually very neat beautifully
written look just a few lines of code
defines the cycle it does it's not
really beautiful okay so can you tell me
can you tell me what are we trying to do
here why this can work what does this
mean why do we need to save here here do
you understand this title thing let me
write it again g equals cyta
one two three
Parts yeah okay good question yeah yeah
what's ear remember what I talk about
the end of this thing right yeah you
give it and the little and this and this
list you can ask computer for our entry
list this is concrete tangible give me a
list of 100 elements the computer will
feel it at least with one two three four
up to 100 give it to you
I I like computer has memory yeah the
memory the brand when memory
computer memory is called Ram
read excess memory okay so you can put
in these elements in your brain right
you can't remember like an animated
number of elements in your brain all
right nobody can do that no computer
they can do that instead computer can
say imagine I have an end list list you
know it keeps growing it never ends but
I can't give you all these elements to
you at once right instead you can ask me
one by one okay one two three and you
ask me again one two three one two three
remember the cycling one two three okay
yeah one two three okay let's mean one
element in the end this uh this iterator
okay one I'll give you one you ask me
again two
ask me again three ask me again one two
three one two three so when you ask it
I give it to you yeah that's what it is
list in in in like a circle like one two
three one two the thing is the end of
this how do you put it in my list
as long as you stop it's not end of this
okay so the thing is that here is an
endless it never ends yeah but
apparently you're giving one one number
at the time yeah yeah and you said you
can't give it all that's right but I
want to give you one okay so this is the
one way of doing it yeah look you ask me
look G cycle and then I can say four I
in range ten
give me 10 numbers in this end of this
list and I can say print
next
G okay look
because in the next G right next GG is
the iterator and then what he does here
yeah once yet happens
it gives back the number to print and
then the next time you call the next
then here will continue to give the next
number
what have you learned today
nothing about this cycle yeah focusing
yield
yes you're trying to
so you have to give one family each time
each time you ask the computer
because look once I go through this x
once I go through this x I can't go back
for the iterator thing is that you know
you can't go back so if this is a
iterator next G
and you give the one next G give the two
next gives the three next G then you
will be stopping here because there is
no such element after iterator just one
way how do we produce Our Endless
iterator the trick is that the first
time we go through the iterator we saved
it in a copy and look because look one
two three after I finish the first e one
two three I know we have one two three
and then the next time
we just look why say why we have element
in the list we just keep doing this keep
returning this yeah keep returning here
okay it never ends here it never ends
here right it never ends here yeah yeah
why this endless thing is useful okay
just imagine you know that they are
unlimited number of prime numbers right
all right how to improve these are
unlimited look if the first number prime
number is P1 second prime number is P2
and prime number needs to be P3 if they
are limited number of prime numbers
let's say PN right up to pm
and how about if we can't sleep together
that's limited I know I know I'm proving
that it's unlimited so let's assume the
opposite it's limited and there are n
prime numbers P1 p2p3 up to PN and that
comes it together plus one obviously
this number is not divisible by any of
these right
am I right so this is also a prime
number we just assume there are n prime
numbers but now we found another one
so what does it mean the assumption is
wrong the Assumption what's the
Assumption there are n prime numbers
this assumption is wrong
okay so what does it mean it means we
have unlimited number of prime numbers
okay
okay so but you're saying B1 btp3 but
you only have n two times together and
plus one that's right and this number is
the prime number yeah you only have an N
to multiply by
yes and that's limited because you only
have n yes sir my assumption is that
okay let's assume they are in term
numbers yeah I know that's a small out
of this number plus one comes together
plus one is also a prime number yeah
that's only one more one more okay so
there's only one more so it contracted
it conflicts with the assumption that
only n actually n plus one and I can
keep doing this keep adding this keep
adding it so that means that keeps
adding
okay I'm assuming they're n prime
numbers but now I found another one
which is not part of this end
okay so I have one more number here
which is the prime number yeah but how
do you add another one
this is another one this is another one
yeah so you times that another one where
the other end yes so this this number
this number is a new prime number but
when you
in our first cry number times
number what about number one free look
look two times three it equals six plus
one equals seven you missed a five
that's okay okay so let's assume that
only two prime numbers right let's
assume okay we want to prove there are
only two that they are Limited Brand
number which is two and three now I'm
telling you two times three plus one
this is obviously a prime number
seven and then two times three times
seven okay so we found another prime
number which is seven
so the original assumption is wrong they
are not just two prime number because
seven is another prime number
my origin assumptions they are only n
prime numbers now I found another one
number which is point number so it's
contracted the original assumption
so the origin assumption is wrong
the opposite is correct which is there
are unlimited number of prime numbers
this is actually one beautifully proved
mathematic proof of uh beautiful it's
not like it's colorful it's literally
black meat I'm saying Need need
Okay neither true okay do you understand
yeah
yeah it depends if it's neat okay okay
let's coming back to this prime number
thing okay yeah unlimited number of
prime numbers give me the next prime
number
okay and they are unlimited number of
prime numbers I can't give you all at
once but instead you can ask me okay now
I give you two what's my next one number
three what's the next number five what's
nice number seven what's the number 11.
that's very good let's hand shooting a
very uh you know not trivial and
remember we talk about how do we get a
prime number up to a hundred one two
three four five this is uh numbers uh
tier 100 right how do we get all the
numbers prime numbers up to 100 we talk
about that right so one is obviously not
a problem number two it's a prime number
right I cross all the duplicates four
six eight right financially the prime
number I cross all the duplicates six
they're just in that time table yeah
those are just multiples yeah yeah
multiple okay I cross it loud and I can
keep doing this and then remaining uh
the prime numbers I well we talk about
it right you do you still remember this
one but how do you know if two is a
prime number what's the definition of
prime number
divided by one in itself okay one is
yeah yeah yes start with this one so you
have to work it out okay so two two is
the prime number we because it's
multiple yeah so you have to work out
four two six a etc and then three is a
prime number or cosine is uh yeah you
have to work out two and three so and
then we walk through okay this is kind
of the equivalent okay uh do you get
enough and do you learn something new
today
if you come from the actual prime number
you have to test if it is that's good
yeah how do we tax uh like a 97 is it a
prime number how do we test it well it
is obviously
what what's obvious the computers don't
know what's obviously so how do we test
it we start with two
and then we start with three and then we
test the five
seven nine
eleven until Nine's not okay until I
know until
square root of 97 right we talk about
that we just have to check all the
factors up to square root of N and if 97
cannot be divided by the factor then
it's a prime number okay make sense
yeah instead of checking though remember
we talked about half right 97 so we need
to check from number one up to 48. why
do you only need to check uh the square
root
oh yeah you were asking this question
means you're thinking yes look 30.
what's the factors 2 times 15. 3 times
10. five times six
times five
ten times three
what's next up to half right three times
ten ten times three five times six six
times five
do you see
it's impaired
so if I have n if I have a square root
of n the other one is square root of the
N I just have to check up to
half right the other one three times ten
if it's divided by three it must be
divided by ten right so I don't need to
check this these two are actually
duplicate right so they go into the
middle which is
how is that a square root
100 100
20 times five five times twenty ten
times ten ten times ten and then the
next actually in minerals at 10 times 10
right
yeah make sense
does it make sense now
okay yeah that's a very good question
that's a very very good question means
you're thinking yeah okay okay so let's
see for today bye bye bye bye
foreign