one two three zero
positive integers
okay so I'm going to write the output
you tell me what what is that okay two
three five five one two three Fields
okay just written all the digits
separate yeah separate the digit yes
separated okay how to do it
split how do we split the digit how do
we get the 35 into 3 and 5.
how do we split
yeah with the split word
is for the string so we need to convert
it is
yeah that's one way so we can combine
these into three we will flip we'll slip
on the banana split okay
[Music]
Okay so
convert it to string and then split okay
actually cover the string because the
bridge we need at the diminutive okay
but for this one we are not using
display we're using the list so what's a
spray okay now let's take an example if
this is one two three if this is a you
can say a does split
straight and give a delimiter right and
then it will give us a list of one
two
three right this is what the split is
and the opposite way is
join yeah so if we can say this the joy
you know turn at least one two
it has to be string right one two three
and then it will give us this thing but
for
this kind of thing one two three how can
we split into digits we can use this
this we just use the list we we split
list
but there's no space the thing is
there's no space so we use this this is
a special case use a list we turn
basically we turn a string into a list
so you give us one two three even simple
okay
that's one way convert into the string
yeah
which one is it already it's the
original one
divided 123 and zero this is a number
okay
but we want to get this so basically we
want to iterate over the digit each
digit and we converted a string and then
we turn into a list
and we convert it back to the numbers
and we push it back right okay the other
way how do we get the numbers one two
three four with modulus 10 divided by 10
right but that will give us
four three two one it's in the reverse
order right it's in reverse order if we
get this uh multiple ten divided by 10
model 10 right
in Reverse also then we can reverse it
right the first approach by converting
to a string okay Define f uh we're given
this that is if this is a
all right I learned it means to return a
list of integer right this topic array
equals empty for I in we go to each
numbers right and then we want to
convert it to string right
so if this is I right convert it to
string Str I
this is converted to the string and I
will use the list
list this turns into a way of strings
but we need to turn each one into
integer so we can use this map thing
basically that means that we want to
apply this integer function to every
element in the list okay so then each
one is that and then we need to
then we need to append all the elements
here to the AR right look if this is ARR
is one two three
okay and if this is a equals four and
five how can we append 4 inside into ARR
so we use the function a r r dot extent
okay so that will push four and five
into
the back of the AR okay yeah when it
says extend we can do the other way push
every element in the a to a r so a
stupid way is for I in a
and then a a pen
a pen all right
this is the same thing as this one okay
these two are the same thing
for you to the first combine into the
string we turn it into a list we map it
back to our integer and then we need to
arr.x10
foreign
this is the
Simple Solution Phantom black State we
go through the a if like an element here
and then if each digit on average is
three okay so the time difference is o n
times t
right because we converted the string
let's face complexity obviously we need
to convert it to a list here if we're
not treating the output array as a space
so we just consider being released list
so let's face complexes I will see we
need additional array to store the
digits let's do another way which is to
convert it to a digit extract that
digits by modulus 10 divide by 10 right
so instead of this I will decorate the
space though he said it has to have a
space in color how does it how does it
create space allocating the space yeah
how does it create the space in between
the digit yes oh another space not a
space I mean the space complexity okay
the second approach yeah the second
approach let's do this
for I go through each digit each number
and let's pull this current in the
current right so then we go through this
we try to teach y i bigger than zero
carbon dot a pen
I modulus 10 right this is the least
significant digit but this is on once
and then we need to get rid of it I
divided divided by a ten now this
current is the reverse so one two three
will be three two one right so
how can we
how can we reverse it right how do we
reverse this one three two one we want
to make it reverse to one two three yeah
in price on this is a common B comma C
right and you can omit it right if it is
a I mean it it will be by default zero
if B omitted it will be the length of
the array
if C I'll make it there will be one
right
so is that from A to B step C so from a
to length step minus one which is the
opposite so we want to get it Opposite
so a r r dot extend
extend currently normal management
why you mentioned a good point two
points I think so how do we do for that
one two three four
two point one and four swap
answer
I model sense I divide the button what
does it mean
if
the number 12.3 one two three we ought
to get the number three
this is modulus 10 right
and then
I want to make 123 one two
123 divided divided by 10. yeah module
is 10 3 divided by 10.
integer divide get rid of the last
stitches okay and then keep repeating
until all the digits have been extracted
okay if we don't reverse it how do we do
it look okay so look this digit we get a
three two this Stitch we get a five
three this Stitch we get a three two one
zero so what's the answer here this is
two three
five
one two three
and zero right this is the array we want
to get and if we reverse each Bit Zero
three two one
five three two three okay so if we go
from the back if we iterate from the
back reverse the first number is zero
zero that's zero this number one two
three right because we reverse it
already yeah we don't need to reverse
here so we do it first it will be three
to one okay and then it's three five
with the reverse it would be five three
and then two three we reverse it will be
three two
what's the the relation between please
two two three five one two three zero
and zero three two one five three three
two
what's the relation between these two
this is reverse right
and then we can just reverse this bit a
little bit so we go song
minus one
I know we don't need to reverse it we
need to reverse it here one one two one
two three okay these three numbers we go
from the last one which is three two one
we're gonna set a camera which is two
what we're gonna first one with this one
three two one two one one okay the
answer is one one two
one two three right it's the reverse
come complexity for these two I think
it's the same right because we go into
each digit for each Stitch we need to
extract the digits of the number and
let's face complexity we still need to
use the additional array to hold the
digit of a particular number right
before we push it using the extent the
Fourth Way return to single line
Integrity for
this is a okay so for number l in a for
t
in
each one s t r n
okay
so we're going through the array this n
is this is the number and then we
convert it to string and we iterate over
the digit and this T we need to convert
it back to the integer okay so that's it
actually the solution is this one a
little Integrity because we want to uh
integer path and the digit
and then this tea is Str converting to n
to the string N is a number and what's
an N is the digit each number in each
number 23 35 okay so here and
this is n right this is an n
we converted n to Star and we iterate D
each digit but it's a string type we
need to convert it to integer type so
these are the four methods okay so which
one is the best which one you like
um
what have you learned today
um we learned how to split number digits
into regular numbers one digit numbers
okay Eric we're having a
one
um
[Music]
we're trying to split them into one this
year we have numbers and we've splitting
them into one digit number and then we
need to append them to the result right
yeah so how can we do it how many ways
yes so reverse yeah
oh the first one which is the first one
okay three four Solutions
[Music]
then we divide 10 we get one digit and
then we keep on repeating until we yeah
but the thing is that this one is the in
the reverse order we need to yeah we
need to reverse it right yes okay that's
it for today bye-bye goodbye bye bye
hello
foreign