yeah okay so we know the string right so
string like uh hello this is string
hello Eric and Ryan okay so look this is
a string s
so just guess what's the output as the
find e f
s Define
A and D okay so what's the output k h e
i okay so what does this mean just guess
if it is
yeah I think you written through the 10
true okay quite close and you can't find
it because it's Capital that's right
yeah let's go find it okay so this is
fine obviously we're trying to find so
we are trying to find a substring right
substring
to see if it's in the original screen so
this is like pattern this is a string so
if we find it when we turn the index the
index here is zero one index one it
finds it so it returns
one but you can't find it yeah that's a
good point if you can't find it returns
minus one okay so another example as to
find what what if the string is nothing
nothing that's a good point if you find
nothing in return zero okay so you
assume nothing is a you know always
found okay this is a substring it can
contain the more than one character how
about index
how about if I replace the fight with
the index
the difference we didn't find anything
what's the index
what does it mean in that it's basically
like you in the book of my non-fiction
and you go to the page about are things
like indexes
are they like value
true okay so find an index is quite
similar right so what's fine you try to
find the index right okay so when you
say it's fine
are you sure you're going to find it or
not
now that's why we have minus one right
but when you say index it's there right
yeah
yeah okay so normally difference between
find the indexes like when the item is
not filed
when the item is not found gonna find
returns minus one the index will return
a value error
value error this is an exception all
right that's the only difference that's
for the string and if this is a list
okay if it is like
you know at least one two three four
okay this is list and then you can do
list of index
okay index two what is it return
one two three four this is this index
two what is a great time it could be the
chapter what does it return
s two
why is this three two zero is zero zero
one two three so index two what is it
written three
three why is this way because three
three zero one one two index two we're
on to five two
oh one yeah zero one yes okay okay
the place then you use this person right
you finish this two then zero one two
and return three okay this is the how we
index find the cutter find the element
at index two for a tuple array on this
or whatever and if this is like a five
then you will throw the arrow right so
this value error because the index but
for at least it doesn't have a finite
function as I said find
three times minus one if it's the
element it's not found index
Returns the
value error this is exception so raise
this is basically raised very well it's
an expression what's extension it's
basically like computer screaming okay
so you you ask computer okay what's the
index of elements I in this list the
computer just screen because I don't
have it you are trying to you're trying
to ask me for the index I can't do it
right but if it's fine it's different
you ask me is there a element five in
this list right you're asking like a
more gentle way and I said okay I don't
have it but I return you minus one okay
yeah this is the difference you're
asking if if he does have a size then
you're telling the computer to do
something with five even when he doesn't
have it yeah yeah true too yeah okay so
given the least how do we find the
element
what's the strategy how do we find the
element in the array
we look real way how do we look for you
what's the strategy
you know one two three four I give it
away
you know one two three
I want to fight like the nine right now
it could be here so how do we find it
how do we ask computer level how does
the computer find this Knight try to
find locate where is the nice return the
index okay
sorry left and right this is
if there are any elements what's the
time cameras
in the worst case what happened
or not in
that or if it's not in the array then
the computer needs to you know go
through all the elements in the right in
the efficient okay
okay if they already sorted how do we go
through it how do we search it
if it's in the array it's okay like one
two three to a hundred I want to locate
if like the number 30 how do we do it
you can't do it like yeah what does it
call binary binary watch binary size
what's the time research
okay that's good yeah overlooking yeah
because every time we cut in her life if
it's smaller
yeah if the animal is in this half we
don't need to search any of those right
so we abandon every time we abandon half
of the search domain okay okay so let's
Implement a fine function for the list
40 what do you mean okay
the first element is 14. okay 40 50. it
doesn't matter right yeah
yeah when we say look in the meter we're
not saying the value meter we're saying
that the meter of the array right so let
me tell it could be 100 or 300 let's put
another element it doesn't matter like
okay so the meter is this one okay so we
compare with this one 30 is smaller than
that right yeah so we don't need to
do any of this what is it what's the
middle is two numbers like before it
doesn't matter you can pick any one it
doesn't matter right because that's just
one difference this makes sense you need
this half I don't need to search any of
those and then here again it's smaller
than that I go into here and it's
smaller than that okay well right now of
choice is a minus one okay so as I said
let's Implement a fight using the linear
search okay because the away income
issue is salted python doesn't have a
file for the list okay and before I
forgot the index function right index
function and the fight function the
first element is the Target and then
there are options so you can start an n
and the range so let's say we don't want
to search the entire list let's say we
want to start from the index 2 to index
five then we can put the two and five
here does it make sense this is optional
parameters right you can give a star and
get the n yeah yeah okay Define five
we want to fight for a list all right
not iterable all right okay let's make
it all right and we want to find a
Target and an optional s and n if we
don't give a star parameter the optional
it's it's yellow and if we don't give a
optional that's minus one okay I can set
a default value for the parameters
if you don't give a value for S it's
zero if you don't give a value for e is
minus one if e is is minus one then we
need to correct it to the length of the
T right if we don't give a parameters
for the end boundary we set it to the
end of the the list each rows for I in
range from the start to the end and
we'll just check if a r i
minus one
okay so if we decide to sew an exception
we just replace this return with raise
a message here we can use the next
function right so we can say answer
equals next I for I in range
s e
e a r r i equal equal t
otherwise we return minus one if you not
fuck and then we can answer or if answer
equal equal minus one then we raise the
exception raise variable if we are
implementing the index function if it's
a five function which is written minus
one right so return answer
okay
okay so look this is the five function
for a list we can pass the at least a
chapter right so how do we use this
function five at least one two three all
one two three and then we want to find
the target three and look that's it if
we don't specify the S and E star and N
the S will be zero e will be minus one
but when e is minus one e will be uh
corrected to the length of the given
parameter right okay so what have you
learned today
[Music]
find an index right what's the
difference between find and index
yeah what's the difference between final
index okay
um index is your brain you can you try
to find like the like Place whatever
it's called
and and for the find the original
finding for it okay so what's the
difference the difference is it is not
there yeah
because if you're finding it it could be
there or not there before index and for
index you're you're telling something
you're telling me to do something within
elements but if that element isn't that
uh is a problem it's a problem the way
it's a very exception okay and the final
will be 10 minus one if it's not there
okay yeah you're trying to find
something you could be now you could not
be there it could be not existent right
but for the index you're pretty sure
it's there that's why you're asked to
find the index
when you say okay give me the index of
element
are you sure like it's there right and
if it's not that and it's going to be
perfect but it's like find me in the
index and it could could be the case
that it's not that right okay and now we
use the linear search we just do this
from a search start to the end and
finally we try to check each element to
see if it's equals to that right also
the find the index suppose the option
the parameter so so we can given range
from s to e we want to find a different
P okay so for example the last question
okay s top five
Eric
and Ryan okay
and I'm give a parameter
0 to 2 what does it return
pause
minus one y is minus one because there
is
yeah zero and one two so he's basically
trying to find it here and
everything
that has more values at than two true
yes true yeah okay yeah this is a simple
way to check right simple way to check
but what's underneath how do we
implement this this is a very
complicated topic it is called KMP you
know substring matching okay this is out
of scope of this talk yeah probably in
the future we can come back to this okay
that's it for today bye-bye bye bye
foreign