everybody
yeah
so I have an array of integer right like
two actually no four a 16. 64.
49 okay just four okay
so these are four numbers what are those
in comments
they are all in this square numbers
square numbers yes true okay it doesn't
have to be square numbers but let's just
take those for example for simplistic
this is our way and then we have a k
equals two so we want to perform the
operations K times for each operation we
want to take the maximum of it what's
the maximum 54 64 yeah okay what's the
square root of it eight yes
so this is AI
okay so then what do we do we erase this
one why do you have to square it down
that's how we Define the Operation so
for each information we take take
Max number
and square squared square root of it if
it's not perfect square number we just
take an integer bar for example 65 will
still make it a right because the
largest square numbers
is eight before that right am I right
what is this what if it's uh okay uh
we need to perform another one so which
number we take
which number we take yeah can you have
some like decimal numbers
no these are positive individuals that's
a very good question project integer
okay for each one I take the maximum I
square a load of it if this is and I put
this back which is a right so I erase
this bit which is a so what's the next
one to take
two operations so what's the sum of the
remaining we just add these together
okay simple as that this is 35 what what
has the cane have to do k equals two
perform two times it's a five five yes
okay
okay make sense so to sum up with
the K is a greater than a
that's very good that's very very good
okay so we just keep performing we take
a number take a maximum we push it back
we take a number we push back right does
it make sense so in the extreme cases
all one I want to perform a minion k
equals a million so what's the answer
I take one one take the maximum
right a square root of it is one I push
it back this one so it doesn't change
right oh yeah I perform a million times
what's the sum update
yeah
yeah it doesn't answer your question
okay okay so what's the Your solution
about that is there a trick to do it or
how do we usually solve this gun yes we
just checked we just we just get okay so
the key thing about that is how do we
get the maximum of an array current
array
we consulted
or remember yesterday we talk about the
find and Index right
the key thing
is going to the maximum I just want to
know the 49 is the maximum I don't care
unless they started but sorting is a
good answer we can sort it and get the
maximum right but we don't have to
because we just need to know the maximum
okay
Define f array okay
four
I in or for underscore we don't actually
need to use the variable range
okay
and then after sorting where is the
maximum on the right on the right which
is a minus one right we want to change
it to
sqrt
s q r t a minus one but this gives the
decimal we can convert it to integer
right yeah or we can use the another
function called I squared I square root
it means that this part returns integer
and then return
some of it sum hey that's it that's the
Your solution what's the time of next
day
that looks nice yes what's the time come
next if you can answer that even that's
even nicer what's the same
here is K okay okay okay okay
so here is okay but what's that here
oh and again okay
okay you're good so what's the type of
recipe okay Logan
translate to get away
so oh
that's Google okay Okay times and login
right and then we need to plus this n
right so which is bigger so this is
obviously bigger so we drop the come to
University okay times n times Stop N
right because we need to perform K
operation each one we need to stop this
is the Sorting complexity times it okay
does it make sense
[Music]
we want to do K things
well you know K times and for each time
we need to do this so the time comes
next time together obviously okay this
one is base complexity
constant space
okay so this is one way
but as I said we don't need to sort it
right most dominant part is this sorting
right
and we just sold it already because we
only get a maximum which is not very
effective
and I'm efficient
yeah
you want to find a maximum or minimum of
mineral arrays a minion size array do
you need to sew them it takes time right
I can just go through the array am I
right
okay look here the a minion array uh
this is a minute n equals Amino okay
I want to find the maximum a minimum
what's the best way to find it
what's the best solution to find the
maximum minimum of our way so there is
our login that's what I said yes it
works but it's not the optimum so just
goes to release right
and then we're going to find it the time
zone next is that one right
three to a hundred thousand twenty
what's on the maximum 100 how do you
know it's 100 it's the biggest number
because I have my eyes yeah I know but
how how does
it come here yes but how does computer
find it
you know what your thoughting is good
you just sold it right you thought it is
2 3 20 100 okay the last one is a
maximum and this one is but how does
this computer find it three okay the
maximum is three two is not bigger than
maximum so my maximize zero three a
hundred hundred is bigger than the color
maximum which is a three so the maximum
updated to 100 20 is smaller than 100 so
the maximum is 100 doesn't make sense
girls doing solar array once and that's
all and okay
eat I can see my eyes so uh this is the
same yeah so how do we get it so we can
again go through it each time color Max
equals Max hey okay look we get a Max
and then what do we do next
shot for Max okay so we get the max
value and then what do we do now we need
to find where is it right I equals a DOT
what's the function we talked about
we will Define the index of the value in
the array what's the two function we
talked about is this index or find
what's the difference between index and
five
uh find is that you're trying to find it
and and also it could not be there and
the computer won't complain but index is
is you're trying to do you're trying to
give it index of of uh value and if and
so you're seeing that it that the value
is there because you asked it yeah yeah
if you don't layer you will return a
value as well
exception okay but in this case it's
there right because I just filed it the
maximum it's already like so it first
final index is fine so now I have index
I just need to change it to
you know that I asked
hey I I land returned some of it right
make sense what's the time I'm actually
okay
and
and yeah so it's uh K times n right this
is two n okay times two n which is okay
times n
and plus plus uh n plus and yes
but obviously this droplet uh trigger
Factor so it's okay time side which is
better
this one another one that one this one
yeah yeah because look okay times and
and this one additional terms which is
bigger than one okay so this is like
that so we talked about
the decimal or many
Q we call it what kind of Q remember Q
first in first hour right five if we is
the first thing priority oh you know Max
our minimal what do we call it a nice
Cube Ice Cube yes it's priority killed
but it can be implemented using his uh
right remember the binary
this is one two four a a hundred so
always this is the minimum this is a
common hip
that they've been hip and if this is the
maximum like 100 and this is 24 this is
one this is still and this is called Max
hip so it's kind of like a binary tree
uh it's called binary here I find a tree
that the loot is always the minimum or
maximum okay
okay this is called hip and we can use
that
the thing is
because the heat is like a heel and if
and if it if a minimum if a minimum was
either root then it would just be a hole
yeah no heat a heat is kind of like a
heel yeah a heel so if the maximum
should be on the top but if the minimum
is over top then there's just being a
hole not a heap yeah yeah I understand
your point yes yes okay so we can
transfer between mean have a maxi
um
so the heat is like this
the maximum is at the top there's a
minimum is is
okay yeah that's very good that's very
good in Python the hip is mean hip
meaning like okay so if I turn an array
to a hip when I hit push hit pop it's
always getting the minimum right but in
this case we want to get the maximum so
at least numbers are positive right so
how do we extend the positive numbers
into the
you know mean hip
like they look two three a hundred if I
do like hip hop
and you'll give me two right how do we
change it to give me a hundred left
three numbers right in Python is Heap
pop
when I do hip hop
you'll kill me too
is there a way to make it give me a
hundred instead hip hop right
but we can do something he
[Music]
because there's no hip-hop on the other
side
he thought right I don't know Max okay
but no I'm keep your hint how about this
number positive if I change it to
negative then what does it become
minus two minus three minus a hundred
what's the minimum of it minus 100 okay
that's I know we just need get it does
it make sense
yeah obviously we need to turn the
numbers into hip right so
but we need to get this a equal we
change to minus yeah because it's all
positive minus I for I in a okay look a
I change it to minus we get each one
minus I for I in a okay and then now I
need to pp5 pp5 what's hipify what's
this means
excellent make it a hit so if I hey and
I change this other way into hipify okay
and then now I can go through this okay
time okay uh for underscore in range k
okay and then I need to take it out so
V equals hip hop a okay I take this out
which is negative I need to make it
positive again right this makes sense
yeah hip
push
a minus V square root of it
I square root of it
and then I need to
get it again for example like minus 100
and take it out it's minus a hundred I
need to make it a hundred I need to
square root of 100 which is ten I need
to put the minus 10 back into the hit
all right that's what it means so V
equals hip hop and I can actually put a
minus here right and then here I'll
become
i s q r t v put the minus here all right
and then sum return
some
hey okay so is that correct
minus yes exactly well done okay thank
you black see hit you five okay the key
thing about the complexity here is the
hippie file if we are making a hip
directly by giving it a list of animals
and the time conversation of hipify is o
n
okay it's the time for next year poop
and
and push is knocking
okay so the time collects is o n plus k
k times right log n
okay and then plus this sum which is o n
okay actually o to the N right chocolate
constant so the time when this is o n
plus K Times log n if we are building a
hit by pushing and animals to it the
time complex is o n log n
for this one is o n plus K Times log n
okay so which one is better space
complexity obviously this one is o n we
need a space
this is time complexity this is Spec's a
starting one
the Time come back says K Times log n
right we talk about space normally see
your one
Eric you said to your approach salty
K times the uh K times o and not again
right the second one by finding the max
the finding the max index index measure
the time complexity is o k times n right
yes a space complexity over one the
third one using the hip
is o n Plus
K Times log n
okay the space complexity is o n okay so
which one is better come on which one is
better by looking at the tables
which one has the optimum time
this one obviously is better than the
one this one and this one this is okay
times n this is okay Times log n
okay
so obviously this is better yeah space
complexity the second one is save the
best one till now yeah but this one has
the additional Ln space right because we
need a hippie file if we can
and space
okay so let's I mean this Andy's
question now because we are modifying
the original array of the week we can
modify the other additionally we don't
need to use an additional array okay we
can just go through this a and then
change each number to negative and
hipify and in this case we are not
creating additional array we're just
multiplying the input array let's learn
it probably is a one okay okay so the
thing is that for this talking okay we
consider is a one space okay usually the
Sorting again a quick song remember
additional array right how do we quick
so remember
how do we cook salt we pick a number
three
in the previous number what numbers are
smaller than three two and one point on
the left four numbers are bigger than
three four and a hundred okay so now
three is here right and then we skip
recursively starting the last time an
apartment okay so what have you learned
today
[Music]
so we're trying to relax squaring it and
put it back yeah I want to perform okay
time so what are the solutions you learn
am I just describe one one is enough
one of them is Heap yeah
one of them is it index so if we want to
find out the maximum minimum of another
way do we have to solve it what are the
best solution to find the maximum
minimum
what's the optimal solution for that you
want to find the maximum of an array
just linear right okay that's it for
today bye-bye bye
foreign