hello hello Mr Runner right okay so
today let's look at the numbers yeah so
okay so just imagine a number like
you know just give me a number random
positive integer and a million can you
leave a smaller one positive integer one
how about one positive okay
37 yeah
can you think of a number which is less
than twenty one one
is easy right it's a special case which
I'm going to talk about in a few how
about 16 16 okay yeah 16.
okay so imagine I have a empty board
okay so 16 I put it there
okay now can you find out all the
numbers bigger than one inclusive like a
smaller than and smaller than this
number 16 right
so can you find any number any number so
from 1 to 16 let 16 modulus a equal
equal one
you know 16 divided by a the modulus
equal equal one 16 divided by one
remaining zero zero okay so this is
yellow close up oh it's three and five
five okay so you've got three and five
right anything else fifteen fifteen yeah
anything well no right three times okay
three times
yeah I know so three five fifteen three
five fifteen once we put down the
numbers on this y box right it stays
there so every number here three you did
the same yeah just two right so for the
two
five four four and
two is there right yeah fifteen two
it's there
um fourteen
seven
okay what is 15. um six
fifteen divided by six the remaining
around seven seven okay seven six yeah
okay so after
a billion tons
thirteen ten to the power of nine a
billion what is that opinion
13.
[Music]
13. I know what I'm saying is repeated
obedient sounds how many numbers how
many testing numbers originally I put a
16 how many distinct numbers what does
that mean this thing unique
liquid opinion times
how many numbers are on here so I keep
doing this that's 13 and I'll be 12.
who have I noticed it
minus one yeah why because
why is it a matter of fact yeah a minus
one is cleanser 20.
19 20. so what numbers are eventually
going to be there one is going to be 19
18 17. but if you don't count 16 and one
then you'll be 14. there's a special
cases originally if it's one if it's one
then
it's one if it doesn't have a ring
remainder one yeah because the thing is
I put it one there and I repeat
and I can't find anything that makes it
divided by it one right yeah and it
possesses but yeah but you you wouldn't
put but one down because they wouldn't
be within a remainder of one okay so the
step is I choose a number N I put it
there this is the starting location and
so I put the number in here
and number I find out all the numbers
that
all the numbers n divided by a if
modulus equal equal one okay follow
those numbers I put in there okay if it
is saying one I put one there and I
can't find anything like modulus equal
one then it ends
okay so what's the number so if I put
the number n what if I choose the number
and what's the answer a minus one but if
n equals one what's the answer one yeah
if n is one the answer is one if n is
other things the answer is M minus one
okay Y is n minus one because one yeah
but y eventually it's going to be a
minus one because you're gonna repeat a
billion times a billion times if n is
more than enough I'm going to repeat it
forever until no numbers no new numbers
or rival so why is it a minus one and
that's billion times eventually all of
them numbers in that range from one to
no one no way
one isn't uh gonna be there because yeah
because your mother is
yellow yeah so from two to and all the
numbers so you have to think there but
you need to persuade the people right
why because if I put an end when n is
bigger than two right so I put a three
to prove it if the number n is three
what numbers can be put there so yeah
you know two four what numbers can we
put there three and two five what
numbers can be for that two three and
four four right
six what numbers can be put today it's
five that's five okay seven what numbers
can we put there
three
so he has six right
and two
okay
33.
okay how about
132 what numbers can we collect
I'm gonna ask you until you know you
know a trick to find the answer quickly
this is the even number
the answer is one three this number
you're you're for sure it's there right
okay another one
yes good job
thank you you'll get my phone yeah for
any number which is greater than two we
know for sure n minus one satisfied
right so mining number I can put n minus
one
the one yeah for two so we put a two
layer we can't take any number right but
the answer is s minus one which is one
number okay for three I can put a two
for a hundred I can put a 99 and then
for 99
yeah I know at 98 97. So eventually it
will come down to one two okay no one
come on another one yeah three one
okay so the answer is
oh
one this is one this is uh mathematics
and we can do this simulation yeah we
just repeat this process okay I'm going
to try this to simulate the process okay
we want to keep tracking of the unique
numbers what kind of data structure can
we use to keep tracking all the unique
numbers character dictionary
counter is a dictionary dictionary is
also headset right headset we find let's
define a process f n okay so we just
need to go through from I in range
we need to start from one no right no up
to n
right
and this number is not in this number is
not on the Y Bar that number is not in
numbers then what will do numbers dot
add we want to know this number I and
then for this number I we want to repeat
this process using the recursion okay
make sense
so what should I put here what should I
put here and then we just call this FN
and return the lens on the
length of the numbers
okay
for I I'm going from 2 to M minus 1
right if this number well and modulus it
equals one right if n log is I equal
equal one
right we found one number we want to put
it there but it's not in the Bible in
the number y box then we put this number
write it down one over the ten we know
that it's 9 we put the 9 on the ball and
what do we do
the next time we need to repeat the same
process right yeah so this is f n so
what should I do put here F1
this is nine I'm adding the number nine
to the white ball numbers this is
numbers
a and I want to count the number of
sides here right
I I yes
the time come next before this one is it
[Music]
um
what what's n
is it all
maximum time how many numbers the
maximum I can put down on the white box
and one is thing anyone needs one yeah
so he's Owen right yeah space complexity
space complexity do you think
how many numbers I can put on a
whiteboard the Whiteboard the whole
numbers
so oh and right we know we're not
talking about a constant okay yeah which
one is better this one this method or
the previous platform
because that one was the mathematics
mathematics this one is the simulation
we are just repeating the process we
want to count the number of the numbers
unique numbers using the hash set we put
all the numbers using the headset
installment unique numbers okay what
have you learned today
[Music]
we have this white wood and he's being
given a number I mean
you're you're adding numbers which
numbers on the Whiteboard which
which is the
the divisible with
um
which is divisible with remainder one
and so
and then we you repeat it a billion
times
and
and the solution is like uh we we get n
minus one
numbers eventually
yeah if we repeat this process forever
right until no new numbers I'll put on
the white bar okay the trick is that if
we put a n well n is uh greater than two
a minus one satisfied so for if we put M
minus sign we can put my M minus two and
if I put n minus 3 I can put n minus 3
and there two right so the number
between two to n inclusive is a minus
one
yeah okay that's it for today bye-bye
bye bye