hello hello Mr Mr Runner right so what's
finally says tree
is
and the one on the left side has to be
smaller than the this parent and the one
on the right hand needs to be bigger and
and they still need to be the same so
like if the one in the left if the one
on the bigger is still have to be
smaller than the the part of the one of
its parents is this a PSD
that's right because this on this side
needs to be bigger than seven okay so
let's put eight right this is the final
search given the binary search tree we
want to find out the minimum difference
minimum difference of any two notes in
the binary substrate what's the smallest
distance the difference
nine and eight okay so these two notes
yeah seven and eight okay so just to
return one okay return one the minimum
difference
okay opening two notes for example A and
B so we want to get the minimum
difference which is the absolute value A
and B right this is absolute value do
you still remember this okay X
mathematics equals x if x bigger than
zero zero if x equals zero minus x if x
is right this is absolute value this is
minor one the distance to the number
zero this is one right for any positive
number the distance
to the zero is Excel for the negative
number the distance is negative X okay
so this one for
A and B belongs to all the nodes in the
VST okay
any idea how we're doing this remember
we are even a binary surgery what can we
do about the binary search tree why are
we giving the minus 3.
finally search three is already sorted
but we need just need to perform what
kind of order to make it assertive in
order yes well what's in order you know
there is a type of water yes so you know
there is an order for a level
is it in order that makes the one
research free in order okay so this is
no left three yeah another Library so
the order will be the last three will be
to the left three first and the node and
the right shoe right because this this
is seven right we want to visit the
nodes that are smaller than seven
right and then we visited now server and
we visited the notifications
doing this in order I think on the left
tree and right three recursively and
then that gives us a salty list make
sense
so we can perform that in order then we
get the salty list so what do we do with
the sausages so after this that will be
minus my
and minus five one seven eight nine a
hundred so okay so we have this 30 days
what do we do with it
we get me to the line with first two
numbers and just yeah compare can you
prove to me can you explain to me why we
just need to check these two numbers
enabling two numbers or you know not any
other numbers because it is in order so
it's it's like if humanity is obviously
gonna be even different it's gonna be
greater than these two yes because they
solve it right because it's a very good
explanation the minimum we are looking
for a minimum difference it has to be
the neighbor to numbers in a substitute
so we can just do this right do this do
this and then we get a minute okay so by
converting to a list right we can use
the you know we can convert into a list
or we can use the generator here the
thing right prefer search
prefer search in order right loot
is not loot
if we have empty nodes you know we've
reached the end I'll just return
we visit the left part first right so
years from
yet from yeah from default search
recursion X such low down left let's
visit the left tree recursively and then
get whatever nose there yeah the year
from that and then now it is time to
visit the calendar right so yeah if we
only eat a single the year load of value
and can you guess what's next
when you visit the left tree you visit
the current now and what should we do
now we did the right tree so yeah
from
that massage was sex right lose don't
write okay
numbers equals this is a return Purpose
with the year so we need to convert it
to
we need to convert it to least year
defensive shoes so basically at least
you would you know travel through using
it in order and after that we can just
do this for you know answer at the
beginning is infinity right Infinity for
I in range
lens
numbers
minus one and answer equals minimum we
also get a minimum answer
absolute value
numbers I minus numbers I plus one right
the neighboring
written answer
okay so if the root is
F if it were given an empty tree then we
will return Infinity if we want to
return zero then we have to check here
we can answer if answer
not equal Infinity otherwise still okay
we're looking for the minimum so we can
say return mean
absolute numbers I minus num I plus one
for I in range length Lambs I minus one
54 equals zero if it's a robust is empty
so the function return mean this
iterable yeah
before
so when the eat when it is empty before
it's zero otherwise will return the
minimum of the all the elements in the
in the either of us this is using the
year right so we still when we go into
the other notes in the tree we still
have to use the additional space which
is o n the tantumplex diesel and N is
the number of nodes in a balances tree
the space complexity is o h h in the
worst case is n
n minus 1 actually so it's n right so H
the height of the tree
because what space complexity for uh
recursion it's according depth right in
what cases H is n minus one it's like a
line
numbers and then we can do this number
extend all the thing yeah all the things
from devices to the left and numbers
append this value and numbers don't
extend all the numbers from like it's
not as elegant as this approach using a
year do we need to store all the numbers
in that array we don't right we just
need to you know get these two numbers
right we don't need to keep tracking all
the numbers in our way how do we find
out the distance this is one is the
minimum
do we need to get all the numbers and
put it down on the list we don't like we
just need to know the previous previous
one remember the previous one okay seven
what's the previous six six go to the
previous three
okay six months I went to the previous
six hey what's the previous seven a
hundred what's the previous nine okay as
long as I know the previous I can get
the distance I have this previous and
the beginning is now right at the
beginning
we need to go to the left tree first
left versus do the left
okay and then now I have to check if the
previous if there's a previous right
obviously at the beginning there's no
previous even the previous then I can
say answer right answer at the beginning
Infinity
answer by the way in order to assess
these two value you have to add the
global or longer okay depending on the
context answer if answer equals the
minimum answer absolute value previous
Top Value minus noodle value right if
laser is the previous value
I get a distance I can compute the
distance and I save the minimum before
going to the right right before going to
the right which no I should set to the
previous
okay now I'm here right look I'm at null
seven
okay and I'm going to travel these three
to the right tree which one is the
previous value seven yeah so I'm here
right I'm about to travel this slide
three so that to the left
is it seven
yeah seven I'm about to travel the right
tree and then I'm in the dude I'm
traveling the right tree so I need to
set the value here the previous value
this is the previous value of whatever
the right show you right if it's a
single node so I'm about to travel to
nine what's the previous value of nine
seven yeah then it makes sense okay I'm
about to travel these three what's the
previous value of these seven seven
right because look eight okay so now I
just have to say previous equals loot
foreign
dude
what's the news about right
and after least I definitely search root
and I already know the mean answer here
they can answer
okay what is an answer
so again yeah we have to visit all the
not the minimum difference of any two
notes in a given binary search tree am I
right so what's any tool
right you have to travel
all the notes to find out the minimum am
I right does it make sense so that means
that the time connects is o n but for
this one the space complexity we don't
need to store the addition uh the
numbers in the additional way right
there is no array here right there's no
here let's do nothing but for this one
the space complexity
this is still oh because it's using
recursion right you can't really say
there's no nothing because there is
something there before you said then no
no think there is something there okay
so even a note is nothing we have to
define the base cases if no if we're
reaching a hundred I know what's next
what is left nothing what is right
nothing right this is the nothing like
for each node
the binary tree for each you know there
are two pointers to the left three and
right three and if it's like this no
this is nothing this is nothing okay
it's nothing but you said they know
nothing so damages okay not nothing
it's not Standard English
okay so how can I say it perfectly
there's no left part of it there's no
right part okay that's it the left tree
and the right tree is empty it's a leaf
now right even you know right right this
nose these are these notes okay what
have you learned today
the minimum difference between
between number in the list in the binary
surgery right yeah and you use a list
yeah sometimes one question why are we
giving a binary substitute what
advantage of it is basically is in order
and that's o-n right if we are not
giving up another Street then we sort it
what's the time complexity oh and Logan
right so look and numbers in the final
three yeah we use the O and performance
in order like give us a salted wrist
right this is Owen but if this is not by
necessary we put it in a list we need to
sort it that's our login right that's
the thing because this is the binary
search tree that's why performing a o n
gives us a 30 piece if it's not a fine
necessary we sort it that would require
over login right doesn't make sense okay
so which method is better this one
another one
yeah because we don't have to put all
the numbers on the list that's a great
advantage of using it right make sense
yeah okay that's it for today bye-bye
bye bye bye