Maybe
what's playing on the tree hey did you
know that five years ago dad had
nothing what's financially uh it's a
tree data structure right it's a data
structure binary tree is a it's like
this is a graph with
maximum two it's dag yeah attack
yeah directly means that some parents
took it okay so it's a data structure
hey that structure is how the computer
how we ask computer how to store the
data in an organized way okay data
structure so financially what kind of
order does the web for search order is
for this particular tree one two three
four five six seven level by level
what's the data structure we need to use
to perform a buffer search
q q yes Q
foreign
Zach what's the zika so one three two
and then the next one will be four five
six seven eleven ten nine okay so what's
this that's not a zigzag it's a line
like one yeah if full had another kid it
would be Sports
seven it's yeah that's what I'm saying
if four had another kid it would be
squashed
is uneven
salmon is a baby
yeah yeah okay so the the key thing here
is that
professor she always from left to the
right right yes
so now I'm just changing the order of uh
every other level okay so one one is
from left to the right
next level is from right to the left the
next one is from left to the right the
next one is from right to the left okay
yes I'm going to return this you know
away other ways so we're going to
pretend this
okay
why is
[Music]
instead of two three that's good
question that's how we perform a zigzag
okay make it make it more interesting so
one from left to the right and the next
one right to the left next one left to
the right next one right to the left
so what kind of the algorithm can we use
to to give this a kind of order
where in the code we need to modify that
to make it dig them you mentioned that
we need to use the Q double ndq first in
first out right
before I prefer search we have a loot
the special case is that if the loot
given is empty if not rooted if loot is
9 we just need to return immediately
okay with an empty this answer equals
this
at the beginning we use the Q equals DQ
at the beginning we put a note in right
there's only one note
okay a kill at the beginning I put a one
in when there is Anime in the queue I
take it out right so but when you want
to take all the notes in the same level
we need to know how many nodes in the
same level which is this lens I can't
remember let's put it in carbon at the
beginning it's empty with these stores
the number of nodes in the center like
one two three four five okay so for
underscore in range and there are nodes
in the camera right and I need to pop it
out
so x equals Q dot we want to take this
element out
what's the message
up left
if we don't specify the lab which side
does it take right side effect and we
look this side is a pen
okay and you've learned a pen on the
left hand side what do we call it this
is a pen
a pen a pen left right A pen left
and this side is top if we don't specify
the left it's on the right okay this is
double ended because we can do this push
and pop on two sides double ended kill
that pop left
okay
current a pen x right then if x start
left we have a left now Q dot append
extra left and we need to do this for
the same for the right tree if there is
the right tree
Q dot upon
x dot y
and return
answer okay so now we have this current
right after these
no we need to push it to answer answer
the apparent carbon node
different answer
this is standard pressure search this is
kind of repeated right if we checking if
let node has the left note we push it
two in it has a rhino push to it right
so we can do a loop for Loop for Kit
yeah kit
in
x dot net x dot y right
and then if the kid is not known if kit
or if kit is not long then we do this Q
dot a pen okay right and that's it yes
so okay so let's emulate these
professors okay I put a one in right I
take everything in a queue how many
notes
now
one right just one right so I take it
out one here
what's the kit of one three three
yeah three and two so I push it two and
three you know right two and three how
many kids are in the queue now
two yeah which are two and three two and
three they are innocent level right so I
take it off what's the kid up too
four or five okay what's kid of three
okay nothing we just skip okay so
basically this is what a professor is on
the left-hand side Lisa keep the order
one two three four five so which line of
code we need to change to make it you
know zigzag coming back to the subject
the second the
last yeah so this one needs to be
reversed but it's not not right this
neither so how do we know if it's an
even land
we check so look at this answer thing
right one
two three
four five right something like that so
we are adding the one two three Low by
row to it so we just have to check the
length of the answer right so if it's
the
if current
elements of answers
is odd number then we need to reverse
this right so we need to reverse these
two three all right but not left right
so how can we do this so we just have to
check change a bit slow right yeah the
answer not a pen current right make
sense so we just have to check if the
length of the answer is an odd number
right if it's an odd number then the
next one I need to I need to reverse it
if it's a odd number
answer a pen
how do you reverse it
how do we reverse current
column color Madison
otherwise answer dot a pen just put it
straight away okay this is only the
difference right we just want to make it
more interesting by reversing the even
row okay
when we have odd number of reverse in
the answer the next one to reverse okay
and then next one not next one could
reverse
okay
one two three four five how do you
reverse it colonialism but if we want to
use the equivalent what kind of eggplant
how do we do verse one two three four
five two points up yeah it's left and
right one five what do we do with one
block
I'll become fire and one line
what do we do
support them
and if they meet today that's it okay
time to next day for Lisa
obviously we need to visit every single
tree every note in a tree right so
what's the name of today
how to make a zigzag okay
[Music]
do we use today
yeah but there's one modification of the
perfect search
I need to reverse the even yeah we need
to reverse it an even number of rows
okay okay let's see for today bye-bye
bye bye