[Music]
that's okay today we talk about the
sorting link list yeah
sourcing link list do you still remember
what's linked list
yeah i talked about that all the time
sought a link list
look at this this is linked is that yeah
why are we doing about link
because it's fine why don't we talk
about something else
we'll talk about something else next
next time okay so look at the link this
you're given this head all right
yes do you still remember that uh a few
weeks ago we talked about munch salt
yes yes yeah yeah we're given a list
[Music]
look this is a list the the difference
between the
link list and the list is that in the
link list you usually given the
hat which you can only travel followed
by head to the end right
but for the list you can
have you can it's because it's stored
continuously in memory so it's a piece
of continuous memory so you can
you can have this random access you can
take
okay i wanted a third element then i can
retrieve it
but if you want to retrieve the third
element of the linked list
you need to oh and it needs to take over
in time right because it
needs to follow from the beginning right
but the principle to sort
the linked list and then to sort uh
uh a list is quite similar for a link
for us
for sorting a list we can do the merge
store remember the merge store
so what do we do about the magisto we
imagine
we cut into half right yeah we cut into
half and then we
saw these two and then we merged it
together right
so here it's the same so how do we cut
it into half
why don't we learn how to measure link
how do we charge it for do number we
[Music]
so we know the middle yeah so we can cut
in half
yeah and then we can sort these two link
list yeah once the tool increase is
sorted
then what happens we can merge it yeah
remember we also talked about how too
much to
sort this right
like a list and another list so we have
a point if these both are
sorted we have pointers and then we
compare the elements of these two
pointers
and then we move forward each time right
remember yes yeah
so the complexity either one no
i won again i won is there one
no of course no no again yeah oh and
logan
don't make a guess oh one is i it's very
rare i mean you do you get it
over means constant means that your
complexity your writing time does not
change if your
linked list is grow as much as possible
right
but for this one we cut into half and
then we smudge it
right yeah cut into half is on
right and then
divide and conquer and then salt it
so we actually we divide and then we
need to
we divide it every time log divided by
half is log n
so all together is over and again okay
yes
yeah okay so so i'm i'm not going to
write
the detail for finding the uh
the only only one difference is finding
the middle yeah
previously you want to find the meter
right you have
uh you have to
um you have two pointers yes one
walk twice as fast as the other one
right like that
okay then here and then and then here
yeah
but when you when this is slow it's the
middle
so now we actually need to disconnect it
right do you understand we actually need
to disconnect it
so what we will do is we return
slow dot next we return this node
but we also no dot next equals num so we
disconnect it
so we it becomes two linked list
yes now once we have little increase
then we can
sort it until we i know we merge it okay
so
what i'll do is here define
thought sort of increase yeah which
given the
head okay so now
look so all we do if
head is null
or head dot next
is now return what
because if it's a head it's not nothing
or
it's a single note we just written it
there okay
then we have a note now we need to get
the middle of the one right so now we
what we do we got to meet equals
uh let's say get mean okay let's have a
function can meet
head but this function does not simply
return the middle of it it also
disconnect it
right yeah we need to make sure of that
and then
we have a meat we have had now what we
do
we we said meat equals salt
meat right
so we're calling this recursively
sorting the meet
the link another link list the half of
linked list
and now we also call the first
uh pet okay let's call it head it's we
had equal assault head
okay so now the head and meat are two
salted least right
then what we do return
[Music]
and
yeah yes does that make sense doesn't
make sense yes does it make sense
yes look that's it makes sense okay tell
me next
okay so now uh any question before we
move on to coding
no no no
turn this off wait wait wait i do it i
don't
please i don't
how do you turn the thingy off i
turn it i turn it up uh can you um
okay this is a bit
is it oh
now
good okay good
yeah that's good
wait
really
why at least the keyboard is still
showing
ah yeah perfect okay perfect
that's fine so is it clear yeah this is
clear
what
what is this keyboard is still
showing just give me a second to
get rid of the keyboard
okay okay so now
let me let me turn off these things so
so it's good okay so now
wow
wait wait no i think i think there's a
problem let me do it
[Music]
yeah that's better let's do it better
okay
okay okay
yeah that's good um that's good uh
so now these we can still use this print
this
and then remember the last time we
talked about the case
the case heads to the last step
do you still remember we don't need this
let me just remove this
okay so now we have a note from one to
ten okay one to ten but
let's let's do a run uh
let's first of all let's first of all um
[Music]
create a note from the scratch okay so
let's see uh
data equals uh just give us some random
number
okay okay
and then let's uh let's let's
define uh data okay
data okay so now if we print the
list so well we can have
if we print at least type message is
just something okay
let's see
oh so nine number nine i i have a
it doesn't look like any problems
nine number nine return new node
is complaining this one
why you can find this one i will not
change it
what i said inconsistent use of tabs and
ah inconsistent
use of tab nine number line
so i i will mess around i i messed
around with the with the tap
so i need to so now
it's this is tap
i i use the tap instead of space
what caption space in the initiation
nine number nine we cannot why what is
it why it does not like it
[Applause]
should be all right what
i don't get it just
why it doesn't like it ah
that's so weird
uh so anything
i
return new node return
that's two space two tap
two tab
what i don't get it why he doesn't like
it
look when you print it yeah it's all
together yeah
so
so look it's there's something wrong
with this one
[Music]
and another thing is another thing is
these
i hope this is okay
add the note it's the other one
ah i don't get it
that's that's i think there's some uh
issues with the
formatting but let's try let's try
just to type it again and remove all of
it
and now we can remove 10 to 15 times
what
uh
but the first one is the ah all turns
white yeah yeah it's very strange
why why is that
it's kind of very strange to find
itself
so the next note equals 19
and then 5 to 8 i remove it
wait i i i spotted some arrows there's
extra space here
this time should be all right right
aha okay so now it's better
for cat okay it's very strange you know
because this is not a very
uh user friendly
editor so it's so you don't see any
leisure space
okay so now this is random yeah it's not
sorted right the link list is not sorted
you see
yeah now let's do the coding
so in order to do this uh we can do this
look this is before salty yeah
saute now we need to
uh first of all
after salty okay let's change this to
after salt
okay let's see me let's do it first
which is the
called uh actually we
actually we can divide it here look um
define this in ethno and then we can
also
say we can define it here define
what uh actually let's write it outside
okay which is clear
much more clear okay we don't want to
mess with the cast let's see
uh define merge a
and b to link list do you still remember
how to do this
we do a strumming head
which is what note
okay and then he will stop me
y a and b
you can tell me what to do with this one
if a
the value is smaller than b of value so
what to do
we need to use the value a right yeah
another x a equals eight or next no
okay am i right you still remember
how to merge it and s
p the next note will be the b right
b will be equals next note alright
and then p equals p to the next note
move to the next
and then if a is still left
we can do it next note would be a if b
p p dot next no
equals p and then return what
dummy the next right okay this is to
tell me because we are not using it yeah
do you get it we're not using it we're
just using dummy the next now
okay let's try the mid meat okay
get me yeah ahead we want to get the
meter
me down now tell me how to do it
fast so wait wait uh
if a head is numb our head the next is
numb
yeah if it's just a single note or
nothing we just return ahead okay
fast slow equals head head right
why fast and fast the next note
then fast equals what
the next note stop next now
and then slow slow slow
that's it because slow slow node will
only work once one step at a time
and then return slow right but before
that we need to
let's call it break meat because we're
going to break it
into break at the middle part yeah so we
need to recall the previous note
previous note before let's do note so we
call it pre
equals nine yeah and then before we
change it to slow equals no
dot next note we do this
previous equals low right yeah so
preview is the slow
source previous note and then previous
note down next
what would be next note will be let's
break it yeah
now right now we'll change though am
right
okay now how to we have a break and we
have a merge
and then like let's saute it sauce
head it had his mouth
or her legs no it's now
three times
meat equals break meat breaking meat
land we break a meal yeah now we have
release then head
head will become salt
wait wait wait we need to solder solid
speed as well right
yes all right and then we can return
it so the complexities then we can do
this
equals soft head right
and then oh i i think i i think
here okay let's let's see if it works
okay
oh look it's sauteed yeah you see it's
salty
got it yeah this is all here
does it make sense so we actually just
need you you you already learn how to
merge two soft deletes yeah this is
you previously know how to do it right
[Music]
and okay and then you also need know how
to break
get the middle right the only new thing
here is we have at least previous
pointer
so previous is always once no before
let's know right
look at 953 look line 53
previous no the next note equals now
what does it do here eric
previously
yeah what does it do here
so you find the middle of the blinker is
what does it do
the slow is the middle of linked list
the previous note is the slowest
previous note so previous stop next note
equals now what does it do here
so 953 what does it mean
[Music]
yeah what are we trying to do here
what's the function name called line 44
yeah what does it do
define the different way commit head
then the 9 15 44 to 54 what does it do
actually
ryan any of you is
getting the middle now and and what and
do one thing
one thing previously i told you about
the aggregate to get the middle note
which is without the line 48
and 9 51 and line 53
now i added this line 9 48
9 51 and line 53 what does it do here
we have a meter node and we have a node
before the meter node and now we are
setting the
previous node of the meter node dot next
note equals
noun so basically we are what
we are breaking it right we are breaking
this
in the middle part right so you are
turning into two notes
two linkages am right yeah okay
so do you understand what 953
yeah and then now when we break the note
look
when we break the note here breaking the
note
then we can sort it right let's analyze
sorted
and then we saw the first half this is
960.
we saw the second half which is 9
59 and then we merged two thought like
this which you already know how to do
that
is in here line 27 to 942 okay
got it any questions
are you sure you understand because
every time i ask you you seems
not understanding you sure
yeah if you have any questions you need
to tell me okay
i probably will come up with an exam
yeah for you to answer okay
do you get it okay you can do a bit more
dancing
okay that's it