what's this I'm trying to go die okay so
duh what's that area of China how do you
calculate the area of triangle
huh sorry so you pretended the rectangle
and then you turn the lamp by the width
and then and then plant those together
and then divide it okay okay so okay so
let's take a look at these rectangles
rectangle if this is a this is B what's
the size what's the area
you know if we move this here
like move it here
so does the area change
what's the size of this so what did I do
because yeah because you're just cutting
off
the area is like like the area or like
how like the okay so you know like
shrinking something and then putting
something you're moving the same thing
like yeah look at what I did I move
right so this one no no you're not yeah
you're not it's Landing yet
um yeah you're just cutting off this bit
and moving it yeah yeah that's what I'm
saying it's not changing that you move
it like that
oh okay yeah there's a slight difference
yes yes because if you move like that
then these will you know move down right
yeah but I'm saying this this will hide
is not changing so it basically is just
cutting so let's like every does not
change that's a good observation so if
this is a what's the size of triangle
uh eight times eight times B divided by
two what's a was B the length I'm always
the lens so okay so look yeah what's
this
all you can do
or you can do it anyway I see okay so
okay so look at this one right so if
this is a this is B right yeah this is a
look at this is basically it's half of
these so what's the shape of this
what do you call this parallelogram
Paragon parallelogram parallelogram it
has two sides of uh which are parallel
okay okay
uh like a word
okay so yeah you know right so it's
basically the side of one side plus its
height h y so is half of 8 times
I'm saying a times B divided by two and
you're saying equals a what's B
yeah that's how we get it from here
you're saying like the height
but I'm saying will then come with it so
your comes only is the rectangle right
rectangle square is a rectangle right
and then we kind of cut in a little bit
parallelogram for parallelogram where
you can cut it in half then it's
triangle right that's how we get it okay
yeah okay so that's the basic okay right
here like you're doing
you're doing like like this yeah for an
equilateral triangle you make it a
parallelogram and and then that makes it
um a quadrilateral yeah but if you have
a right angle you can you make it a
square uh yeah yeah any arbitrary
triangle yeah we can fight any point any
point here and if I'm telling you the
size of this is four this is two this is
three and the question is what's the
size of this
so by the way for given arbitrary
triangle ABC we have a formula to
calculate the area right but we're going
to talk about that maybe in the future
okay it's three full to the area yeah
the size of area how big is this area
yeah of course
okay okay so yeah bear in mind this is
the question okay so let's look at this
I need triangle right any triangle if I
find this on any point any point here
right yeah okay I draw this
okay if this is a this is B this is C
this is p okay we'll see
this is the point okay it divides this
into two triangles am I right what's the
average size of ABC equals half of
this
is PC times the height
okay this height is e okay so this size
this area side is equal half of PC times
AE this is the lens of BC
so it's this page oh our food is
okay so it's p okay I put this okay it's
PC the levels of PC times the length of
a okay and what's the area of a c d
size of ACC half of c times d a c d the
length times
which height
uh is it AC the blind
AE okay the size of ABC is PC times AE
because this is the height divided by
two and the size of ACD is CD times the
height divided by two so the size of ABC
divided by the size of ACD
right so it's this right it's this look
they got half they got half they got AE
they got AE which got cancer so it is
actually the same as BC the size of BC
divides the size of CD the size of this
ABC
divided by the size of ACP to triangle
is the same as PC divided by CD if I'm
telling you
this size is one PC this here is one
here is two here is two the area of ACD
this triangle on the right is twice
as thick as the ABC remember we talked
about motor car simulation
which is basically we want to calculate
the PI right so we've asked computers to
generate points I know we count how many
points in a circle and how many points
all together so the ratio is this bit
divided by line we can do this the same
but it's it's a it's just an idea not
maybe not easy to implement so we can
generate the points and put it in this
picture and we count how many points
I don't know why why okay and then we
count how many points
falling into this right but it's hard to
test in in here right so this is just an
idea multicolor simulation okay that's
coming back to do this mathematics
okay
how about E5 that's fine that's fine
it's just number five hundred and six
actually
okay so how about look if I
connect these
cut in half
if I say this is X this is y
so look at this it's listed and this bit
right two triangles
this
please okay 3 plus X this is the size of
it right
divided by y 3 plus X is the size of
this right divided by size of Y is it
equal the least length divided by this
length all right this triangle divided
by this triangle is equals DC divided by
CD right so it's equal to least divided
this it's the same thing right it's the
same thing and look at this cylinder
there are two right four divided by two
is equal to least divided by this
so they both
equals to least divided by light so it
means that that equals four divided by
two all right
now I I have an equation of X and Y but
that's not enough let me repeat it again
okay
this
4 divided by 2 the area is equal to
least divided by left the length of
least divided by left
3 plus X
divided by Y is it the same as least
divided by that so they both equals to
this divided by that so I can put it
together
equals c so a equals c all right
2 plus y which is this bit
divided by X
is it equals to least divided by that
yeah this is divided by because this one
4 divided by 3 is equal to this divided
by that
so the policy equals to this divided by
completely together
how do you solve this
in you know how to solve it the a
divided by b equals equals c divided by
B how do we solve this
is it the same thing as a times D equals
B times C okay A times T equals B times
c b and t not equal to zero
mathematics dividing by zero not defined
one divided by zero notified we don't
know the answer okay it's zero no it's
not defined mathematically notified
that's a divided by P equals c divided
by three learn how to make it multiply
as long as B and D are not zero we can
do 80 equals b c right B is times this
six plus two x equals release times this
or what four times x equals
six plus three one right two equation
two unknown we can solve the value
we times two okay we times two here why
we need to times 2 because I see the 4X
here there are only two x here so I
times two on both sides so is twelve
plus four x equals a y subtract
subtract 4X from this right so it's 12
equals
5y minus six right five y minus six
five y equals eighteen
y equals
y equals three point six okay and then
we don't know why let's put it back six
plus three times three point six divided
by four
today's weather
4.2
x equals 4.2 so what's the size of this
X Plus y
X Plus y equals 7.8
to sum up okay so we what we have
learned today we covered the how do we
get the area of triangle which is the
equals to the length of one side and the
height on each side right so it's half
of a times H H is the height to the to
left side you pick based on that we can
say here this is arbitrary triangle the
area of ABC divided by ACP is the same
as BC divided by CB okay and based on
that we can solve this mathematic
question any question so far
okay that's it for today bye-bye bye bye