right
so just imagine we have a great
n times n great
not a loopy Q right yeah
this is one times one times one
for example if this number is one that
means I put one Cube here if you look at
Infinity wave
how can I draw it because it's like a
solar panel so look this is a two degree
a little bit Q right can you give me a
loopy kill okay
thank you yeah yeah this is perfect this
is
[Music]
like last time okay this is one times
one times one that's a great yeah turn
it this way
okay so if this is one so it means
actual one here if this is two
I mean I put this one two on top right
if this is three I put three skills one
two three make sense
okay okay so
so let's say if I just put one Cube on
that how many surface how many surface
service is that six six good counting
the top and bottom as well okay so if I
put two cubes on top of each other so
one Cube here how many surface
do you count these two as one or two
or two question yes two but yeah without
the surface they they're the same like
levels yeah yeah but it's different but
the thing is that internal one right if
we have another Cube on Top This surface
and the surface of another do you have
another one are you sure it's better to
have the same size the cube so I can I
can draw I'm not very good at drawing
but if you have
like this is this good enough that's
good that's good okay okay so yeah I
will have six which is one time so I
remember all the cubes is one one okay
this is yeah no this is two but this if
you count these substitute is six and
this is basically the same but with it
yeah okay okay yeah you understand okay
so look how many surface
first six how many surface how many
services that's right yeah because these
two are gone right okay yeah okay
look
they're very one two three four so
they're eight right
yeah eight and then nine ten okay that
was mine that one's Eric's so if I put
another one on top you know how to do it
right
okay
so how many surfaces if you put it uh
horizontal each other
one two the same the same yeah the same
okay so how many service if you put
another one up here
um
[Music]
like this
exactly yes
how many service
ten minus one
Plus
is it 14. we want to call the surface
for example like if I put one Cube here
two cubes here
thank you okay one kill here
one kill here two kill here how many
servings okay how many surface
you can't how many uh so one two three
four five six seven eight nine ten
eleven twelve thirteen fourteen fifteen
sixteen sixteen how do you calculate
this wait
we know
[Music]
yeah
no that is ten yes and then we add one
on top this one surf is like this is
gone Okay so
and then we have five okay yeah is it
five there's five surfaces left
so is so is nine plus five it's not it's
not ten because this one is gone
okay okay interesting okay so okay so
you know this one this is six right
yeah
and these is ten all right yeah and this
is
fourteen three times four one two three
four five okay
yeah so
if if they are n how many
yeah
okay I told me this because it's too
much
this is
yeah it's basically okay so if they are
cute
and cute what's the formula if n cubes
what's what's the service I need one the
answer is six n equals two the answer is
ten n equals three the answer is
fourteen the N is four
yes so how do we know it's adding four
so you always have this the top one and
the bottom one and you always add
yes
one top one bottom and you have more of
these how many how many of these which
is Hawaii four four around yes four
around so what's left what's that it's n
what's the number
foreign
cubes
so how many surface does it contribute
four times eight cubes right this is the
formula right
we are n cubes in the service
is four times n plus top and bottom
how about by putting together to each
other horizontally like the here is one
and here let's do
something you know this right you know
how to calculate this one at a time
right one at a time if I think putting
together is it 14. yeah I'm not looking
for a exact number I'm just looking for
the how do we get it it doesn't need to
tell me that because we know those two
ten
since we know uh we didn't know a cube
has six surfaces to connect it to the
other part when it connects the
intersection
so it's subtract one surface like there
yeah subtract you'll mentioned a good
point subtract okay look I'm putting the
cubes here right put a lot of kills
if we look at each number you know
vertically right this is two cubes yeah
this is two cubed this is five cubes we
know how to get it service individually
on its own right but the thing is that
when you put it together like this is
one putting one here and this is two
here so they are internet they are
connecting we need to minus subtract
this part MRI yes
so we know how to subtract right how
many look here this is one this is two
so how many surface we need to subtract
just imagine here like one thing the one
to the two yeah yeah it's one here is
two now how many surface we need to
subtract two yes because you put two
together is two right so okay if they
are
three here and there are two here how
many service do we need to subtract four
yeah so how do we get a four I counted
oh
from
[Music]
nowhere you said this is small yes
you're all right okay how about yeah how
about this is three how many service
[Music]
you can come yeah okay one no one two
three four five six seven why is it
seven no I mean subtract to subtract oh
subtract I I think this bit I added this
bit and I need to subtract this I just
asked you how many I need to subtract
this
okay okay
ah okay I see what you mean no no okay
so uh yeah my questions are not very
clear okay so what I meant is that we
already know these according to that
right so this is how many three is
fourteen right fourteen right am I right
yeah fourteen
service of this clip plus 14 of service
so this week but they are common parts
in the middle which we shouldn't config
we need to minus something so how many
we need to mind the minimum yes it's a
minimum
and isn't it the towers uh minus one
because three minus one is two and
there's two there
no I just will say this bit this bit
yeah this bit yeah no so how many of
these
power minimum there are three towers
here there are three towers out here so
how many I need to subtract from 14 plus
14. two of each right one two three four
five six you need substance six right
easy times three times two right doesn't
make sense
okay so here a hundred here is a hundred
imagine this is a hundred this is 200
how many I need to subtract subtract
okay just this paid just this common
part how many I need to subtract
is it 200
and 532 how many I need to subtract
[Music]
that's right yes that's what I want to
hear okay so this is Horizon mentally
right look listen I'm considering here
one here too now I need to subtract this
bit right yeah the minimum of it okay
okay so now here two and four I need to
do the same right
this is vertically and this is
horizontally yes yes yes but this is the
three dimensional just imagine this is a
three dimensional I put a one Cube here
I put a two Cube on top of here I put
the two Cube on top here I know the
contribution for each color right each
top you place a formula right but I need
to subtract this common part right these
are hidden these are hidden all right
this makes sense now if
and for this Edge combat Edge right if
there's a number above it
then I need to subtract this part if
it's a lumber on the left then I need to
subtract this part right
We compare the minimum
okay so now is three towers
three towers I need to subtract six yeah
two dollars I need to subtract
four okay so how many I need to Snapchat
here
how many I need to subtract here
how many I need to subject here yeah how
many I need to subscribe here
how many ironies are there
eight yeah yeah well done now you get it
yeah so the idea is to add it all
together and subtract these three speed
has two sides either on the top or on
the left F and answer at the beginning
is yellow
fourth row in range
and
for column in range
and this is liquid Okay g okay now
answer plus equal G
r c
this is the number right and
the contribution is this one times four
plus two if R is bigger than zero we
need to minus subtract if a row if it's
from the second row right
this is ah
this is C if it's from the second row I
need to subtract this common part from
here all right answer minus equals the
minimum of G
R C and G R minus 1C
times what's the number here
yes and if
if it's
the second column to the right you see
bigger than zero answer minus equal mean
G R C and G are C minus one right C
minus one is the number on the left and
times
two and return
answer I I give you this to count
it's hard right it's hard to imagine you
need to count but the idea becomes
simple if we add the contribution for
nqs
color Harmony service
is n times four plus two
plus two plus one here plus one here if
we add these but we also need to get rid
of the common parts right so the common
path here this is three this is four how
many we need to subtract six
sticks for here and how many minutes are
here
and square easy
n Square o n Square n times n o n Square
o n where n is the number of the
of the sales in this grid okay so what
have you learned today
about this uh we have
um
this platform for cubes to go on yeah
kids and we want to count we want to
count the surfaces number of services
number of services
and what's the idea how do we do it
what's the idea counts so
[Music]
common common part which is which is
which is the minimum times two minimum
times two yeah so look at here minimum
is one and one minimum is one times two
because here is one here is one times
two okay if there are another one here
minimum is still one right it's times
two okay so the idea is that to add the
numbers
this is uh six plus six minus
two make sense yeah this is the idea
okay
okay that's it for today bye-bye bye bye
bye