oh no this is a square actually
Square so this is 90 degrees Each corner
obviously this side is one one one one
this size two two two okay so guess
what's the question
what's the side
which one
smooth Square which is slightly okay
yeah that's good
so most of you know this is a square
because because they will decide because
well if those questions is wobblies
because look all of these are the same
like one two one two one two these are
the same yeah
these are the same look these right and
these right this is two this is two this
is one this is one and this angle is the
same as end so these two triangles are
identical so that means this angle is
the same as this angle all right
yeah these angle plus this angle how
much
if in this triangle 90 degrees all right
this class list is 90 and I'm just
saying this is equal this all right yeah
so this plus this is 90 degrees right
yeah so 100 minus 90 this is 90. okay
you're right yeah yeah but this anger is
not the same as this anger this anger is
the same as this angle makes it yeah
look yeah yeah but I'm saying like it
feels good five then then that is 45 and
then and then that one will be 40.
that's not 45 because this is one this
is two it's 45.
if it's 45 in what cases it's 45 this is
two this is two so it's in a meter
in the middle then it's 45 right because
in the right triangle
if this side equals this side
then this is 45 degree I'm right okay
but if this is not the same this is not
45 if this side is not equal to this
angle is not the same these two ends
added up together 90 degree okay yeah
okay very good very good okay we have to
ask ourselves why is it Square okay so
you prove your point this is a square
okay so we want to calculate the size of
the square so what's the strategy so you
figure out the area yes the area so you
need to find out you need you need to
find out
this line so you can just basically
count it by four okay to find out that
line you have to find out the triangle
is like here you need to find out this
one
okay so actually there was a move hey
because this is too easy right if I'm
saying like this is two this is one I
can get this right
this is a this is p this is a 90 degree
what's this
if this is C if this is the right angle
this is a this is B this is right angle
90 degrees right
you said right okay okay
APC what's DC
remember a squared plus b square equals
c Square this is very important right if
this is three this is four what's this
five yeah okay remember that very very
important okay
okay
are you confident no it doesn't look
like
okay so let's remove the black lines
okay how about how about that that point
to D
wait yeah you're right yeah uh
the point today
yeah yeah yeah yeah
okay so easily is
slightly different right previous one
that was easy because you can usually
you can decide if they see the square
will be C square right that's the area
of that square but for this one is this
a rectangle you have to
where
to remove it with a rectangle you need
to prove that it has 90 degree a right
angle yeah so do we know this is this a
yeah
uh
this is
a right angle why is this a red line
because it's a triangle and it's like
this
how do you know this is a triangle this
is the thing how do you I can visually
see it this is mathematic but the way
you see it you need to prove it okay so
we don't know maybe you know this is the
homework for you today okay because this
is half this is half
why is it half because it's half no it's
not half it's not half the only thing
you can do is that because this is one
this is two the whole size three all
right this is one this is two this is
one so this is the three one this is
three one so these two triangles are a
straight identical right it's the same
three identical all right so
yeah but so what does it mean so it
means that it means this angle is the
same as this angle right yeah so these
endoplasm this angle is 90 degrees so
this is
identity right if it's 90 degrees this
is
I just prove it cut it look don't get it
you don't get okay okay
look at this this
yeah please try and all right is it the
same as this triangle
yeah because this side is three this
side is three this style is one this
size one right and this is the right
angle this is the line all right yes
this angle is the same as this angle
right yeah
makes us
okay so this and the plus this angle is
90 degrees this small angle plus this
small angle is a 90 degree one right
yeah I just said this angle is equal
this angle right yeah so this angle
France this angle is what
yeah so this is 90 degrees right yeah
okay so this is 90 degrees this is 90
degrees this is 92 in the same right
understand because I can prove it
similarly the angle inside but
in inside the rectangle is also 90
degrees at least
one inside okay because this is a
straight line if one of the angle is 90
degrees it's just said this is 180 minus
90 this must be 90. yeah okay we want to
calculate this area the size
so your strategy is calculate this side
right yeah
that could work but what's the other
strategy because it's hard maybe hard to
calculately side right if you calculate
at least it's C then C Square do you do
something with the numbers no no just
forget about the number I will just say
we want to calculate at least how many
ways we can calculate this one way which
is very good is calculate one side
because this is a square right yeah you
see the square of the tangle yeah we
have to prove is a square obviously
right yeah because the numbers outside
please because mathematics you have to
be very very accurate
active Square first of all you have to
prove this square right
in order to use these right now this is
a square right and each side we know so
we know the size of everything
and we learn the size of everything we
just have to get rid of
the outside to the subtract many sense
okay so how many triangle we need to
subtract
therefore right look which which side do
we need to subtract four times in this
one this one one
two
three
four all right yeah right so we just
need to figure out this triangle right
the size of it yeah yeah but if you can
that's basically doing the same thing
because you have to figure out the
triangles
yes you have to pick up we're trying
Booth to subtract it so it's so
basically will be as e as uh easy as
you're figuring out the side it's pretty
similar pretty similar but this is the
opposite right you're saying calculating
this which is nice yeah I'm saying that
I want to calculate this side and I want
to do this yeah if you want to calculate
that triangle you need to subtract it
okay so you have to figure out the
triangle as well as in the other method
that I was saying so yeah you you'll
figure it out one side that's right okay
so the answer is sabcd the whole thing
minus four times
this moment let's say this is e okay 4
times s a b e right s a b is this one
right four times does it make sense
this one is three times three nine right
yeah we know that right yeah
this triangle a b c
this one
p e f
it's just bigger it's just bigger
similar okay if I'm telling you the
angle a is the same as energy the angle
B the same as angry then these two
triangles are similar what's similar so
you just shift it Transit transition
or you rotate
right and rotate
why it could be flipped
you could be Millions oh yeah yeah okay
or another way is a scale right you make
it because think this is called similar
triangle if two triangles are similar if
a b to d e is K right if this side
divided by this side is K if this K is
number okay so we know that all the
corresponding size is K
the ratio is okay and the angles
corresponding angles are the same angle
p is the same as angle e the angular C
is the angular F right
or even a medium if I pick the middle of
one side this is Mu pick the number of
one side and okay so this is called the
medium
a n
divided by T M is also okay how about
the size of ABC area divided by size of
uh d e f what's this if it's similar
it's two similar so what should I put
here is it something to do with K yes of
course
the size of the ABC is
PC times this height right times this
height the size of t f is T times this
height this is K this is K this is K
this is K so times together K Square
okay yeah
okay this is called similar triangle
Okay so similar triangle there are a
couple of ways to determine two angles
angle angle if there are two times the
two angles are same they are similar is
three sides
are proportional or the same then they
are similar
and another one if two sides and then
corresponding angle are the same then
they're similar for example look this is
the trend line
if I draw a parallel line okay this
triangle this angle is the same as this
triangle this angle this angle parallel
right this angle is the same this angle
is the same as this so This triangle is
similar to this triangle okay
is the same as this angle
this side
to this side is the same as this side to
then these two triangles are similar
right yeah how about
SSA this is not so these two are
obviously not similar right
this a here this B this C this D
and this angle is the same this angle is
the same okay this angle
yeah this angle is the same but a to c
is the same as B to D
this angle is the same as this angle
they are obviously not similar
make sense it's just like the top part
is the same yeah look at this one I can
I can rotate these
there's a possibility this angle right
this angle is the center but I'm just
saying look for example here right I can
put it this side for example let's just
compare when they are equal right this
is the same as this right and then I'm
just saying this angle is the same as
this one so look here
yeah all right I can put it here
but within this one I get
longer I mean I can just put it here
yeah
the bottom line is longer than the
longer
no it's no longer it's the same it's the
same
yeah I just put it here when you do like
meow yeah
it's possible to find these right to the
center right it's geometry so this is
not right it's just these three cases
a right triangle what do you call the
triangle with the right and what do you
call it all right
if one of the angle is the same then
obviously it's two angles right that are
similar I if okay this is a special case
if one side the longest side
longest side and one of the other side
are proportional they are similar
identical triangles are similar right
yes identical trials mean okay so we
want to find out this right these two
triangles are similar right similar
right they're actually identical
identical triangles are similar I want
to calculate an area of these right at
least I want to know this and I want to
know this right because this is the
right angle I if I know this I notice I
know the area right if the right angle
triangle if this is a this is p the size
is a times B divided by two right yeah
so I want to calculate at least I want
to calculate
right so we know this side right along
this side yeah inside
this is uh let's put it f d f what's DF
DF is it equals to look look at this
triangle uh triangle okay
dfy this is T this is FY so this this
side
this side is one right we know right
yeah
80. this this 18 83 right yeah yeah so
this side we know right a squared plus b
squared equals c squared so a squares
nine plus one ten ten Square so this one
is square root of 10 right DF is square
root of ten doesn't have no
sorry 80. we want to calculate a g and
GT right a g and GD okay A G and GT this
triangle right is similar to this
triangle so this these
these two these to let is similar to
this to that three two two lists right
yeah so equals three two this this is
the longest side which which we just get
it which is a square root of 10.
okay so we can get this AG what's a g a
g is
is three divided by square root of 10
right okay now we just need to calculate
PG right but look at this the triangle
this side is three right this side is
three and a g three over ten right three
over ten square root of ten and I can
get these right
this is the three this is three over
square root ten what's this side
Three Square minus B squared equals nine
divided by ten
so equals this is nine right
81 81 over 10 81 over 10 square root
okay so what's this is
square root of ten nine right okay so
this side equals this so t g
equals that
okay a g equals what this one
so what's the area these times this
divided by 2 right
square root of 10 times 10 yes
pen
27 divided by two
Point twenty okay and I need to times
four times right times four times
makes sense because this is just one I
need to transform all right so this is
27 over 5.
5.4 5.4 yeah okay 5.4 the overall is
nine nine minus 5.4
6 okay this is Panzer the area this size
is 3.6
okay so to sum up we want to pick a
release speed the first of all we need
to prove this is a square how do we
prove this is a square I just tell you
right because this triangle is the same
as this triangle so this angle is the
same as this angle this plus this is 90
degrees therefore this first list is 90
degree and in this triangle to end up
adding up 93 so this must be 90 degrees
so this 90 degree because it's straight
line so this must be knighted quick and
I can prove using a similar way these
are 90 degrees right your approach is
the second least bit right which is all
right my Approach is to calculate one
time and multiply four times four times
and subtract from the entire Square
which is nine okay so how do we
calculate this we want to know this side
and this side right because the for a
given time if this is a this is B the
area is a times B divided by two right
how do we get this side we use the
similar triangle yeah talk about similar
triangle two angles are the same similar
three sides as proportional all the same
similar
two sides and their corresponding angles
are the same similar okay this is the
base of three cases okay an identical
triangles are similar okay and using
that we can do this equation right this
side as to this side right because it's
the same and this side to this side is
the same as this side to this side and
along this side we know we notice a
equation and this is a this is B this is
C 90 degree so a square plus b square
equals c squared right so once we can
decide now we can use the same thing we
know this C we know this a and we know
this B right because C Square minus a
square equals P Square right and then if
we Square it okay what have you learned
today
about
the area so let me learning about this
this square the square and there's a
small square inside it s two and we want
to find the area of that smaller Square
so so to find out we
real your approach is is to find a area
of a triangle of it on the outside of
the smaller square and times it by four
and subtract it from the area of the
whole Square we know that it's a
rectangle as the a as the as the square
it's the corners is obviously 90 degrees
and that corner like where like a is
and the triangle a a to f a to d decimal
triangle is identical to the D to one so
we know that those two is 90 degrees and
then since it does a straight line down
from a to
so we know that it's 90 degrees so
there's you know just a rectangle a
square is a type of rectangle just
special that's good thank you bye-bye
foreign