something language structure something
language what's cute anybody where queen
queen
structure query the language okay
clearing structure clear language
we know we learned this before right
yeah
it is
language
or somebody prefer extend the query
language you can think of it as a
programming language there's a scripting
language that allow us to interact with
database so let's say we have a table
what's Taylor
how to explain okay that's fine so the
table is a thing that has four loads and
you put food on it and eat and sometimes
you work with the emperor flowers at the
right and the table cover that's good
explanation for another table okay table
in database my database database can
consist of one or more tables right day
tables are the container that we put the
data let's say name right we have a name
and we have a score okay this is just
the column head
okay so now here is the data from here
is the data so we can say Eric
score 100.
and then
Ryan score of a thousand okay okay and
then Mommy
500 okay 500 that's it okay so this is
the table the third is called okay I
don't I don't mind okay okay so look
apart from the first
first row this is the metadata this is
we specify the name of the columns right
the name of the column so this column
the name the First Column the name the
second column the score which is the
integer the First Column is a string
right and then we have a four records in
this table make sense this is uh how we
store the data in an organized way in a
database so if we want to get the
highest score
high is the distance go so we can say
select
Max right Max this is a function Max
score
here right from
if this is the table name right for each
table we give them let's say this table
we call it
data okay data database
score from data and then it will return
return a thousand that's it yeah okay so
another way of doing is that select
score from data all the
by
score we're going to solve a score in
descending order by before is ascended
indecent in order but we want to return
the first record so we can say limit
one that's it how about if we want to
get the second highest score
which is 500 okay look remember they are
a thousand they are twice what I mean
the second highest this thing what's
this thing this thing is another word
for unique
okay so you want to return the second
highest distance score record which is
500 how would you write it any idea
I mean forget about the SQL so
but you need me to you will return a
thousand a thousand it's not 500. in
this table how would you know 500 is the
second highest
okay let me give you
highest okay with this information how
do you get 500.
so I already tell you a thousand this is
the highest score in this table so I
want you to find out 500 how would you
do that you do the thing there yeah yeah
but ignore a thousand we're done ignore
a thousand okay so that's it so
you know I already tell you how to get
the highs right which is a thousand
right and then you can do this again but
on filter out a thousand because I said
this thing okay this thing a thousand a
thousand could have multiple requests
Mexico
Max score wrong and we don't need to
solve okay
look let me do the highest right select
Max
score
from
beta this is the highest one right this
is the highest right I just have to do
this again look I I do this like select
select Max I want to do the max again
Max score okay
from
data
but I want to add one more criteria
which is where
the data
well it's not in not in here and that's
it this B is a thousand right we just
get it this is a sub query sub query
this is a thousand no I'm doing this
again select Max score from data where
data not in a thousand right if it's not
in Thousand you can say not in Thousand
or not equal right or you can say
smaller than right smaller 20 30 you
know 300 400 right so what does it do
look where first of all you will get
this you will run this sub query which
retains a thousand right we know this is
a thousand
and then
where could it right you would run
through the tables and
filter out those records which is we
where data is not in or smaller than
that smaller than a thousand right
smaller and a thousand four hundred is
more than seven twenty is smaller than
thousand so your handle is smaller than
a thousand but a thousand is not smaller
than a thousand okay so this is the use
case that we have a SQL with the sub
query and to get the second highest this
thing highest okay another way when I
select Celeste score
from
data order we need to sort it right
order by
score
then
limit
one offset we want to skip
two if I we have to this thing we don't
put the distance because we could have
multiple a thousand
we could have multiple thousand and we
want to only return the unique
okay this is another way to to get it
okay so if there is only a thousand and
if there is only one record right and it
doesn't have a second highest then this
will return nothing so how do we do it
we can use the function if none
so we can say select
if none this is a software all right new
okay so this thing will be will be this
one yeah go here right so if this thing
if the parameter this is basically this
is a function I if the first parameter
is new then we return the second
parameter okay yeah actually offset one
okay because the offset style is a zero
offset one limit one so it's a second
another thing I want to mention is the
silver Max we can have a extra as
something as a title new title new title
for the column as eighth so you will
return us a table instead of Mexico you
would have this eight a thousand okay
okay so what have you learned today we
have learned about how how do you find
the second distinct how you struggled in
as a table in a table okay so how would
you do it you just didn't get rid of the
find the maps and get rid of it and then
find the max again
final Mexican yes okay so we use the
South Korea this is a sub query right
before we only talk about that's
something from somewhere right select
something from somewhere where
conditions right order by something
limit
one limit one this is basically the
number of Records written offset one
limit right they mean a number this is
the number of record we want to return
offset is basically saying that skipping
the first
field record okay yeah
yeah offset one means that we want to
skip the first record which is the
second highest okay this thing this
thing means
so how many ways we can do it
so one way is
we find the highest we and then to find
the second highest they ignore that
the highest and then we just
kind of high end yeah yeah
the second way the key thing is they're
too soft
the first way is to ignore this is
software the second way is to sort to
order I have to sort it so based on this
which one is more efficient for a little
much and then important
you're shorter but the first one is
better better yes this is the same thing
as Echo right we have a number right a
thousand a thousand
five hundred twenty Thirty we want to
find the second highest how would you do
it
how would you do it
yeah how is it doing uh in Accra
well if this is a array okay
a
the second highest is minus 2y if a is
more than two elements okay obviously if
there is only one distinct
then that's going to be a problem right
because look look a does salt and we
need to actually need to make it a set
first right so we need to first of all
we need to accept a
set contains the unique number set a and
then we can assorted and return the
second what's the time from next day
oh and Logan yeah
this one remember the max so and so once
okay a thousand is the maximum yeah
second round we just also and ignore a
thousand okay 500 is the maximum the max
is the time direction is 11. which one
is better
and I said okay you want to find a
thousand I don't need to solve it until
right I think just go okay this is a
thousand current Max color Max
color Max is a thousand a thousand a
thousand okay because these are not
bigger than the southern does it make
sense yes that's it for today bye bye
bye
fight ing