hello Mr Mr Reiner right yeah okay so
let's say we have 10 persons from one to
n right so one two three four up to n
and at the beginning the first person
has the pillow pillow here
and it takes one second to pass the
period from one person to another to the
neighbor right so at the beginning the
first person passed the pillows to
second person and in another second the
second person passed the period to the
third person and when the pillar reaches
when the pillar reaches the nth person
and the next time you pass it back so
after 30 seconds we want to know where
the appear is let's take the example and
the three percent right so daddy Ryan
after four seconds who has the period
after four seconds four seconds
second seconds
the third second pass it back
the fourth second
okay after four seconds ready has it
right
and then the fifth second sixth second
seven a nine ten eleven and this is the
parameter of N and T we want to find out
who has an appearance at the end the N
antique arbitrary like T could be a
Minion Okay this is nothing p p could be
a minion
if you didn't know that that many
persons life is that if you want to do a
million seconds under a million persons
it's a it's the second last person yes
okay but nnt could be arbitrary that's
the thing so how do we find out easily I
mean obviously we can what did Daddy
just do we can simulate right we can
simulate the process but this is not
very efficient because tea is a medium
and it takes many all iteration that's
very slow right
so any better ways to do it
take it all around the back okay I know
what was that if there are three person
how many seconds to go back to four yeah
one two three four yes if they are
another one money yeah how many seconds
four percent how many seconds
one two three four five six okay so and
how many seconds to take a long trip and
two okay and times two minus two okay
this is the same thing as n minus one
times two right n times two minus two
okay okay so we know
the amount of seconds it takes to do a
long trip and then we are given T
seconds so what can we do about it so do
we need to you know do these uh long
trips no right because after a long trip
it doesn't change right all right so
what do we do with this tea goodbye
goodbye
divided it's modulus right we want
together yeah yeah because we want to
reduce this big number if like you get
the integer and
and they've easily just put it but if
it's odd number then you're still on the
way back X modulus 39 how many
possibilities
what's the possible values
0 to 38 39 various right so any number
three modulus this one is this number of
hospitalities all right so we're
reducing the T to end right make sense
so after that okay so let's say
t modules n minus one times two
this is K okay suppose we have this
number K this is first person after the
wrong tricks they are K remains so how
many possibilities
do for now persons yeah I know it could
be this way or it could be this way all
the way back yeah yeah it could be yeah
it could be here or it could be on the
way back right so there are two
possibilities Ela is here all the way
back this bit is equals to n times two
minus K so we just have to get a minimum
right it could be this way or leave
whichever is minimum for example like
five percent right one two three four
five five percent k equals four
obviously it's this one right k equals a
k equals four this year
k equals a which person is it yeah but
if k equals four then you'll be five
because yeah okay that's a plus one yes
it does
it has a five week subtract two because
because
okay so k equals these plus one okay A
plus one here because when the remaining
is a star from zero right remain is zero
I plus one to make it the first person
so let's say k equals four so obviously
the fourth person k equals a one two
three four five six seven eight is here
all right
how do we get these two from eight
is five times two minus
a okay what it means is that we want to
find out if it's closer to this side
yeah to the left because if it's closer
to the left this K is closer to the left
then it's the speed it is on the way to
to the to the right if it's a closer to
the left the round trip right this K is
bigger than this portion is closer to
the left all right yes okay so the
answer will be just there the minimum of
these two but what if it's like going
back this is the way to go back go back
is this bit go back is this bit we want
to calculate this bit right to the left
uh yeah we actually want to find out who
owns the pillow actually is the the left
bit right is this bit or this bit
huh well let's say there's like four
people and the Seven seconds
four people in seven seconds yeah
one two three four five six seven yeah
uh-huh I mean like how would you work it
out and nothing like okay
four percent n equals four how many
seconds to travel around is
total T is eight
minus six six right six and then you say
seven seconds right yeah
seven multiples six is
one right yeah
one and one needs to pass one because uh
plus one to make it two
okay yeah so two so we want to find out
two left four percent four times two
minus minus two
two and six which is smaller is two so
it's the second person okay
okay do you understand why we need to do
the minimum of K and N times two minus K
okay so let me repeat okay is it is
there any situation that it will be the
right side by n times T minus K let's do
this the example again like let's say
how many seconds let's say 10 yeah eight
nine ten right ten okay that's a good
example ten so this speed is the same
right so uh which is that t equals six n
equals four n equals four T equals six
the small T equals ten right ten modulus
6 is
4. we need to plus one right we want to
find out five and
minus 2 and N times two a minus five
three okay
so five and three plus three seven eight
nine ten so sweet this is on the way
back this speed
this bit or
or listed whichever is smaller this is K
and this speed is n times two minus K if
this n minus two is K is smaller than
this k then it's on the way back
otherwise it's on the way to the right
yes Define f and T
so total round of T equals n minus one
times two and T
T modulus
equal T and then we need the t plus
equal one right modular give the value
start from zero we need plus one to make
it the person right anonymity so we just
return minimum of t and n times two
do we use any addition of one yes
arbitrary and then T we can just
calculate it
almost immediately right another one to
solve it if n and T is smaller
okay so let's say x equals at the
beginning t
four underscore in range t t equals one
okay and then X plus equals d
if x equal equal 1 or x equal equal n
D times equal minus one return
x x equals one t equals one range T
times
X Plus equal D if x equals one or x
equals n then T times minus one okay so
return x what does it do
so yeah this simulation right pull on
the pillow after T second okay the next
two is key second time for each second X
pass equals d p is the how much times t
t equals one and then times equals minus
one will be minus one and then times
minus one will be one minus one one
minus one what's this thing yeah it's
like which way is going like it is that
yeah which way so X plus d if D is one
if T is one it's going right if TV was
minus one coming left right so when do
we change the D
well we change the B
when the partition is at the first
person or the last person will change
the direction and then after T re round
and X is the person who holds the
periods right what's the time come next
before this one o t o t yes we are
talking about the complexity yeah it
means T iterated okay let's face some
Legacy
oh any additional space constant space
only right oh what yeah okay OT do you
understand this Ultimo yeah yes that
simulation that's a mess so which one is
better
one okay left one okay this is the
exception and today I talk about the
Ultima at the beginning and this is to
give you an example okay
so
so why this is better than this one
because I won
the computer just do this simulation it
takes time right if T is very big like a
minion then this takes a million
iterations to n right OT right yeah but
this one
if T is a minion it doesn't matter look
the second line T modulus please you
immediately you'll become smaller value
okay
what have you learned today that's it
[Music]
yeah people think yeah so what's uh what
have you learned I mean what what
solution here can you tell me the
problem
and solution and that's it
uh so the problem is we have the
[Music]
have to have another second with his
teeth and
and so
so we end every second the person path
to the next person and to the next
person and at the end of the line the
last person I'll pass it back
and we want to find out what person
doesn't end after finishing 30 seconds
so we have a left one which is basically
like math you just find out the the N
minus one times two and then we just
moderate it and then give a remainder
and then you you have to remember to
plus one because when the first person
passes pass it on the first second this
is on the second person and you don't
count the first person because nobody is
passing through the first person on the
first time why are this is minimum of
tea and a minus two because because
uh it might have a remainder which is
which is larger
to go back yeah go back this go back and
we have to check which way is there but
is it on the way or is it on the way
back okay okay that's it for today bye
bye bye
foreign