[Applause]
numbers
and the right side needs to be bigger
than the no I'm just in pregnancy
this is the loot
um these are the leaves with no children
right at least the trunk and each node
has almost two kids with me because
yeah look it's upside down right yeah
this is the tree yeah yeah but it still
doesn't look like okay this one looks
like a tree
that doesn't look like a tree this looks
okay
okay yeah yeah this is Christmas tree
okay the whole Christmas Tree
Finance tree is a tree tree is a data
structure especially how we store the
same time yeah yeah specifically okay
so binary tree is also attack directly
assigned to the graph
and it's a graph right what's the order
we can perform on the tree
perfect search and better search okay
perfect search perfect search professor
in this particular tree what kind of
order is this one two three four five
six seven
level by level we use the keyword and
therefore surge we actually talked about
different kinds of deficit deficits put
all the you know the post order right
note left to right yeah pre-order
because we reach the North First in
order
[Music]
the nose on the left tree is smaller
than strictly smaller than the nodes on
the right are strictly bigger than the
null if we perform uh in order we get
the Salted list right if it's a buying
research
exactly okay so for example this
breakfast search Okay D5 let's say F
loot
assuming the root is not none okay
Q equals TQ all right we put the nude in
wire Q we can use again right wire kills
current equals
Q dot Pub left then we can yield it
right yet
current we visit the note if carbon dot
left Q dot a 10
current 11. if we have a left node we
push it to the Q is current or right
Q dot append current or right and that's
it right if we're using a year that's it
yeah let's suppose such Okay so
today's question if we change this
to stack
what happened
if we change this to step what happened
we know
yeah
okay
here is
FIFA first name first one yeah
which is lost in first out yeah
different way of saying okay
okay good that's very good okay thank
you this is yeah and if we're changing
this to stack what happened
so on this tree so if we change it to
set what order we can get you know let's
say right let's do this
step okay
one now at the beginning we put a one in
right
now we're taking one hour right here we
take one now you know for the stack
there's no problem we need to change
this to pop okay
so one take it off okay let's resize one
what's the kit of one left and right
right two and three yeah so we pushing
two in first right two and then three
okay
yeah and then okay so the next time
which element we take it out and then we
put it here three
what's the kit of three six
and six and seven
okay and then seven seven okay what do
we take out we'll put it here okay one
to the kingdom seven nothing right and
then what's next what's a kid of six we
take it out six
what's the kid of six nothing two two
okay we take it out two
what's the kid of two one five
five four and five and then we take the
fire out
and then we take the fall out one three
seven six two five uh two one okay four
four sorry two five four is it two by
four yeah
do we make a mistake no you just wrote
it wrong okay okay so one three seven
six one three seven two five four okay
what's this order
is it no to right left
yeah so this is reverse pre-order
reverse pre-order okay
how about I want to at least pre-order
thing what should I change
left and right look this one is reverse
pre-order
I want this pre-order
so look at the difference I'm saying
instead I'm setting for breakfast search
instead of going left to right you're
going right to left that's what I'm
saying so in when you pop two when you
get two and three you put it put you put
this three two instead of two three we
already changed at least from Q to stack
it's not perfect anymore it's a yeah
we change this queue to stack we change
the list to pop and then we perform
these we get the note right left now
this is the note we visit the right and
then we visit the left tree this is what
we get we want to visit the left tree
first so look this is not left to right
what's the difference
what's the difference here right
yeah so in which places you are pushing
to the kit determine this order left and
right right yes look I'm pushing the
left and right right because this is the
step I push the left here I push the
right tree here what's the order of
taking these I push it and I take it
what's the order
ah yeah yeah
okay I want to get the AR so what do I
do
believe us yeah so we push the button
first
pushing the right first and then left
right so all you need to do is
switch those around so yeah and then
that that's it
eight
nine
11 okay
this is a stack at the beginning one
okay
remember we push the right first and
then left okay what's the kit of
one
two and three now we push the right
three first so we put a three and two uh
obviously one we will put it here right
we take the two hour right yeah
what's that kit of two four and five
okay but we push the five and
four okay take the four out right
what's the cable for eight or nine yeah
we'll pushing the nine and eight okay
and then we take a out
nothing right
okay then five nothing okay three we
take it out what's lucky that's three
six and seven yeah we'll put you the
seven and six next
six yeah
eleven so eleven ten right
[Music]
next ten nothing
nothing next eleven nothing
next seven nothing one two four eight
nine
five three six ten eleven seven
this is the third pre-order
note left to right okay if you want to
do this using recursion easier we know
that already it's simple we say
everything
you can see right if loot if loot is
none well not loot
return
then
we visit the no first right so yeah
yeah the root of value or root right and
yelled from yes from that first search
Blue Dot left and then you know what's
next yeah from that first Search doodle
right we're just changing the professors
using the Q from Q to stack and changing
the top left to pop
and I will also change the order of
pushing the left key to the right kid
right because if we're pushing the left
key first
we get it last because it's a step by
first in that cell but if we want to get
the left left tree first we need to push
the right tree into the stack all right
does it make sense okay so what have you
learned today
we learned about anybody come on
complete the sentence to finish the
lesson
we learned about we learned about
um depth search
using yeah using stack using stack and
it's very easy to transform from
Professor so we just simply change the
implementation of prefer search from Q
to stack
and then from top left to pop because
the stack if you want to get items that
you get it from the Valencia which is
pop and also we change we swap along the
order of pushing the left tree and the
right tree all right yes
okay
that's it for today bye
bye bye bye