right
okay so today
let's look at these simple questions we
are given an integer right four three
seven five positive integer non-negative
integer and we want to find out the
minimum sum of splitting it into two
non-negative integers so we achieve the
minimum sum so using these digits we
want to split into two
number one
and number two these are non-negative
numbers which can contain
ddlers we want to find out the minimum
sum of number one plus them two okay so
for example this one how many ways can
you split into two integers
you can split 47 and 75 you place it
together that's 118 right you can split
into four three seven and five number
right
this adds up to four four two way you
can split into 35 Plus 47 these
is 82. okay so we want to find out the
minimum okay
so yeah yeah the minimum sum so for
example the minimum sum I guess is 30.
is it thirty five okay you already done
that that's the minimum yeah is it the
minimum
[Music]
let's try a few other examples like
75 no I always down like that 74 plus 53
equals 127. okay so any idea how we get
this minimum so so there's two things
so we can so we want the minimum so
we're not obviously not gonna have a
three digit plus a one digit so we got a
two two digit and two digit so if we
want to find the smallest tens and and
then we can leave a bigger digits to
develop uh ones yeah that's a very good
thinking so how about you say the two
and two how about three digits like one
two three what's the minimum
you can't split evenly right but in this
case what's the minimum you can speak
one two plus three you can speak one
three plus two this is
okay you can speed with two three plus
one or two one plus three
this is first 15 this goes the 24.
I obviously this is the minimum so for
the minimum
Digi you uh put it as like the biggest
place value so you can put like
the tens so when you put one on tens
okay so what's your schedule you said
Put it on Wednesday put
[Music]
will be the minimum one
the
[Music]
two so we put it into five five I'm not
saying one two three
um I'm saying wait can we put the zero
in at the front of course yes so so we
put zero and one and yes
two three like
uh-huh okay
yeah okay okay so this is the optimal
yes you're right yes so we always keep
the smallest smallest and the biggest
number is going at the end that's right
so one at a time right another and it
doesn't matter if there's a odd number
so we just have one more extra for one
application because because the bigger
digits if you put the biggest they get
it as like the ones in the ones place
the first three is like eight and nine
it'll be as as less value if it if you
could have a like front like well done
okay so for any arbitrary Lumber right a
big number what's your strategy the
first step you need to tell me how we
designed this algorithm right so first
step is
so what do we do with this okay
I don't know so for this digit how would
you do it
so first step is
salty that's the thing I'm looking for
keywords sort it so we sold it so let's
zero zero one two two three six seven
eight nine nine right okay and then we
started what's next
and then and then we put the first two
the first two yeah as as the first to
get as a this is the first digit uh
first digit this is the second digit
second number okay so so
how we describe this process
zero or one
one
two two
[Music]
three
six seven eight nine nine suppose I have
another nine here I just can just put it
there yeah it doesn't matter doesn't
matter put it here out here no actually
it matters right yeah so yeah we want to
put it here right so we always pick in
turn there are a couple ways of solving
these questions all right so today we're
just going to one and the next one we
talk about the second solution and the
next lesson nine on the
if it's old and you have one spare
when it's bad do you put it on the
smallest
we just take in ten right because the
first number is always we pick this
number this is the smallest right yes
yes
remember that's right yes we just take
digit in turn right take it in turn
right make sense and then okay so as I
said there are a couple ways of doing
this okay the first way is sorting the
digit
sorted the digit right
the second way is we use the package
stop we should we are going to talk
about like sorting why we can use the
bakkie stop remember we have a limited
digit right that only 10 buckets all
right
you can imagine there are 10 buckets
yellow this is color number zero one two
right so we go through this number and
we count how many digits of zero how
many this is the one right okay we'll
talk about that in the next lesson the
Third Way is using the parallel Cube or
hip right so the idea is that we peel
the hip and particle right every time we
take a digit the next smallest digit
for the first number and the next model
digit if there is for the second number
and we take these digits internal okay
but today we focus on this sorting the
digit
so it's actually quite simple right so
let's give a digit is uh individual time
right so minimum sum
so we're given this n which is the
integer type and we want to return the
integer the minimum sum I
okay so this is the integer why we want
to get that digit so it's we want to
solve the digit so we convert it to a
string right okay so Str converted the
string but we want to
sort it right converting a string how do
we saw that string
string is immutable right so we can
ah we can convert it to an array of
digits right and then we sort it
sort it so this is a
okay
so after this what's a look if this is
one two three okay str123
back to the code to make it string type
least
if we do like this three it will be one
two
three right
array of teaching and sort it it's
already insulted so after that we want
to pick in turn right so look one
two three four five six seven so for the
first number for the first number we
want to pick these these this this life
for the second number we want to take
this this okay
[Music]
and then it plays the a here I want to
pick here right
so how do we put it this way so the
first number
S1 equals a is least right so we want to
do this a
dash dash two jumped
step two right
this is a list we want to convert it to
uh convert it to a string and then
convert it to an integer so how do we
convert a
array to a string
split what's the opposite of split join
yeah we want to join with empty join
and then now this is a string and I will
convert it to the integer right
okay and then S2 equals in this is the
same
The Joy but there's a slight difference
a
Bata two what should I put here
what should I put here
one way you don't put anything here this
is zero but for the second number we
want to start from yes one exactly we're
done okay and that's it no no yeah
actually 10 S1 plus s2y this is the
minimum so this is called the python the
least comprehension so for at least
right interval you can entice and you
can do listen this is the least one you
can do I column J column k
so it means that from I to J not
including the J step K when I is omitted
is equal to zero When J is emitted is
default to length of the a when K is
omitting is defaulted to one column
column minus one what does it mean
reverse so it's the same as look it's
the same as
which is if this is a and then minus one
okay so it means that from left to the
right but I want to step minus one going
backwards so let's reverse
okay so the time complexity for this one
right if there are n digits if this is n
digit uh Pick N digit then we obviously
we need to solve it so o and log begin
okay
okay so what have you learned today
about a thousand splitting
minimum what number sum okay so what's
your strategy today what's the algorithm
we talked about today
yeah so we thought it so what what
do you call it a number the number the
digits right the digit of these numbers
and we need to First convert it to a
string right we started the string right
yeah
and then what's the strategy of picking
them
into spaces yeah so we take the digit
for two numbers we take the digit uh the
smaller digit in term right we construct
the smallest number we take turn to take
the digit and right yes okay that's it
for today bye
bye