all right
okay so last lesson we talked about this
uh problem all right we're given an
integer and we want to split it into two
integers obviously this is the
non-negative integers and both integers
can have these leading zeros I'm going
to find out a minimum sum right and the
strategy we taken is creative right so
we saw the digits and then we try to
pick the digit from a smaller one to the
bigger one all right because we want to
leave the larger digit to the right hand
side right yeah okay so look this is a
strategy we sort of the digit yeah we
convert it obviously we converted the
integer to the string we break it down
into an array of the digit characters
and we solved it this is a sorted array
and then we use the list complications
to pick every other digit the first
number we start picking every other
digit from the first digit the second
digit from the second digit so you will
pick the second the fourth the sixth
right and Etc when we pick the digit is
a list We join it to a string and now we
need to convert it back to the integer
and then we add it up right the Time
come back stays oh and again if n is the
number of digits okay the key thing here
is that we sort it right we have done
quite a few sorting again right and
quick saw the merge so much bubble
sorting selection so insertions over and
we also mentioned about the Pakistan we
saw about using bucket
bucket that's right basically like a
package each packet is a counter to
count the number of digits right given
this you know in decimal how many
different types of digits we have
yes 10 from zero to nine right you know
any number can be represented by at
least 10 digits right so we can just
count right for example we can count
using these buckets so how do we call
these in a bucket look so just imagine
how many packages created at the
beginning okay
yeah so 10 packets right each bucket for
each digit right so look I pack it right
I'm just going to draw a simple version
of it okay
right
here one two three four five six seven
eight nine ten eleven okay so this is
yellow one
okay
okay so Etc okay so let's consider this
number two three uh one four four seven
okay
this number
so two
two first introduce the second bucket
all right zero one two so the third
bucket so this is one here
three one one here four here four okay
another four so we increment this
counter
seven
yeah okay bye so now we have ten buckets
each bucket has is a counter
right so okay so just imagine okay now
and all the rest is zero how do you
construct this S1 s two two numbers
okay you could do it
all right we just go through these
digits and then we uh
count how many times they appear right
yeah make sense
okay so how do we construct these
stitches so obviously we need to check
from left to the right right the left is
zero this is the smallest number right
look here F1 S2
now I have one zeros here so where does
it go
here right yeah
see hello nothing one where is Jessica I
have one two two for tip digital I have
one where does it go
yeah all right
and move next where does it go let's
wait
yeah
okay move next four I have two
okay four yeah right because I have two
zero zero zero now like seven please you
all right
okay so the minimum
what what is it why is there two in the
second
okay zero so this is a mistake yeah
[Music]
okay so actually it's here yeah
sorry so this one should be here right
okay
so what's the sun yeah is this the
minimum one two three four four seven
it's the same right it's the same as
sorting right one two three four four
seven so one two three four
four seven yeah okay so this is
basically the same as sorting but we use
the Pakistan because we know there can
different digits and then we just count
how many of them but when we count it we
can pick the numbers from the left hand
side to the right hand side so we are
now dealing with the numbers here we are
not in number one number two number
three number four if there are more than
one we can just keep doing that am I
right this makes sense
yeah okay let me try another example
okay just to make sure you actually
understand
and then we can do the coding okay so uh
try another number right
um four four three two two seven seven
six okay how many numbers a number let's
make it another zero here certain
package yeah
okay this is ten bucket
four
make it two right
three
one
two one
two make it to one yeah that's one not
two
one not two okay so yeah that was a
mistake yeah you always listening yeah
that was testing
okay good job seven six
yellow yeah so what are the rest what
should I put here it's yellow okay good
okay
now okay so now S1 S2
we have one zeros
so where should I put it on the number
yeah okay
okay now move it what do we do is it
nothing
okay and
and then give it to your first number
yeah and
one move where because two huh
and what's next put three in the second
three
and
perform in the first room and then put
four in the second string yeah then move
and then skip dancing and then put six
in the first ring and then move on and
then
put seven in the 739 the first ring and
then it's getting arrested okay so this
is
my sense zero two three three four four
six seven yeah so it's basically this
number plus this number
okay why can't we do it why this
approach is okay
can you just say okay why this is the
gives the optimum the minimum because
because place values and you can put
digits in different place values because
like there's in the fat one's column two
tens column like if you put like a one
in the ones column will be one but if
you put one's in like a thousand column
it'll be a thousand so it'll get B more
so you want to give a smaller so you put
the the smallest number or in the bigger
values and the bigger numbers in the
smaller values so they'll they'll uh
value less good job yes that's basically
it yeah so basically we are sorting yeah
it's the same as sorting right so last
time when we sold it we just sold it
right what do we get zero two two three
four four six seven seven right and then
we
pick the number from left to the right
right this is the same thing right so we
just count it we have these ten buckets
because there are only 10 possible
digits and we just count how many times
they appear is there a packet right if
you have one more two you just increment
the counter two and then we try from the
left to the right because the left this
is the zero the smallest
five zero one two this is in the
sourcing order and if it's zero if the
counter is zero just get
it is the the Sorting this is the faster
why is it faster because we only have 10
buckets if we are empty it here
we just go through these end times and
then we have all the digits in place
right but for 13 if not regular salt in
quick shot the time complexity is O and
again right and then if we use the
bucket sorting look what's the tandemic
speed
what's the time from Leslie OS right
which one is better this one is better
right because they have 10 buckets so it
just goes to one
okay
okay so yeah that's a strategy but
writing this in code may not be elegant
as the first approach remember the first
approach is just three line number two
right but for this one it takes the more
than three lines of code and it's not as
elegant as the first approach the bucket
equals at the beginning 10 10 buckets
four
I in this n Str n converted to a string
this I and then B integer I automated
back to the index the values plus equals
one right this is bucket oh yeah
incrementing we are putting the numbers
in the bucket right this is the bucket
and we're putting the we go through the
digits and we put in the DJI to that
bucket okay and
and once we have that then we can start
S1 equals zero S2 equals zero right and
y i equals zero wire I is smaller than
10.
all right
first of all we need to skip the packet
which is yellow so
how do we skip the bucket which is you
know wire
why I is smaller than 10 and
s i is is actually p i is is actually
zero then I plus equal one right
so we skip the empty packets and then
and now we need to take the numbers
right we need to take the numbers so so
how do we take a number S1 equals S1
times 10 plus now this is the bucket we
are now a bucket I so packet I now once
we take the one bucket what should we do
with it we need to decrement the counter
right
I take one four already so I need to
decrement it to one right so right now I
take this eye and I need to decrement it
which is b i minus equal one so once we
take this bucket now we need to check if
the voltage is for the next number right
so we need to obviously we need to keep
skipping this digit right and
p i if if zero then still I plus equal
one and if I is already as a 10
if we are using up all the digits then
we just break otherwise S2 equals S2
times 10 plus I and p i minus equal one
okay
and then at the end return
S1 plus S2
okay so look at this is not very elegant
right
because there's some
special case we have to make yeah but
the strategy the point is that
we take the digit we all always take the
digit in turn right in turn and then we
move the counter I
move this I to the right until it
reaches the the 10th for example the S1
is zero to four right so if I take the
digit six what does the S1 become
now S1 is 24 so if I take the one more
digit and put it on the right what does
as one become
246 I
so how do we get 246 from 24
24 times 10. and put a 6 on the right
let's let's basically it right so we
multiply the number current value times
10 means that okay this is the number I
have I multiply it by 10.
yeah yeah I squeeze one
location for for the new digit right
this is 24. so 24 becomes 240 plus 6.
this is where it is well done so we
take the number Take the bucket I and we
need to decrement it right take a move
it and then we move to the right okay
okay that's it what have you learned
today I learned about how to what we
didn't like last time we could end on
Monday about it's fine it's splitting
number and I don't remember and today
we're using bucket sort okay so okay so
what is bucket sorting bucket sorting is
basically using buckets or counters
yes okay okay and then you and then you
lay them out and can't get enough of
them put them in the rebels inside and
they don't have right hammer and then
you go through them and then just put
them in three one strings and keep a
good part yeah the fucking sauce is
useful if we know the lumber the the
data the data type is limited for
example in this case there are only 10
digits right so we can go through it
once and put it in different buckets but
if the data is a lot of the you know
different contents you can always have
unlimited buckets all right
make sense if you have if you have
unlimited packets the performance will
be not as efficient as this limited
buckets make sense anyway any comments
no
that's it for today bye bye bye bye