[Music]
yeah okay so what's this problem I mean
do you still remember
a number into
two parts and I give them up to get to
get to minimum song yeah minimum sum so
we give in the number we want to split
into two parts and we want to minimize
the sum and we have to talk about two
solutions so far right the first
solution is solar digit we apply this
greedy strategy we saw the digit and we
start picking that digit from a small
list to the largest right because we
want to leave the larger difference to
the right hand side to the ones am I
right yeah the time complexity for the
one is oh and okay because it takes the
o n log n term to so the teacher if they
are integers the second approach we're
using the topic starting because there
are only 10 digits and we can sort the
number
we can solve the digits by placing them
in corresponding packets
what I mean by putting that digit in the
bucket we just simply increment the
counter for the bucket right and once we
have 10 buckets of the counters meaning
how many digits for each packet then we
can
what can we do we can go through from
left to the right
because the left is the the leftmost the
bucket is zero by zero one two three
four up to nine
this is it okay
so we're just taking here we talk about
it we're picking these numbers from the
smallest to the biggest okay so today
we're going to solve this problem using
this uh yeah using this priority queue
and hip
hip
so let's attain a structure I have do
you still remember what's a priority
queue
is using Heap yeah probably
the Q is FIFA priority Q is
that's what I literally said what does
it stand for first in priority out yeah
first thing priority all so in Python we
use this hip right hipify if we hit P5
and the next item to Hip Hop is the
smallest we can helpify the digits
and then we can just ask it Hip Hop
and then if they are more digits we can
heat up again all right yes because the
hip-hop you give us the next smaller
smallest digit doesn't make sense okay
so I'm going to write the code and then
tell me you explain to me right like I'm
five okay
Define name some
and we have this and the digit equals
list
star and
S1 equals zero S2 equals zero
keep
P5
pp5 ep5p
wire B why we have digits
while we have a digit what do we do so
S1 equals S1 times 10 plus the integer
part of Hip Hop
d
if digit if we have still have one more
digit
S2 equals S2 times 10 plus integer
here pop
the
return S1 plus S2 that's it
okay so let me explain it and then you
tell me again okay
Define your function we need some given
this parameter n which is the integer
type is a digit number so Str converted
to a string least breaking
the digits the string digit into a into
you know characters into array a list of
the characters
S1 S2
F2 list is just the the value integer
value of the two integer we want to
split okay hipify
hippie file even this parameter T we
want to keep if I we want to make it a
hip okay so if we want to use the heat
push Hip Hop we have to hit before at
least uh the hit first okay by now look
D this is an array we hit if I and we
can use the Hip Hop
okay YT is the same thing as y layer
elements in the array in a d or why
lens the bigger than zero okay it's the
same thing
so we have digit we we still have the
digit here
we have a digits so what do we do we can
take the next smallest digit
S1 equals S1 times 10. remember that if
this number S1 is one two and then the
next digit is three so S1 times 10.
plus three okay
and after we take one digit because
we're taking two digits each by digit
right so we give one digit to S1 and
then we check if they are more digits to
give to S2 if they are more digits if we
still have at least one digit then we
give it to S2 and we repeat this process
until all the digits are taken at Pop
hip-hop okay the key thing is that you
know hip-hop is taking you know just
like Q right first in priority queue
the hip you can think of it as a
priority queue first in priority up
okay
the first thing first of all right the
first important means the priority
what's priority here
the higher priority the smaller digit
the higher priority right two and three
which one has more priority two yeah
okay you're listening okay good
okay so then we take the priority out
right and I take the number we stand
higher priority means the smaller lower
number exactly okay and then we repeat
this process until all the numbers are
taken good yes so the time complexity
okay if there are n digits right and
digit
so obviously this is O and we need to
convert it to the list pp5 oh and if we
are building a hip out of array is om
right but if we are building a hit by
pushing heat push and element
n times let's o and log in okay that's
the difference
okay now heat talk is login so look we
are taking n digit
and here all the digits are taken so the
time convex is O and Logan right because
here is o n
and here is login so over login
okay yes okay so these are the three
approach and obviously there are more
like we can do first right
yeah how many ways we can put we can
split into two digits not a lot right
it's no trivia to the right approvals
right
yeah you can prove for using the test
research process search we can find the
different ways of uh splitting this
number into two but this is not the most
elegant most optimal solution there are
three approaches
the first one so the digit which is
creating the second approach bucket
sorting which is greedy greetings yeah
the second approach is so yeah it's also
the equities okay a third approach using
the parameter Cube okay okay so what
have you learned today we learned about
using YouTube and what we learned yes
last time which is yesterday I think
okay so what's that yeah and we and
we're using this one okay which is very
close first in priority out okay so
what's this function doing pp5 what does
it do sort it it makes it a hip in
English why five something like that
make it make it yeah so you basically
make it yeah make it a thick this is
what it means so the original is an
array at least when you're making it
because when we're making a hip we can
use the hip push or heat pump right hip
push is push the element to the to the
hip and then
in the meantime the hip will be
maintained right the structure will be
maintained so we can hit proper can so
hip hop who is taking the next element
with the higher priority which is the
smaller one okay yeah and it's also hip
replace can you guess what hip will
replace
just guess what what does it do replaces
all the replaces
oh no no keep replaced it's basically
hip-hop and he push okay so we take one
out and we push another in okay okay so
yeah let's replace it yes yes okay so um
these are the three approaches I believe
we've covered it all
and which one is the optimum
the first one is the Owen Logan the
third one is our login the second one is
Owen why because Buck is something so
which one is better which one is nothing
it's the second one
second you know no not always sorry
sometimes not always okay and also it is
different to the rest so why would two
of the be the most of it when you say
you're just gonna be one you know
there's no question I'm just saying
there's a two of them are looking and
one of them is obviously gonna be a
because why would you why would two of
them be defaulted when you said which is
the fastest so it must be only one of
them yeah I didn't say that I don't care
but that's a good point yes yes there
could be two solutions which are equally
the best right I didn't say that yeah
that means I know the best okay yeah
equally the best right in English you
can say they are equally the best right
like Eric Ryan you are equally the best
okay yeah but you didn't
okay
okay bye-bye
hahaha