you know the browser right you visit the
internet your browser right
is that software
you open the browser right that's how
you spell it yes what blouse are you
using
is it
ping is a search engine
so what's the name of the software Edge
yes and also
what's that browser from Google what is
it called Shrine Chrome yeah Chrome yeah
okay so these are two popular browsers
five songs when did you use the Firefox
never
how do you know a Firefox
Island okay
Safari yes
I don't know how to spray it okay but
anyway browser is the software
[Music]
s-a-a-f-a-r-i okay so browser right
so there's a close button right let's
maximize button there's a minimize
button so what's here usually
https what do you call it it's a dress
bar right
so you put HTTP s column
www.google for example like Google or
microsoft.com
we call this thing u r l u r i right the
very minimum difference between these
two terms so URL what's that uniform
resource location uniform resource
identifier
uniform
they're wearing clothes or unified it's
a uniform or unified you need five I
think it's Unified
which one makes more sense uniformal
unified unified unified unified resource
resource
get back okay anyway it's just a termite
and this is identified
okay so let's talk about this Uriah
http
www.bing
dot com
slash
a slash b c dot PSP
question mark a equals one and
okay b equals two hashtag V okay
so this is a more complex example okay
so when you put these in a address bars
of a browser and the browser knows where
to locate this content okay and display
it in your browser okay so let's look at
these first
as TTP
HTTP is a protocol is a schema
protocol so what does this stand for
there's also yahoo.com
yes it's a difference
[Music]
it's also a search engine
nowadays it's not as popular as Google
Google has at least 97 market share of
the all the social engine and pin has
like three percent Okay Yahoo maybe less
than you know small amount of people
using these days HTTP hyper test I don't
like Yahoo hypertext twice full okay
transfer protocol
yeah look that's a good question Ash
t t p okay hypertext transfer
okay yeah what are the Alternatives this
is not usually when you want to view a
website you know type in a browser lots
of case HTTP or https
a skewer version secure version okay
usually it's https most of the case
okay I love FTP
fire transfer protocol
protocol what's the what's the meaning
of protocol
is that protocol okay so I want to talk
to you in secret so for example Ryan is
here I want to talk to you in secret
he's listening as well right I want to
send you a message talk to you a message
but in the meantime only you understand
right and don't understand so this is
there is a protocol secret protocol
between you and remember we talk about
this rods 13 right notation
you mean they to end okay half is so
thirteen each and then they swap around
yeah yes well right something like that
right I send you something I you
understand this is the original text
with Ryan crap because yeah that's the
thing so secure we have a skill version
uh we talk about it's more complex skill
version is that I encrypt the message
you know here is message I say hello
hello this is I want to talk to you Ryan
is here
the name
yes okay hello I want to say hello hello
Eric
okay but why is also mayor but I don't
want Ryan to understand this message so
I will have uh I will have your public
key right you have a public key you have
a private key in pairs yeah public key
you have a private key
so you're probably I know your public
key right so I probably
the king takes the message takes the
message and also your public key
and then this will give me uh some in
quickly text
right so this encrypted text
reach your side because you have private
key you'll be able to decode this
message Ryan doesn't have a private key
of yours this is your private only you
and you know you have it no other people
have it that they don't have your
private key right and don't have your
private key you have your private key
but everybody knows your public key so I
use your public key and what's my public
key I don't know it's just a publicly
and private piece is in pairs right only
this private key can see the message
which is being encoded using or public
key okay so that's very complex I don't
know what's my
Minecraft me like translated to like a
regular like like if you say uh like ABS
SDS one two four eight dollars convert
uh your message into uh like
um a code and then you send it that's my
private key
does my private key conver translated
back so I know yeah yeah the problem of
this one is what if it's Dwayne guess a
to n b to o or he will be able to decode
the message right because it's two-way
right you get the a you translate to n
and I send it n to you you know n so
it's a bit back to a
am I so it's kind of like a very simple
protocol right to guess
but with this approach
Ryan come
to decoy because Brian doesn't have your
private key private key could be a very
big thing uh you know a key that nobody
can decode your message without it okay
okay so let's protocol so FTP and also
we have a skilled version what's my
public key though
it could be any you can make up a public
Republic equipment it could be a limited
number like it just comes in pair okay
we talk about that later it's quite
complex it's about the encryption
cryptographic okay cryptographic this is
the foundation of blockchain okay so
this is a schema or we call it protocol
schema
www what's that
[Music]
worldwide website okay so this could be
it could be something else
technically www is a supplement so it
could be you know I could say video
video.bing.com so people know this
video.bing.com is a sub domain sub
domain of bing.com this is the main
domain everything before the mentorman
is the supplement so videos
no HTTP this is the protocol this is the
domain here this is
okay okay technically after this right
this is the schema protocol this is a
domain man domain subtle man okay
okay and why.com what's.com company
company okay originally the one that
domain was invented uh.com is the uh top
level government TRD okay so.com company
right but nowadays the mods
TRD is coming right we could have duck
UK Taco dot UK dot io.net right
anything right
and then these are the paths right so it
means that where to find
what weighs the past a no you can
imagine as a photo structure a photo
goes into a folder and then B photo and
then in a for the B photo there's a c do
php5 so this is the nude right so load
laser photo a and let's further B and in
photo B I have at least see the PHP so
this is just to tell the uh browser
Telltale server where to locate the zero
PHP is at the server of bing.com at
photo a for the BN okay location PHP
okay so this is a file okay any
questions so far and that is one part
one pass yes one pass yes it could be
any pass right
and how do I know my private key without
telling it to you
you have your primary key okay so you
don't share your private key to anybody
else you don't tell me okay this is so
perfect it only belongs to you yeah but
how would I know where to look without
you helping me Ah that's a good question
yeah because when you are uh and you are
18 I'm your official you know Guardian
so I deserve to know everything yeah
sometimes even your password
[Music]
okay
okay what was the question again sorry
there's only one part so you can find it
okay yes
you only can go to B okay okay maybe I
have another C and I have another T and
I have another E and I have a f okay so
we don't know the structure of the
server but if you put it this way then
you'll actually be telling people that
okay on my server a b c the PHP you need
to find it okay most of the case but
actually this is the case we serve the
fire is there in most cases but
sometimes we can save it okay now let's
totally another story okay
so look this is the question mark and
after this before the hashtag this is
the core query string
clear history why do you need a question
mark
this is just the format right before the
question mark this is the file name this
is the task after the question mark is
the it's optional by the way okay this
is optional and this is optional as well
if we don't specify left
anything so what to look for is by
default right the server can configure
it as well the by default is looking for
index
index.html dot PHP or whatever right so
we don't know buy before we can
configure the server to go to a default
fire
when the past is not given okay so after
the question mark we can give a credit
string query string look a DOT one a
equals one and b equals two basically
we're just passing two variables to say
a equals one and b equals two to release
C dot PHP so instead of PHP we we know a
equals one and b equals two that could
be multiple right so you could say a
equals one and b equals two and C equals
three and D equals four whatever blah
blah blah okay and hashtag hashtag
this is just taking so when you open the
browser right when you have a page HTML
page
right so so for example right you have
uh something here blah blah blah you
guys you know some text some text some
text so if I'm saying here I want to tag
it as V here right this is a there's a
tagging V here so if you type in
the browser or when you open it
you were jumped
immediately to this section V okay make
sense they all we call it anchor
a-n-c-h-o-r Okay so
the only thing you need to know is that
this is for the browsers to jump to the
corresponding section if there's a tag
here
okay
so any questions so far what have you
learned today
[Music]
no we are not in your browser we're
learning about that whatever web
computer thingy blah blah that uh blah
blah you are air remember yeah yeah okay
so I'm going to uh we learned about URI
Yuri okay area
yeah yeah
okay so I'm going to write a few UI you
tell me if it's a uniform uh if it's uh
you tell me if it's uh correct URL okay
Okay C dot PHP is this a UI
what's amazing
yes yeah and that's the thing okay
actually I forgot something okay http
okay
s y this is secure version a video
Dot
thing
.com okay so there's a column afterwards
https
sorry
and then they're supposed to be column
after HTTP yeah yeah yeah they are okay
double slash yes okay so what I'm not
missing here okay by default it's
optional right by default if we don't
give it it's 80 80 means the web server
right you could give another Port so
what what is the pot so pot is just a
number right so there are some reserved
for example 80 is the web server 443 is
the https right uh some other like
FTP
2223 which you don't need to know for
now so Port is just like you know I can
talk to Eric right Eric is a server
bing.com right for example I want to
talk to Ari impaire you know in Paris
for example I want to talk to every part
80 and Eric should tell me okay so
present a page that's a website web
server so it's just basically a channel
right so a however this is a server a
port 80 it handles it handles the web
server the web pages and other ports it
do something else
can you imagine that right it could be a
have a a lot of ports
these are the parts right it's a just
like we can talk to each Port
individually without affecting each
other okay each pole handles the same
thing okay yeah all right doesn't make
sense yeah
okay https
picture oh
abc.com dot UK
column 91 slash C slash D and question
mark a equals one
tag
D okay it doesn't like show Bing or
Google that's that's okay it could be
anything that's the UI okay that's not
my question my question is that where is
the port number which one is the problem
91 91 this is the whole number well
that's the only number basically
okay okay yeah you all right Paul number
okay Paul number 54 if we don't specify
anything that's 80 okay
[Music]
the fire lamb is missing but the fire
line is missing it should be here but if
it's missing most likely it's index okay
so if I put another uh G here the final
is G this is the finance
where is the subtle man people
suppose
supplement what's the mental man ABC
UK this is the main domain what's the
schema
what's s security
what's http
http what does this stand for hyper
attacks transfer protocol okay what's
the query string
um
no no no has this is called angular okay
okay I would say explaining it a bit
earlier okay I'm cool oh what does it
mean what does this woman
yeah
yeah and he's like the anchor drops down
yes
okay that's it for today bye-bye bye bye