hi hello eric hello ryan hello mr eric
hello mr ryan
we're not a teacher okay yeah can you
say mister
okay so today we talk about
using a binary search remember we are
very interesting in
interest in this binary search to find
out
the case largest number
in yellow okay so for example like if
this
is the three four two
one six nine what's the
third largest number
four two four third
largest three four four is before
nine four yeah okay so one way of doing
it at any size how do we do it
uh we can
we may find the largest
[Music]
we can make this already for example if
this is nums yeah
we can do this define okay let's say
k largest yeah k is largest okay
and this is numbers yeah and then that's
okay okay so we can do this
lam dot sword yeah
so we make it in order so that will be
that will become
nine six four three two
one yeah when you're doing this the
numbers will become
slick yeah and then you just need to
return
lumps what no
actually it would be reverse it would be
because dumb soft sword
it will be this will be one two three
you'll be
increasing order if you want to make it
in the
descending order you have to put it put
a key
reverse equals two okay
so after this it will become this and
then what we return is returns one
the third largest number so that would
be k minus one right because it starts
with the
zero third number will be zero one two
which is one
right right or or if you want
if you don't want to do this then you'll
become these numbers will become one two
three
four nine six and then
instead of lumps k minus one is
numbs minus k you see using the negative
index so it means i want to use the
k numbers from the other side so the
third number to the end which is four
okay so this is two lines of code you
can do this so get the
largest number in an array but today
we're going to use the final research
so what's the complexity of that sorting
remember
[Music]
n log n yes what do we talk about
when we talk about sorting is log and
log o
and log n because it uses quick thought
yeah sometimes quicker sort combined
with some other simple soft or
multi-slot yeah
usually when we talk about assaulting is
overlooked n log
and n is the number of elements in the
array
okay yes okay so now
if we want to do uh do this test using
the binary search we can do it like
if i have given a function like count
count how many
equal or bigger than
length like x number okay so
so we can this function we can just do
this
and you tell me what it does okay can
you tell me what it does
i like i have a numbers here numbs
if i bigger or equal than
x answer plus equals 1
return answer can you tell me what what
does it mean
what does this function try to do this
number this
is the number we just talked about 3 4 2
1 9 6 and actually let's say
x is 2 so what does it mean
answer equals 0 for i in numbers
if i is bigger than x2 then answer plus
one
they can answer what does it mean
what does this function mean ryan any
thoughts
any things what's this mean what's this
once you mean
and then i look into i iterate all the
numbers and i check
if the number is bigger than uh 2x oh
those are the numbers
no another i can't what's this what is
this
count how many equals okay so what does
this function do
count how many people
than that number so it's easier i need
to release numbers
and then i check if it's bigger than x
then i count it right
does it make sense i mean this is the
very simplest
function yeah i easily i go through
these numbers
i check if the number i is bigger than
x then if it is i can't increment the
answers and i return this answer yes
yes the counter what's the complexity i
and i log in i end again
yeah because i iterate these numbers
only once right
yes yeah that's very easy okay very
simple
okay so now with this function so now
now what how can i do this the binaries
i mean final research
i can do this mean uh if these are
numbers yeah
these are numbers three two one
nine six seven
so now what's the minimum number of
leads on all these
one yeah so i have a left bound
equals mean mean numb
which will become one right and right
bound
can you guess what should i write max
we're done numbs which will be
nine nine okay so now let's bounce right
down and i if i do this meter
i do this middle and then i can use the
function i just created count how many
numbers are bigger than all equal meter
right yes then
look now i can say x equals count
how many then that is
x then here it will be finally yeah y
left smaller equals right right
and then meet the equals i get the
middle yeah left plus right
divided by two okay yeah middle if x
if x if there are more than k numbers
more than k numbers
so what does it mean if there are more
than k numbers
that bigger than the current mid number
so what does it mean we need to reduce
the if we have more than 10 for example
if k is 3
and if there are four numbers bigger
for this column meter number if there
are four numbers bigger than it so i
need to reduce the
meat right so i i need to increase the
meat right
i'm right yeah because if i reduce the
meat then
then the x will become bigger which is
not what we want
so left becomes meter plus one right
and as can you guess what's this
left right right equals one
max minus one
yeah all right yes yes
oh okay one right we're done
this is a special case because right
sometimes it's written left but in this
case we are returning
right which is because we need to minus
one to get this boundary right
okay yes so what's the complexity of all
together
this is o logan
i went again what am i trying to say
this is o n right and the final research
is o
log n so all together o and again
all right okay good job okay let's do
the coding turn on the light please
[Music]
sorry you need to connect
it's okay is it cane is there is it is
it
clear all right
okay let's find i think that's fine i
don't
need to turn this off it's very
very clear okay sit down please no
touching
okay i'm going to can you can you please
good boy okay sit down okay look at the
screen okay
let's do this uh case case last case
okay case largest
case largest
now let's do this let's let's do these
numbers which is
just given some numbers okay and then
you tell me what's the answer okay
uh i'll duplicate no okay
define three k is largest
case slices two threes okay
let me make it one one three thirteen
okay so numbs
okay remember we we talked about they
saw team yeah
yeah yeah and now we can return
numbs minus k let's just try to see if
it's all right yeah
k is largest nums
let's say three okay the third largest
number is which is
seven seven yes all right
uh uh oh i think i have a spelling error
so case largest okay
key slices okay so that's not what we i
want
seven all right yes and you can do this
the
uh using salt the other way which is and
then you tell me
what's right and reverse
when i say reverse equals two is sorting
from the biggest to the
smallest so what should i put here
what should i put here okay yes we'll
add on k
minus one because they start with a zero
okay am i
yeah let's try if it's still 0.27
i have a duplicate uh
duplicate unnecessary bracket
closing bracket too many closing bracket
yeah seven yeah
okay now let's try uh try the binary
search okay so let's delete this
remember we talked about we need to
define a function
we find count let's just do a count okay
nums k comes
x then you tell me answer equals yellow
for i in nums if
if i bigger or equal i uh x
what what should we do here answer plus
equals one right
and then return what return what answer
well done and then now let's do this
finalists final research k is largest
lumps uh conditional please numbs k
right then left
equals mean nums getting the
smallest of this number which is one
right
right equals max nums which will be
13 right yes white left is smaller than
right
one boundary not matting each other and
meet
me equals one right
and then divided by yeah divided by two
okay
using double divide means that we're
only interested in an integer okay
then x equals count
nums mint okay then you tell me if
if x is bigger or equals than k
then we need to increase the meat
right yes yes then
what left equals
one yeah and s
equals one okay and return
right in this case okay let's see if it
also 27 okay
yes we're done you see so it's the same
yeah
it's the same let's get it is it
any question so far are you sure
what's the complexity of the card
function
what's the complexity of case largest oh
log f no oh and log n because they use
the code from here look the call
function is o n
and this binary search is usually o log
n
so when it times it together you see
together it's o and log n
all right yes so what can you
tell me why when why they are more than
k
numbers larger than
the meat we need to increase the meat
because for example
we want we are interested in the third
largest number and then we found out for
this current meat there are five there
are five numbers bigger than the meat
so we are interested in the third
largest number and there are five
numbers bigger than the meat it means
that we need to increase the meat
so this x will be reduced right
when we increase the meat what should we
do we should search for the upper half
so that's why
we set the left boundary into the mid
plus one
then it was this meter will be
increasing
similarly if they are smaller if we are
looking for the third largest number but
there are only
two largest number in ugly meat then we
need to
reduce the meat now we set the
right hand right boundary meat minus one
so you keep the middle will be
meter will be in the lower half am right
yes
do you get it yes it's like a searching
it's like
you make a guess from zero to a hundred
and then if i say fifty
if you get some number uh 50
like i said if it's a smaller than what
i i thought you need to
consider searching between 50 to 100 i'm
right
yes and if i say it's bigger then you
need to search if between 0 to 50. i'm
right
yeah not 50 exactly 50 minus one and
in other cases it's 50 plus one do we
get it
yeah this experiment is very very
important okay
okay good job good job let's let's do
um
[Music]
okay so now you can turn on the lights
and do some
dang things to other people in the world
okay