okay so just imagine I have three bags
three different bags okay so three
different kinds of bags so each pack is
given a number zero minus one one yeah
three kinds of bag so the question is
that we want to pick a exactly K bags
there are only three kinds of bags right
and then I tell you how many of each
candies all right so for example like
this is zeros yeah
there are zeros there are Z
Eros
this is minus one negative one next
minus one and this is the one so we say
one okay if we have five bags of zero
three bags of minus one and two bags of
one and we want to pick pick the K bags
K is smaller or equal then these three
numbers added together okay obviously
right so if we want to pick k equals two
bags
so we want to maximize the sum so what's
the sum easy question you say everybody
it's easy okay so put it this way no
back so I find numbers you know three
numbers three times minus one
for number one we have two times and we
want to pick two times we want to pick
two numbers we want to maximize the
numbers we pick is it
two yes two okay if I want to pick
exactly three numbers what's the sum
look I have five zeros which one is the
noun and which one is the amount
it's numbers okay this is a mouth
oh this is the number
oh okay
I want to pick three numbers the ones
the ones and uh and one of the zeros
yeah so that's three or two right okay
you get it okay I want to pick seven
numbers
you get all the twos and then
the zeros what's awesome two I want to
pick a numbers versus some one okay good
then okay so that's good you understand
too hard
it's hard to explain right
so do you understand this zero minus one
one I have five times of zero three
times a minus one two times a one the
question is I want to pick K exactly K
numbers and K is smaller and equal than
all the three numbers added up together
so in this case it's ten K is smaller
than 10 obviously because they only ten
items I want to pick K item which is
smaller than 10 right so if we want to
pick two items obviously we'll pick the
ones because they give you maximum then
if I want to pick three numbers so you
picked it from a zero right it doesn't
change and if I want to pick seven
numbers obviously you take all the tools
and all the zeros right the sum is still
two if I want to pick a numbers
unfortunately you have to take a minus
one am I
make sense now no which probably you
don't understand
in the last part he said unfortunately
you have to take away yeah because the
question is that we have to take exactly
K numbers
okay yeah so I want to find out the sum
what's the stress again to get the ones
all of them and
[Music]
oh yeah I thought you had to make a sum
of two and I was like two ones is two
and and it's like five zeros and two
ones is two and I I and then and then I
was so confused when you said you minus
one okay so let me rephrase this okay
the only three types of items zero minus
one one right they've done this and we
know exactly how many of each
all right I want to pick exactly we want
to pick
K numbers
PK numbers and we want to maximize the
sum maximize the sound
okay
so let's strategy yes we picked the ones
first you pick the bigger numbers
because it's worth all of them
so how do we solve this problem because
we said okay we pick these numbers first
we pick the ones and if we still have to
pick one we pick the zeros if we still
have to pick more we pick a negative one
right okay
that's a corner case I like that I like
the way you think okay Corner case
what's Corner cases
when you pick more than that right okay
so this is the requirement it's smaller
so you can pick more than 10 numbers
here don't get it okay so there's one
corner case think about it what's
another Corner cases look this is the
color cases you want to pick more what
happened okay so the question already uh
said you can't pick more than that right
this is the constraint
on the other hand if we pick nothing
what happened right if K is yellow
just given these three numbers right
like this is the z neck one and then
this K how do we get the sum maximize
some how do you implement it yeah I know
the solution is that okay we want to
pick this pick we are pillar but but how
would you do it and pick the biggest
numbers if K is smaller than one what
should we return
if K it will pick one number what should
return
just one right but if there are two
million two million ones and if we want
to pick a hundred what's the answer
okay what's the answer this is two
million a million yeah and how about if
I want to pick two minion and one what's
the answer
that's right yeah okay so we can do this
if else right
and check if this K is smaller than one
if K is smaller than this number right
let's make it all okay just to to be
different than this number one if K is
smaller than o
then we do 10K otherwise we need to pick
all the O's
and we still have K minus o
numbers to pick right I know we have to
compare this number
to this to this Z right
and if it's more than that then we have
to pick the minus one right
does it make sense
not really anything right you have too
many effects how about if I tell you
this away here all right minus one minus
one minus one minus one all right and
zero zero zero zero and one one one one
okay so now a lot you know how many of
these right this is n times this is z
times and this is
yeah this is a possibly three numbers
only three numbers I mean if you want to
pick K so which side are you going to
pick we want to pick the K numbers
pick from the right yes so okay so this
is the array right I don't want to just
pick a
from here we want to pick K items so how
do we write it minus K to the end
and we just need to return some of it
sum only 10 summer return
so how do we get this a we notice three
numbers right so a equals n times minus
one
plus c times zero plus
plus
o times
one right okay so we construct this and
we do 10 this and obviously K if K is
zero we have to check otherwise it will
not work right because if k equals zero
minus zero equals zero and you will
return the sum of everything which is
currently lonely answer so we have to
check if k equals zero then we can zero
otherwise return at least bit right the
times the next day for this one check
this one the time complexity position
we have to construct the speed right and
we have to do this right so the time
complexity is all
this n plus Z Plus o
and plus KK obviously is smaller than
this term so we can drop it so it's all
this one right
because we
wait and we wanted to pick the numbers
from the right hand side do you get it
yes okay another way another way is
simpler but it's harder to think about
let me write it here and you tell me you
explain to me okay return
I mean
okay I will number of ones
okay one k minus one
minus zero okay and that's it
but this bit this one
okay obviously why you you guys
it's masculine yes
concise okay yeah this is the maximum
what this is the maximum you can get the
ones if ones is more obviously your
return okay if K is more you return once
yes this is two minutes that's a cool
question let's take a look at that later
I'm saying this this one just once this
is the ones we can get right if this is
two million this is a hundred obviously
return 100 if this is three million this
is two million obviously less than two
million all right
okay so now we pick the ones
now we need to pick the zeros if K if K
is smaller or equal than once plus zeros
it doesn't change right if it's more
than that then we have to pick the
negative ones right am I right yeah
this is the thing to pick the negative
one and obviously it's smaller than zero
then we don't have to pick okay
yeah I do notice here there is no even
mentioning about the negative ones
because we don't need to use the value
does it make sense
a tiny bit which pick if you don't
understand I don't really answer
so this is the picking once right I
don't really understand the canines
that's a good question K minus one but
you understand this bit right yeah
yes and you pick the ones and then you
subtract you need to subtract what in
what cases does the answer change
if we haven't reached the step to pick
negative one it doesn't change right
yeah because if there are enough zeros
it doesn't change right so K minus ones
because we have to pick ones yeah bless
you look K minus minus one we have pick
ones yeah and then when you want to pick
the zeros right
and if we pick pick the ones and pick
the zero if this number is still bigger
than zero what does it mean
yeah yeah
it doesn't change the answer right
because here Max is yellow here if this
is negative
this bit is zero minus zero is zero only
if this number is like two what does it
mean
s
yeah because we need to pick two
negative ones right yes
there's no negative
oh that's a good question
okay smaller than equal than once plus
zeros plus negative one right yeah
if this is zero
yeah
if this is zero K will be ones and zero
so if this is zero so what happened K
minus ones minus zeros smaller than
equal to zero so what does it mean this
is smaller than zero then this bit is
zero because that's additional time
because that's very good makes sense
okay that's very good okay so what have
you learned today
we learned about this we have K back the
three bears and we want to find
okay the maximum number you could get it
and exactly K numbers of the amount of
the bag
yeah what's the strategy basically we
like
get the ones and then and then if they
decays more we have to go to the zeros
so if it's still more we have to we have
to go to the negatives
use the negative level what's the time
complexity for this one if there's like
nothing
zero zero zero yeah yeah then K must be
zero because that's the additional
requirement
K is smaller than equivalent zero so K
is a positive number so K is a zero uh
number okay what's the time complexity
um
oh
Wow Come on under this number right then
remember
what's the number I should put here okay
what should I put here
okay
come on what's the time of last day
we're just doing this mess what's up
remember this one remember what did I
say what number should I play right
number not a letter
yeah I saw one right because we're just
doing Real mess yes this makes sense no
okay
if you say no I'm gonna repeat okay okay
thank you bye-bye