okay so let's look at these numbers two
for a 6 okay so we are given a list of
integers positive integers and we want
to find out the product of it right so
we Transit together what's for that I
can't do numbers together
for that this is a way I we've given
this which is 64 times 16. 1024
that's right for example like this 1024
can be represented as 2 to the power of
10 right okay this is the plan Point
number so we want to find out that this
thing number of the prime number
right which is two so you return one
let's take another example
two
four three it doesn't have to be
ascending order okay what's the answer
here
one six eight
so what's this number is it
okay so 168 equals two to the power of
three times three seven is it so how
many numbers one two three so we'll
return three numbers
okay so what's your thoughts about
solving this problem Oh yes do the math
the two times four
times yes
you want to calculate all the numbers
with the products okay and then okay so
once we have this number so what do we
do yeah we give them no no I don't know
what we do what do you call this process
one six a becomes that that we call it
uh factorization
if I get to the power of three
two to the power of three why each
integer yes so that's a good question
each integer can be represented as P1 a
p two B times together okay so this P
are the prime numbers ABC this is
non-negative integers why is it two to
the power three two this is already a
point number two to the power one this
12. is 2 to the power of 2 2 to the
power 1 to 2 to the power 2 equals 2 to
the power 6 okay and three and seven is
already a prime number we can convert
integer back to this format right we
call it the factorization okay your
solution is that we find out the product
and then we do this process right to
this person so 168 we just try if it can
be divided by the first prime number
which is two if it can then
168 divided by two
this is 2 times 84. 84 can be divided by
2. so this is equal 42.
times 2 right 42 can be again divided by
two
is two times twenty one right okay so
look how many two three
okay so what's the next number because
it can't be divided by two again so
what's next Point number which is three
right so 21.
make sense okay so okay so one question
this number could be very big do we have
to do we have to to find out a product
know no right we don't have to put oh
what why would you ask that we are given
this array right we don't need to
multiply it together we just have to
find out the factorization of this
number and this number this number this
number and then we find our owner this P
listing prime factors and put it in the
set then we count the number of the
distinct because set Only Stores the
unique uh numbers and right yes
doesn't make sense okay so let's repeat
this process okay let's take a look at a
more complex example two four nine eight
ten
a okay so one approach we also is
something together and do this person
right but this number could be very big
so how do we do it look these two
to the power one this four two to the
power of two
this nine three to the power of two
10 2 times 5 right
a two to the power C okay so we just
look at this number how many twos one
one one one okay that's two that's three
and that's five so we'll return three
doesn't make sense our task is to
multiply together right we multiply it
together we're still doing the same
process right so we don't have to
multiply does it make sense okay so if
we multiply it
what's the number
hey
320 times a right times a that could be
I don't know you know but once you get
this number you do this reverse right
you don't need this verse
yeah
so I'm already missing number eventually
you're going backwards right so there's
no point to multiply because we already
know what numbers comprise of it right
okay it's five seven six zero five seven
six zero okay so this number is 2 times
again this number two times one for
foreign
obviously
talk about how to improve it
and we're going to talk about the
Improvement in the next lesson okay be
fine let's say F function only given
these numbers we put all the prime
factors in the set right
we put all the prime factors in the same
let's say a equals set it's a data
structure yeah what's the difference
between a set and uh array is everyone
I said what was that stores are unique
it's a hash Table Restaurant unique
number right we want to find out the
number of distinct factors okay yeah it
doesn't make sense right
because of each number X in numbers
first prime number let's say is 2y P
equals two wire X not equal one
wire
X can be divided by the p
then we put this point number in the
headstep right this is the headset and
then
x divided by P right so this is
basically saying that if this number if
if this current number can be divided by
P
which is the point number then we keep
dividing it right okay and if we can't
divide it by a letter we try the next
Point number P E plus equal one okay and
okay we try the next number then return
the length of a
Can you spot the knees you know problems
here or any questions here so far okay
I'm telling you this is the prime number
right this is
and if this number is not one then we
check it can be divided by this prime
number and we keep dividing it and I
will put this P into the set because
this set it stores the unique numbers
right unique number so we finally return
the length of the set which is the
listing number right okay so any
problems here any questions I mean it's
not a problem but any questions so far
[Laughter]
prime number
why is it plus one here
second plus one season prime number so
next prime if you find next prime number
first one is the next phone number no
okay so that's the problem okay U plus
one is not the next one number right
yeah because two what's the next three
what's the next four right do we need to
check the four no right five right
so because of this P we try to let it
represent the prime number but here we
just plus one now this approach still
works because it just you know keep
doing two three four five it's just
doing some useless work when it's coming
to four coming to six because look
when P equals four there is no point to
do this right there is no point to do
this
when P equals six there is no point hey
no point why is that because one p
equals two it's already checking if it
can be divided by two and then if it can
be there divided by two it would just
repeatedly divide it right so when it
gets to the four there's no point right
it doesn't make sense yeah
okay so let's take an example a
so look it comes to this you can divide
it by two four divided by two two
divided by two one right when it reaches
one that's it how do we find all the
prime numbers under 100. you just
basically one two check it every time
table and then cross it out yeah that's
diagonal I'm talking about one two why I
don't know the name right
okay
okay suppose uh this is a hundred so
first of all one is not prime number
because okay okay two
two is the prime number because without
the multiples
okay nice one three because of the
multiples six already because of nine
right
Etc five E three and the remaining is
the prime number right yeah okay so this
is similar idea okay this is the similar
idea right yeah but yeah when you take
three you're gonna check six which is
already that's right one is closer it's
close up right a number cannot be
crossed out twice
yeah I'm saying yeah
yeah I know but this is still the the
most efficient experience to find all
the prime numbers uh under the ranger
given a range okay so one Improvement
you can imagine is that instead of P
right so how about if I can get the
equivalent so if we calculate the prime
numbers if these numbers are given a
range is smaller than a thousand right
so if all the numbers are smaller than a
thousand and we find out all the prime
numbers under a thousand and instead of
incrementing one we just get the next
prime number does it make sense yeah so
instead of p p equals to what's the next
number here P plus equal one that's not
very efficient we say get me the next
prime number which is three get me in
the next one number which is fine get me
in the next prime number seven and
what's the next number
phone number eleven eleven yes instead
of plus one you can get this right okay
okay so what have you learned today
we want to find out that this thing
prime factors of the product of the
array so we need to find out the product
of an array no why because we could just
you could just count
if you could divide the by T each number
and then count five numbers are in that
thingy and then return how much numbers
are in that you counted okay so we want
to find out this thing so how do we find
out that this thing here
suppose a unique number okay so for
example like a equals
one a DOT add two a DOT add three three
three okay what's the length of a adding
one adding to adding three adding three
adding three what's the length of the a
the set stores the unique numbers one
two three three one three okay a equals
at least
a DOT a pen
one a DOT ten two a DOT ten three three
three what's the length of number of a
how many elements in a one two three
three how many elements do you know five
five okay so if I change this to set
only three right because one two three
three is a duplicate it doesn't go in
three is there another deal okay going
make sense yes yeah okay that's it for
today bye bye bye