[Music]
okay
so today um we talk about
something fundamental in python
we introduced two functions
one is called zip yeah
is it what's chip i like
what you have on your code yeah your
encoder you zip
yeah and also a similar
cheap long list okay
so this is deep for short shortest and
then we have
two longest longest so what's tip uh
let's see this
a is one two
three four a list okay
oh and then b equals
five six seven
eight nine okay let's add one more
element
so we have zip
a b what does it return can you make a
guess
yeah what does it mean
no so what does zip do
can you make a guess close it can you
make a guess what
zip them two sides meet each other yeah
yeah yeah so zip your return
it's a generator which i've mentioned
later but it eventually will become like
that
one comma five this is a two player it's
like a list
but it's immutable you're not immutable
you know what's this mean no
mutable what does it mean
mutable means the change you can change
it immutable means you can't change it
yeah one five it's like a list you can
if this is you can change it you can say
if this is
a0 equals 2 then you can change it you
what does this happen when a 0 equals 2
then you can change it yeah
yeah but at least you can't change it
one is a 1
5 you can't do this because it's
immutable okay
so why it's just the symbol this is
called tupa
t-u-p-l means
okay so one five comma
two six comma one what's
[Music]
so this is zip to get it so you take one
animal from each
and then you put it as a two part a
group and then
chip longest can you make a guess what's
the difference between cheap longest
and a b what does everything
no four a we got a four a here but zip
longest
you were according to the next longest
which is four nine
no no no you're quite close so you
eventually will become a lung here
because there's no element here yeah
then you'll become a nung knight
okay yeah it doesn't make sense yes
longest add one more animal okay okay so
let's
implement these two functions okay you
can do no none
yeah and then it's opposite ba if it's
zip longest ba
yeah so like defined let's do a zip
function a b so first of all we want to
blend the length yeah
the length length will become
mean of these two right
lens a and comma lens b so now
i will have this small list yeah
and i can have this the answer if i
convert it to a list
yeah for i in
range aira right
yes because the mod is the answer
drop a pen open what
a tuper yeah you can another bracket and
wow
[Music]
and then
return answer yeah this is returning at
least but in the
in python it's not retaining a piece in
person you if you do it this way
it's not a list you have to convert it
because this is called the generator
so basically we are not returning here
because we know returning we are
returning the entire list
this this thing will return one at a
time so we remove these
and we don't need this and then we don't
need it but we we are retaining that so
we call it another keyword called yet
what's
yet why yeah yeah so every time
i give it yeah yeah i give you one
element and then you can use it as
you know you can use this for i
and then every time you give me a
element okay
the longest okay now the longest one
so i changed this to longest yeah what's
your turn here
but now
now we need to do this let's store it a
a equals
in that a equals a i
if i smaller than
length a as
noun right yeah because
this i may be bigger than the length
then we have to
put it as noun and bb equals
b i is i
smaller than length b as what
[Music]
zip longest you see yeah let's do the
coding
[Music]
maybe do the coding you'll be more clear
yeah
can you sit down please can you see that
please
oh no connection here no it's a little
bit
yeah that's very strange
so is it is it okay no no
no let me let me move this here
okay take some more time
a little bit early bloody
oh yeah let's korea let's verify it now
yeah
it's very clear now yeah yeah okay let's
do it
no i need a couple cup of coffee
yeah look at look uh let's do this chip
function first okay look uh
zip let's get a equals one two three
four
five okay and b equals
uh like uh six seven nine
a okay let's just do this and then you
tell me what's what's the
that i can convert it to list okay let's
dip
a b what does it return
1 6 1 6 2 7 3 8.
look you see look yeah yeah
but because the smallest lens is b yeah
then i can i need to follow it away to
us
import because this function is in this
library long list
okay now if i do this it's
longest what what's you
what what's your line later what's your
in return
what would your return
[Music]
wait it's still not very clear
wait wait wait
better better okay
let's make a guess okay you see
it adds one two more elements four now
five now
right you use now to fill the space
yeah correct okay
uh okay let's do this
zip zip the dot py okay let's implement
this
a equals one two three four five p
equals six seven
eight okay oh why is this still
okay okay it's blurry it's not it's okay
okay let's
let's do this define my jeep let's call
it my zip okay
just to avoid the same name okay
look let's do this uh then lens
equals mean length
a lens b okay we got the smallest then
four i in range l a right
what y e y e i l b
and then a i what
b i okay let's do this let's see
okay so let's let's print my zip
uh list my zip
a b okay and now we can print
the same as the the other side okay at
least
my zip ba okay yes
yes does it make sense yes yes
okay now let's second function
which is my zip longest okay so you tell
me what to do okay
define my zip longest
a b okay so what what's that a equals
what
instead of minimal yeah max and i'm
getting the length of the
a lens
[Music]
now we got a a equals if it's smaller ai
if i smaller than length
a that's it
[Music]
let's do this longest
what's the problem can you make a guess
9 20
15 20 and
what
ah the lens another b okay not lens
there's no aoe there okay okay that's a
mistake yeah
yeah you see doesn't make
what's the difference between cheap and
deep longest
the longest uses none
yeah to feel the space yeah empty space
and zip you just have the smallest
yeah smallest length okay so this is the
function we
this is very important useful function
uh
so i i'll let you see one more time okay
okay yeah what's the complexity term
complexity
if we convert it to i mean
we can convert it to give me longest
yeah
uh n yeah oh
and n is the length of the maximum of
yeah
if there are n uh elements
in the longer list yeah which whichever
is
longer which is uh could be a could be b
yeah it's always the longest
do you understand this you have to
keyword if
it's not your keyboard if if okay let us
do this okay
look if if this
is not one two three okay if b equals
one
and then if you do this a and b you you
will have an object iterator because
it's not a list and then you have to
tell it for example you you have to tell
it like uh
for you can convert it to list or you
can do this
for i in zip a b
and then you can print i uh do you need
to
print the i yes does it make sense
yes yeah when you're using a
generator you can put it in the for loop
okay otherwise if you want to
convert it to a list you can do this c
equals list
zip a b and then c is the list
yeah got it yes yes okay
okay okay
okay good job today good job today turn
on the lights and you
i can't see