hello hello everyone ryan
okay so today we're going to talk about
the another data structures so
can you tell me what have you what kind
of data structure have you learned in
the past
remember we got a queue yeah and
towers and stack yeah
and at least as well yeah at least yeah
they both these three kinds of things
can
all be represented in python using this
bracket yeah
yeah it's a square bracket this is
square breaking right
yeah okay so today we're going to add
another data structure so remind me what
is data structure
it's the structures to hold data yeah so
we need to
let computer to hold data so then the
computer can process the data
right yes so we're going to
add another data structure called set
so can you tell me where it's set
up no setup okay set
is a collection but only
it's a collection but only with the
unique data
okay do you understand unique data so
for example like
okay so if i if there's a bunch of data
one
one two three four four okay
so look there are duplicate elements yes
duplicate elements ryan you play
there are two fours two ones so this is
uh
you can have a list of that but the set
we
only if we convert it into a set it will
only contain
one two three four okay
they understand because because these
are the unique
elements so how can we do this look
so look if we have a numbers
nums yeah equals
we're given a list okay this one
two two three three
okay that's it and now we're converting
it to set
so how can we do it we can do this uh
let's call it n okay and equal
set we use this keyword set
and bracket yeah you can take you can
create the empty set by doing this
right you can create an empty set by
doing that or you can take a parameter
with the list
yeah numbers so what do you think will
happen
now the end we are content
we're content one
two and three okay and the set
is an order it means that it's just a
collection and you don't know which
comes first
but it tells you those the uh elements
which are unique okay
okay so now look we can do this
it's simple yeah yeah okay so we let's
call let's introduce another graph
called
van graff this is interesting van graff
okay so basically let's say
we have a collection here a
okay yeah collection and here we have
another connection
b okay so this connection
we can call it uh
we assume it's unique so we can use the
set a set b
set okay so now a sub b say
so a let's let's use this one
a equals set okay i can't see
a a is a set okay a is a sense
okay b equals an asset
okay so now what's this part
what's this fit a
and b both a and b so the elements both
in
a and b all right so we can use this a
and b this will give
me these will give these elements here
right
so you all you can write it this way a
the intersect
intercept b okay
a and b so it will be you will return
this part so for example a
is one two three and b is two
three four a and b will return two and
three yes because two and three appear
in first one okay yeah
yeah and how about all together so
a plus b not plus b actually a
or b okay it's all single a or b
a dot is the same as these two are the
same okay
eight of union what's the meaning of
union
unions union i union u so we put it
together so
look a b union together that would be
what's the answer of a union b
a or b what's it it'll be
one two three four okay so all elements
from
how about i want the elements not in
not in common so it's this bit only
speed
this bit so that we call it what we call
it
a plus b
now a is too same
so we use this uh
symmetric difference okay symmetric or
just
symmetric so maybe uh
so how do we do this is a dot symmetric
uh right difference
okay b i don't know how to spell it but
you know these meanings
a uh we call is exclusive so this will
be 10
on the side no no you will no
it will return all elements which are
not in common in both sets
so you will return one one and four
okay one and four okay
how about a
minus b can you tell me what y is a
minus b
so it's in
it's in set a but it's not in set b
all right one yes
so you return one okay that's the return
one
and the the opposite will be the same
okay so we can do this a
smaller or equal b we can say if a
is a subset of b okay
or b if it's a subset of a
look at any set is a subset of itself
okay because there's an equal right
yeah so if we remove the equal then you
will exclude the equal
case which is that is a strictly subset
of another one
so how about if we want to check if two
sets have something in common
yeah what what do you know how to know
if there are two sets have something in
common
so look we can use this one right a and
b
and we can check the lens yeah that's
one way
the other way would be a dot
is disjoint
b okay if there's anything in common
okay so this is the set data structure
and we can add and remove it
so for example we can do this we have
this set
we can say a dot at
another one element like five
after this a we have five okay
here we go and we can remove it a top
remove
remove five then the fly will be removed
okay okay do you understand
okay so so this is the basic uh
operation of using how how we use the
set in the python
it is actually very powerful okay
so how about we know we if we want to
if okay so let's let's
let's do this okay
if i give you a string if i give you a
string
a b c you need to return
return true because
only numbers all the characters in the
string are unique
okay but if it is a a
b c you need to return first
do you understand because the a is not
unique it appears twice
got it say if it it try
yes false yes yes so how do we do
it how do we how do we use the set to
define
to define it that
yeah i know i know death that's
definitely
let's write it okay it's fine
[Music]
don't worry you got plenty to turn
afterwards okay listen carefully and
then you write it
practice define how to record the
function
then graph set unique let's say unique
you and iq you need a string okay a
string and what's
missing here yeah that's the answer
you always get it right right
so so how do we do it we can
we can have different ways of
implementing
for example we can do this okay the
easiest way
the most intuitive way would be i create
a set first okay
let's go create uh uh
let's let's call it uh
what the
uh st okay
set it's uh equal set we create a set
okay
now what do we do we can iterate the
function
for for i
in s
okay then we need to do this if
i is
so how do we check if a set has some
some uh
we can use this right if i in ins
plane inset right
can we use this if i insert then we
return false
otherwise i will place the st
i will put it at i
and otherwise i will return true that's
one way of doing it okay
let's see if it works okay yes let's see
if it works
wait be quiet
yeah he was walking
what daddy
yes when it enter look what happens
okay where is it space
oh yeah i've got something yeah and if
you've got something
okay so this is one way of doing it
we're creating a set look we check if
this integer
uh you know if the character is already
in the set if it's
ignoring the same i would determine for
otherwise we put it in the set
and so to get it yeah so this look
a b c that will return true right
because every time it's
it's only appearing once but aadc look
what happened with aadc
a it's not in the set
i put it here but the next one is
already in the set we already put it in
a set then we determine first
do you get it okay how about the other
way
we take these we take the whole string
and put and and build a set
and then check the size if it's the same
as the swing size
so it will be even simpler so how do we
do it
yeah we can do this this is the same
unique
so we build a set we build the set
and we we need to take we need to
take the s build it okay
and then how do we do it we pretend
we just returned s dot size no no size
length s t equals
length s right do you get it
look we're building this
if we build a set using this string
using these
characters then the set will have three
sides
three three elements they're unique
right so this is true but these
if you build a set using these
characters in the string the set size
will be three but the string side will
be false
they are not equal am i now not equal
eric do you understand so you see
this is not one quicker way of doing
that this is the traditional way of
doing that
checking checking if they are
if they are duplicate if this string
contains
only the unique characters okay
do you get it so which one do you like
best
which way do you understand
[Music]
which one that one this one is more easy
to understand yeah yeah
okay but this one is cool yeah it's just
one land
yeah okay two lines four lines
okay okay one no no no this comes there
i mean
this is one man this is one one two
three okay
ryan any questions no is it
does it make sense yeah okay good
okay okay thank you