hello hello everyone ryan
hello today
uh today i'll talk something um very
fundamental in python
it's a function called illuminating you
may heard of it before
he knew numerous what does it mean
i think it's something about fractions
not exactly okay i i i give you a code
here for i
let's say let's say s
equals hello hello
okay it's a string yeah say equals
a new melody don't
[Music]
yeah yeah print i v
so guess what's the input what's the
output
hello what's your guess
what is the point you print two things i
and v what's i what's v
oh hello i'm a numeral
um hello
and you need
[Music]
stop being funny okay come on i and v so
what's the
what's what does they print out yeah i
think it's it brings
in new melee and then hello not exactly
okay so
you print this basically one
two three four
this is i i will i will
okay
because there are five letters and then
you will have print
v will be h e and uh
do you get it do you understand oh
they understand enumerate your general
tupa the first element will be the index
from zero zero one
okay and the second
second element of the tuple will be the
value so it's
exactly like it's exactly like what
so it's this is exactly like for
i in what range with
a range and then what are we looking for
lens lens s
and then print dot com
i and then what s
i okay so it's the same thing you see
these two is the same thing okay so
which one you like
better this is
this this is the second one okay
so second approach i don't know okay so
this function is basically to it so how
can we implement this in numerator
look it's i it's almost here yeah so how
how can we write it
i'll write it here okay
let's say define
let's call it enumerate or enumerate i'm
not going to write down okay d minor s
[Music]
instead of print what are we going to do
return do it now
remember that yesterday there was a
keyword everyone can use
guess what i'm going to end again a
keyword come on
keyword yeah style is y and then e
we're done y-e-i-l
[Music]
okay let's see let's see that's the
implementation of the enumerate do you
so basically these this thing means that
give me these paper on the floor give me
these
one at a time okay so this is exactly
what the illuminate does okay
everybody is watching you on youtube you
know you're famous
you're famous okay
okay i need to sit down
okay let's do it
can you know please you're on youtube
please
let's say e let's just tweak e
numerator okay numerator okay now let's
see
let's let's do it hello hello
eric and ryan let's let's see i'm lying
okay okay i
i let's say for a b
uh i i think it's the same
double that speech mark wait i
i forgot the c
quote for ib
and then point a b so guess what's the
output
oh it will bring one two three four five
and then next week
yeah hello if you read it from top to
toe you'll be hello
eric and ryan and the left will be the
index yes starting from zero
can you sit down if i i can also do this
i can also do this alright for i
in range s range
length s then s will be given this yeah
and point
what queen i s i
okay so this is the printer same thing
okay
printed the same thing so this is
exactly the same thing yeah you printed
the second time okay
hello let's do let's
let's divide it uh
yeah let's do this uh
uh let's do this blue my
enumerate okay and as you tell me what
to write are there four
i in range
length s one and
one what's here the word style is
y u
[Music]
and then you can use it as this you can
say for i i
in my initial life okay
s and then you print i
asi so it's the same thing yeah can you
can you be good boy please
the string index must be integer
so that's a problem a problem
i think i'm going to make a point to our
plane so what's the problem here uh
okay for enumerate let me try
look look i here will be i
s i a okay so here will be
i there's a problem
okay let's see
too much is too much uh extra brackets
here
did you know that sometimes there's a
mistake okay that's okay but let's
we call it the box okay so now
everything is the same
you see every four to six is the same as
a to nine okay and then this is how we
implement the enumerate function in the
front
in the line number five okay so
basically the same thing
yes yes do you understand now
yeah do you understand perfect yeah do
you understand
do you understand
okay that's it let's take it quickly
okay turn
on the lights and that's it for today
say bye bye to
people and we'll talk see you next time
but