hello
[Music]
hello hello guys hello
you're not guys so today
uh so first of all what's this one
uh two
[Music]
basically you're doing so can you what's
this first first of all
[Music]
basically it's the two times two
dimensional it's a
matching usually it's two times two so
in that person you can do this
a list of this yeah yeah so at least
at least a big list has three three list
smallest so also can you notice
something special
about this magic yeah it goes down
zero one two three four five six seven
eight
nine ten eleven two oh well
i actually didn't notice it's already
salted yeah
so basically basically for each row
it's increasing it's salty yeah each
column
is increasing yeah yeah yeah i saw that
okay well done okay now if i give you a
number
like four is it in the metric
yeah right yeah i know but computer you
need to take computer other search right
[Music]
target like t and then this matrix m
so can you tell me how to certify it mmt
so how how do we search for it i need
any sauce
we can the the easiest way the most
intuitive way is to go through
each row and each column and then check
if this element is the same as t
right yeah yes
and what's the complexity if they are
if they are m rows and
n columns what's the
[Music]
what complexity there are n rows and n
columns how many elements are there
yeah m times n not every time you're
guessing
you see because you are looking big you
are
you need to go through each element to
check right
right in the worst case in you know what
state i'm right
okay so this compares to your worst case
for example if the number does not
appear in the matching
then it takes n times n to check right
if i give you a number nine how do you
know how that how does the computer know
it's not in the metric
it has to check please list this this
this how many times
nine times n times n times okay yeah
do we can we do better three times three
can we do better
three times three all you need to do
is sort it what do we start it
ryan pick up one wait any thoughts
i give you a hint how about if i start
here
and then if i want to look for number
four let's play number two
okay it's two bigger or smaller than six
smaller okay so does it go left or
down it goes like yeah
no no i'm saying if if it's two is
smaller than six
should i go left until i go down to look
for it
sorry no no i
i said i go left or so i go down just
one choice
left because down is seven it's not
possible right
should i go left or should i go down
left so i get left now left
left yeah down wow do you get it
yeah you can also search from this
direct direction
so i go up up up yeah okay do you get it
yes okay so now for the first first
aquarium so we quickly implemented okay
define
please
[Music]
i n times n yeah m times n or
o yeah o m times n if the dimension is o
m times
n okay okay now we do this the second
version
look at this babe what no no look
the second version is if we have these
rows columns
equals uh let's do this rows
equals length m yeah that envelope
i'm well thank you if zero equals rows
if it's empty then we need to return
four right
this is anti-magic a magic can be empty
yeah i'm empty
row columns equals n
let's get in the first first element
and the same if zero equals columns
return first
okay now let's the interesting part okay
so now we can say ah
equal uh let's let's um let's put it on
the top
right corner which is zero yeah
minus one okay start with start with
zero
and then why why this location is still
in the metric yeah if
it's outside then we can't find it yeah
we don't find it
so y r is smaller than rows
yeah and column is bigger or equal than
zero
where this location is still in the
metric if
okay you tell me okay if metric
ah c equals
t what's what's your idea
what's your identity
if the t is bigger than if t
is bigger than that element so we should
go no
we should we should go down remember
remember we should go down which we
should
should i do so i equals plus equals one
if is smaller then we move right how how
can we move right
how can we move right yeah how can we
move
right okay how can we move left
c move left columns
move left left c minus equals one
one yeah and then after this
wow okay okay okay now wait
what's the capacity i'll give you a hint
and and i know you need to do something
here
time time i am
time oh n times n is the previous one
you
you just need to harmony so look
yes look if i go from here to here
i need m plus and step all right i need
to
i need to work horizontal and step right
and i need to work vertical and step so
it's o
and plus o m plus n right got it so
so which one is better which one is
better
om at n yeah you see it's better yeah
it's quicker
it's quicker wow yes okay
please please stop right ryan
i think this is good is it not babe
wait wait okay
i think we are good
[Music]
i got this
i think that's okay yeah we can still
yeah it's okay
you can see it yeah yeah okay where are
you
i'm running the table okay okay
wow that's a cost wow wow that looks
very strange
let's do it okay
let's see let's do this metric okay uh
metric equals how do we define magic we
can do this yeah
can i get water yeah
it's also bliss
how do you do the big brackets big
brackets canola easter egg
square bracket one four
one seven yeah and then
two five eight right
three six nine right
okay now now
this is the magic and then let's do this
look we we do this search version one
which is let's take a m and let's take
it
if c equals t return true right
return fourth all right yeah
let's say let's let's see the search one
let's end let's find five is there
and then let's find search one and let's
find the 10 you should point what what
should you
win what should this output
i like false two and fours right you
have two
two and four all right because i print
twice right
the five is in the array but if the two
is not
in the metric and ten is not okay now
let's try the sec
uh let's just try to write another one
let's just put random numbers here
no no no m t
such two okay so now please ym
rose equals len m we got a number of
rows
if zero equals rows we return
four right columns equals
length and the first row the columns
then if zla equals columns
[Music]
because a list consists of another three
list and then now
r c equals r will be the first row and
then columns will be columns minus one
y are smaller than rows and
what c
bigger than zero yeah if
r
[Music]
true
you can put it as a yeah as if
it is bigger than mrc now we go down
right
should i go down
so what how to go down r
and s what c minus equals one
then you return
let's do this uh
search two since two
yes still two of us yes
[Music]
okay so let's go through it again this
is the blue force we go through each
element in a metric that takes
an o m times n right
and this one takes all m plus
n because we we at most we are visiting
m plus n elements in the metric
right depending on which comparison of
this value if it's the same
then we found the target if it's bigger
than the current cell in the magic we go
down because it can't
be on the right left hand side all right
we can go down right
yeah otherwise we go left and return
force okay
any questions so far
[Music]
okay that's it for today good job today
good job today
good job good job
turn off the lights okay turn on the
lights and two big thumbs up
okay that's it see you tomorrow