hello
today we're going to talk about the
inverted binary tree okay
so what's the invert what's backwards
[Music]
adjective verb adjective verb
okay so so yeah you're right this is the
verb but this is the
adjective okay so look let's let's let's
take an example of
how to do this like this
this is a furniture yet yeah and
2 7.
so one
three six nine okay
okay so can you tell me what's the how
do you invert it can you
write it daddy
no no no we don't need it
[Music]
oh okay so can you explain to us
what yeah you're all right so why why is
that say
thank you
you stop it but how about this 96 why is
it become on the left side
and three one is become on the right
hand side why is it not
like uh 31 69 why is
why this is not right why this is all
okay
because uh all you need to do is write
it down
and it's like looking on the mirror but
the numbers are the right way around
okay yeah you're all right so yeah when
you it's like a mineral so when these
three one you'll become on the left side
okay
yes yeah yeah okay we're done so so we
can do it
here okay so look
oh wait if you tell me what to put up if
rude is numb
so what should we return
you're doing this part okay yes
inverting this part which is left left
here and then
right equals inward
low downward right right
okay that's good okay now we cut this
left beat and wipe it now
we need to assign loot on left
equals what do the left equals one right
right yeah
okay good job oh what's the complexity
what is n number of
n number of nodes in the root in a tree
yeah
got it yeah yeah bye so where is the
recursion happening where are the
recursion can you point to me
where are the requests in this
in where are the questions what's the
one guys
which part is calling itself
[Music]
[Applause]
where's the invert because yeah these
two yeah
these two are calling itself until the
root is numb when we turn now
otherwise every time we work we
invert that time right but we need to
swap it
like mineral right we need to swap it
bye