hello today we're going to talk about
symmetric three what's symmetric
symmetry
the same on both sides okay so
how about if i give you a tree is this
magic is this no no
okay so can you draw a binary tree which
is symmetric okay
wait i probably could give you a nice
this is can you get the more notes like
another two or three you know i will do
it another one
okay that's fine i'll get ten another
one
okay and then yeah
so let's put here yeah four yeah
[Music]
oh wow okay let's see now let's see
enough right now i don't know
let's see right you don't you don't need
to stop can you tell me
why can you explain what are the
symmetric trees
and then and then
and then
and then it's what yeah
it's quite similar to yesterday we
talked about invert yeah
even when you use police thing in here
right
but now we are just we just like a piece
of paper we just fold it
yeah when we fold it it needs to be
together exactly the same yeah
that's called symmetric okay got it yes
does it make sense
yes okay so now you tell me
so symmetric if a tree even i give you a
root yeah a root
and then you know the left tree or right
tree
then one way of thinking a tree is
symmetric
is that its left tree should be mineral
to the right tree all right yeah this
should be middle
not the same so in order to do this we
can define
first of all we define uh a function
is symmetric okay symmetric
a b and i wait wait a two three is a
and b okay okay and
if if we wait wait wait
let me say if a
is noun and b is non so if both are
empty
so what should we return why because the
empty nodes are
called uh if two two threes are nothing
both nothing
then they should be considered as
symmetric yeah
and then if at least any stage
the blade must not be the same
noun at the same time so if if one of
them is noun
if a is noun or b is noun
why because if one is something the
other is nothing
yeah it's not lovely confidence magic
right
yeah yeah so can you give me an example
for example like
look look if it's one two and you could
do nothing on the right hand side
so this must not be a symmetric because
we've got nothing yeah you got something
on the left hand side
so return four
this is return two yeah i forgot to put
it okay now
now look look
now i check at this at this stage now i
need to check
if their values are the same right look
if uh so this is
left and right a and b okay this is a
and b
and then i need to check look this is
c d b e
f this is a and b okay this is a and b a
and b
and c d e f so now i need to check a and
b's value should be the same right
so i can say return a the value
add the equals equals
b b
so look if the play they are not the
same
then we know it's not symmetric right
because they must be
mirror yeah they must be the same right
and now we can recursively recall itself
right return
n is metric asymmetric
okay i'm going to write a the left
just be the left now now at the left
should be
the same as b right you see yeah it's
not left look
in order to symmetric a the c should be
the same as
f symmetric right because it's folding
yeah so this is b
dot right and then can you tell me
what's next it's magic
b the left is this one so when you fold
it together these two should be the same
yeah these two ship in the same least
value should be the same
okay and then if you want to symmetric a
binary tree
no then we could we just need to call it
return
symmetric reads left magic
right because look even loose then i
just need to call this okay this left
tree and the right tree
should be symmetric okay
yes okay so what's the time complexity
where is what's the end the numbers oh
how many nights the number of nights
a number notes in the final street okay
well
okay okay wait wait what's the space
complexity
why because
and another all night again because we
need to
check each we need to check each note
right
we actually need to check each other
okay so can you tell me which parts are
the cushion remember like yesterday
which part exactly is here yeah
yeah look the cushion is calling itself
not this
here and here right here yeah yeah
because we are calling itself
to iterate and recursively check if both
stop trees no no yeah
[Applause]
[Music]
okay no more