hello hello hello
look this is yesterday so we talked
about how to check binary tree is
symmetric right
remember this yeah yeah so this is
requested
yeah we check if a a and b the variable
and then it's sub
it's subtree is also symmetric okay so
today
we talk about a few things and then we
talk we'll come back to these
again okay so it'll be very interesting
because it'll be
very interesting okay so
first of all how do you make a copy of a
tree
you know first of all if i give you a
tree yeah give me your
if you copy it the same way yeah
okay so at least i i want you to copy
you know copy so make another copy so
this function will be like clone okay
you know what's clone
clone chrome is the copy yeah
to make a clone make a clone yeah make a
copy
yeah so what do you do look
this we the copy in computer we have two
kinds of copy one is
called deep copy the other one is called
what's the opposite of dip
yeah we're done deep copy and shallow
copy deep copy
did you get that correct share a little
copy
so can you tell me what's the difference
deep copy and share copy
they're the opposite yeah they're
opposite so
what's yellow copy what's deep copy
can you make a guess deep and shallow
yeah so okay you can think of it as a
complete
you know i want to make a complete copy
so once i copy it
copy and paste it copy it you'll be the
same
you'll be exactly a copy right so
you i make another copy yeah
so these in memory you'll be different
places
so what i mean different places is you
can change
the things here but it wouldn't affect
here because they're different
yeah yeah they look the same they look
as simple they're different places you
change
this place you change the value to seven
and these ones
get one effect won't be authentic
shallow copy is the other set
and on other cases it's like alias
do you get it it's like alias so you
make a copy
of these then you'll be just a
another pointer points to that okay so
you'll be
point is it's not an individual it's not
an independent copy
right so when you change the value like
if you change the value here then you'll
be
linked to here your chain also be
changed it's the other way right
it's like in areas for example like
i give you another name like what's your
favorite name
salty shark yeah salty shark yeah and i
call you salty shark
and you you'll respond that's called
shield copy
it's like ryan is a clone of you
right i call ryan right
and then you wouldn't respond because
it's different right
do you get this point okay so we are now
talking about
the difficulties with deep copy
in in computer look
if a shallow copy so what's your copy
wrong
shallow copy in in python you can just
do this i create a node
right root a new node like the same
neural new no no
then you can say let's uh let's call it
tree okay three this is three and then
island return return new law
okay so you just copy this no
but you are not copying its subtrees
right you are not copying these subtrees
so this subtree is the same is exactly
the same as the previous
right it's just good you don't know but
for the column
let's talk about clone the entire thing
and then you tell me what to do okay
it's like look
define clone
loot okay
[Music]
new node equals
equals 3 is the root value yeah with the
root value
and then and then now
top left equals
one clone calling itself crown and left
string
clone what clan wait
do the left yeah because we are
controlling the left and then
new and then new node
right equals one plane
we don't write we're done very clever
very clever the next one
the next one
[Music]
white come on what are we doing
no no yes no yeah
do you get it we're creating a new node
with the value exactly variable but we
are because
we're recording itself to clone its left
tree and the right tree and we're
retaining the new node yeah this is
called deep copy
look at
so now we talk about another one which
is called uh
checked with two trees are the same
yeah we have one two three two three how
do we check it's the same
one it's the same i mean the structure
is the same
and the values are also the same okay
so yeah tell me how to do it all right
define let's call it same okay
same or maybe maybe equal
equal same it's not quite a good word
equal right because they are not the
same but they can be equal right
yes let's call it equal equal
a b equal and
column if
a is now
and p is now
what should we return in this case none
no no we are two between
two and fourth yeah we are retaining a
pulling value here
pulling
if both trees are empty we should call
it
yeah then if
a is noun in this case
or b is noun what should we determine
or false yeah because at this stage one
of them is none the other is not
right then one is something the other is
nothing
then they must not be equal right all
right
it must be not be equal
okay man let's say
if a dot value not equal
check these both trees first up trees
left yeah and then one b b
what right no we're
[Music]
is
so do you get it we need to check and
the values are the same
and then its left trees are the same and
the right trees are the same
and what are the recursive cores here
where are the recursive of course
how many questions here
how many how many
how many recursions in music in this
call
two three two where's two where's three
you probably never western education
western call with the importance
[Music]
what's the complexity yeah because you
need to visit the same time yeah
to be honest it's not exactly o n if
i tell you because there are two
parameters here no no no
no no don't don't make it again random
guess this is abc sp
if i tell you there are n notes in a b
nodes in a no n nodes in
a n nodes in a b n nodes in b
so what's the complexity n m
[Music]
minimum and and m right right
because you for example even know if a
tree has a 10 knots and another tree has
a 100 no you just need to
check the 10 nodes at most then you'll
find out if they are not equal
right you get it yeah so do you see
yeah yeah i is a minimum of
in minimal okay so that's it don't make
the random guess okay
when you when you
make a case of log n usually it involves
dividing something into half
right you get it let's look and where
the rocking comes from okay so now we
we know how to check the trees are equal
and we know how to crown a tree so how
can we check if the trees
and we also know how to invert the tree
right remember how do we invert the
binary tree
remember remember let's
let's let's do a review okay invert yeah
we talked about this before yeah invert
load
column okay look if
loot is now return one
now and then left
equals invert blue
tower left yes and then y
equals one we don't white inverse yes
inverse right
okay and then then we need to loot the
left equals right right
let's call it inverse yeah universe 5
yeah and do double y equals one
huh look at that we go right to do the y
equals
left left yeah we are working and then
we turn one
watch through you're not making return
what
left right wait
you're making it you're not no why are
we doing here we are writing new words
we are reading the root i thought we
yeah i know look we are creating the
we are loot and we need to assign that's
why why you say between two or four come
on
don't make a guess okay now we are
inverting so now how can we check if
two trees are a tree is symmetric
remember how do we check the symmetry
tree
okay you tell me okay you tell me okay
symmetric
loot okay i can i can do this yeah look
clown uh let's call it new
uh copy okay copy equal as
clone let's clone this tree first
okay yeah yeah yes and then what should
we do with it
then we also need to invert it
yeah invert the tree okay
yeah and then
how do we check if the two three sides
if the tree is magic all you need to do
is
the other one is
uh you make a guess come on equal root
n1 we are comparing the load with
white claim clock yes copy
copy do you get it look
we copy the tree right we copy the tree
we invert it and if the inward version
is the same as the root
then it's symmetric am i right yes i'm
right
look one right
two two
three three four
look four we make a copy
and then we use this what's in that
your inverse version will be one
two two and one
it will be the same as this one yeah
yeah exactly
so because that and you check if these
two are the same even
is equal it's it's symmetric got it
do we have to clone it no we actually
don't need to clone it why can't i have
a razor please okay
look if we allow to modify it we can
just do this okay you tell me okay
return
that's the same equa
left plus
and something here
really
what does it mean look even three
and that means okay let's see
let's do this look
look this blue we want to check if it's
symmetric
we can compare its left tree right
and then right three we need to invert
the right tree
even writer will be this yeah then if
they are equal
then it's symmetric do you get it yeah
yeah yeah if you're comparing the loot
all right then
then it must not be equal right
right because this you'll be you'll be
like that and this is not symmetric at
all
right okay what's the complexity
i went yeah for most the final
things yes it's awesome because you need
to visit the trees
end times nine years number of times so
do you get it
so what do we learn today can you review
everything yeah
what kind of function do we learn today
we have we know that deep chrome and uh
yellow color can you tell me what's deep
color what's yellow color
what is sheer copy deep copy is yellow
copy
just in one word
come on copy what's the deep copy
and what's what's the difference between
deep copy and shallow copy
it
[Applause]
so if a tree if a tree
i want to make a copy exactly
then you'll be another tree totally
independent yeah if you make a just
assign a note
to it a copy of the note
yeah and then you visit this copy to the
left you'll be pointing to this
you get it this is called yellow copy
yeah
apart from the chrome method what do we
have what we learned
also we check if
two trees are symmetric
uh yes matrix and also equal right this
is equal right
yes and then we also know we invert we
know how to invert the binary tree yeah
yeah based on these three we also can
know how to do this symmetric yeah
symmetric do you get it so these are the
four
four things we have visited today yeah
we are visiting today today
yeah do you understand yes okay yes i
understand
okay wait wait wait okay that's it
bye bye
bye