hello hello hello hello
[Music]
today we're going to talk about uh
converting a sorted list to find a
research tree so can you remind me what
is finally search tree
bsd is a tree yeah it's the final it's a
tree it's a binary tree
uh it has numbers yeah it has
numbers they're in circles
so what if this is four this is
three and this is five and then this is
two
and then this is four point five maybe
this is seven
so do you get this do you get it the
final research tree
first of all it's the final tree yeah
and the other left nodes are smaller
than the root
all the right nodes are bigger than the
loose so you can search it
yeah like if i want to search two i can
go to the left side because it's smaller
than four right
and it's all getting smaller than three
and then i go through this side yes
so if you do perform and in order
remember what's in order so
in order to traverse up
in order if i if i visit
the left note first and then i reach the
root note and then
visit right now so what you will give
give us
is a sorted list am right yeah because i
always visit the smaller nodes
and the current nose and the bigger nose
so this is an assaulted
order right yes do you get it
yeah okay so now today yes
do you get it
today we talked about assaulting this
remember something this like
one two three four
five six six seven eight so if i
want you to convert it to a binary
surgery
obviously you can convert it using many
uh there are many ways right
so how about if i tell you that i want
to you convert it with
to a balanced final surgery or minimum
height you know balance such
[Music]
binary means that uh at any note
that the difference between the depths
of
two subtrees are always smaller or equal
than one so it's
balanced this is not balanced look this
is not balanced
right you can obviously you can please
and
one two three four five like a link list
yeah
look this is the final three final
research three
it is also a linked list yeah but it's
not parents
right it's not parents yeah it's
territory yeah do you get it
so the the complexity of searching
in in a balance in the binary search
tree in the worst case is o
n right because you you're not making
use of the fact that uh
you're making the balance if it's
balanced then you can say
it's o what one o log n
yeah yeah if if it's not balanced in the
worst case if it leads then it's over
yeah we're done okay so now given this
sorted
sorted list how can we convert it to a
binary
balance binary search tree
i think how about if we take the current
which no i if i take it as a route
the one in the middle
okay so look at three or four it doesn't
matter yet because they're too long
three okay i pick three so now
all the notes before it are smaller than
three right so it goes on the left three
yeah
it goes these two goes here right i've
got a big
thing yeah yeah i know look and every
nose after three
goes well
right on the right yeah we're done look
it's on the right
so again it's on the right look again we
are dividing
this into two sub problems right for
these two and
one and two right we again can pick one
in the middle and then do this
recursively and for this
four five six for example pick one in
the middle which is
five five okay then i put a five here
and then
put a five okay so now we are dealing
with five five
four goes on the left hand side of the
five right
and six yeah right yeah you see so we're
building it
look yeah yeah so what's the complexity
if you do
if i w1
in what cases you need to tell me it's a
what one constant is like
compared to the sum of the first n
numbers you
you have equation right yeah and you
don't need to iterate
over the numbers you can just do do a
mathematics equation that's all one okay
that's the only time
you need to tell me is the one for this
one is o and why because we need to
visit
we need to use n numbers in the sorted
array
to make a list okay to make a tree so
now
so now let's do this defy
okay let's just call it uh fear
bst what's bst
uh binary such tree okay and then let's
go in numbers
we are sorting this is thought number
and what's missing there
yes okay that is if the length of the
number
is zero then we need to return one
return now
okay we need to find the meter in the
middle okay so what's
what's the one in the index is mid
equals
length dams divided by 10
yeah divided by two let's see roughly in
the middle yeah
not exactly in the middle sometimes if
you have four numbers what's in the
middle you can pick the
second one or the third one yeah yeah
roughly as long as roughly in the middle
okay so now
roughly now we we pick here the root
which is three three now again we put
the tree now
which is the the one in the middle so
which one is put in the middle
lambs meat right yeah yeah
because any number is in the middle so
now we have the loot of this value right
now we need to recursively construct the
speed
and then we spin okay so the
the peak on the left so we can say loot
dot left
equals beard pst f we because we
call it yeah yeah i am looking
okay the numbers now we need to take the
numbers between look one two three
four five now the meter is three yeah we
need to take the numbers before three so
we can use
lamps look look this one bracket
and column anything up to
meat yeah the meat is the index yeah
so look there must need
and then lose the right again
we can build it yeah because we build it
so how do we take the numbers after
three look you can do these
lumps one thing meat plus one okay
meat plus one so start from meat plus
one
column that's it you don't need to
specify the grains
actually look you numbs from
column 2 so this 2 is not
is it's not equal right for example 1 to
3 it will be one two not including three
okay
up to three not including yeah so from
from anything up to mid not included
mean
from mid plus one up to the end not
including n
yeah that's okay so then this is
nums need plus one yeah
and then we turn what we answer
wait yeah we are building this little
note
okay so that's it let's see uh how we
building this tea
and can you tell me how many recursions
are there
again i asking i'm asking this question
again three
weighs three where's three why do we two
yes building the left tree and building
the right tree look we divide this
problem into two small sub problems
which again we can recursively build it
right this is building and for a
recursion to work we need to specify the
terminal condition which is
if we don't specify this what will
happen you are
in in differently calling itself itself
is there and
but it doesn't know how to stop right
am right if you don't specify this then
you call yourself again itself you say
itself until computer dies do you get it
yeah so we need to tell you if the
number is empty then
you just give me a noun right
then you will stop that and it will come
back you will build it build
this building step by step you get it
yeah this is top bottom top button from
the top bottom recursion yeah
look we pick we pick the one in the
middle
right yeah we pick the one in the middle
then
we know because we salted this we know
the left three
the nose are before this meter now right
and the right trees
are after the middle right yeah and then
we know this
left tree left three again it's a tree
right and we can we can pick the middle
note in the left tree
in the middle yeah we can always pick
the middle and then
separate it into left and right okay
do you get it do you see it
yeah yes i see it
okay okay that's it for today
okay