hello
[Music]
[Applause]
hello hello hello mr eric hello mr ryan
hello so remember we talked about this
much the two sorted list yeah nice
build bst yeah i i know i left yesterday
but we talked about this the merge two
link list
starting increase like one two
four and there's two three five
remember yeah you want to merge these
two assaulted
linked list or this you know if it's the
least it's the same algorithm okay
so look we have we have a
tummy head this is tummy head so what we
do
that means we don't use it for the
moment
okay so now we have two pointers it's
one smaller than
two yes so i point i i take these
put it here okay now
it's two smaller than two it doesn't
matter so i think the two
so i can link i can take this
it's two smaller than three yes so i'm
i take this here and put it here yeah
okay
is it sweeter than four other than four
smaller than four yes
so i put a three here and i take it off
is four
smaller than five yes i put a four here
then pop then i need to take the
remainder yeah five okay
so now this line is assaulted like this
yes
okay got it yes the complexity
[Music]
right if m is the link sorted link list
the number of the
uh the number of notes in the first
linked list the n
is the number of notes in the second
english yes yeah okay so let's always
oh n
oh we can call it o n if n is the number
of the linked list
in the final sorted
one okay so the version yeah yeah okay
so now how about if we have
k salty list if we have
no no n so yeah
if we have k how can we do it if we have
one line can we do it how can we do it
can we look look we can three pointers
we can merge it one by one right yeah
so let's define merge
okay list and let's do a list
here here is list okay and then
we can do this the answer
the first first answer is let's do it
first answer
is okay so now look if length
of the list is dialog
then we return nothing right right
yeah return the list all nothing it
depends on what you want to return okay
and now we
we can set this answer equals list
zero from the first list first link list
yes
and then for i in
rent one start from one to
lens list yeah and then
we can say answer equals
much
answer list
i right yeah we are actually merging
these this one by one yeah
and then return what return
match the answer yeah so basically we
have
filtering we have a list of linked lists
yes we have a list of languages and then
we
we take the first one we mulch it to the
second one and we must keep merging
until
all of it yeah what's the complexity
[Music]
this is oh this is all right
emerge and they are kaylee's how many
are we
okay
yeah merging each one takes n
for complexities are okay and okay so
can we
can we do you see in a way
how about you look if these are if there
are like a list
yeah if i can look like like
list like this there if therefore okay
fourth linguist let's say for english
okay for english
can we can we merge divide and conquer
they look like lollipops
look can we can we merge these four
divide it into half small to these four
and model these four yeah
yeah and for this four i can merge this
for two and only these two
and here we know it's number of two then
we can merge it
do we get it so so we divide it into
half
and then we every time we merge much
keep merging and there is smaller one
and here we know okay so how can we do
this look
if land let's say let's
let's do this land equals length list
that's the number of lists yeah number
of lists we want to merge
okay now can you tell me if air is
zero return one none
by
itself right return leads to one because
we
this returns at least not so list one
how come
how can we get the first first and first
element
every year right key what number for
here
one zero star from zero okay if
lens equals to
return what we have only two lists
two linked lists we can just merge it
yeah
yeah merge remember we have this
multiples here yeah
so what what should i put here please
what
this yellow and
list what's the next one
what should i put what number one yeah
because the first
this and the second is way down okay now
the three
now the middle one what's the middle
mint equals one
hour divided by what
the meat roughly the meat what's l
yeah it's the lens yes divided by two
okay
so now we have we know the middle one so
the left
the left let's say left
left okay that's the equal
merge okay list we are calling itself
yeah
right now listen list
up to meet yeah remember yesterday we
said remember yesterday we convert a
sorted list into a final research tree
we use least
notation as well i mean up to me but not
including right
and then right and we want to merge
another half
merge k list
this meat meat and column yeah
that's that so that basically you have
you know the meat here yeah this is the
meat yeah
and you want to imagine it is calling
itself to merge this path and calling
itself the merchant of this half
that's why it does wherever and then we
have the left here
and we have the uh right here so what
should we do now the last last sentence
return what
much left left last one
yes left between and what
left left and right yeah yeah
you see it makes sense yeah yeah so we
because you're dividing into two how to
list
and then we're calling itself to
deal with a smaller problem right and
here
the length is zero one or two then we
know how to deal with it
and after we get this left and right in
english then how can we merge it
we know how can we how we can merge it
the complexity
[Music]
okay
okay it's the okay and why is it still
okay because
it also needs the k times look look if
like i have one two three four
five six let's say i want to
oh how many times i need to merge look i
tell you look
maybe seven eight okay now that at least
how how many
times we want to merge three
one time two times three times four
times yeah
five times six times seven times
you see it's actually k minus one time
do you get it
yeah even we divide it into two but
still we need to
merge these ones yeah merge these ones
yeah
and merge these two ones much less one
more this one much less one and the
multi ones
and i think we get at least that so it's
still
even it looks like you divide into two
but still you need k times k minus one
time but we drop the constant so it's
okay
yeah okay yes why is that because we
need to merge the k list
it's not like divide it's not like the
log and
binary search what will we divide it
know how we don't need to consider the
other half right
yes we make we click a number and always
we divide into
let in that case the complexity is what
again yeah we are done okay do you make
sense yeah does it make sense
yeah so today can you sum up what's
what have you learned today just one
sentence another people
in the world know okay can you tell me
about
magically okay salty list yes yes
and what is right eric can you tell can
you tell people what have you learned
today
how many saltines
what's the function name this bit
yeah merge k sorted list list has to be
merged yeah we land the merge two sorted
list and we apply this to neg
technique to merge cases what's the
complexity
okay