hello hello hello
hello everybody hello mr eric hello mr
ryan
today we are today we talk about
um okay can you make a guess okay what
i'm going to talk
[Music]
another one so can you tell me what i'm
going to talk about
not exactly can you just tell me get
in the section yeah
yes intersection yes what what
what what no don't do the german notes
okay so look
this is the linked list eh yeah come on
come on
language is a yeah go this way and
english b
and then we should do that and then
we our task is to find the intersection
okay
to get it yeah so we this is
intersection point like
this one two three four five
six and then seven eight nine so what's
the intersection
what's the intersection what
nine where's nine in this session is
four look this is seven
eight nine four five six this is one two
three four five six
you'll get it yeah
yes any idea how can we do it any
thoughts
any thoughts any songs remember i give
you a
set because she said no book
yeah oh when yeah
you have two notebooks you put that one
down
then you put that one down
yeah look when i visit this note i put
it down put it down nope
put down and then i travel
using another now check if it's in the
notebook if you don't look in vienna
it's in the more book then return this
yeah
yes do you get it yeah oh oh i have no
way
yeah pretend daddy
is here and erica is here and
they want to go to the supermarket okay
and this is
[Music]
[Laughter]
so it's right and stop looking it's not
exactly the same okay come on
uh in the intersection so look in this
section
yeah i don't know
okay so the notebook we're using the set
look notebook so we got it
we put in the notebook yeah notebook
equals
equal set okay we still remember this
set yeah
yeah yeah so look we can do this
why hey okay why
we hey we put it in the notebook yeah
notebook.ad
and we go to next which is a equals a
dot next okay
yes yes okay now
now we put a is reaching the end okay
eric has got
has gone to the test
now ryan's brian starts to walk okay
so why why i'm not reaching the end okay
i'm walking then check
look if if b i'm
a
[Music]
p next right yeah
that's it you don't need to return
anything right
here that means there's no intersection
okay yeah
got it what's the complexity o n
o a plus b let's say okay because a and
at least
the length of the a b that's a b okay
what's the space complexity i went
look we are putting all the notes in a
to
in into the notebook right right if you
know which
which one is length bigger than you can
probably
wait look if if a is
a hundred node and b is ten nodes you
want to optimize the space complexity so
so you can reverse this yeah you can you
can
you can put a notebook
put the notes in b to the notebook
instead of a so in this case that would
be ob
okay so i let you do it so you can do
this o mean
a b yeah you choose the meaning
[Music]
do you get it right yes yes okay so now
can we do better can we do better yeah
can we do it without the notebook can we
do better can we do it
okay i give him look oh
okay and that this is the linked list
okay
okay and then another link list
okay so now this is a
this is b he needs more more
i like look so so how can we do this
i'll give you a hint okay look here yeah
walk walk walk
walk and then look this is getting the
end yeah
send that one no no no no no you will
move to this
this yeah okay walk
this is go to the end and then comes
here
yeah walk
and walk and then meet here why it is
working so basically when the a goes to
the end
and it needs to start with b when b goes
through the end then it starts with
a and they will eventually meet here
okay so let's say he didn't have destiny
then we just meet here look look there
what look look okay you
don't even have this it's still work
look you see okay
okay okay okay
okay and then here go back to okay
here okay okay here
here it still works okay
do you know why he's working okay okay
do you know why is working good question
look just think about it if if this this
bit
is air okay before the common part yeah
air node air a node let's say smaller a
nodes
here and smaller b notes here and then
there are c
notes they they after the common
intersection part they are signals yes
yeah so look in a
traverse a plus c okay
and then if we let it go here that will
plus b
go to this yes all right look
a trevor here a plus c right then i let
a star is here again
and then b notes here right okay
and then b plus c right
and then like let it start with a that
would be a no here so b
plus c plus a so do you see what's the
problem
what what's the problem what what are
these
these are these two equal yeah
look they're like equal yeah yeah so
they are equal what does it mean
they will meet here yes yeah yeah do we
get it
is it interesting what's the term
complexity
o a plus b to be exact yes yes b
oh maybe you are right a plus c o
a plus c plus b c b
actually is two c but we drop the
constant okay yeah
okay a plus b plus c is the number of
nodes okay
and then let's do this coding okay
define
okay get intersection okay and a
b you see then let's say
a head maybe i i do this uh
look this is smaller a okay a b equals
a b c d
now they are at these two okay then y
a not equals b
right look a
equals a dot next
is a s b
look yes and then you tell me what to do
b equals b dot next look at this hey
if b if we still not reaching the end
as we make it to the star of a right
and what should we return return a or b
here right
a or b because after this loop a and b
will be equal right
see it can you tell me yeah can you
explain to me now
what can you explain to me what what is
it doing
if you get
[Music]
y a and b are not equal and not met each
other
a will move to the end and when you
reach the end you will come to the b
yeah when b will be reaching the end
you'll
come to the a and after this loop
a and b will be equal all right you can
return a or return b
do you get it yeah any questions
sure what which one is better okay
that's one question
which one is better this one
this one is better because what's the
space complexity
um oh something
yeah i know do we need about b
no look space complexity right again
don't think logan no a
the a the one you like to guess
a1 yeah what is the one constant do we
need any more because
what the lens do do you see
the problem the previous one why is on
because we have a notebook yeah yeah and
if
that the link is a 100 million items
in the notebook you need a hundred
million space
right but this one if it a notebook it
has a hundred million notes it doesn't
matter i still
only have one variable a one variable
two variable that's it right it doesn't
scale it doesn't
grow as the solution as the size grows
do you
get it this is how we talk about the
complexity okay so don't make a guess
why is log log gain it doesn't make
sense here right you get it
yeah look at it yeah okay so let me let
me
tell you a little bit about the
complexity okay
yeah yeah yeah okay yeah yeah okay
okay what's the time complexity of
merging two sorting lists
solid list non-linked list okay list
like this
one two three four and then another one
five
six seven eight what's that if this com
this size is n this size is m what's the
term complex is your motion
and add or multiply
are multiply sure oh what is
add look you just need to go through
each one right
what's the space capacity
[Music]
and and add
why what what space do you need uh
[Music]
tab space complexity if you
if i walk oh what can you keep saying
and
adam why because we need why
because the merge merged the final
merger is the knees the end plus m
element right yes and then you need this
okay and one more time
come on come on finding
finding an element in the sorted list
okay this is the sort of this if i want
to find four number four
what's the complexity if there are n
elements i want to find the number
okay how about if this list is unsorted
and sorted if it's just random number i
want to find
any number okay a random number
and run them and run them with n
we want to find the find the number in
there
space complete time capacity
uh if it's unsalted if it's not sorted
[Music]
it's not salted and what's the way to
sort it you need to find one
yeah what's that
what's the space complexity to find this
number
do you need a space
why do we need a space this is not
encountered
do we need to allocate more space to
find it
do we need to allocate something what
does
like mean to create like the notebook
you need to educate the notebook you
need to allocate that
much this no that was all logan
why not yeah oh oh one come on one is
when you don't need it you owe one do
you get it yeah
yeah why you say no don't say it again
okay
come on another one another one and here
you make it right okay
okay what's the
if we don't uh
remember this remember we talked about
the magic yeah when this is magic
and everything is bigger than than
previous no
yeah do you
still remember yeah
yeah we want to find the number of news
talking
[Music]
tests it's it's very important salty
salty metric and we want to find anybody
in a certain
metric in the thought matter is m times
n what's the complexity if
there isn't any nine i know i know if i
want to
find the eight okay what's the
complexity
if i want to find a that gonna have to
be
remember we took this a few days ago
definitely not a1 definitely not
oh what it's sorted remember we move
move oh and
yeah if it's not salted
if it's just one i want i want i want no
it's not salted
if it's not salty we just we need to go
through each number so
once and why you always keep saying vlog
where's the load
and and yeah because we need to follow
it yeah
okay okay don't get it yeah well tell me
when
when yeah
when well can you give me an example one
is logan come on
you like logan and tell me when is it
the time complexity of logan
you know what's logan you're not look
not too based
the graph is like that yeah yeah log
i know two a equals one plug
two eight equals three
yeah and not to 124 equals one
something like 10 wow well yeah that's
good job
good job yeah yeah yeah
yeah let's let's not too the only time
having this
yeah carving having let's look
the first thing when you want to say
lock is
is halving okay so sorting algorithm
usually is
oh what sorting if i want to solve
something
and sorting
log and log n remember this is you just
remember yeah
let's for any sorting angle on the most
and square okay the simple saudi regular
okay let's leave for today too much
talking today
say bye to people bye bye
bye bye