hello hello hello hello hello
hello hello mr mr ryan hello hello
hello so what's this tonight
do you still remember this word what
does it mean guess
i think you like something with magic
not exactly so monotony look
if i tell you nothing one two three
four five six seven and then five four
three two one both these two links are
monotony
this one is monotony increasing this one
is not any description
they all are doctor 6 black scale
no it means the monotony you can at the
moment
increasing increasing or more level of
decreasing
okay so the mean look alright
function by function look this is the
monotony
monotony function because when x grows
when x grows the bigger x is attention
monotony when x
grows y also grows the bigger x will
give bigger y
right yes less monotony so how about
this
how about this how about this graph is
this monotony
no no it's monotony increased decreasing
the bigger x the smaller y
do you get it so because the trend is
going the same direction
but this is no monotony this is not
right because it goes down and goes up
right this is what morning monotony
means
it can be monetary increasing or
monolithically decreasing do you get it
this is monetary increasing array
because x array is always increasing
right yeah and this one is always
d decreasing right okay so our task
today is very simple
simple so you're given the numbers at
least
arranged at least the numbers yeah one
three
five like like two seven is this a
monotony no
no okay so given the function
it's easy monitoring yeah
any given numbers so return true
if it's either monetary increasing or
monetary decreasing
return force if it's not so
any ideas how can we do it just see
it's going down number one yeah i know
but how to do it
how do you do it one
is what smoothness is
one is smaller greater than three so
it's smaller so we just keep smooth it
is smaller
yes
not not not nice quite close quite close
so all right quite close so
so basically quite close so one hint is
you check the
neighbor numbers yeah for example if i
want to check increasing like
i check it's less number it's always
bigger than it's five bigger the
next number is bigger than current
number is fine this one
no right because no because two is
smaller than five
that in this case would return false
right yeah okay so
but but but you need to have two
functions right one is to check either
monotony
increasing or the other one is to check
monitoring decreasing right
right yeah so here you will say return
is it increasing i am just increasing
okay
nums this is check increasing numbers
or decreasing yeah
decreasing numbers
okay and then i need to implement these
two functions right
all right define pay attention
increasing and then you tell me how to
write yes
this is num num so now i need to check
for
what i need to index from here to here
what's the index for i in range
the length will be length lumps
minus one minus one remember we are up
to here
yeah why does seven over n and
and then look if
none current numbers which is i
yeah this will be increasing then if
if it's bigger right
if it's bigger than lungs what should i
put
here if this dance i
is bigger than this way so what's what's
your happen here three
this is i and what's what should i put
here your index
it's next next something dot next
i dynamics i plus one come on
if this number is bigger than that it's
not an i
it's not a monotony increasing so what
should i return
false
okay now if i change this function to
mono
to this squeezing look
if i change this to the squeezing and
then do you
can you tell me what should i do to make
this function work
if i want to check if it's decreasing
yes
uh could that be
opposite way which is
small yeah okay so
what's the time complexity of this
function
yeah yes but you need to go through this
array twice right
yes because the first time every first
time you go through to check if it's
increasing and the second time goes
through to check it with this squeezing
right
yeah okay can we do better
can we can we do it in one pass
so how about look define look
okay i write the code and you tell me
how
how it works okay look monotonous
monitor just monotonic monotonic
lungs okay and then now look
magic yeah look increasing
equals to decreasing
equals two
that's the fact okay and then for
i in range this is the same
same thing lens numbs
minus one right okay look
if lamps
pay attention okay
if numbs i bigger than num
i plus one if this number is bigger than
that
then it's not increasing right the
return focus no no no
increasing i set it to false right
because current number is bigger than
the next one so the increasing will be
false right
it must not be increasing yeah yeah
i minus what i plus one if the current
number is smaller than the
next number then the decreasing is not
false yeah
all right all right
yeah you can air is equal is false
[Music]
and then what should i return here
return
no oh look at these two numbers
two flags look in return what
what or what guess
increasing or decreasing yes we're
why is that can you tell me how how this
work
so we assume make the assumption that
it's e
is both increasing and both disgracing
right
yeah but once we find an opposite
case we say to false right we set it to
first
and after going through this one time
then
if it's not set to false if we still
true then it's increasing or if it's
equation reset two is
still decreasing yeah can do do you
understand
yeah can you repeat can you say
no
[Music]
um if
if if it's bigger than it
is smaller return false not return force
here is just setting to force not
returning all
okay then
so we make an assumption how about
how about if i if you just look at one
increasing i
i assume the array is not only
increasing
right and now if i first
find a place that this number is bigger
than the next number then it must not be
increasing right
yes
it's the same goes for the decreasing if
i assume it is
decreasing but i found the number
current number is smaller than the next
number then it must not be decreasing
i'm right
yeah and if i go through this number of
numbers
once and if the increasing is still true
then it's increasing monetary increasing
if that decreasing is still true it's
more than decreasing
okay right something or something this
is all
okay what's all okay
oh it could be that one okay
oh two is what two or three
two two or
two or four is one both
two or fours finally look this is the
binary
binary operator two or fours three two
three
two two of us is two it's two okay
first or fourth is doubles
for a fourth thing that's it yeah fourth
or two
it's false false are true
true so for the binary or is that one of
one of at least one of it is two
then is two right yeah you got it okay
so how about another one
n what's n mean
okay okay two and four
a three fourth
fourth and two
fourth and fourth
so for this n that both sides must be
true
to be true but for all one of it is two
is two
right one eric or
ryan okay one of them is okay but eric
and ryan you both must be the same
they're gonna
eric and ryan go to eat lunch
you two must go to long island eric
o'ryan go to eat lunch one of you go
that's fine two of you better but it's
right do you get it
yes let's end that's all okay this is
very important look
increasing that that's what it means one
of one of them is
two that's two okay got it yeah this is
finally and
all and how but not not not
is a single it's not it's a unary
you know unary so not
is this is binary you return you require
two things yeah two things a and b
yeah a or b yeah but it's not
not it's just one so not a so like
not two equals one
false false not false
two yeah we're done okay so that's unary
you know unary
yeah one one binary two
okay and then also there there's a
tendering
ternary this is three
timer three okay we'll talk about it
later but you first of all you need to
know
no no a and b two this is more important
than two
not okay and another one okay the last
one
which you have a guess xor
exclusive o x or what
x or y exclusive o
okay look two x or
two equals four okay
2 x or 4 equals
right fourth x of 2
equals 2 and then fourth
xor 4 equals 4. so can you tell me
what's the principle here okay
oh if if they're both the same it's
false
if if they're different it's true well
done yeah let's exclusively okay
we're done very well done
okay for today
yeah okay that's it