[Music]
so today we will talk about how to add a
two-linked list
so for example like you mean exchange
no edit for example that sounds a bit
easy okay so tell me 46 plus
74 equals
120.
[Music]
okay so one way of doing one way of
doing this is
start from the least least significant
digit yeah so so it's the right most you
start with
six plus four is ten right you carry
over one here yeah
so 1 plus 4 plus 7 equals 12
you put a 2 here carry over one so 1. do
you get it
yeah okay so now
this is easy to understand how it works
okay so how about i tell you that
this number 46 is a linked list
represented by this six link to four
and then 74 in reverse okay so the least
significant bit
digit is confirmed yeah this is the most
significant
uh digit this is the least significant
pieces the left most
are the most significant the right modes
are least significant right because the
left mouse are bigger carry more weight
right
70 70 7 is 17 four means just four right
okay so these you're given two head
linked please this is
equal forty seven yeah a and b and what
i want you to do
is to to edit and then
and then put a link list like 0
2 1 any sauce
y 0 to 1 120
is it
you have any sauce any sauce just just
some random
uh brainstorming how are you dealing
with it
you don't want me to worry about coding
just tell me what's your source of
solving this problem
yeah ryan any thoughts
no wait wait wait wait all you need to
do
is the
answer then write it backwards
find the answer and write it backwards
okay that's one one solution
so one solution is that we
we come up with the method to convert
these liquids
into a number right so we convert this
into 46 and we convert this into
74 and then we know in python we just
add it together and then it will be all
120.
then we find another message to convert
120 back to this right
to link this yeah yeah all right yeah
that will work i mean
it has some overheads of converting it
converting from linked list to the
number and backwards converting the
numbers back to the english level what
random network
so look when we deal with the
addition we added these numbers one by
one right the from the right to the left
right
then we how about we are now at least
at the beginning of the two linked list
why don't we just add them together
now we know it's 10 we carry over one
yeah it's like you're adding numbers
from left to right but
from right to left now i'm from the
right to the
to left right yeah yeah six
plus four ten i put that here
and then i carry over one yeah you put
it here i
carry over one okay so one plus four
plus seven
two twelve i put a two here i carry over
one right
yeah and then one yeah so it's it's
exactly like this but in in different
direction right because this
is good because we we are now dealing
with these numbers
from the right to the left from right to
left and
now it's good we are here right we're
here at the point into the
least significant digit do you get it
yeah yeah okay so can we
uh how we i write it and then you tell
me what to write okay
define add
let's call it as yellow and l1 okay
link list yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah okay so
yeah we're done so uh
that's diff let's create a link link a
thumbnail head yeah this is
yeah dummy means that uh we are not
actually using this dummy head to
represent any value we're just using it
as a
placeholder it's next value will be the
bigger result okay so like dummy
equals this node
uh node minus one that's just two minus
and then head equals dummy also
i'll show you why we need this dummy
here okay and carry let's
do a carry carry is carry over will be
equals to what carry equal to
one at the beginning carry is zero right
no no no zero because you don't have
carry at the moment okay
so now this is interesting b y
l zero while we still have the s yellow
o l l1 oh carry right
yeah any of these remember only oh
what's all
oh if any of this condition is true then
it's
it's okay yeah so what am i missing here
okay so now current sum okay current
digit let's do it digit
current digit okay uh maybe current
current digit current digit
carry first okay carry okay
now we need to add a carry right yeah
okay then
is this l0 next one is
curry current digit
a equals a z out of value right
okay you tell me what to do if x what
if l1 what should i die here
if anyone even as yellow like if n0 we
still have
lcl value equals current digit
plus equal
yeah yeah okay now the current digit is
the sum of this current and then i need
to do
what head dot next
right look i'm adding a new note
equals this note
so what should i do with the current
digit at the current digit
current digit is 12 i need to add a two
right currently this is
three i need to add three currently it
is is 23 i need to add the three so
currently so we need to add ten no no
no we're adding this number we only add
one digit by digit but we
adding the three but we need to carry
over one right for 13
all right look look
47 plus 64. seven plus four one
eleven yeah yeah i i put the eleven one
here
but i need to carry over one okay this
carry over is this carry
over ten
yeah i know tens but what when here
i'm not adding ten plus four plus six
yeah i'm adding one plus four plus six
right yeah but that one represents ten
ten
i know yeah i know so i'm telling you
like
what should i put here seven plus four
eleven i just needed the left
right most digit right yeah so how do we
get it let's know the current current
digit right
current digit what
remember the modulus divided by 10
remains
remain yeah all right
remain what we mean
one remain 10 do more than
10 okay okay now we're linking this list
we're linking this value and then
what head equals head
dot next right moving this to the next
one
look if we a1 if l0 if
if this value this link list okay like 3
4 43 okay if if we still have this value
we need to add this value and move it to
the next so here
missing l what is zero equals s zero
next right and here again a one equals
a one dot next right yeah and then when
this is
again when there's a carry over then you
keep doing until and then
this current did carry over carry over
equals one
look 11 is current digit
and i'm adding one here to here
and then i need to add this one
to the make this one as a carry over so
carry over equals current digit
divided by 10 right yes all right
yes and then at the end of return return
what
we say guess can we call it no no no no
no a header will be equal remember
no head yeah dummy
but remember we're talking about the
tummy tuck yes
next we're done yeah yeah
you're listening yeah tell me done next
look tell me
now you see why we're using the dummy
right yeah dummy is the
placeholder it doesn't hold the value
but it's next
pointer it's pointing net pointing to
the answer
that's why we tell me you can put any
value here yeah
any value any value i don't care because
i'm written in term in the next
and then i had equal stomach why is that
because every time i create a new note
look dummy i i created you know what i
do i create a new note and put a
head would be dummy i had the next
equals this create a new now
and header equals head next then i move
to here every time i create a new note i
put it
link it linking okay
what's the term complexity
what's n what's n what's n you need to
tell me what's
n the number nine where down
the number of notes impose linked list
okay or you can say
o n plus n where n is the linked list
for
number of notes the n is the number of
notes in one english m is the number of
notes in another english
okay what's the space complexity
[Music]
something it's the same yeah because you
need to create a space for that right
a type it'll be o o
yeah it's just o n you know i went yeah
for no reason
yeah because look you add in two numbers
and then
normally you will be you you'll be
actually o
max and m right
you get it because you're adding two
numbers and the length will be
maximum of the the maximum of those
two right yeah i'm right
9099 999 plus one
there'll be a ten thousand thousand yeah
look
nine nine nine nine four digit and then
you one digit and the result will be
four plus one digit yeah yeah the longer
one yeah so that's what it comes from
okay
eric any questions for so far for this i
i assume this is a bit complicated am i
am right
do you understand
which part you don't particularly
understand i can teach you i can
explain a little bit more uh
i'm fine you know fine okay so how about
i
so what why is this why is this why do
we need a carry here
why or carry can you tell we need to
carry this yeah
yeah if you have like 794 is over
10 yeah sometimes when you finish
adding the numbers and you still have
one carry like
99 plus one yeah you add in the numbers
yeah but you still when you add it
that's zero zero right
you still have one carry if you don't
add this carry the answer would be zero
zero which is not right right
do you get it so that's why you need to
have this carry
and then you need to finish when this
carry is zero as well so you put one
here
got it that's what it means and then if
if our error zero if
it means that we we are adding the
values of the notes if
that we still can have this linked list
note
right and move it to the next move it to
the next
okay this means divided by 10
like 123 divided by 10 is
12 right yeah
this means that okay so 17 19 17
a divided by 10 equals one uh
seven point eight no this two means
just integer power is seven okay yeah
just seven that's what it means and then
seventy eight
modulus ten equals one
seven eight divided by ten
is seventeen seventy eight is minus
seventy is eight right
so basically these modular ten is the
these eight them
the the right digit the lemons digit why
eight i wanted eight and then i multiply
ten if i only seven i divided by ten
you see how we get the numbers yeah yeah
this is how we get the numbers okay
okay any questions
okay i'm gonna see you tomorrow okay bye
bye