go hello everyone ryan
hello how are you today why
you're good yeah okay so
uh previously we talked about a list
they
had nothing to do we got another list
we have uh talked about the stack
remember yeah and we talked about the
queue
yeah yesterday we talked about the set
remember reset yeah the van glove okay
today we're going to talk about the tree
tree
why it's a tree it's a tree the tree
okay so tell me
a draw what kind of tree you think it is
i think i can't really do it with
straight
that's okay okay that's too much details
okay three what kind of tree is there
[Music]
does the tree have i think i think
the math train something like something
like maple tree
laboratory like that actually really
i like that okay okay
okay too many airports okay
ryan that's that's good enough ryan
okay maybe you should color it later
with the airport red okay
yeah that's okay thank you okay sit
there please
okay so what what do we have for a tree
what does the tree have
a tree i have a the loot
yeah the root yeah um
leaves stems apples
okay apples green fruits okay
but but not every tree have these apples
or fruit yeah all right so we don't
okay so now we and the trunk okay we
have a trunk yeah
the trunk okay let's go okay so
these are the trees in real life but in
computer
in data structure we we we plot a tree
this is an interesting part
yeah yeah you saw this picture yeah ryan
yeah it's like that yeah
is upside down right this is loot
yeah root and then these are the leaves
leaves okay leaves leave note
okay so it's upside down so
another another thing yeah another thing
notice is that every note
can have only maximum one parent
that's his parents okay so if i
okay don't worry about it okay so look
that's right let's write this 1 2 3
4 5 6 7
so 2 is five's parent
okay that's his parent and that is kids
so try and not okay five is the kid of
two six is a kid of three
six and seven are kids of three three is
the parent of
both six and seven okay so can you tell
me which note does not have a parent
there's one note which doesn't have a
parent
which is which no does not have parents
a parent a one yeah one doesn't have a
parent
ryan can you sit down please
so one does not have parents because
it's the loot
right okay come here right so look
a tree so a parent
so one property of three is that
a triad
can have all at most
one parent yeah okay
okay and a trial and the parent can have
many many childs i have children okay
okay so this is called a tree now
another property
is that if if we say
uh a parent can have at most two
kids okay so if a parent can only have
two
kids so you cannot have more right like
that
it means four that's that's okay so
these
if but if a note a parent
can have at most two kids we call it
binary tree
because you know what's this meaning
binary
library i know binary is two
you know it means zero or one two
two maximum let's call binary tree
okay to get it so we cannot if it's
binary we can call this left triad
and this is right trial right left
we can call it right all right
let's try that because it's finally yeah
this is very
hot important apparently okay so another
thing is
another thing is what if if it's a final
tree okay if it's a final entry
so if it's a binary tree like that
finally three three are terrible
so that's one two three four
five six seven so if it's a final
retreat
and every every triad except the last
you know it's every parent
yeah has have two two kids
and except the kill and
[Music]
mom and dad um okay yeah
no no actually this is a parent a parent
and then i have two kids
then we call this uh perfect binaural
treat because it's perfect every
you see heavy so can you tell me
if look if it's a tree
if your final tree is perfect but how
many knows
is it suppose that we see the depths we
call these steps
you know the steps yeah okay april 7.
yeah it's seven how how do you know and
how about if the depth is four
and how many how many notes are there
two can you count
if it's the depth look if stats is three
if it does the three we got the total
notes is seven you have
one two three four five six seven if
it's steps or four
we can have another two here another two
here another two here another two
so how many how many is that fifteen
baby
[Music]
how do you know because i know do you
know how to get it
no suppose the depth is d and the total
nodes will be
two to the power of d minus one
i'm right look with these ryan
i'm not planning on youtube if you
behave bad people
we see your friends will see okay so
behave
well okay can you can you come here
please
anyway that was well done okay d if d is
three
look two to the power of three minus one
is
seven two to the power of four minus one
is fifteen
two to the power of five minus one is
thirty one okay
get it nine yeah nine
how do you get is thirty one because i
know
because nothing we know that's 15
so 15 okay so
that's that's eight double sixteen
sixteen
sixteen thirty one dab okay
okay so this is the equation yeah if the
depth of the binary tree is c
the perfect the perfect minor tree is
the node has has two to the power of t
minus one notes
okay we'll get it like
two two to the power of two minus one
equals three okay there's
one two three okay get it easy and only
one note
two to the power of one minus one equals
one yes
it makes sense yes yeah because we only
have one note it's only one depth
depth equals one okay this is called
perfect binary tree
okay got it no you don't get it
do you want me to tell you again okay
that's okay you can can you sit there
please
probably ryan you've been you've been
good okay
okay you want to sit there okay okay now
now this final three if it's a perfect
financial okay
we're just talking about the perfect
balance perfect binary tree
perfect fine energy
so how can we store it in the computer
yes no not that we can use the list to
store it
so how do we store it like like that
look if it's
one two okay one
okay let's call it
let's start from zero okay that's yellow
that's one that's two
i feel tickling left three that's four
that's five that's six
so how do we store in computer we can
store in a list
by left list this is
the root note okay let's store it one
zero
one two three
four five six
okay so look
the definite the triangle of uh
should you try you ever ever
ever look the
the evil parents parent if the parent
two
two two parents two and how can i get a
parent uh kid five
two kids yeah how do do that
two to the power two is two
parallel each kid is five one five and
one six so this is index
so we can get to the index right look at
this two
two two times two plus one double p
is left kick two times two plus two that
will be
right right right and right kid all
right the second kid
let's take one for example one times one
times two
plus one equals three right
and one times two equals plus two equals
four
okay so get it okay so let's do another
example
zero cl times what two plus one
equals one zero times two plus two
equals two
okay so does it make sense so if it's a
perfect binary tree
if if the index we store it in a in an
array
if the index of parent of node is i
then its left kit is two times i
plus one and its right kid is two times
i plus two m right
do you get it so we can store in a list
okay
you get it okay so how do we
visit the let's say okay
let's give an example okay for example
let's given this tree
can you please pick a boy please
okay that's the coating part okay that's
the coding bag
so if a tree is binary and
i want to i want to compute
i i want to compute the path
how do i how do i read how do i do it
like if it's a node is like that it's
3 five
seven nine nine
eleven ten eleven just just this one
and the other seven okay let's give them
a treat like that that's given a tree
so if i want to visit that tree
in i want to visit this order in
in in an order
so if i want to visit these three
by my list by three
and then five ten and seven nine eleven
seven
how do we do it um
[Music]
so that's one example of right right and
can you please come there
it's still running yeah
okay so this is interesting okay we can
do this
we we can have a q right this is grill
okay look remember we have a q
alright we have a q here
q remember first thing first out right
okay so now we put we we are given the
node three we're given another three we
put it here
okay learn
why why q is not empty we take one
element
from the kill yeah we take it out and
push it on its kids so his kid is 5 and
10 okay
and i put it five and ten here okay so
now now three is here right i pretty
sweet
and now i put another this q is not
empty i
take another element from q which is
what
five five and its kids is
seven and nine right i put it in a queue
yeah at the end okay okay so now ted
tell me
what what's the next item i need to take
from you
okay ten okay here and i what's his kid
why okay so that before is ten yeah okay
now now number seven doesn't have a kid
i just take it out
now i don't have a kid i take it now he
never doesn't have a kid i take it now
and seven then i take it off okay
so look this is the seven yeah
because they're two seven so look this
is level by level trevor okay do you get
it there's none of me okay
sorry there's no me me was me
i made no way i know i'm just making it
up okay
so we use a queue to to
to get it yeah every time we push a kill
we put a note here dude here and then we
we push we push his kit into the kill
and then we until we do it until the
kill is empty
okay okay and i'm going to introduce
another another key
another tree okay come here right
how so these three how is that useful
one use of a thing how about if like i
said this is seven okay
tell me what kind of tree you find is
this one okay
and just example okay
how would you know six and ten goes with
seven
maybe up i just made it up
[Music]
can you tell me what do you find this
tree
i find that a
seven and three yes i look closely what
what what do you see this tree
what is it like
i found out that i i'm sick and good
thing
and i never excited
eric can you find out what what is this
tree i mean what kind of thing
is particular about this tree what
i give you a hint look at the numbers
is 6 smaller than 8
10 is bigger than 8.
[Music]
so what happened to the tree i mean look
the left are always smaller oh yeah
yeah can you tell me please
you're very close to it you're very
closely right
you want to have a look yes ryan you
have a look
the left nose is always smaller than the
parent the right now is always bigger
than the parent
look nice smaller than 10 is bigger
seven is smaller
smaller this will get bigger yeah yeah
so for so we can call this tree
binary search yeah final research tree
how do you know
i just heard it before okay so for
a final research tree it means that the
left nose
always smaller than parents but right
now always speaking apparent
why is that useful because look if we
want to find the number nine
right yeah if it's in another way we
don't know if it's
like that if it's a way list
we have to search for
player and and items we need to search
end times to to find the nine
okay if we see in the last element right
but for this we don't
we knight if it's bigger than a is it
bigger than a
yeah yeah yeah so it must be in
somewhere here
right and we don't need to consider this
bit right because
this bit is the left left is always
smaller than
a but i'm looking for nine so you must
be somewhere in the right tree right
okay and it's nice smaller than ten nine
smaller than that
yes then we could go left so every time
we go
left or right depending on the value
don't get it
yeah so we look we only need to find
three times
compared to these linears we are faster
right
yes yes get it yeah
good job okay so uh today
there'll be no coding okay because this
is a bit difficult we'll do the coding
in the next lesson
we are going to introduce more about a
tree okay
happy happy nothing happens
what happened nothing happened
okay so
okay so can you draw a tree compute a
tree in computer right
yes come here come here just to make
sure you remember this
can you draw a tree a
you draw a good tree
okay that's good okay that's it
so can you tell me it's okay i mean can
you tell me uh
yeah so what's these three
what's this three final three binary
three also
uh perfect by ninety three yeah am right
okay good no this is upside down
actually
this is the loot and then it's the
leaves
okay okay good job okay say bye to the
video