[Music]
do you still remember this pie
second ring pie center ring my finger
how big is this how long is this t five
five yeah
why is that because that's three squared
plus four squared
equals five squared yeah this is called
python given
lambda right angle right so five
five five five
okay so today we could talk about poison
garden
triplets let's just please so what does
it mean is that if i give you a number
one three one five
seven four you need to tell me
if they are paisable and triplets in
this array
means three times it means that i can
find three numbers
which satisfy a
squared plus b squared equals c squared
three four exactly so what how do you
approach
this problem if you let n numbers how do
you approach this
do you understand how do you process so
our target is that you're given a list
of numbers
and then you try to figure out if they
are
triplets three numbers yeah abc let's
satisfy that a square plus b
squared equals c squared this is called
pythagorean place
yeah it's like a is a and b are the size
of the right triangle and the c is the
big largest side yeah look at it
yeah this is the slow uh
slope okay so you need you know in the
right triangle
a plus b bigger than c yeah do you get
it
you know why do you know why
we're going to see do you know why
look this is okay
it's bigger than this already yeah you
know why
look look at this this is a line yeah
between two points yes
given two points the shortest distance
is a straight line right
yeah yeah is the surface distance
all right yes okay so look this is the
sausage system
so any so these plastics must be
bigger than that right because it goes
and this is bigger than that yeah i know
but i'm talking about a plus b
equals bigger than c okay yeah
okay please please so now uh
coming back to the question say now
coming back to the question
given a list of numbers sit down please
and then
how do you find out if there are
these three numbers that satisfy like
any idea any source
you need any any any songs just
are you using the projector
maybe tomorrow okay oh
any thoughts just random sauce without
coding just give me how would you
approach how could you
ask computers
[Music]
choose the first number yeah that's good
choose the first number and
and
[Music]
so this is nine and then add one
equals ten but ten is not square so you
go to the next one
[Music]
twenty-five
34 is not a square so
you go do the next one so you approve
four things yeah you're
searching every three numbers yeah yes
okay so one way
is that yeah you can certainly do it you
pick the first number
yeah and then you pick the second number
yeah and you try the third number if
it's equal right
if it's so you can simply do this look
all right look
for i in
suppose n is the length of numbers yeah
am i range lamp
now we determine the first number yeah
look now we can see
the second number j e range
we we only need to try after i yeah
yes
right yes
to j right and now we just need to check
if
lambs i
square plus numbers
j squared equals numbers
k square right right then yeah we just
check
look everything can you listen to me
okay don't
just walk around and wrong okay my
headache okay so you try
you try the first number you try the
second number and you try the third
number which they are not equal and what
i can say
loves i squared plus num j squared
equals numbers k square and so many
columns we found it
okay
[Music]
otherwise yeah outside
n is the number of numbers in the array
what's the complexity
that would be interesting something we
haven't seen for a while
let's end let's another end let's
another end
[Music]
no n times n and then here's
one more n what's that n
times n y
there are also three and together so
what's that
[Music]
and n times three
times three cubic three come on to the
power of three n times n times
n yeah just look the first first one you
need to
look iterate in times yeah
this is very slow right it's very very
small complexity right so can we do
better
can we do better how about look
i give her nothing how about look look
we just interested in
first two numbers and then we can find
out if the
i squared plus j square the first two
numbers square
that's something how about we
we put these something c-square in
a notebook so then we can look it up
with constant time
do you get it look we can do this we can
do this
look we can do this look uh
alright let's do it d equals a set
yeah what's that yeah a notebook
okay let's put it in notebook like
notebook
yeah and then for
i in numbers
notebook dot add
i times i look this is magic i put the
number
square itself right then i just need to
check for i in range
n okay suppose n is the length of lambs
okay
why i never see the fine that's okay
i i can write definitely
four j in wrench
i yeah look look yeah
this is
i square okay square which is ten times
two okay
plus num j
square okay
notebook we put
they put the numbers square itself in
the notebook right
if we see notebook then return what
folks
true and outside is written
[Music]
what's the time complexity i went what's
the time conversation eric
i just remove one four and why is this
three coming from how many what
what's the time convexity you must get
this right come on again
don't say look where's the logan come on
[Music]
look this is for loop yeah you try n
times yeah
and then for each end okay for each end
you try another end time
so that's up to n square right so which
one is better
[Music]
we have another solution okay
what's the space complexity for that one
for the number
something number that's the oh something
notebook no we use a notebook so it's
always right
yeah i said then yeah why because we use
the notebook
we don't need that now okay
[Music]
so now i'm going to solve this number
first yeah fine
now reverse equals true
what does it mean what does this mean
it means that
[Music]
yeah i saw the number in reverse order
so i saw the number in from the largest
to smallest
can you stand up please okay so now
if i look then i saw this number that
would become
uh seven four
five four three one okay suppose this is
numbers yes
yes yes yes now i
if look look for
i in range
again range n okay we're making the
first number i
choose from seven i make sure it's five
seven
five this way okay i need to learn slums
now if i make sure the j
will be i plus one okay if i i if i
i check this is the first number okay if
this is a
column yeah look if this is a
and i start from here this is b okay and
then
look every time i make sure this is a
and then b will be a plus one
c will from this side okay
so i check if a square equals b squared
plus c square if it is
that's great we find this number okay
right if b
squared plus c squared is smaller than
a square so
what should we move we should move c
here or move b
here because they're sorted here do you
get it
i i tried to explain one more time okay
this is the tricky
now a i'm i i make an assumption that
a is seven yeah yeah okay now b
is next to a c is at the end
right so now i check b square is 25
plus c squared is six so that's 20
uh 25 plus 1 is 26
7 square is 49 26 is smaller than 20
49 right yes yes
so should i move here see see because if
i move here that will be smaller right
you'll keep smaller so i move here okay
great
c square 9 plus 25
9 plus 25 34 it's still smaller then i
keep moving until i meet yeah let's see
here
16 plus 25 16 plus 25
31 41 41 yeah yeah
it's still not 49 so we can't find the
answer okay
now we can't find this answer then we
move a here
okay and then b will be here right yeah
c will be here at the end yeah
b squared plus one square equals
seventeen
smaller than twenty-five whatever should
i know uh c
yes i move here and i check okay when we
got it do you get it
if it's bigger then we move the b right
because b
one b moving to the right will be
smaller b
squared plus c square will be smaller do
you see this this is called two pointer
two pointer algorithm why we can do it
because this is sorted
this is salty we're looking for remember
we we we started this a few
weeks ago about finding
the number the two sum remember
finally if we are looking for a number
like if
a plus b equals a target then we can
check this if we smaller
we move here move the right pointer if
the bigger we move the left pointer
yeah okay now i write the i learn the
program and you tell me okay
for i in range i j equals i plus one k
equals y k
equals m minus one
minus y on the right hand side yeah
[Music]
why they are not meeting each other why
when is wild wire j smaller than k
look away if
numbs j
uh i okay num i square
is equal to num
j square plus
[Music]
if
what did i tell you about this moving
pointer thing you forgot it
k square if it's bigger
than b b j
okay j if it's bigger than that
now the left side is c is bigger than
that so we need to move the
k right right k y
okay minus one minus equals one okay
that's what else we're
okay so where do you put the return
first where do you put the little phone
here
i would say okay oh wait
remember where's four you need to write
where
here here yeah outside that's what i am
yeah return first
yeah that's why i do it really without
that
give you the hint can you do it return
first
okay like lie down like
daddy okay okay
you need the caterpillar
okay that's it okay good job okay what's
the time complexity
i i i i i i i
this is for n right and here
is another n right and the n
yeah how about this here sorting
remember we talked about
wait wait no yes we talk about the
salting this one
this is outside so these complexities
should be this one plus this one yeah
yeah look at it so we can you know make
a mess here
so this one is all and log
n okay yeah okay
yeah sorting l and l so the overall
complexity look at that two parts
this one is o and not n
and this bit is all n square so which
one you think is
bigger it's dominating
this is n times n and this is n times
log n
so which one you think is dominating n
times
n yeah n times n log n is smaller than n
right yeah so this one is documenting so
you
when we talk about an aggregate
complexity we only pick
the most dominant part we are not saying
the complexities
of and log n plus n plus n times
we only say okay this overall complexity
is o n square
even there's a small bit sorting here is
o and log n
we ignore it because this one dominating
do you get it
this one takes most of the time and this
one can be ignored
compared to this look at it yeah
so the complexity is this one what's the
space complexity
[Music]
no okay so that's oh one
yeah well what constant when i talk
about space complexity you can make
against it for one because most of the
time it's a one if you don't use
anything right
yeah yeah yeah look at it okay
[Music]
okay so what's this stupid
i plus one i know this is
and my nice one and how are you uh
yeah i i know agreeing
[Music]
okay yeah good job good job
every day i will when i finish the
coding i will
erase some of it and then to do it okay
and then good job today okay okay you
can say
[Music]
it bye-bye okay