[Music]
factorial
please yeah what does that you got
one one time two
is six yeah okay how about
five factorial what five
[Music]
how many zeros how many zeros
one one zero okay so the question today
is very simple
n factorial called how many zeros at the
end
yeah think about it look five factorial
is 120
so one zero it should be 21.
and then maybe
[Music]
six bacteria equals 720
is still one zero so do you do you see
any
the problem when you're working yeah
quicker yeah how do you work it out
quicker
without just getting to count of course
all you just
first of all the solution would be you
can't you calculate this actual value
yeah
and then count how many of these yeah
yeah it's really slow yes you're right
let's see we're now
doing it i'll count in 24 times five
okay count zero let's add bacteria okay
look answer let's say bacteria okay f
factorial equals one first four
i in range
two to the n plus one right column yeah
and f1 f1 times
equals what f times equal
n every time yes you're right
now with f is the n factorial now
f is n factorial now we want to count
how many zero right
yeah we want to count how many zero
right
equals one yes right we want to call how
many zero
right right so now look we can have
these
zeros let's zeros equals zero first
yeah first then look why
why what what are you doing
now what f modulus 10 is
0 is still 0 then f divided
equals 10 remove one zero and zeros
plus equals one right and then return
zero am right
yeah is it is it is it true
what's the time complexity what's the
time complexity
[Music]
look do you understand this look if this
120f is 120 yeah
why 180 divided by 10
remain is what zero right yeah
and then i i f f is least then
divided by is 10 it will become l
becomes 12. i take away zero
and i put one increment one zero right
so it's one return right to get it
yeah yeah what's the term complexity
one no a1 not a1 and
another you say
oh
[Music]
look this list looks like o n right yeah
but actually look you times it together
this number is is actually
when you count how many zeros it could
be
actually goes to o n square right
because this is a very huge number
yeah yeah yes and
this number could be actually oh and
squares
i think think about that way yes if you
if each eye had each each multiplication
as one more zero
right yeah so how many years
at most
yeah how many zeros at most
yeah yeah one i think
one yeah one
[Music]
ten thousand ten thousand
ten thousand no just kidding
three what why we want one thing
okay okay anyway this one is very very
slow am i right this is very slow yeah
is it very slow so can we do better
[Music]
this the com complexity for this one is
all n square right it's a bit
complicated we
leave it later okay uh so can we do
better
how do you know why we get the zero at
the end
what what times what is equal to zero
can you think about it zero normally
things
no no but effectively look n factorial
there's no zero in there
right so anything as a path from zero
so how do we get 120 what comes what
times
one twenty two times three times four
times five
and four times five which which which
numbers
make ten make a zero at the end
two times five yeah we're done two times
right yeah
okay so now these actually 4 is also 2
times 2 right
yes the factor we call talk about factor
so actually we want to count the vector
2 and 5.
yeah so to these 2 could go with
two times table yeah yeah at least it
would be
five times table right yes
yes so look any of these
comes together you reside a zero at the
end right
this is two times table five factor
right yeah so we just want to count how
many
factors of two and how many factors of
five yeah
and the minimum will be
[Music]
so do you think we need to count both or
we can just count one of it which one is
definitely more
which one yeah which one is definitely
more the
factors number of two or number five
which one
has more is more two
yes of course look yeah each even number
has two right but this is every five has
one right this is
this is and this has two right five
times five yes
yes yes so we just need to count how
many fives
right yeah how many fives we don't need
to
tell a calculate h of factorial
we just need to count how many fives in
each number fact factorial right
so how we can do this
we can do this zero
because first of all is zero okay now
four i in when we start from five right
because because from one to one times
two times three times four
seven produce zero right yes
so five and then this will be m plus one
and
every five every step five
right and now we can say current equals
i y current
so now we need to count how many fives
in this number
well column is five sorry uh
what do you mean counterfeit huh what do
you mean
we want to count how many five so how do
we do this
how many five no zero yeah we have how
many five
so if if current five current
divided by five is zero can be divided
by five
then we added this zero plus equals one
and then current divided by five
right and then return zero y divided by
equal five we
need this current this thing
is the same as current equals current
divided by phi integer to to divide
is means i want the integer only the
integer yes
all right what's the time complexity
what's this term complexity
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah this is n this looks like
looks like possibly i mean because
everything divided by five so i'll log n
but actually this is quite
quite small because look it could be
any number divided by 5 will be 5
25 125
600 what 25 yes
i need at least this will be
a very very very uh small okay so
actually you can say oh and lock
five base n yeah yeah yes
yeah yeah okay so this is the same same
as uh i can
i can do it the other way so current i
can say
power of 5 power 5 equals what 5
right and then i can say this
is the same current multiply
power 5 and a nice and powerful
e times equals five right this is the
same thing yeah
is it the same thing is it the same
thing
is that something yes it's the same
thing here yeah
so look first of all is five i divided
five
and then five times five twenty five i
checked how many fives
how many fives yeah like because 25 has
two five and the next one is
125 has three fives yes yeah got it
got it yes
so can we do even better yeah
can we do it even better
so we just want to count how many fives
right yes
we just want how many five this has one
five
so let's say let's say
okay look 30
factorial it equals 1 times 2 times 3
times 4 times 5
yeah and then
20 15
20 25 30.
how many fives how many fives
how many five
probably six five
not exactly look this is six five yes
six five
you need to 30 divided by five that's
six five at least look
this is this is another this is another
one
five times five okay so that
means i need to plus 30 divided by 25
this is one right
only integer one so it'd be six plus one
equals seven yeah yeah yeah yeah
so again if i go to 125 go to
250 what and here would be
yeah so 5 25 so basically
the number of 5 is what n divided by 5
plus 10 divided by 25 plus n divided by
125 plus n divided by
625 plus yeah
do you get it am i right yeah
yeah so how can we write this code
how can we write this code and place the
answer my answer is yellow
yes and then why at the end
okay so think about it what how do we
how do we calculate this
divided by n divided by and divide by
five sorry and divide by
five yeah and divided by five yes now
when n is bigger than zero
then
and divided by five and divided by
five that's right and answer plus
equals one
left back yeah wait time how do you know
first thing what i need to answer yeah
you'll be single look
if it's zero i divide it by five and
then i can
count it add it right why
why this helps why this is okay
why this is okay you don't know
look if it's 25 look 25
you should give me how many five 25
one two one times two times times 25
will be three five yes
25 divided by 5 is 5
answer plus 2 yeah look
25 25 divided by
5 is 5.
n is 25 n is 25 factorial
so how many fives are in there 10
no i mean the whole answer one times two
times three times four
times five one there they are
five ten fifteen twenty
twenty five they are one two three four
five so at
25 divided by five is five i answer add
to five
okay so that's and then five divided by
five equals one
i answer add one more plus one so it's
six
is it how disgust yeah look at the first
thing
i divided by five and then
i can see how many how many count
how many five time table right and then
i
again divided by five the last 25 time
table
yes yes and i again divided by five
that's what time table 125
times table so these these were
and do we have another way of doing it
is the similar the same
so we can say this math we can say
current multiple
okay so answer answer equals
zero and now we we have let's say power
of five
power of five equals what five
why why what
why what y n bigger than the bigger
lambda equal to power five
answer e plus equal one
and plus equal and divided by current
multiplier
and divided by
power five and then power five
times equals five and then return
written one
answer yes answer so it's the same thing
as look look
it's previously start from uh
look this is five and then i
answer and divided by five and then
n divided by 25 and
n divided by 125 yeah this goes in yeah
yeah yeah yeah again and again yeah
so this complexity is better is better
so what what's the complexity
what's the complexity what's the combat
when the complexity you can ignore this
you just ignore this yeah
look yeah so the complexities is oh
what
log five base n right because this
yeah yeah because look times five times
five and here
bigger than that right is it
no five ten no base
five and and yeah is it true
let me just think about it yes yes
yes because because that was a long time
away
uh this is basically the same as look
because every time 5 5
and then the next one is 25 and the next
one is 125 right
so it's every time is 5 to the power of
x should be smaller
is equal to n right so this
n this n
5 to the power of x equals n then what
can we do
so x is log phi
n right yeah yeah so the complexity is
is this one it's the same as previous
log
base and yeah do you still remember
previously
do you still remember the first one no
the one
previously like answer equals zero
y we divided by
divided by five what how do you get this
n yeah and
zero yeah yeah and then
answer plus equal one
and
actually it should be n it should be
divided by five first
yeah yeah and and yeah return
return answer it's the same thing yeah
so this is
also every time divided every time i
divide it by five
and then
yeah and then because look only n is
five if divided by five will be one and
the plus equals one okay
so written answer so let that complexity
is
still the same all right okay okay so
now
i'm going to erase this the last thing
can you write it
fine um
[Music]
it thick say so i want to add this
to the answer how do you read it
i don't have time to think so i don't
know
equals yeah yeah
wait you want the challenge i didn't
have any
neck you can look at the way and then i
open this one
okay you want to look okay one two three
okay
okay so now i'm going to erase erase
please
finish it
saying goodbye can you say goodbye
no why
you want the area to help you okay
that's fine
okay eric you want to have you have a
diddy
that's fine this one
yeah ryan you look look at it look
everybody helping you
come on you're a good boy yeah your own
youtuber
be careful remember yeah don't
more dynamic it wasn't more like it's
more than
why it's okay okay okay how about you
okay okay come here wear this one
now you should remember what does it
mean
okay okay that's good that's good good
okay that's it for today
face and