hello hello hello hello
hello today we talk about something very
basic the
the fundamental of computer com
computing uh
computer science is called a
s c e
[Music]
computers are invented by americans
this looks like computer i guess ugh
[Music]
information
yeah information
inter exchange
okay so american standard called
information interchange
you don't need to remember it you just
need to remember it's asking
so what does it mean is that it you know
it's computer
yeah we have listed letters and
key and wow don't
this is basically defines that how we
mapping the letters and keys with
numbers okay okay
so for the example
for example is that the
example is what is that look
32 is represent a space
okay don't have it don't don't look at
it okay
please maybe you can have a look at this
one
wait yeah ascii yeah space
so
[Music]
you can you can have characters
mapped to integers okay so 32 is a space
and then 65 is
a letter a y
i mean it's just the way it defines and
i know too many
okay okay a and then b will be 66 yeah
you go on
and then another thing is that 97
is the smaller case a yeah 90 a uvp
and number 0 would be 48
one will be 49 okay so
so from from 1 to 127
from 1 to 30 it can be divided into
1 to 31 these are
non-printable non-printable so it means
that
you know maybe uh 30
13 is a carriage return so it's a
control
characters like you know backspace yeah
and then 32 to 126 these are printable
like
abc numbers uh lowercase uppercase and
uh
some symbols you know exclamation mark
question mark this is like within this
range
and then there's a 127. it's a thing
punctuation okay
okay so so in python you can do this
look
in python if you write chr
65 okay so what does it give you sure
you'll give me a yeah why
this is asking okay
and then chr 97
do you steal the number okay yeah we're
down wait
what 48 what even that means
it's just mapping it's just that this is
how computer sees this
character in in numbers this is
it yeah inside inside the computer's
brain
it's just yes we are done yes right
okay yeah yeah yeah that's obviously
and then how about this ort this is the
opposite
so if you already give a number a
what does it give 65 yes yes that's the
other way so it's the reverse
smaller case a 97
[Music]
okay 49 okay
so this is the way to do it so
how about look
in python yeah look a
is like top dot upper
upper this will give me a yeah
and then a stop
i don't give me lower lowercase a
okay so can you implement these two i
mean
like like look like
define lower okay let's just give one
example lower a
okay lower eight no no big a okay
so now we know we want to change we want
to check this
right look we can do this look
that
we get the number a right right
if it is is this ascii
or maybe maybe maybe we can just do this
if
a is bigger than or equal
a right and a
is smaller equals z so if it's basically
what it means
if if this is the uppercase letter right
right yeah now we need to return smaller
case
so
now this is asking 65 and you need to
add 32 right
let us okay plus what plus yes how's the
number here seven
and we can otherwise i just just written
eight
if we look at this one if it's uppercase
letter
yeah uppercase is better yeah zero
asking is this math look 65 is a and
then
i need to what was the a this is what
97 yeah so i want to make 65 to 97 so i
need to plus
one 32 yeah this is what it does do you
get it
this letter is between a and z so it's
an uppercase letter and then i get this
asking mark
as you called plus 32 then you make it
lower case
and then return it and how about if i
want to make it upper
so given the number given the character
if it's small it's it's a longer path
look if it's the lowercase yeah and then
what's your letter here
eric what should i do here if it's the
lowercase 97 and i want to make it
uppercase so what should i do
30 minus 32 yeah
okay that's it so what's the
um complexity no there's no complexity
it's just a one or one you just
look it look it up it's all one so
not return return carriage return you
have character return is 13
okay that's a space space 32
okay yeah okay and
tv is 126
and 127 maybe i
may forgot and a eight is
is backspace backspace so you know the
backspace
yes yeah so this is asking ascii code so
it's basically the whole computer sees
the characters
yeah and it's only it's used in in the
first
generation of computer and not till
nowadays you know we're going to
keyboards yes
but we have some chinese japanese though
that's kind of thing
which cannot be expressed in
ascii is and we have a
much bigger character set which we call
unicode we'll talk about later but this
is unicorn
unicode unicode but this
it is a character set okay so what's
ascii it's a character set okay
character set
yeah and the basic is 127
from 32 to 126 is principal
so you can print these letters you know
like abcd these are printable letters
and then otherwise
they are not printable letters yes okay
okay good job today that's it
bye bye bye