go guys
[Music]
hello hello hello mr
mr ryan today we're talking about number
one
yeah yeah yeah that's okay i add plus
plus one okay so means add one yeah
i see oh yeah so if a list given at
least one
two three a single digit and then you
need to tell me
the add one will be one two
four okay 24.
any ideas 123.
123 plus one oh oh
you change it to zero and add one from
the next
and how about this is also nine what if
this is
nine ninety nine how about ninety nine
plus one
take one okay so you keep going right
you need a carrier okay so
so how can we do this
[Music]
yeah okay okay look d5
plus one let's call it the
something something clothing bracket
column
let's call it a okay first of all i need
to get to the lens
the length what's the lens air
okay okay then now
kelly will be equals to zero okay i set
it to zero carry okay
and then i start i need to add one to
the last digit so
how do you add one to the last digit
a what's the how do i add one to the
last digit
bracket what i put a number here
plus equals one so what's this number
last digit last
i'll give you a hint it's a negative
number
the last digit negative negative
1 1 yes negative 1 means the last digit
so
look it's one two three and then a minus
one is this one
plus equals one now it changes to four
right yeah
yeah and now look return
no no no let's do it minus one okay so
this this n will be pointing to this
okay so now
why
and bigger than equal and zero right
i want to add it from this way right yes
then i need to do this a
and d plus equals
this carry i need to add the characters
right
and the camera which is zero first and
then if it's bigger than zero
then a and
how can i get this if this is 10 how can
i get the
rightmost digit
right digit negative
so the a is 10 for example a is 10 and i
want to get this zero
and get this one so one equals a
divided by ten right zero equals a
what what ten times
modulus yeah divided by 10
yeah got it so now i add the 10 and then
i need to
like the same yeah yeah yeah so first of
all i need to do what i need to
get a carry because if it's bigger than
10 i do this okay
and then a n would be modulus equals 10
right
i just need one digit and if
c is zero if carry is zero then we don't
need to continue right
yes so what's the key word here
what's the key okay what's the key
sorry break i want to break the loop
yeah remember break is breaking the loop
continue is continue with the loop okay
and then look look and there's one edge
cases look
99 you add a zero that will be zero
zero but you need to add one the carry
is one fc is one right
you need to add before be before the a
so if c is bigger than zero a
dot insert insert put it at a zero the
beginning and then
put a c here and return a
okay that's it what's the time
complexity
yeah n is the number of the elements
okay
so basically what was that what it does
i add one to the end
right right most of the digit and then
and i keep going this way first of all i
will add a digit i add a carry
and then i will get a new carry new
carry
if it's bigger than 10 i get a new carry
and then this number for example if it's
10 and now i i just want to keep a zero
right
yeah that's what he does here like if a
carry is zero
means we don't need to continue to look
to the left right
but be careful at the end when you enter
99 plus one
and then you only have two two two two
numbers in the right you become zero and
zero right
and in this case there will be carry
carry will be one you need to put this
one
at the beginning so a dot insert zero c
let's put a one put a c right anyway
yeah a dot insert zero c you put a one
at the beginning so if the ray will
become one zero zero got it
yes
so fast looks so easy
can you see me
every time connect
every time okay let's say it's very
clear
yes okay don't don't just don't shake
okay otherwise
we can't see 192.168.1
we don't need that computer on thank you
that's okay that's okay
okay minus minus
[Music]
plus one okay plus one plus one wi
now look we a will be
let's do this uh one uh let's do uh
99 okay first there you
minus one here c equals zero yeah and
then i need to add a one to the last
last digit okay y
and wires yeah look at them
a n plus equals c c
equals a n divided by 10 the
updated carry and then and i just need
the one digit
and if c equals zero break
okay then here if c bigger than zero
we need to insert it in in the at the
beginning here a dot what eric
no no please please either the word
insert yeah the first thing the
beginning
zero and then and return
a okay let's try if we print
plus one it should give me
100 yeah
oh no that's not right you become 91 so
there's something wrong okay
let me check um
and you can learn minus one let's let's
try
see plus equals one will become zero ten
yeah and bigger than uh n bigger than
zero
okay okay look because we need to
decrement the one we forgot the least
i forgot n minus equals one yeah we need
to decrement it
yeah there's a problem with that yeah
it's 100 yeah we forgot this yeah
because when you move to a long belonger
you see that's why we need to do this on
coding because when i talk i may miss
some details
but when i put it on computer yeah and
then i can check right
do you get it yeah because let
line 9 14 i miss this 914
right yeah because i need to and
if n is not then it's not
it's not changing and this might we
might have a problem okay let's try this
try uh 100
123 okay let's see
i okay one two three four five okay
so one it'll be one two
three four six yes you see that's plus
one okay any number you want to try
one two five six and nine nine ten means
too much too much one two three four
five
one two nine nine okay so you should
give me one hundred
thirty three hundred s yes
yeah you see one three zero zero okay
one zero zero
okay uh let's do this one more time
okay so look this is getting the length
of the a
carry and then this num what's the line
number seven can you tell me line number
seven
a minus one
and then past one yeah and plus one and
you will become ten right
but we don't want to stall more than ten
more than nine in one
single place so look let's write that
10 divided by 10 that c will currently
one yeah
and 10 modulus 10 will be zero
and if carry is zero then we just break
otherwise we
we update the carry along the way to the
left
yeah and after this loop if we find out
the c
is still bigger than zero what does it
mean what has been 15 and then 16
what does it mean 15 and 16. yeah
what does it mean if carrie
is bigger than z right then we put an
extra
yeah on the next on the beginning
even 99 that's what you mean even 99
plus 1
that would be 100 right but now we only
have two zeros right
so now we need to put a one at the
beginning all right
yeah do you get it yeah okay any
questions
any questions what's the space
complexity
[Music]
do we need the extra space i want yeah
one concept because we don't need
okay legs
oh that's it