okay hello hello guys
i'm inspiring mr ryan hello hello
today we'll talk about power
up power off sweep
the power of three okay so what does it
mean it means that
given the number like 27
you need to return
because it is in three times tables
because it's not exactly in the three
time table it's in three to the power of
three so it's basically three to the
power of
x equals n if i give you n
so it's basically three times one three
three to the power of two nine three to
the power of three
eight no no look 27 and
what's next three to the power of four
eighty-one right
so basically the three nine twenty seven
and then you need to tell me it's the
it's true alloys is first
any ideas any ideas
any thoughts uh all you need to do is
try
three to the power of then
um go like one and three
to the power two three zero power three
it is bigger
[Music]
yeah yeah and then if it's if it's equal
then one
okay so look little is zero
three power if the input is zero what
happened yeah
this is yellow uh
we can't find it so we're false yeah
yeah
and if it's minus anything you'll be
false yeah right because minus
negative numbers can't be power of three
right yeah
okay so one how about one a power
one three power of zero this is special
so one is okay so
look at your equilibrium is quite good
okay define
power of three power of three okay
and right yes
so look uh if
n is smaller or equal to zero will
return one
okay then if n is z one
return two right yeah i'm right
here okay so now we start from x
start from one okay yes you tell me what
to
what to write y
x y what do you say before
if it's smaller if it's bigger
if it's smaller than n right yeah that's
what country how do i write to the power
three
x can multiply equal three right
and then what's your right here return
one term
return we need to check if x is bigger
than n or
equal right so what should i put here
no no not written true look at x smaller
no one now look
you just say multiply three multiply
three and here is equal or bigger
yeah right so and here i'm there are two
situations one is smaller one is bigger
one is equal so
one is equal is two once this bigger is
false right
so what should i like we turn three
opposed no written
x equal n right if it's
n then it's true right yeah yeah i'm
right it doesn't make sense for you
yeah yeah that's what's the complexity
yeah oh look at the power 3. yeah look
knock three n okay
[Music]
okay so okay so this way
base complexity space complexity
yes okay
okay look this is going up how about
we're going down
from starting divided by three yeah
and until it's one right yeah yeah for
example 27
yeah yeah it's multiplied by three like
i divided by three that's nine
it's multiplied by three divided by
three three three
three one so if it's one
it's uh power three right no you don't
need to yeah am right
yeah okay so this is the same yeah look
we can do this
why are we while why are
n can be divided by three right
y n can be divided by three
[Music]
daddy
right let's return what the
and equals what and equals what x
and equals what
actually you can divide it but you
so look this can be written in recursion
yeah how do we write it but
that's a college this is the question
look
can you be good all right
look we can do it in retesting look
return
return and divided by three can be
divided by three
yeah equal and
so and no you don't need the right power
three
and one how
yeah okay okay good job this is one way
of doing
how about
all right all right look 3 to the power
of x
equals n right so how can we write it we
can write it
x equals 1 log
3 n right yes
yes 3 to the power of x equals n and x
is
not 3 n right yes yeah
ok so if we calculate this function
because we don't have
log block three but we have log two
and we have a lot of ten okay these two
functions are available
and then why because in mathematics in
computer knows these two functions
and possibly then you can convert this
to this but it's a bit tricky okay
it's a bit tricky
it's a bit tricky how how do we compute
the left the log
a b right equals
log 2 you can choose any base yeah
base c b divided by
log c as long as the same base okay
okay so these can can be converted to
log two and divided by log two
three okay yes you just need to know and
if we calculate this number
and as it's a voltage number then if we
can
compute its integer path yeah integer
part
and then let's say if x is in the value
then we can just
write between three times times x
equals n return less thing okay
you don't need to understand fully but
you just have to
see that that's the one solution of
using mathematics okay
how about final research
remember we talk about binary search
yeah
yeah so look define you tell me okay
power of three and right
the same if n smaller than zero
right left right equal left will be zero
right will be n
okay yeah two boundary okay
why why why
l smaller equals r why this two range is
not meeting in the middle
yeah meat means equals what
we cut left and right what's the meter
uh what's the meter
that's three that's four that's what's
in the middle four
yeah right divided by two okay let's
meet up yeah
yeah okay
let's calculate this pick n value yeah n
equals three
times meat what does it mean 3 to the
power of
3 to the power of meter yeah this is the
same thing as power
you can use this 3 power meat it's the
same thing okay you can write it like
as well right then i calculate this mean
okay now if n equals
if n equals n what's your should we
return
10 minutes if n equals n what will
if n is bigger than n no power no if
n is n yeah because we found a value
if n if this value
is bigger than uh n what does it mean
no no no final research remember we need
to
we need to look this is air this is r
and this is it yeah if if this is the
bigger
please if this is bigger than then
the value will we want to find
is we eat now if this is the bigger than
what we want to find you go
go yeah is equal to if this 3 to the
power of
meat yeah is actually bigger than
the 3 power to the power of x right we
want to find the x yeah
so the value must be in here all right
yeah
so ah
ah out here i equals what we don't move
here i equals one
minus one yes and then es if it's
smaller
if it's smaller then it should be in
this range yeah
so what else
left equals made that one where the hell
and then what is when we can't find the
value return what
false identifier yeah
what's the time complexity
no what's your answer
final research is not
not yeah yeah however
however look at this this needs time
right
country 3 to the power of mid
remember we talked about how to
calculate the power function using the
binary search
yeah remember remember we talked about 2
to the power of
5 equals 2 to the power 4 times 4 2
right
2 to the power 2 4 equals 2 to the power
of 2 times 2 to the power 2 right
remember we talked about this
previously right so we need we this
needs the log end as well
yeah it does not come free you just
cannot calculate it
in one constant time right the computer
needs the o log n to find the
power function right so that would be
log
o log n square
okay this is a bit tricky but final
research right look final research log n
right
yeah every time i divide into half right
square
yeah define your half half
half yes and then
this is by the research okay so
you want you want me to raise some up
some bitterly and you feel a blank or
you want to erase everything and you
write one of the approach i just
talk about which one which one do you
prefer
which one do you who do you want to come
first you you want to change
yeah yes or no i want that
turn around okay i'm going to raise this
okay can you tell me what should i put
here
if n equals n we find it we should one
return to
so yeah
[Music]
what's the right boundary what's the y
power
n n yeah yeah oh a very big number is
okay
as long as it's bigger than yes yeah
bigger than yeah
bigger than that as long as this number
is bigger than three to the power of s
yes yeah yeah okay we're done we're done
good job today very well done today
bye