go hello hello hello hello
hello remember what we have talked about
yesterday
power of three okay so today similar we
will have
five two i said about
two yeah power of two so can imagine can
you
apply this power of three aggregating
the power of two
uh yeah can we
i guess yeah yes yes okay so uh it's a
good exercise we can do this review okay
yeah and then i introduce one more
agreement in a specific to the power of
two
so are you okay all right
so can you tell me which algorithm you
remember from
to check if the power of two oh just
keep dividing by
two two okay so you tell me what to
write okay power
two okay and
if n smaller than alpha equals still
what one minute yeah if n smaller or
equals zero
[Music]
and two of us
yeah yeah yeah yeah i mean mean okay if
n
equals one three yeah because two yeah
because two to the power of zero
yeah okay okay now
look y wire
n can be divided by two
and
divide equal to right yes
yes written what
reason one return
n and what
when when look a to the power two
divided by two divided by two
divided by it will be two and divided by
two will be one and even nine can be
divided by two and
count which is one if six divided by two
equals three
three divided by 2 can't be equal so
it's 3.
so if it's a power of 2 so n will be
divided until we get one what one
one yes well done it's the same look
yesterday 12 3 we just change this to
three
yeah do you remember yeah it's the same
okay so look n is an integer
we can replace this and if n is an
integer
n divided by two equals zero is the same
as
you know in the binary yeah in the
binary if it's an even number so
the last digit of the binary is zero so
it will be
n and n n yeah this is n
how do we write n n
1 equals 0 it's the same thing and then
n divided by 2 divided by 2
in binary right look this is what in
binary
this is what number you binary
6 yeah this is what environment
no no no that is the this is four in
binary yeah because two
one to the power of two is this is this
is four right one and this is what
this is one in binary one times two
power one that's two
right yeah and this is what
what in binary one so do you get it
if you're moving moving one to the to
the right
then you'll be you'll be divided by two
right if you put a zero at the end
point times two okay so this thing is
you can do it like this
and shift shift equals one look
yeah two double
to greater than means that i want to
shift one position to the right yeah
and how about this n one one equals
smaller smaller equals one what does it
mean i want the shift
to the left yeah times two that is the
same
what's the complexity um
uh log base
no look three bass no there's no three
two
uh two i mean log two n yeah yes
yeah okay
okay let's divide by we can multiply
right look yeah x equals one yeah
you tell me y x
smaller than n right yes what's right
here
x1 x that's what
i want to times x equals two yeah x
equals x times two yeah
all you can do is shift t shift equals
one that means times two right
return
[Applause]
until you for example if i give you 33
and then 32 it can't be 30. yeah so
what's here remember it's the same as
yesterday yesterday is x time
not false come on you're not remembering
me i can't
i give a number i times a two and here
is bigger
or equal to n when it's equal
it's true when it's bigger it's false
okay so what should i write here x
equal and then equal one
one no no no n come on
this thing look double double equal is
the same this thing
is the same as right
this is the same as this is the same as
if x equal equal n column between
what
[Music]
yeah this is the same thing yeah this is
the same thing you see
yes okay so what's the term complexity
yeah it's the same thing okay we can do
it recursively as well look
possibly n equals one return
return okay then return
it has to be divided by two yeah and
divided by
it should be an even number yeah even
number
and it looks like and n one m
power two and 1 divide divided by
2 right yeah yesterday it's it's the
same
divided by 3 yeah and then you change
this to n modulus
equals zero yeah yes okay so this is the
same okay and how about
anything power three oh well look
if i do this if i basically we want to
to find if there's integer two to the
power of x equals n
right yeah yeah okay so x is
log 2 n right yes
okay so let's do this x equals log 2
and but this can be could be an integer
or not could be in this area
so we want to check if x is integer so
how can we do this
return 2 3 integer
convert into integer if it's equal to c
what does c i mean c so look
integer is the flaw so like 2.5
inch that is is 2
right into 2.5 is 2.
okay okay this way and int
and sia c what's c c means cr
two point five is three so it's okay
it's ceiling yeah and integer is like a
flaw so so look at them two point five
seven is three
and four would be two right yeah oh okay
how about this
in in the one point nine into one point
equals one
and zero one point nine
yes so so what does it mean here if it's
the
integer part and equals sieving power
okay so look
in in the two is two okay
here two is also two okay okay
yeah because if it's a whole integer
it's the same
yeah yeah okay so if it is an integer we
find
find this number okay what's the
complexity
[Music]
if we think this is a one so what's the
complexity
what if this function is a one constant
i assume it's
very very fast it's one yeah or one
constant okay
so this is better it's the fattest yes
yeah because i just do the calculation
yeah and how about if i can do this if
this is the integer i'll convert it to
initial part yeah integer
yeah and then i can do this return
to i'm giving y two times times x equals
three then there is two
this is i i get i i
compute the log to end and then i return
the integer path and i
reverse check i check 2 to the power of
x if it's equals n yeah
yes yeah what's the time complexity
yeah because this takes all log to l
yeah
this is the same thing as power function
as power to
x right this takes oh and oh look and
remember we talked about this
before yeah two times if you times these
x times
then is o n right n times yeah but we
can
we can actually depend on look okay
2 to the power of 6 equals what
2 to the power 3 times 2 right
yeah yeah good so so look at you every
time you can
do this faster you you just need two
times instead of six times right
yes got it yeah yeah okay so okay
final research 19.5 remember my final
research
yeah m smaller equals zero return
return false yeah so this is the same
okay tell me l r c l n
okay y air
smaller equals r right meet
what's made me do
means what what does that mean
let's add white divided by two
yes okay and then like i have a curve
current value is two times times
meter yeah two to the power of me you
can write it as
as this way power to meet is the same
okay if current equals n
what do we do 10 if carry
equals equals we find the meter value
and we times it 2 to the power of mid
if it's 2 to the power of means
yeah we can true yeah and if
current is bigger than n so look
this is l this is r and we find the
meter if this
value is if this to the power mid is
bigger than the n
so where is it where where is it
is it in this sound itself if it's what
if this middle value to the volume is
bigger than
n so what's the value okay so what
should i
like here uh
[Music]
right equals mean minus one okay
and then l let's equal
add one and then click on return what
return was ryan return what
we turn mid no leave this line return
true
return what's the time complexity this
is later today
except this one yesterday this is three
to the power meter yeah
yeah the only difference between the
power of three and power two
the final research is this one and that
one yeah yeah that is functional yeah
remember yesterday this is three yeah
okay
so what's the complexity divide yeah
what's the complexity
[Music]
and what is it again
this is log n and yeah square you need
to square it
it's actually log n times log n because
this is log n
and the final research is okay okay so
it's
logan okay so for now we're just
reviewing the power three we can use the
power three aggregate
to the power of two to change these
three to low right
mostly and today we talk about something
very good very very specific for the
for the binary for the for the two
another two yeah
computer loves the number two right why
because the computer is based on the
binary
yeah by computer computer understands
two numbers what are the two numbers
computer understand one and two
no yes because zlo you can
computer can simulate as power off
one can be simulated as power on right
yeah high voltage low voltage the
computers are
loving these numbers it's simple for
computers yes
so then finally we talk about the binary
yeah yeah
2 to the power of 0 eric you tell me
what
2 to the power equals 1 in binary okay i
have a binary here okay finally and then
you tell me what you found yeah binary
is one okay
two to the power of one equals two right
in binary is what
one zero yes yes
two to the power of 2 is 4 in binary is
0 0 yes yeah
yeah 2 to the power of 1 2 we have 2 to
the power of 1 yeah
2 to the power of 3 equals 8 in binary
is what
1 zero zero zero yes
yeah two to the power of four equals one
sixteen one zero zero zero
four zero so do we need to
keep writing one one two three four five
okay so in binary if it's power of two
what is it it means that we only have
one one and followed by lots of zeros
yeah
yeah do you get it this is finally yeah
yeah okay
yeah so how can we do this how can we
find a binary remember
we use this n yeah n
and and logic this this this symbol yeah
yes
and logic yeah yeah this is n
in but if you want to end the binaries
you usually find
and then there's an oh okay so we just
talked about this n
yeah you know this symbol in the
keyboard in the keyboard here
yeah this one seven yeah seven you see
it's on the seventh
yeah this is n okay so what does it mean
in finally yeah
hey what does it mean it's something
like
that's what it's like okay okay so we're
done look
look so these n yeah the numbers
numbers look in binary okay so look if
it's
four and three exactly
in person what so what what's the value
of four and three
so computer will change this to binary
which is
zero one one zero zero yeah and three
is what one zero one
uh zero one one zero one one yeah
because one
one plus two is three yeah that's four
yeah
yes so this n what does it mean
remember two and two is two two and
fourth is
first fourth and two is first first and
fourth is true yeah it has to be both
one
in order to one so this will be zero
this will be zero this will be zero okay
yes yes
do you get it so four so look
eight yeah a is the power of two
a is this one yes yes
one zero zero zero if i substitute
if i substitute seven what's seven seven
is no
power two i know seven is what zero one
one one right
yes so the end together will be zero
okay
another one sixteen sixteen one zero
zero zero zero
minus one is what zero one one one one
yeah
yeah you end zero so look at it
yes this one minus one zero one one one
one one
you end zero
yeah because look at zero and one is n
is zero okay
do you get it because you only have one
one yeah you substitute one all the
zeros become one yeah
and then this becomes zero yeah so you
end together will be zero
so what so what can we do look define
power tool
if it's a power of 2 then you minus 1
then yes and
return first of all it has to be bigger
than zero yeah bigger
yeah what should i put here
what's this number this is n what's this
number n minus one
yeah and it will be yes
this is the fastest what's the time
complexity
oh one yes what's the spray complexity i
i i i i
[Music]
okay so which one is the price the
better best
this one yes of course look this is
magic yeah binary magic because computer
laughs
battery and then based on the binary we
can just check if the integer is power
of two just using this
it's amazing yeah it's quite amazing
yeah yeah we've got lots of
algorithm this is the fastest because
it's a one it doesn't matter if you
add this opinion a million a trillion it
doesn't matter
computer computes it instantly
yeah first okay so
oh i raised it okay so how about i i
write uh
i write the problem and you you tell me
okay
one by one okay you want to who want to
do first what do we do yeah
check the power of 2 yeah if n smaller
equals
0 what's here and then
okay x equals 1 y
x smaller than n
x you turn x equals equals n
yes good job okay good job
good job today good job today good job