hello and today we're going to talk
about cutting binary surgery
yes yes you are right hello mr eric
hello mr ryan
today we are going to talk about cutting
your banner surgery or we call it trim a
binary search tree okay
can you remind me what's the final
research tree
it's a tree like it has numbers
yeah can you can you call it can you
draw a final research tree
any spine is that's true okay you can
have try
you can just try as okay try one more
time
i'm yes remember what's binary search
tree now you just
what that's not about research tree like
ryan
because please a child cannot have more
than
one parent right look you are having two
parents so
this can be your finances too okay
okay sorry
we need to take it yeah let's find any
any okay then put a number so you need
it
because this is the final tree but it's
not yet a binary search tree
you need to put numbers in it uh we do
that
no no this is not a pine research tree
because look it
has a circuit besides a cycle can you
put anything on
anything anything i just put a random
random number yes i just put four
what no this is not a brand research
tree look this number
we disconnected and then the number
remember the numbers on the left should
be
smaller the numbers on the right should
be bigger
yeah well done eric that's
that's good this is the final search
tree look at the nose love the left hand
side are always strictly smaller than
them
[Music]
yeah it's okay you can draw one is the
same thing yeah
look underneath the left nose smaller
and the right bigger yeah
oh yeah smaller now the on the left hand
side should be smaller on the big and
on the right hand side look two is
smaller than four six is bigger than
four
right and one is smaller than two three
is bigger than two
oh maybe another one yeah let's see
nine yeah yeah yeah we're done ryan
yeah you're right yes one yes yes
and then perhaps you don't need this
this is nine and this is
maybe eleven yeah eleven yeah well yes
that's the price
you need a tree and you don't need it
okay
okay good job good job i can have it
please yeah that's the final research
trip okay
where's the deet where do you put the
lid well
i don't know okay
so look yes you're right finally that
[ __ ] so let's take a knee
for example okay let's take it this way
down there
the left nose smaller the right no
bigger okay how about if i tell you
letter
i want to keep a range like from one to
two
to three to three to five
okay three to five inclusive
so what does it mean is that you need to
return the tree trim color tree which is
not in this range
four is in this one i keep it two is not
in the range
i drop it six is not in the range i drop
it so
one in 20 you you should return me a
four
okay so if i have this uh
two and two and seven okay every now
inside two and seven is five four is it
to enter
two point seven this is inside only one
is not
so it's this one yeah can we get it so
how do we show
more than one sorry more like what
happened
if we need to do more than one cut
no what can you give me an example we'll
do
more than one cut you always have one
you don't
understand you only understand your
no i mean this is the range like a range
lower
low and high so i want you to cut a note
that i want you to cut the nose cut the
binary tree
in such as that each node
is within this range if it's not within
range i'll cut it
yes yeah
okay so do you have any idea how do we
do this
any thoughts all you need to do
is take one away
we need to check current value
everything is red
[Music]
um
if this note is smaller
smaller for example like if i wanted uh
i want to the range is 5 to
10 okay 4 is it smaller than
5 yeah yes so 4 is smaller than 5. so it
means that
this note that we don't need it yeah
these
we cut it yeah yeah
because it's outside this range
yeah got it the same as if it's bigger
like if it's
11 and i need to cut it right yeah
so together this is once if it's four
let's do this one if it's 11 look if
this is 11 then two this way yeah
two this way yeah yeah yes
and how about if it's can't be eleven
because this would happen
yeah i know i know i'm just giving the
example good good good job
if it's if it's something between this
range we keep it yeah
then we do this recursively on the left
left tree and the right tree all right
yeah okay so let's
do this coding very quick very quick
coin
and now six minutes cut
cut three okay country copy as c3 okay
if load is
num
uh oh we need to get a range right we
need to give a range
lower high okay let's just do this l and
r
okay and then come right yeah if
lu is now what should we return we turn
if it's empty
root yeah all loot or down okay it's the
same blue island and we can do it okay
okay then now if the root of value
is smaller than air right remember
remember this is four yeah this is
three this is seven if the range is five
seven if root of value is smaller than
this value is smaller than five we don't
want
any of these yeah so what should we
return
[Music]
we need to determine what country yeah
country for yourself that's
the value is smaller than that left we
don't want any of these so we need to
return these bits so what's this thing
right right yes and then
passing this out ready okay okay
is more it's bigger than what is bigger
than what
left no it's small right right ah
okay and then return y
return similarly we can country what
can't we
do left yes
we don't okay now the the only case left
is that this note is within the red
it's ready we or we already checked
those cases when this root is
on the left hand side yeah this is this
is an air this is ah
we already have it yeah this is air
addition
we already checked this route
on the left side yeah yeah on the right
hand side here
so where's the cases it's here yeah
yeah yeah so one is here then i i can i
need to keep the load right
yes
so what should we do blue dot we keep
the
root of low value root of left
keep it look yeah it's inside the range
yes yeah
and then we need to check if it's luxury
we need to cut the left tree
and then we need to cut the right tree
yeah yeah
and then we return this route okay
what's the time complexity
i i i i i i i
what come on
n is the number of the notes in the
partnership yes
okay so can you close your eyes i'm
going to erase
erase one of it and then you do it okay
okay i erase two and then you will keep
you as a team
to work on it okay closer yeah yeah
okay uh wait wait
no please please
okay so they are too big can you can you
please do it
you want to do it all right
you
beautifully not just randomly writing
please
yeah right
[Music]
okay that's it i know this one
we want to check if this value is
smaller than the left
then it returns country to the right
yeah right here please hurry up
and wait what's next rudolph
oh yeah i forgot okay
compared to the value r l or r this pip
is bigger than r and look this bit is
bigger than r
this peak is on the right and this speed
should this change should be on the left
so what's this
yeah yeah one left
is here what's left
this dot leave do the value bigger than
r here i know the value what what er
smaller smaller yeah
yeah and you have
more slaves what's that you have missed
something
you haven't you have missed something
[Laughter]
okay okay let's see that's it
good job today bye