so today we talk we want to talk about
something uh interesting problem is that
to check if the leaves you know the
leaves in the binary tree
yeah they're all on the if they're on
the same level so
look at this one okay
yeah yeah this is the the the levels
look this is yellow
this is one so look where are the leaves
the leaves leaves
leaves leaves this is improved
this is the finger yeah yes
so the leaves are level one so you need
to return to and how about this
listen up yeah what are the leaves
where on the list no this is not that
deep
so what's this remind me what's leaf
[Music]
is
does not have any triad yes exactly so
it does not have any child okay
so now we're done so given the final
tree
so how can we make
coffee and check if our leaves are on
the same level
uh just give me any thoughts how do we
check any
if there are only seven and remember how
many ways we can
it can travel all the notes in the
binary tree
how many ways
yeah do you still remember this
d
[Music]
okay today we talked about that versus
to solve this problem yeah we talked
about that before and
tomorrow we talk about breakfast search
okay breakfast that makes me
hungry yeah that's research so what's d
d e b e
p t h
[Music]
so look one
two three so remember
so it's like a different searches
is pre-order right
okay and how about this if i have a five
here so what's the sequence
there's six what's the sequence
one two three
five four six seven so
basically we visit there then
we so basically we can go down as
deep as we can right yeah and if we know
we cannot go deep
then we go how do we go left sorry why
do we go there
yes go left first of all let's go left
as deep as we want as we can and not
even we cannot go deep so we are now at
three we cannot thirty we go back
and then we go right so basically
is the loot so it's
what loot
left right actually that's the value so
let's and that's the
value current value
so what's this what's this this is
pre-order right this is kind of
pre-order
do you still remember that in order in
order is what
l v r yeah first order is what
post order is
so when we talk about the sequences we
talk about why is the v
naught p v is the value current value
or maybe how do you represent this note
so basically look this is post order
first order is
the left left tree left notes
right now the current note okay yeah
yeah so remind me if it's a binary
search tree
and which order gives a sorted list if
it's final research tree
which order makes it a sorted list
for binary search tree there is no oh
there's another one the uh yeah
it's actually this one in order yeah
all right look one
zero minus one
zero point five two
three so this in order will be
[Music]
minus one zero zero point five
one two three okay yeah
okay so that's in order yeah because
this is you know so in order of a binary
search tree
is a sorted list right yeah
there's another one called reverse in
order so what's reversing order
yeah we
[Music]
descending order yeah it's from the
largest to the smallest right yeah
okay yeah don't talk too much about this
let's talk about it yeah
yeah so it's been so
six minutes and a half so let's the
how can we solve this problem one
solution is that we visit the notes
with the tree yeah using the different
search okay
and if we meet the loot uh
the leaf which has no children we
put the depth we put its current depth
into
d on it yeah on a set another set yeah
and then if all the leaves on the
of the panel 3 is the same level what
does it mean
it means that how many elements are in a
set
if they are all in the same level so how
many how many numbers in a set
if it's all the same level the leaves
i put it so look
how many levels how many kind of levels
do we have less and less
two for the leaves from the leaves oh
one
yeah so how about this one
how many they are on the center how many
leaves how many depths of the leaves
have
there are four leaves yeah and they are
all
one whatever okay so we should check how
many
check the size of the depth equals to
what it's a set so i put a set
i put a i put a leaves levels in the set
so how many elements in a set
if it's all in the one level
what yeah you just tell me
how many how many different values of
the death
[Music]
this is one one uh
one two three three or maybe zero one
two okay two
and this is six
two two two so how many numbers
oh some how many different kinds of
numbers
three why is this three it's one come on
there are two
oh and what do you mean all of this okay
i mean the leaves
i'm what i'm talking about is that look
the algorithm is like
if we i travel a tree and if this is a
leaf node yeah i put its depth which is
two here
a set yeah and then i go to here
and it will be the same i put a two here
yeah my set doesn't
accept me a set does not store
duplicate an event do you get it
yeah so if i said look if this d equals
z alright
and then look d dot at
two and then d will be here right look
if i add one more time
d dot a two what do you think will
happen
a set what do what do you think will
happen d dot
set is theta set is this one at two i
put a two and add another two what will
happen if you said what did i just say i
said a set does not
store duplicate elements so what
will happen uh
nothing will happen right because we
already have two yeah that's what i mean
so you put another you need another leaf
note i put a
step which is two and another note which
is two
so if all the leaves knows are on the
same level
so how many elements should this set
have
one yeah that's it i was looking for
this answer for a long time we're gonna
just say
one did you get it now yeah yeah did you
get it
okay boom
okay now we do the fifth step search
and then they call them yeah dude is the
loot okay
and look we can we can have
another death inside of that yeah this
is new right
yes yeah so look i can have this
death here this is a local function
yeah local function so i use it dfs
right dfs
okay and then here i load
and then i need to pass current steps
yes current depth i put a current
current this okay
what's what's missing here okay
if loot is num
okay then we return nothing right return
just return
how do you check if it's a leaf node
how do you check if it's if not if it
doesn't have
any child okay so how to invert it if
loot left
are you okay
i know look we have a we put a depth
here okay remember this d
equals set yeah this is set okay
[Music]
and then if it's if it's a leaf node
because if no i don't i don't need to
travel there are no more children i can
just return yeah
right now look if we loot it's not
not leave no then dfs
blue dot left yeah
trevor is left left what should i put
here
current add one wow how do you know yeah
because
yes no this is not current yeah and then
it's the
next note will be current plus one yeah
why yeah
you get it okay and what will happen
here we need to travel the right
right tree right yeah dfs read the right
current minus one minus one
and what should i put at the beginning
here
yes yeah okay so what after this
the d should contain all the numbers of
the depths
of the leaf notes
we need to check the room now what what
what do we need to check
i was teaching a cup return
how many numbers are in the d three
how many numbers remember i was talking
about the
thing how many different numbers of the
yes or how do we do it return what
reason one come on then
plants yeah plants was b and
what we want to check the lens if it's
equal to one
so how do we write it
[Music]
equal equal one come on why
oh yeah is that is that enough yeah
yeah yeah okay so
term complexity out time complexity
oh i i i i i
what's the space complexity
are there any additional space we need
to use
what's this is this a space set yeah
yeah so what's the complexity one no no
no no no
no no no no we are using what it says
no
this way look yeah it contains all the
notes different levels
actually is it a one could be a one or
no maybe maybe look
yeah look now look this kind of tree
look
yeah so these notes
can be on different levels yeah
yeah this kind of tree so if there are
ends and nose
and properly some lines stretching out
yeah yeah i'm just talking about that uh
look if there are enough of the
look how many how many notes are there
one two three four five six seven eight
nine
nine notes and there are four one two
three four five
five different levels of these notes so
if we
n minus divided by two plus one
yeah so it's o n right do you get it
oh n because in the worst case
this kind of tree yeah you need
at least on space to
to keep the different numbers of
representing the level of the leaf nodes
right yeah okay okay so
everyone do you want to do the quiz i
erase some of it
and then yeah you two as a team okay
yeah you want to take a look yeah okay
who don't
do it first i thought
okay close your eyes now close your eyes
okay
close your eyes
okay there are two places
[Laughter]
[Music]
left not right
hey
okay eric can you tell me what happened
why why you put
that fs little right thousand plus one
what does it mean
i know it's current plus one what does
it mean
because you go down and then what
happens
you go down level what happened to that
current column will be
add one yeah because it's calculated and
what's the
the last one return lengthy equals one
what happened
[Music]
yeah equals equals one yeah what does it
mean
d what's t
t what's the on the first line what's d
the d the first line there's no d
on what's t
is x it's a set so lens t what does it
mean
we want to count harmony okay okay
what's then t length what's the length
function
the length is the length
to count how many numbers in the lens
yeah i know if it's equals one that
means
there's only one element in the teeth
right yeah
what does it mean it means that all the
lymph nodes are on the same level yeah
yeah got it yeah okay
okay that's it for today good job bye
bye bye