mr ryan how are you today
yeah good so what did we talk about
yesterday the same leaves yeah
thumbs up yes yes let's give it a thumbs
up give a thumbs up okay
we're talking about breakfast
look this is the final tree yeah so the
leaves are on the level one so we should
return two yeah yeah
and how about this the leaves are on
level one and number two
so we should return first remember
yesterday we talked about different
search so basically we go down the tree
and then the dfss remember
that dfs with a root and then a current
depth yeah when it goes down to the next
level
we increment the depth plus one right
yeah
so and now when we when we reach the
leaf node how do we check if the node is
the leaf node
[Music]
that doesn't have any child yeah so lose
the left
is numb right yeah
and blue dot right is not okay so that's
the way to check if you know it's the
leaf node
when we reach the leaf node we push the
current
the depth of the the depth of the node
the leaf node into a set
right and then we finally check if the
set it contains only one element because
if it's only one
element it means what all the leaves are
on the same level
right yeah yeah okay so do you still
remember breakfast search
so what's breakfast search we travel
the notes level by level yeah so here
and then here and here and do you still
remember how we do it look this is one
that's two that's three and that's four
so if a binary tree is like that so
what kind of data structure we need to
use in order to
perform a breakfast search
what kind of data structure do you still
remember first thing
first out what's that
a key yeah first in first out q
okay point as well so how do we perform
this look we have a queue yeah
this is cube first of all it's nothing
yeah it's nothing
now i'm looking i didn't have one yeah
because i i'm going to put the elements
in
look one yeah well i'm here loot yeah
yeah
root so p so first of all i put the loop
first of all i put the first see in yeah
yeah because at the beginning i put the
first load in
okay and then what's the q what this is
the beginning of the queue yeah
why n this is the beginning of q yeah
now now
i do this the q the q is typically from
the q which is the beginning of q
yeah yeah which is one yeah i take it
out
okay i take it off because i have to
kill and then what's the
children of the one two and three okay
so then i put a q here two
three okay okay three is eight
look yes three is the leaf
and then i should put a level which is
one
yeah it's never one in in the in the
set okay this is one here
two now the next item to take out from
the kill is
one two two okay
what's the key what's the triad of the
four four and i put it here right
and the q is
here okay so now look what's in the next
is three yeah
yeah but it doesn't have anything
to add that's fine and what's the next
element form it doesn't
so you should get it do you see how how
we use the q
so we take a triad from the q
which is at the beginning of q we push
each kit
into the queue and meanwhile we check
if the kill is the leaf now or not we
visited now
if it's the leaf now we push the level
okay
yeah so the most important thing here
is that we need to carry over the depths
so look this is loot one we possibly we
need to
put a zero the second element coupon so
to say it's a loop
is depth yellow and when we take it out
we push this kit kit now we know the
next
steps is one right because zero plus one
right
so so we when we deal with the
leaf now we know exactly what depth it
is
okay so do uh first thing first out
and then the queue do you know in python
what can we do
how what kind of data structure we can
use to implement a queue
at least yeah yeah this is a list yeah
you can use the look q equals list and
then you can q
dot pop 0 right but this is not
01 constant because this is a list so a
better way is to
use this q dot dq what's the queue
double ndq so this this one because then
you can say
q dot pop left
yeah which is one constant this is
faster okay
yeah okay so now i'm going to write it
okay
super fast if i check
let's just do over maybe same okay six
minutes
same okay
okay if if root
is numb if like three is none return
we can return two or fours it doesn't
matter okay it's a very special case
okay let's return true because all the
leaf nodes there are
none okay you can say it's true right
yes okay now q q
equals t q yeah
the q and then i can take a parameter i
put a loose note in that
so this this parameter takes a list
uh it uh innumerable so i put a list
and then put a root okay so now the list
the queue contains only one element
which is root okay
yes and then i need to check why
why why okay lens q
wireless element in the queue right wait
why is
this anime in the queue right yeah lens
is to count how many
elements in the cube then i need to take
one element from the beginning so how do
we do it
one element in the beginning p let's do
p
okay equals q dot what
remember what did i just say
pop i said pop left yeah
yeah okay remember we are missing
something which is the
we need to put the depth in it so
instead of single animal we can do this
a tupa
root zero okay and then do this
and okay so now we put an animal from
the beginning
yeah and and we also need a
a set yeah let's do a set set uh let's
let's remove this okay let's remove this
special case okay let's set uh
t equals set to
this is to store the num uh the
the depth value okay of the digits
look now p p
is the p 0 is the root and p 1 is the
depth right
so
if p
0 dot left is num
right and
p zero dot y is num
so what does it mean it's like this now
right
all right yes i'm all right
so now we need to push this is
this one so p1 d dot at p1 right
okay d dot s p one
so means that when when p zero is a leaf
node
p zero instead of now we push the depth
into the
set right and uh
then that's it and if p0
p0 left is not long then we need to push
it into the kill so
q dot append
attend what
p zero dot left
and then p one plus one right p one is
the depth plus one
and the same as this one this is p0 the
right
and at the end we need to return one
return this is the same as yesterday do
you still remember
return one what do you return at the end
less
uh
[Music]
you see so look at this p you can say p0
p1
which is you can still look because this
one recently
you can also have this current comma
that equals q dot pop left
okay so in this case these values will
be
different into two so current will be
the p0 and that will be p1
yeah this is the one thing okay yeah
okay so now can you tell me
if there anything we can improve look
here
can we check can we check here
when we adding a a number
into a set we know how many numbers are
in the cell right
yeah so can we check if if the length d
look all right
if i if i add it
okay if i edit this
here right b dot l there if i i added
something here
if i said if then d
bigger than one return fourth
can i do it yeah yeah because here
if they are iphone they're only they're
already more than two elements
more than one element in a set you will
you'll be returned
as four anyway right yeah because we are
all we are adding the numbers into the
set we are not taking away from it right
the set can only grow right right i'm
right
yes okay so now can i
what should i change the return what
look here i'll return the force and here
should be turn one
2 yeah yes we can two
do you see it do you see it yes do you
understand look
because we all we our target is the
chest is
our target is to check if at least there
are only one element in the d
right right yeah and now
in this case when we added we we found
out that
if it's already more than one so there's
no need to continue
right we can just return fourth
complexity
do we use the additional space i want
yes yes
i want a hand oh and because the kill
wrote and they said
yeah but sadly if we're using this it
doesn't have
content more than anywhere because once
it's more than one we just quit
yeah yeah look at it yeah
okay so now i'm going to close your eyes
i'm going to
i'm going i'm going to erase some of it
okay
[Music]
hello okay
okay now
[Music]
well what's the data structure
that yeah okay
right ryan
okay erin you have the right okay
okay
okay what's here
the first first statement we want to
take away from
the first element from the q so what's
it
what's what's it q q what
the pop yeah q p p dot
p equals q dot
no write it properly p equals what we
are taking one element from the queue
at the beginning so what's that what's
that
q p pop
that's it okay that's it for today good
job
good job bye bye