one two three hey hello mr eric mr ryan
hello hello uh how are you today
hello good good okay so do you still do
the final
final numbers yeah can you tell me
what's binary numbers
uh they're only using one and zero
we're done one zero okay can you tell me
what's leasing
101 in binary what is the equal in
decimal what's this number
this is one yeah this is means two this
is means four so what is really good
seven why is it seven this is zero
this is this one means one this zero
means zero times two
if this is one is two okay if this is
one is
four so what's this four plus zero plus
one
what's what's that
five five yes another one example one
one one one what's that in in
uh just wait wait like that one
oh no no no no no no no no no
[Music]
plus four plus eight so what is equal
ryan one time
okay okay
what's that
so do you understand expiry yeah
one plus two plus zero plus
yes so do we get it if this is one this
is one if this is one this is two
four eight sixteen thirty two and if
it's zero you just skip it yeah
yeah okay so another one example okay
just make sure you understand
one zero zero one one
one is three sorry
three one two four
eight come on what's that
nine yes man okay we're done okay so now
if i give you a binary number i want you
to
return the number of ones in there for
example like 15 yeah i give you 15.
four yeah it's four and i give you 128
what's that
how many this is 2
what's this is 2 to the power of
what 2 to the power
how many twos comes together
lots 4 8
16 32 64
and 2 yeah so it's 2 to the power of 7
so what's this in in binary one
zero zero zero zero zero zero zero
so how many ones one
yeah you see it do you get it yeah
do you understand yeah if it's a power
of
two then it's one yeah yeah
okay so so given a number we want to
count how many
ones in there do you have any source of
how do we do it
we first of all
[Music]
can we count it by converting to binary
yeah and they call how many of them how
many ones
yes
do you stand remember how do we count
the ones how do we
count them um so look this is binary
uh 1011 okay so suppose this is
yeah then how about we
count we can we know this this bit
we count it and then we shift it to the
one position and we shift it
recipient okay
do this understand right define
chord okay count one okay one number
yeah look let's say answer equals zero
okay
okay y
and bigger than zero
y n is bigger than zero
plus equals look n is
we want to know the the right most digit
if it's uh if it's one
it's a odd number right if it's
zero it's an even number right the
binary yeah yeah
for example three is is one one right
and four is one zero zero so in finally
if the rightmost speed is 0 is all
even number if it's one is all number
so answer equals n
and one yeah the rightmost digit yeah
am right yeah now i i counted the
driver's stitch if it's one and any one
if it's zero at
zero right now what should i do i should
remove the right most digit all right
yeah so how do we remove that one more
digit
and shift to to one position to the
right right
yeah look this one this is the number
fifty fifty equals one
means that i shift one and i remove the
five yeah one five
return
yeah yeah okay
okay so do you still remember what we
talked about
a few days ago to check the power of two
the very good uh
the the last method we get divided by
takes every time until it reaches one
yeah yeah another one look because it's
two it's power of two
in binary all right and finally if it's
a power two is one followed by a few
zero
yeah actually quite a lot yeah
at least one yeah so if it's power two
it finally means that one
followed by a few zeros yes yeah look
one is two to the power of zero 2 to the
power 1 is 1
0 2 to the power 2 is 1 0 0 yeah
2 to the power 3 1 0 0 0 okay yes
so now we want if we want what's this
and n minus one what's this
n minus look i'll give you one example
okay
if it's binary one one one one this is
binary yeah
and n minus one is one
zero one one one into this end remember
this n means that zero and one is one
zero zero zero zero one and zero yellow
yeah
one and one one yeah so do you see
n and n minus one you because you will
change
from one one zero zero to one zero zero
zero what happened here what happened
here
from this number to this number what
happened
what happened uh
ryan did you see from one one zero zero
zero to one zero zero zero zero what
happened
what happened what happened to
what happened to this number what
happened
71 well if it's 15 you'll be too zero to
one
if there's no one there's only one
there's only one
left okay i'll give you another example
right one o
zero zero zero yeah yeah minus one is
one zero zero one one and you end it
so what is the equal zero zero zero zero
one so what happened from this to this
yes
we moved which one
what what is that one the right most one
yes yeah
so n and n minus one means that
i take away the right most one
okay look i take which is the rightmost
one here
i take away it and make it zero okay for
example like another one
okay and and and one n
minus one is one zero one zero zero one
yeah
you end at zero and one zero one and
zero zero
zero one zero one so look the rightmost
one is
taken out yeah so we can call this every
time we take away the rightmost one we
increment one
don't cut it yes so yeah
so look answer yeah plus equals
one yeah and then what how should i
change here
here i take away the the rightmost one
is
n equals n and one
yeah whatever yeah
what did i just said this is take away
the right most one
n minus one yes look at it i added one
i added one and i take away the
rightmost one and here it's yellow right
one here which one is better which one
is faster
what's the complexity
[Music]
so if n is is unlimited you know if it
could be a thousand
i won a thousand digits
[Music]
look how many how many zeros how many
zeros
yeah it depends on the number of the
it depends on the number of the size in
binary right
look this is if this is uh
if the number is n how many digits how
many digits
if the number is n how many digits i win
okay look if even like
m no no no no look if they are n if the
number is
n how many digits in binary
n if it's
number eight how many digits in binary
is zero one one one zero zero
zero yeah even sixteen
if sixteen is one zero zero zero
it was n is what how many digits look 16
is five four eight is four
right thirty two is six
yeah roughly you have one followed by
six years
okay so look if it's 2 to the power of
n this number is 2 to the power and how
many digits
if this number is 2 to the power m how
and plus 1 digit yeah that's it yes
because look if it's 2 to the power of 3
then it's four digits yeah
2 to the power of 6 is 32 right
is is 1 followed by 6 digits yeah
all right so if a number is n then how
many digits
is log n yeah two base two log n yeah
yes yeah so the complexity is not n
right
log base to n yeah i'm right yes
n is the limit of range for example like
if it's a
32 bit if it's the maximum is 32 it
means that
the at both this this digi in binary 32
bits
then if we know the size is limited
it's a one right constant because it
does not grow
yeah yes yeah but
this depends if i say n is unbounded if
it could be any any length then you have
to say
it's long or logan okay
okay so in 2017 yeah in python look
in python and we can use this function
pin
binary yeah if pin five
yeah inside you will return
your return string like i i think is
uh is what
one zero zero
one yeah no no no one one zero one
yeah i think there are two characters in
front okay
so if i turn it into string then i can
count how many of of one
that's another way of doing it right
yeah you can say okay four
four i in pin right
answer equals zero and then you can say
if
i equal equals one then
answer plus equals one return answer
yeah you get it
yeah first of all i converted to binary
and then
yeah defined yeah pretty different okay
so but this
is always lower this is more important
okay so what does this do okay
i'm going to erase it can you write it
come on the most important thing what's
here
n and equals
[Music]
n okay okay
equal a n n minus one yeah
okay so this is actually look and
f equals n minus one is actually equals
n equals n and minus one okay
yeah do you get it yeah it's okay look
do you get it i i i know this and when
you roll this this is short for that
it's like look away a plus equals b what
does the equal
is e is the same as a equals a plus b
yeah all right like
n and equals 2 what does it equal
what does it is it's the same as what
and i know what
and and
yeah it's the same thing okay
okay good job today they're very good