[Music]
okay so
today we're going to talk about
different
different approach to check if a string
is a palindrome do you want to remember
this parenchyme
yeah right andrew lumen police
palindrome yeah paragrams you know
string or list or numbers what way is it
[Music]
okay good job okay
ryan to get it yeah what where is they
like
okay good job good job okay good job
yeah
yeah okay so here better so how do we
check if
a given let's say today we want to check
define
define is palindrome okay
per syndrome let's
take a string for example string so we
need to re
we need to check if the different string
is the parent so how do you check it
how do you check it do you have any any
other ideas how do we check if a string
is a pending germ
[Music]
how do you check it wait wait yeah you
got some idea
so how do we check it approach i mean
if given you're given a string like abc
how do you know if it's the parent or
not
cba yes that's a very good
uh hint so
it doesn't be the same abc
well there will be cbi yeah yeah yeah
reverse it good point so we reverse it
yeah we reverse it to check if it's
the same so how do we write it we can do
this return
return reverse reverse
this string if error
if it's the same as the input okay
that's one line of curve okay yes so how
do we check
yeah no no no no you need to define this
left so what is the graph
you can define another function right to
reverse it right
so how to reverse it
[Music]
remember the optional approach this easy
approach
like we can define the answer here first
of all
equals empty string then for
i in s
answer equals i plus angle yeah put it
put every character before the and
before it so it will be
reversed yeah return what
return reverse
return what this is a function return
what arms
yeah return answer
yeah that's easy how we in python we can
use a
much better quicker way look this
housing
can be replaced by what return
because look look carefully it's a very
special keyword s okay then what should
we do
bracket
column column minus one
okay it means reverse it okay so this
whole thing can be replaced
by python this means to reverse it why
does two
columns begin on a list sorry
why are there two columns
this is just a keyword any a string then
we can do it
this way then it means look if s is
a b c and these will become c b a
okay okay so that's one way of doing it
yes so
how do we i mean we this is one way of
doing that we
can also do it this way okay we can
check so how do we check
we can for example like a
b b c
b b a okay so we can check this
character if it's the same as this
if it is the same and i move it to b to
b
so i have two things one here left
one here right
got it so if it's the same i move it
towards each other the left plus
equals one yeah and left
right minus equals one until they meet
they're gonna
understand that then yeah yeah yeah okay
okay so how do we write this look look
left equals zero
right equals length
s minus one yeah because it's uh the
star always in computer always start
with zero
still means the first character okay yes
so we can
check this y left
smaller than right yeah when they don't
meet each other right
i'm right so we can check if
s left not equal
as y
not equal this is not equal equal
not equal
yeah yeah but how do you put it in
computer we use this to
to put it in computer not equal don't
get it okay because
we don't have these in computer keyboard
okay so this
yeah yeah come here look if if the left
try
that character is not equal to right
character what what should we do it's
not apparently
right then we turn fast right
we can fall no no no
no because then we need to move the
left to the right and move to the right
to the left right and then if they meet
in the meter that means that
minus equal plus equals the left would
be increment by one
right would be decrement by one okay
then in after this
what what should we do if they meet in
the middle also we don't
return true right because we find we
found this
i'm right so what yeah so so look
this race car can we do it with the race
car thing
yeah like that race car
okay so left left is here
right is here
why left smaller than right is here
we're here yeah right here
if x left equals not if i
was r yes yeah so left would be
a i'll be a and then check if the same
yes
the same yes okay in the middle they are
in the middle so we don't check so
return true
okay to get it moving moving towards the
middle
yes okay so this is one way of doing and
we can also use the four
how do we use the four look we can use
the four
it's quite similar look for
i in range
land as rightly this will give the
number
index actually we don't need to check in
the meter right
because we only want we don't we don't
need to go
too late entire we need to go to the
meter so range this will be divided by 2
in a meter just in the middle so how do
we do
when we do this if s i
what's the corresponding if i is here
i is zero then we want to
find these corresponding so it will be s
lan s minus one minus i
right if i is zero then you'll be less s
minus one i zero i is one you'll be less
s minus one minus one minus two if it's
not equal
then return first
otherwise here return true okay it's the
similar
thing but we are doing a different
implementation so do you understand it
sorry we don't need airs because look
this is inside the floor right this is
in inside the floor
if we return then it will return it
doesn't go
it doesn't continue then at least we and
now we'll return to
after this for loop to get it we got a
space here yeah intent
like that that return is belongs to this
if
okay so this is one way of doing can we
do
can we use something like stack remember
do you remember the stack first thing
okay so how do we do it with the stack
that's the last approach and then you'll
tell me which one is the best okay
and today you're going to implement one
okay because i have it i've
i've told you now three approach right
three or four i can't remember you can
you can remember yeah now how do we do
it with the stack
first in our stack so first of all we
need to convert
this as string in string into a list
of finger space now there's no space you
you don't have the
space look we convert it into a list so
we use the list
as now it will be this will become a i
will become what
a b c
right okay so now
now we got these so what do we do what
do we do
how do we check
so we want to check if it's backwards
right it's backwards
it's backwards version is the same as
this
so column so what can we do
they are away array already just
standard
so what can we do with it so we need we
have this
then we have i we can say um
away just wait
for wait for i
in f so we're iterating from this a b
c right and now we need to take the
element from the aar
a r dot pop wow
what yes what do you want
i told you don't worry i i'll come back
to you later okay
remember yeah you'll be good boy on the
video okay remember
now we take the last element at the end
right we take
the last element at the end and we need
to check if
x if we not equals to i
then return first i
explained to you later okay otherwise
here we will return to
so to get it look we converted this
string into a b
c the list and every time we take an
element from the end
and pop it which is c and we compare to
the a if it's
if it's not equal then we'll do 10 4
immediately and
this way look if you race car race car
yeah then race car will be become a
a list and i take the c first
uh let's cut r here right and then
it's the same i could continue pop it
poppy poppy poppy poppy pop
and here if it's n and return so do you
get it
okay so which way do you like the best
but the most easy way would be is
pairing drum
s remember this
is s yeah you just need one
return yeah return is
we can leave this is the easiest way you
just only write that
yeah we turn left you find you know yeah
yeah
that returned that remember previously i
told you this is in a separate function
with red right
but you don't need to define two
functions you can just put it
there at least it's one way remember we
use the four
we use the two pointers left and right
right left and right and
put it in the middle right and we also
don't need to check the entire string we
just need to check half of the string
and calculate
the index okay so any questions
before you pick up one of your best
approach you know you like your favorite
approach to implement on your computer
and one final last thing say goodbye to
the video
say bye to the video
you know