hey hello hello mr eric hello mr ryan
how are you today
good good okay so today today i'm
talking about
um i'm your teacher
talk about this coming distance you know
humming hey
[Music]
so actually it's quite intense so
look what's coming distance um it's a
hermit distance is applied for two
integers
no a and b okay so for example if
15 and finally is what
one one one okay and then let's say
a in binary one is
one
why what one it's if it's a power of two
it's one followed by zero yeah
so it's one
[Music]
yes so what's happening distance how
many
how many many beats are they different
how many beats
three three yeah look three so this
these three the timing distance is three
okay
yeah yeah so basically humming distance
is that the number of
bits different different bits in two
different integers so let's say another
example like this one
so look this is the what this is
two two plus one uh this is one one
uh four five yeah five yes one plus four
and then this is one plus two three
three plus eight eleven right yeah is it
eleven
is eleven so having distance between
five and eleven
is
[Music]
how can we do this do you still one
thing do you still remember this x or
exclusive or one exclusive
or zero is one one exclusive
zero exclusive one is one zero and zero
is zero
one and one is zero when they are
different one are different
like exclusive o is one when they are
same is zero so look if we do this
exclusive or it will be
zero one one one right look at this
if we do the exclusive or you'll be one
what will be that
zero one one one do you get it
so if we apply the exclusive or and
then we call how many ones
all right do you still remember that we
we know
how to count how many ones in the binary
yeah we talked about this the day before
yesterday remember
yeah so can you tell me how to do it
we need to do define i mean distance
yeah summing distance
a and b corner right okay
look look so first of all
a n equals a exclusive b
right exclusive this look let's
use this b
this means exclusive oh yeah this
is in let's look in the sixth
number six this six yeah this is
exclusive oh so look
yeah so when you done this right when
you done this
and will be the lamp we're contents
uh we contains the exclusive of both
integers
and then if we just count how many ones
in that that will be the humming
distance i'm right
and do you still remember how we compute
the number of ones in
a integer do you still remember
why why okay then let's do this
answer equals zero okay
right y and
bigger than zero
so remember what we do
after is work is the i no
look answer plus equals one and we want
to get rid of the
we want to get rid of this one do you
still remember
this still remember this do you still
remember this
do you still remember this no no please
yes
this one okay so can you can you write
the rest
please
[Music]
we need to remove the one remember
so tell me and and equals
what
[Music]
right look and once again this one will
become zero out
and once again this will become zero
when when the righteous one becomes
yellow i increment one
because that's the number of serpents
all right
written one
[Music]
we talked about this speed before it's
exactly the same the only difference
today is that
exclusive oh okay you get it
so now let's say if
if okay let's talk about the exclusive
okay okay
so if if a number is three exclusive or
three equals one
think about it if the two same number
exclusive together will be
one one one six
think about it three if the same number
see
three is one one one and then three is
one one so exclusive row would be one
exclusive yellow okay
a hundred and eight exclusive 1081
a minion an exclusive or a minion
zero yes because it's the same each beat
will be the same
then each spin will be zero right you
get it
yeah so this is the property of
exclusive oh if a value
exclusive itself will be this
zero and it is if it's inclusive
one and an exclusive one it will be
look if this is zero exclusive one it
will be one
yeah if exclusive one you'll be zero
okay
so look if z one exclusive zero if you
want
right yeah and then if we exclusive zero
you'll be one again right
so what does it mean if a number a
exclusive b and then i exclusive b
what does it mean your b equals to a
did you get it do you get it
if a number exclusive another number
twice it will be the same you'll be note
if
being unchanged
if you look okay let's say three
exclusive five exclusive five all right
look that'll be three yeah look
three three would be zero one one
five would be one zero zero right one
zero one yeah
exclusive that would be zero one one yes
yeah and then again one one zero one
will be
zero one one look this is the same as
the beginning
yes okay now what's the time complexity
of this one
if
[Music]
the size is unlimited it means that
there's no size limit
what is it look if it's binary because
it represents
entirely do you remember we talked about
this in let us say
o one o what a
one n minus one no don't say
remember if a is one
how many bits of the how many bits of
a in binary a one three
three so that's locked to eight how many
bits in
sixteen there are
four four so lock lock sixteen so how
many
what's the complexity i love sixteen
what's the 16 i'm saying
yeah come on you you forgot this is the
lesson we talked about
two days ago and you kind of forgot yeah
yeah
do you understand i said you have a
yeah yeah yeah it's you can have a ton
alright so it's uh okay
okay now close your eyes i'm going to
i'm going to close your eyes please
close your eyes close your eyes
turn around turn around
[Music]
one at a time
okay
[Music]
okay so one more question what's this
what does this mean what does this mean
n and
equals n minus one what does this mean
can you explain
n minus one is zero 1 1 1 and your n
will be 0. so what does it mean
it means that what does it mean
it doesn't matter i need any numbers
here okay it doesn't matter
um does it mean
what's the what becomes here what's the
change between this and this
is
yeah look this means that i and finally
i want to take away the right
most one okay okay
okay can you help me with the lid please
thank you goodbye goodbye goodbye
goodbye bye tomorrow my birthday
oh happy birthday ryan bye