hello hello my name is
hello mr ryan today we're going to talk
about binary tree
uh how to merge two binary trees okay so
binary tree can you remind me what are
binary trees
it's a tree with numbers so it was
numbers can you draw a banner tree for
daddy
i need buying a tree it doesn't have to
be
super fancy you know to spineless shoes
yes brian do you want to draw no
okay okay that's that's good
whoa that's okay that's okay
yeah it doesn't matter any values could
be fine yes
that's it okay yep so it's timing
except the last bit okay i don't know
what you're drawing next
the final tree is basically a tree with
notes and an edges and each no
has a most two children and each each
children
can have almost one parent
except which note which knows
okay so this is the root look
and that's the leaves okay leaves
it's this upside down tree okay yeah if
you look from
upside down load loads growing upwards
left
upside down yeah that's the edges okay
so today we'll talk about
merge two binary trees like look one
like that three
four no no please good music
five six seven
okay so so now you can you tell me how
to merge it uh let's do this eight okay
so when these two magic you should give
me
six and then that should be
eight y and then seven
y and then eight and then there will be
three four
what yeah good question why so can you
tell me why
when you merge two trees right when we
merge to find the trees
how do we actually proceed uh
this bit looks like like that bit yeah
and that infinite if it is supposed to
have
all of it so easy
you have to even read this then you just
add them
up i think yeah good good point if this
both knows
both notes have both trees have at least
no
the same position no you just add them
up right
look two plus six eight but look
six has a right like it at least two
does not have like it
so we just simply add it just
move it here yeah just copy over and
then look there's three
it doesn't have a right bit and if i put
another one like
five and then you need to change this to
one eight
yes look and then eight you have a left
child this does not have
a left trial let's let's just move it
over
so let's call how we merge to manages
okay
so how how can we do this thing uh
how can we what's the so what's your
approach to
to merge to binary tree
you just draw one over the other yeah so
it's
basically moving yeah
so then you just add them up
if they're both layer right define
merge and then two three is a and b
okay and what what am i missing
[Music]
this returns the merge if a is num we
can return what
if a is now you can just return a
no if a tree a is yes yes good job
if a is long b
yeah so basically if one of them is long
we can return simply with another one
right because you when you merge the
final tree with something with the
binary tree
emerging with nothing and the result is
what
the other one right yeah it doesn't make
sense that
if you merge
eric with nothing
is eric when you must ryan is nothing is
right yes
zero yes yes exactly what is zero okay
so at this point can you tell me these
two a and b
are none or not
yeah look if a is noun it returns b if b
is not written a and at this point
both trees are nino and them are long
right
yeah so they are both noun
both the binary trees with the loop with
at least one note right
yeah okay so now what should we do
with if the both three one one of them
is one the other one is two so when they
merge it together we
you become three okay so
let's do let's do it let's create a new
note okay
let's let's do c okay c
equals three now three
notes okay and a stop
value b dot value
what should i put here
i create a new note add yes so this new
note
i'm creating contains the sum of both
notes yeah
right right so now look
so now i have these three these blue
trees
now i want to recursively merge i need
to be constantly merge
its left tree and the right tree on the
both sides right
yeah so let's look c dot left you tell
me what to do
let's use the left equals much much what
okay so now this is the c and then this
left tree should be
mud to call this self um
recursion recursive function too much
value but the left tree of
these two right so this is a this is b
so what should i put here
a value a dot love tree
left g left b
and then b down right why are you left
left you're both birds in the left tree
the next one
is
[Applause]
[Music]
no no please okay so let's see
i win okay so
if there are a notes in a3 and
b knows i have m times
n times
okay or you can say o a plus b that's
right because that
because why is it because we need to
visit the number of nodes all the nodes
in three a
and then all the nodes in three b right
yeah
this is term complexity what is the
space complexity
a max and plasma
plus max and no no no
o space complexity yeah
space so what's the space and
n the maximum of both numbers yeah
right look if emerging means
if if there are a tree with three notes
plus a tree
i merge a tree with four notes and the
number of notes is
four in the final merged tree right
can you imagine is it true
yes yeah so let's we get a maximum of
both
okay because that's the number of notes
n m sorry n m okay so it's the maximum
of the notes in the first string
[Music]
close your eyes close your eyes close
your eyes
it's not exactly the same as nose okay
don't look at me
don't look at me don't look at me don't
look close
close your eyes and at least just
okay right at the rest
please like it come on you can't see
guys
right now hurry up
okay what's in that bit what's that big
that what's that
right that equals mud
[Music]
yeah so why can you explain to me
why why you write that what what does it
mean seed
if if you're adding if you're
going if you're going to
the right you go to the right
and
[Music]
and ryan can you explain to me why you
write a return c
why because you want to find out what c
because that it's the merge no yeah
[Music]
yeah okay okay that's good that seems
good
okay any questions no no okay so
you can say hello bye bye and i'll see
you tomorrow