hello hello hello mr eric mr ryan we
have a teacher
happy chinese new year how are you today
not joining new year
right now it's on saturday okay okay how
are you today good
day so today we talk about
single number what finger number
singular number is just one number
okay no that means that if i i have an
array okay at least listen to me
i have an array some numbers
some number at least of numbers or some
numbers okay
so look tttgcc
well only one number appears once all
other numbers
appears twice yeah yeah
so the task is to find that
single number so this is single number
okay so any thoughts anything how we can
do this
the one with disappears one time yeah i
know
you just go on the first one and look
for it is it in this part
you found it so you don't need to say
yes
[Music]
okay so basically basically
the numbers and check if it appears on
the if it
appears more than once yes you just
check like
look you you have one two uh you have
you are now looking at
two and then you check the rest is rest
okay okay yeah
yeah yeah okay so so yeah this is the
work
so what's the i guess complexity
yeah what's the camera
[Music]
okay now now i'm at i and now i need to
check
for j in range
again n okay but you again you need to
you need to exclude exclusive case when
i
am equals the j is the same number right
yeah every right okay so how can we do
it if
i not equals j right
and
[Music]
right that means that we find it
duplicate numbers now we need to set
this out of
uh flag equals fours
okay and then here uh every time we
locate the
i we say this flag equals two okay
and then we find this flag equals fours
means that it's not a
two it's not a single number we break it
okay
and then here outside if flag
is left means that is the single number
then return return we can
numbs i okay
here so basically look i with i is the
index yeah from zero one two three four
five
and then every time look
every time i locate it at two i need to
find
i i need to find if the numbers other
than this number
equals to 2 right and if i find it
i set it to 4 which is which means that
it's not the number we want okay
and i break it and then if you frac
means that we can't find that
number twice that we do the service
number okay
what happens if they need it sorry
neither even
eating anything yeah yeah yeah
let me know
yeah good question why happen if they're
not single numbers
but at this point i mean that there will
be a single number
so this is the requirement okay this is
the given okay do you get it
what's the time complexity i went i uh
now if you are looking at i and then you
need to
search for items this is n times this is
f
n squared with o n square what's the
what's the space complexity
and square oh one
one oh one yes
okay so can we do that can we do better
this time what i'm going to do better
so it's better wait
let me yes you think about it
can we do better
yes so look we look for this number
and we said we we just need to find if
the number
appears more than once or not right so
how about we use the counter
a notebook oh yeah yeah
look look we can delete
all right
no book equals counter do you still
remember this character
counter numbs okay
and then for i
in notebook if
notebook no 4a in nums
okay therefore e i num
actually for i in notebook is okay for i
i uh for
value count in
enumerate okay enumerate
actually not enumerate it's actually in
i
uh enough okay notebook if
if c equals one means it only appears
one then we determine v
okay yeah that's it
do you get it
look at this counter so what happened
these two two three three one five five
what happened in this notebook
notebook will be up up yet contains what
two two what's what two what's the value
of two
two three two
one one and five two so this is the
value
two three one five please stop at one
no no this this counter means that
it counts how many elements
in this array so look it has two how
many times it appears in an array
two two okay how many times appear for
the number three
ten how many times appears for number
one one
how many times well let me know yes and
then we go through these
these objects and then find out okay if
it's c equals one and we return this
okay yeah that's that's one way of doing
it okay
and you just add all of the notes
yeah you can all together and if it's
odd
then it must be your own numbers
now you can do this v i equals goes to
the numbers and
if notebook is the same thing as
notebook i equals one and returned
i okay it's the same thing okay you have
to go through these numbers
and if we check the counter notebook
if it's valuable as one means it only
appears one yeah
okay yes how about
how about we use the exclusive or do you
still remember this
one and one is yellow zero and zero
is zero one and zero is one zero and one
is
one okay please still remember yeah this
x
y this is x y this is x exclusive y
okay so
it means that if it's the same it's
nothing
right if it's the same it's zero right
yeah
okay so look if it's different it's one
okay so look
there are only one number every look at
me look ryan look at me if
there's only one number only one number
that's different right
this one is appears one yes and all
the numbers appear twice so what happen
if you exclusive oh
those two numbers
what happened if you exclusively
exclusively excuse me
what did i just say even the same you'll
become
zero okay so what's the result if i
exclusive all the numbers what's the
reason
the result will be one will be the
number we're looking for
yeah remember previous is what i forgot
to say the
counter thing what's the time complexity
oh oh n come on because we need to
iterate once yeah
[Music]
if it's news in space it's all no come
on
okay so this one
so can you write it look x equal
c l and then for
what should i do here x equals one
x equals x one i and return y
can you can you write this can you guess
[Music]
excused by x we have written
is right exclusive or all the numbers
the numbers is that we looking for so
the exclusive return answer is
what numbers are we doing here
so look what's the time complexity
[Music]
what's um come on n o n because we are
iterating these numbers only once yes
yes got it yeah what's a space
conversation
are we using anything new one come on
okay i just said it before okay then
you can actually look
that therefore you can you can just
simply using this return
reduce as a function okay reduce reduce
means that
i want to reduce all this into one
single number okay
so here's what reduce i i can
pass a function in there okay let's say
i can pass the function
f here and then the numbers and given
the star with the zero so this
f thing is i can write it define f
a b return
a exclusive or b okay so look remember
that therefore
fourth thing for loop thing yes
it's the same thing as this yeah you
define a function
a and b return the result exclusive or
and then you pass this function turning
that i want to reduce
the array into a single value
which let's start initialized by
zero and then i take these
the way how we reduce it okay so
basically it's the same
okay and then basically so you f you can
right because it's a one-man thing you
can just do it return lambda
okay what's this
[Music]
single
find the single number try our best
five
[Music]
and then we can
return something here and then you write
the for loop okay that's it
yes come on stand up please fall
yeah four stand up please
follow up yeah foreign
so it means that the number i will be
two two three three point four five and
then
what should i do yes and then what
should i do with the x
x
exclusive i went down you can do it look
that's it yeah got it yeah
what's that come conducting
what's the space compressed
okay so what can you explain to
mommy like mommy don't know what's this
doing here what what's this big code
doing here
what does it do here now
yes x is
it is x
everything sorry what does it mean what
does it mean
i mean what are we doing here what are
what is our task
[Music]
what's a single number it only appears
one once
okay because all others appear
more than one twice because the other
appears twice if
we do an exclusive our own number the
same number twice what we will
we get what do we get
what do we get if it's like eraser
exclusive or if you
exclusive or the same number you'll
become
zero okay so two and two will become
zero three and three becomes zero five
and five will become zero
and one is any number left
would be the single number got it
yeah understand yeah okay good job okay
so can you stand up
in the front why and say hi
happy journey okay bye