hello hello mr mr ryan how are you today
good okay so today we talk about happy
number
okay happy number what's happy number
okay so i'll tell you in a minute
happy numbers are ones that can get lots
of different time tables
uh no okay so look
19 okay so it's one another
so i transfer it to one power 1 to the
power of 2 plus 9 to the power 2
which is what 1 plus 81
that's 82 right yeah 82 and then i keep
transferring to
a square plus 2 square which is
when you stop come on you see 64 plus 4
yeah 17 it gets more 64 plus 4
68 68
that's 36 plus 64.
100 100 okay and then that would be one
power plus zero power plus zero power
which is one okay and then you keep
going you'll be one and one yeah
yeah so one if it's ending
using one is a heavy number okay
so basically you take it you split each
you take each digit square it
and get the sum yeah and repeatedly do
it until you get a one
or does that oh it's repeatedly
all for example like 2 2
4 16 and i was at 1 plus
1 plus the 36 which is 37
and then 3 square plus seven square
which is
what what 9 49 49 which is what
58 okay so 58
5 square a square this is
25 plus 64
which is what 89
yeah keep going keep going
64 plus 81 okay that's what
1 plus 16 plus 25
42 yeah 42
42 and 16 plus 4
20 20 20
four yeah yes four
four so look it's four we see this 4
before and then you
go to 16 and you go again and again so
it never ends one and it's
it's repeated it never ends right so
this is not a happy number because
it won't end at one right
it never ends right this is a sad number
because
it just don't stop okay yeah okay so
given the positive
anyway it's a positive number okay you
can so any number given is a positive
number okay
so given a positive number check if it's
a happy number
or not
so can you tell me how um
in order to check if the number has
appeared before what kind of data
structure do we need
yeah notebook or headshot yeah also
because we need to
need a place to remember the numbers we
have
calculate we have seen before right yes
and then how do we how do we extract the
digit for example 19 how do we
how do we get the digit 9
and how do we get the digit one so
how do we extract the digit so this one
equals what nineteen divided by ten
right
and this is nine equals one 19
what okay fill in the operator here
i already teach you this one is 19
divided by 10
yeah the integer part and 9
is 19 what 10. remember that
symbol modulus do you still remember
how do we do the modulus in circle
so can you write down
yeah go down modulus this is the model
ryan
percentage okay you can also create
percentage so basically this is
19 minus 19 divided by 10 right right
yes oh no this is nothing but it is 10
and then
times constant okay okay
so let's see that's the basic
okay let's let's write it okay define
is happy okay he's happy
and um
okay so we we're just using the very
this is tilted
yeah yeah i know okay so you just kind
of
okay so now we use the d it's a set
okay this is the notebook okay yes
yeah why why why
n is not equals one right because one is
n
one now we need to stop and
and one and not
n in d so we we haven't seen this number
in the notebook yeah
one happy number yes of course because
one times one time one
one square is one and the u squared is
one it always
stays at one it's happy yeah yeah okay
so why
why n is not one and
n it's not seen in a in a notebook
so we need to square the numbers
right square the num digits
yeah so so let's do current current
equals n okay
and then the number sum we add it as
zero okay
yeah this is this will be stored as the
number of the
the sum okay this is the stoner sum and
this hash means the common okay sum okay
wire c u r bigger than zl outcome
yeah a plus equal
what c u r modulus 10
times times two okay so square yeah
look see one percentage
yeah percentage modulus 10 is the
it's the it's a one yeah it's the ones
it's the number for example 1
9 is the 9 okay yeah and i square it
yeah
right i add it to a and then what should
i do here
i need to divide the column by 10 right
so c u r
divide the equal one 10 where down yeah
yeah yeah yeah because i i need to
separate on this okay
and then a now is the
sum yeah ae will be 81 plus
1 is 82 right 82 and then now i need to
set n equals what hey
how do you know ryan good good job
[Music]
n is one it's a happy number n equals
equals one
okay so now this is the oh do you see it
this
is the okay there's one one thing
missing
because look at this set we need to add
it to the set yeah
it's not in the same and i need to add
it the number in the set
right so next time when we see this
number
then we we don't want to compute it
again right because we need to add a
number
yes this is the way
to calculate the numbers digit by t
but we can also compute the numbers
convert the numbers into a string right
so this bit okay this bit how can we do
it
okay this is return and equals one right
so anyway if
this n right i can convert it to i can i
can do this
um a equals zero and then
for i in star
i convert it to i convert it to string
yeah when i have converted the string
the i
will be the character what's the iascii
code
of 40a what 40a
what's the a no 40 0
65 category 97
hello okay so look i converted to
i converted to numbers and then i i
plus equals i convert it back i convert
it back to integer right look
look these be integer i squared square
two okay and then n equals a so this
this thing can be represented by that
okay okay
okay so look this end i
in i will turn this i turn this two
to the number two okay in the means to
convert
this string to this
yeah alternatively i i can do this
right i can do this all right remember
asking code yeah
yeah basket i minus
one minus one
if it's a single digit minus what
what's that what's the asking of the two
48 49 50 yeah
yeah and this is 50. i and i need to
convert it to
50 i need to convert it to 2 so i need
to minus 1.
48 yeah yeah okay or
i minus 48 okay yeah
so this thing we can use
this thing we can use the python in you
know a very fancy syntax which is look
these three yeah this way i can do this
look look this at least these four lines
i can do this
and equals sum okay i want to sum the
digit
but what's the sum x square
x squared s square okay x
square
actually is in x
times times two is a happy number
not really no no a good guess
but i don't know maybe maybe it is you
have to prove it okay
for example like 2 is the prime number
but it's not happy number
yeah we just blew it yeah then
okay three okay let's get three
what nine eighty one
yeah i see one what's this uh 64 62
64 65 yeah and now what's this
36 plus 25 36 plus 25
61 yeah yeah
and 30 37
and nine and
so 49 yeah 58
25 plus 36 64.
89 yeah we haven't seen the 89 before
okay 89
64 plus 81
145 1 plus
16 plus 25
what what's that 42 can we see 42 before
no
16 plus 4 20
okay and that's four it's not a prime
yeah
so it's it's not true okay bigger than
five and
bigger than six okay you can you need
yeah you can say okay uh any prime
number which is not two three five
you pick the one yeah i see how this is
going good good job good job you can
write the program to test your theory
okay
look this this one i can write it some
which take a somewhat a list
into x time times two for
x in star
n and bracket nothing
so look list can be replaced by left and
that can be replaced by the single line
okay but this is quite fancy
present syntax i don't expect you to
learn you just have a taste of how it
looks like so look sum is a function
somewhat sum the functions some have a
noise bleed
okay go get the sum the length
sum the list of numbers look
times itself and the x is in the n
which is converted to star okay so
can i can i raise a bit
okay close your eyes close your eyes
please
close your eyes close your eyes
[Music]
so a we want to add the digit to a a
yes e so tired
why you're so tired external please
stand up please
a a plus equal one you need to
plus equal one the current
right amount of stitches of current
i think is
yeah current modulus 10 yeah and then
you need to square it
do you have anything of the equals
take a guess take a guess take a guess
current
mother is 10 modulus 10 yes
times two
right nine times two what do you do
not times two power of it okay okay
modulus 10 means i wanted the right most
digit at once right and i want to square
it right
yeah okay do you understand okay good
job today
bye bye
[Music]