hi hello hello hello mr eric mr ryan how
are you today
good good okay so today we're going to
talk about
eric and
ryan this is a string yeah huh
we're gonna talk about that lion uh
maybe
[Music]
okay ryan okay just
arrogant ryan and then i want you to
reverse
it by not by characters by words so you
become
white lion and
everything it'll be named
yeah so if remember if you have
something more than
[Music]
[Applause]
you reverse the center uh words not the
characters okay it's not like like that
ryan and then you reverse the
characters you'll be n-a-y-r right
okay so did you see it yeah what's the
word
eric and rice
so we start on this letter b
how do we go to the next words we need
to
find this space right yes so okay
so in python remember we have a very
useful
function which is called split split
space spread what's split
just what what is this yeah just to make
it apart yeah
yeah and then you can take a parameter
then if you put a
it'd be three minutes you put a space it
means
i split by space so look if this is s
yeah look this is a string and then if i
say split
stop split a you should do a
let's let's okay if s is a string s dot
split
space the way it becomes you you will
split the
sentence string by this denominator yes
the limiter what what does it mean
delimiter by this thing you're given
into a list so you become a list yeah
bracket
and eric come out
and come on and ryan
okay that's me yeah
yeah that's me uh
okay so there might be a small problem
which is
s string is not
yeah you can spread the string yeah and
by this will become this yeah
yeah yeah yeah and then you just need to
reverse this part
and first reverse this part how do we
reverse that
hold with the list reverse this bit
and then another the opposite so how do
we do the opposite from the
lead to the string for example at least
i want to conver i want to
make it back to eric and ryan so if this
is
uh a okay if this is an array
a so how can we make this back to this
we can use this space a space yeah this
is a space
join a that's
it so what does it mean it means that i
want to join
the elements in a list
by a space
[Music]
so this way you you you will make a
string
based on a list by its delimiter
and this this direction you split a
string
into an array of strings
by using this split function okay so
what's the complexity no no no yeah okay
so now
i can do this i can do this okay so
let's do this okay
i can show you okay so
for example if we want to reverse the
string how do we reverse string
there's an agreement to do it
look look look it does become the front
look if this is the remember the reverse
string
we are using the reverse string we can
use reverse to check if a string is a
panning drum yeah because it's spelled
backwards like race guys better
it's also let's go yeah yeah okay so
lease
a b c d e okay we want to
we want to reverse this speed it will
become e d
a okay yes how can we do it
we just we just move the
last one to the beginning so that last
one to the beginning and then how do we
do it
from the beginning one to the end then
the second beginning one okay so
yeah you mentioned a very good point
which is to
look look i have two pointer yeah
yeah yeah yeah ryan look line look i
have two pointer
i swap to these two yeah so you become
b a e a and then i move it closer one
step
closer yeah yeah yeah yeah and i swap
these two you'll become t and you become
what b and i move it and then meeting
the meter
that's it you see does it work yeah
i have two points and both ends i
swapped
i swapped the elements at both ends and
then i did
and then i move move one step closer to
each other until i meet in the middle
which
will be in the middle right yeah okay so
so
but interesting is in prison
the s is c the string are
immutable so what do you mean by this
mean
immediately what does it mean means he
can't talk
no no no mutable what does mutable mean
change it can be chain immutable means
it can't be changed
so what does it mean like if it is a
string eric eric
if you ask a string right s
0 will be f e yeah
will be equal to e right yes
um but you can't change the string you
can't say i want
s yellow i want to point it to capital
a you can't do that
because this string is immutable you
can't change it
you can only read from it don't get it
[Music]
yeah that's okay but you can't you can
say okay i want the s 0
is equal to e double equal means to
check check for equity right
single equal means to assign a value
assign a value but you can't do it in
person okay
yes you can better so how so
so we can only in zoom yeah you can't
talk
yeah yeah look if s is the string now we
can convert it to
array right let's say array equals
list list s
then you will become a character
when you do this the f a will become
what
it will become like that e ah
a single letter y c i c and
and then now you can this is mutable you
it means you can't
you can change it right yeah okay so now
i'm going
i'm going to do uh i'm i'm going to talk
about
if we if it's uh okay that's okay
if n a is at least reason how can we
change it so
look
so define reverse let's just reverse
s from i to j yeah
if s is at least yeah if s is released
then we can store this
y i is smaller than j
column yeah and i want to solve the
position from i to j yeah so
s i s j
equals as they as i
okay you see s-i-s-j
s-i-s-j equals s-j-s-i
okay so it means to swap it and then i
plus equals one and then
what should i do with j
uh i is on the left s
in i is on the left j is here i plus
equals one i move
one step to the right and how what's
your idea with zayn
yay minus equals one well done
brilliant that's what i want yes and
when i meet in the middle
that's it let's swap it yeah stop it
yeah good thing
okay so in person we don't need to
reinvent that
yeah we can just do this in person
we can just do this i want to reverse it
all right
i want to reverse it either is a string
or this i can just do this
s and i can just use this one here
reverse
reversed s then you become reverse let's
say
or alternatively you can do this or
automatically you can just do this as
bracket
column minus one
okay so
minus one so it means double column
minus one
means to reverse it it's a reverse
version
of s right
yes so
and one way of doing it first of all
a more complicated approach is to
reverse this by
letters so reverse this letter will be
you'll be one and a y r
and then the second step is to reverse
the words
so this will become ryan
this will become and this will become
eric
yeah you see that's what we want yeah
right
you see yeah
[Music]
and another approach because another
approach is what
this is one approach another approach is
first of all
look we split it as the sprint
okay so now anyway what do we have
you become what we have
e r i c yeah
and ryan
means okay so now look
okay this is it and then if we
if we we
if we want look if we use this
you could tell me what happened okay if
i put this
column column minus one so what happened
and then you'll become you'll become
what if i please
at the end you will become
ryan look i reverse the words
in the array right ryan
and and one away yeah
right all right yeah
and now i just need to connect this by
space by space so now what do i do
and then i do what do i do
space dot join
again
space.join and then you become ryan
you see
okay so in a single in a single
function in a single function look
single function
define reverse again this is reverse
words okay reverse one
and then s we just do this
return space
stop join remember what we talked about
join
and then stop split
by space and then
column column minus one
that's it
correct so this is the simple done to
make arrogant ryan become ryan and eric
got it that's it yes yes it's simple
yeah all alternatives can this one you
can do this you can do this
this is reverse you can just do this
reverse remember it's the same thing
reverse
stop split yeah
okay it's the same thing all right it's
the same thing
join okay same thing okay
do you get it yes okay now i have two
quiz
okay you just tell me what what what
okay
i just have two quiz okay yeah okay
you tell me okay
a space b
space c dot split
straight space what does it give me
what does it give me cba
what does it give me c
where is the c what i don't have a
leaver
what does it give me this is a string i
split it by a space what does it give me
a b
it's a bracket it's a list yeah
three element got it yeah next one
will give us okay and how about
ah r y a
n okay ryan
bracket minus space space uh column
column
minus one what does it give me a y r
r and a y while because this is the
reverse
it's the same thing as if you go column
here
okay so how about this how about this
reverse
a bracket and minus my uh this is
if i want to apply this to the list what
what's the result
um
[Music]
okay so that that's pretty much the
the seventy minutes bye bye
bye bye bye bye