hello mr eric mr ryan how are you today
good good good yeah so today we talk
about binary trees
binary trees okay can you tell me what
is the binary tree area
is it is the tree with the number
okay every time last time i ask you and
you say the same thing can you
stand up can you write write the binary
tree ryan doing to draw a minority
okay that's fine draw a banana tree
please
come on it's not drawing lessons come on
no no it doesn't it's a final tree it
doesn't have to be a final research tree
yeah
it's a binary tree okay so look
the the maximum pass between the loop
this is the root to the leaf is what
10 to two notes yeah yeah so this is
which is very smooth
so this is we if we call it the maximum
depth
is also equal to maximum pass
maximum pass between the root
and the length
okay so so
um so look what's this if i add one more
two more what's the two threes that's
right so what's the
maximum term maximum pass
four one two three four yeah
we're done so how can we do how can we
compute this
maximum thing you just look
maximum steps okay you look at all of
the leaves and which one's the lowest
look define max
steps we can use the recursion yeah
remember
yeah the number three how can we define
the tree
first first of all class three
yeah and then define
underscore
left right okay
and then we can say self talk
load equals
uh set of top value top value because
equal at least we can do this value
equals value
and then sell the left
equals left and self
right so this is the definition of
a tree so look we can specify left left
you can say by default is the lung and
diabetic
now yes so basically we can say
root after we define this we can say
root
equals 3 and then we give a value so
then you a quick creator
you will initialize you initialize a
note which is the value one so basically
what what happened is
is like that yeah
okay yes and then i can say a equals
three two what does mean it means that
another note and then i can say blue
dot left equals a
so what does it mean it means like that
yes
yes why do you have a number right i
don't know
this is the reason this is rule this is
children okay
so look i can say b equals three
three so what does it mean i create
another three here
and i can say loot dot right
equals b so you put this yeah
yeah yeah select the left equals left
and then
left and right but this is the call what
what do we call this
initi constructor
constructor of a class so this
this is a special function that is
called
when we do this right if we are doing
this
eric we were doing this we were doing
three you call this constructor okay
yeah okay so now going back to this
problem
so look if loot
is now so what's
what's the depth of uh
empty note what's the depth
return what number return where down
within zero yeah
yes because empty now has zero
depth now we we need to call this
recursion
left and right three to get the depth of
both
and then the value of the maximum depth
of the current load that will be
the maximum right right what you're
doing
right uh
so how can we do this look
f left equals max
steps what should happen here
left right no low dowa we are
calculating the left tree
so look this is the left and right okay
okay so now i'm here blue that here
and i want to calculate the left depth
yeah
so that will be do the left right the
next one must be white
and right i i want to calculate the
right depth
so we need to do the same with the left
change
look so this this bit is the depth of
this tree and then
left is the left of this tree and then
we turn one
so what's that what should we do 10 with
the left and right
so which one is the maximum yeah
they're both the same maximum left
and right but again we need to do what
because one yeah yeah exactly we need to
plus
one yeah right because look
the this is if this is maximum
this one is maximum two right yes this
is one
two is maximum and one right and the
depth should be two plus one because we
are we need to add the
depth of the root got it yeah
do you understand yeah
you can actually don't need assignment
you can just put
return max maximum download left
comma maximum dashboard right comma plus
one and then you can squeeze these two
lines into one
okay yes okay so
what's the time complexity
[Music]
first complex not the time complexity
in the worst case in the worst case the
binary tree is
is just like a single list since it's a
it's just one uh linked list yeah okay
then nonlinear will be n depth yeah it
will be n
and depth yes okay okay
[Music]
okay so now um any questions
i'm going to erase this
and then always please okay
so somebody want to find uh
yeah yeah yeah okay
write clearly please
yeah ryan is doing good job today
right right right hand right
perfectly you're not drawing
okay okay then erik's turn return
one
[Applause]
we want to return what return left
and right left and right what you're
looking don't look at my nose come on
it's just a one nine and you need to
look at my nose that's not right
add one correct
we're done with them okay let's see see
you tomorrow you need to say bye bye
bye say see you tomorrow say
bye bye
bye