hello hello hello mr
mr ryan how are you today good remember
this
this is the recursive implementation of
how we getting these the
computer math depth of a binary tree
which is the distance between the root
and uh
and the leaf yeah so today we are going
to use another algorithm
breakfast search but for ourselves tell
me what's happening
yeah let me let's breakfast
means horizontal yeah
dfs yeah we talk about this
death okay compared to this depth
so one is horizontal the other one is
that vertical
deep okay yeah deep yeah basically
deeper is the
adjective and this is the norm yeah
yeah this is a dj yeah
yeah big bad
um okay so basically
we we visit we visit the notes
in the horizontal order so look can you
tell me
what this is how we pushing this to the
tree
uh how we visit it
okay can you tell me
how we how we how we use the preference
search to visit
the order of the notes yeah
one two three four five exactly and then
how about that first search
thief deep versus the one oh yeah
two three three four five
it's the same yeah yeah it's about
different yeah but yeah different kind
of logics yeah
it just happens to be the same if i put
it
if i police i put another six here the
breakfast
simply one two three six four five yeah
level by little but that's one third it
will be one
two six three four five
got it yeah okay so in order to do this
uh what kind of data structure are we
using
are we using eric we talk about data
structure when we talk about a breakfast
search
we usually use the data structure which
is
yes and why is that a kill yeah well
done first thing first out okay
oh my god what happened to this first
thing first out
first thing first up okay and first
thing
what is that
okay so so look we have a basic
framework to do a preference search can
you can come out please
define max
that's that i don't call it
because it's not nothing nothing is zero
zero zero depth okay now we we create a
q in python we can use the double ndq
okay so look
q
and then bracket and then we need to
push the first first note which is what
we need to push the first note which is
right look but we also need to push
these steps so we put this bracket yeah
at least yeah and then we do this two
parts yeah super
loot and then one okay because the loot
has the number one right
cute yeah like that
okay then we also need to store the
maximum
uh depth in in in
in a variable we call it answer right
answer equals zero
yeah so while the q is not empty
yeah while the queue is not empty why
huh
wire not empty queue how do we check the
queue if it's not empty
away file length lens yeah because lens
q we can use the length length q if it's
not empty which is
what that's in the wrong place
what bigger than zero yeah that's in the
wrong place to be here
that's okay that's always the same yeah
that's okay sit down sit down please
and then how we can pop it we can we
need to remove it from the head of the
queue which you will use the best called
pop work pop which side we
it's a q we push it and we're going to
put pull it from
left yeah so so carbon we can assign it
to a common node and then the
second node is f yeah because it's two
parts right
current
[Music]
top left okay now we have the test
we know we are visiting the node then we
need to update the
uh uh answer so answer
will be max value of answer
and and what that what variable is you
put here
what variable is put here
depth because we are getting these steps
value okay
yes so this is the same thing answer
this
this is the same thing as if answer
if death if death is bigger than
answer then answer equal steps right all
right
yeah erin pay attention please yeah
ryan i'm going to test you later okay if
you're not listening okay
yeah now we got a current note
we need to push it that kid or right kid
into the queue right
yes only if it's not empty right if it's
empty we just skip
okay so how can we do this
how can we push it how can we push it
remember the breakfast search usually we
take a taylor
note from the queue and then we push
push its kids okay so
i buy one okay if current got
left yeah you cut on the left then
q dot append yeah open to the right yeah
open what
so in order to do that we need to push
current dot left and comma what
what's the depth of the new node current
current on the left and now what's the
depth what's the depth
of the new node we push to the one level
now so which
what it means what it means
that that's i know what
current depth current node has this one
and what's the
next level
[Music]
what's the next come on this is the note
i'm
this is the loop one and then i'm
pushing this so what's the depth of this
what what's the depth depth
level level and then that's what
three two yeah this steps is one and
then
what's next that's what
ryan that's what
right and we do the same thing and kill
the opponent
a pain current
[Music]
can somebody feel it what's the time
complexity answer oh
[Music]
right yeah yeah and we
because we are using the queue right
yeah
we're done okay so now clean
uh yes please chris yeah
[Music]
can you close your eyes please no please
otherwise
it's not fair turn around
[Music]
mean
we talked about this before yeah you
forgot yeah it's
kind of cute but it's d dapper
so which means that i can push i can
up top left and i can pop and i can
append
left and i also can prepare so basically
it's a cue like you can do this
operation
push a pen and pop from both sides yeah
so it's called double
yeah so it's it's efficient the pop
a pen and a pop takes oak on constant
time yeah
compared to a normal list almond list if
if it's a normal list do this pop zero
to remove it from the beginning which
could take
o n right so that's why we use the dq
which
has higher higher performance of the
push and append and pop operation which
is
one constant right or one constant one
constant means that uh
it doesn't it doesn't matter how many
elements are in the
queue in the data structure it's always
very instant faster right
yeah yes got it if it's o-n
it means that if there are minion items
in the element
and then if you if it's o-n and
invention it will take
long long time to do this right which is
what we don't want to
okay so goodbye bye
so which one um
yes i think that's pretty much it um
see you tomorrow