hey hello mr eric mr ryan how are you
today
how are you today i'm a teacher they say
mister we know a teacher don't think
okay mr is a good
kite you know if you're a boy we call
you mister okay
so given an array okay so array of
numbers
like 1 2 3
5 7 9. so i want you to
find out how many numbers that it's next
number is also in
a range nine three like one
it's next is two is it a number yes oh
yeah
yeah two three is ten
yeah two the next number is three it's
in the number in in the list
three no four five no
seven no so yes two yeah yeah i said two
yeah got it do you do you understand so
this is what you want to count
doesn't have to be an order no it
doesn't have a connex
number of context elements so basically
we want to find out how many numbers in
the array
[Music]
how many numbers in the array that it's
next it's plus one it's also an array
okay any ideas
how we can do it we we do the first
number
then we go through the rate and see
if it's any number plus one do that
number
yeah that's a good pro approach uh in
the beginning this is called blue fox
yeah
blue four brute force
so very intuitively like we iterate this
number yeah
and then we iterate again to find out if
next one is
is in a array right yes so
let's do this define okay let's say
okay
[Music]
yeah four look
we go through this number once yeah and
then we need to go through it again yeah
anonymous look if
they yeah
yeah if z
is equals to i plus one
answer one add
one answer add one yeah yeah
return answer right yeah
will that work will i work
look let's try i will be one and then i
try
one two okay i plus one yeah you know
i plus one because j is equal to i one
yeah now i'm here i
yeah j j star from i yeah
it doesn't equal it doesn't this
condition is not
met because j is equal to i right
j will be here two equals one plus one
yeah
so answer is one and then it doesn't
meet okay and then i
too right three here yeah
no okay here three plus one
two okay three one
so yeah it will work how about if we can
have these duplicate numbers
like if we have uh another two here does
it work
one one two two so you pass two two
times
okay and then two
two
for one yeah and then yeah yeah it will
work
okay so basically you'll find these
pairs i and j
you will find this pair i and j yeah and
if i
j is i i plus one so i basically i
i plus one this pair in the
array so what's the time complexity i
i hit that look this is look
n times yeah i go to this end for each n
i need to go through n times again right
yeah
can we do better uh
n times then no it's not look
remember the n times n is like that yeah
n times
n is this graph look and what
yeah look this is n and then this n
times n yeah
so look when n is a hundred and then the
n times n would be
what what's this number ten thousand ten
thousand and when
n is a thousand that will be another
three zero yeah
so that would be what's this number a
minion yeah
yeah so look when n is a thousand it's
already a million so it's a lot so n
square is not very good
right look n square this is square this
is n it's very slow do you get it
right okay so how how
can we do better i'll give you a hint
the notebook yeah
the third one in the network so because
look
we can do this we can go through these
numbers
and then put it in a notebook yeah and
then we can just check
check if the next number is in the old
book notebook and that
only costs you all one constant right
previously we use another for loop this
is takes o
n time right yeah am i right yeah
do you realize the difference so look i
show you look
define f launch
a notebook column okay let's call it d
equal set remember set yes
yes okay so now
actually we we can just set and we can
take the parameter numbers
so we put the numbers in the set so we
put all the numbers in in the notebook
right yeah then four
i in num
if i plus one right we want to check if
the next number right
right in
t answer plus
equals one right answer equals zero
and return answer correct
yeah what's the term complexity
what's the hapticity sorry um
look our n comes in
just o n what compare previously the
previous
method has this for loop as well but
another in order to check if the number
the plus one is in the in in the array
the previous method used another for
loop right
this is times n but now if i plus one in
d
this is a one so that will be all n
times this one will be o n n times one
yeah got it so do you see look
i plus one in d yeah this is called we
putting all the numbers in the notebook
in the notebook intercept and then we
just want to check if
i plus 1 is in the notebook we can do
this i plus 1 in d
and that only costs you how many times
how much
complexity oh one this is a one yeah
correct yeah and we can also use the
counter remember we use the counter
look another one t equals counter
capital c how the numbers so
can you can you give give me example
what what's d now
b equals countless numbers what does it
what what's the
counter what what's counter mean
it's like a pointer no it calls the
numbers and how many times they appear
so i give you an example t
d will be a dictionary now yeah so
you'll be
look look alright one one and you tell
me what it is okay two
two three one five
one seven one so what does it mean
d equals counter numbers so what does it
mean
ryan can you give me can you tell me
what does it mean
one one if it's odd you say
one if it's even it's two
not exactly or how can i put it back hey
so
[Music]
yeah exactly so this key this is called
key yeah
keys key is a unique unique
element in the array okay so look
there are only these kind of numbers 1 2
3 4
3 8 5 8 in the numbers yeah
and the values this is called the value
yeah
it's the number of times they appear
right yes
yeah because two appears twice i know
other elements appear once okay good job
so now we we do this we have that d
structure and then how can we do this we
can just do this look
we can go through that for
eric again we can go through this i in
numbers yeah
we can do this if i plus one in
we have before again in d no no no
no yeah this is four and another one is
look i plus one in d
on the same right then we talk answer
plus
okay so now look we are going through
these numbers again but we can
we can we we we don't need to go through
these duplicate numbers right
look if you do leave for i in numbers
you'll go through the two
twice right we can we can just go
through these three
dot keys yeah yeah so if
i in d dot keys
right now we can say
if i plus one in
in d then we do this answer
plus equal what it's not answer plus
equals one one no it's not one again
because we only
we we iterate the two only once
so we need to add two instead of l1
right yeah the previous one we add we
iterate the number twice
so we can add one right so what's this
no
two it's it's not constant what's this
d1
p what value i o i plus one
f not i
yeah look i i don't think two two has
two right
yeah but three is in the table look
three is in the table but i need to i
have two
two two two times of two so i need to
add two right
yeah so this do you understand return
one
answer okay okay so
uh
do you want me to which method do you
remember
because i talk a lot a lot and which one
do you remember
remember happy number yeah
okay so yeah yeah
wait wait okay good job so now
we we can also use the uh you know this
this is traditional way of you always
writing a for loop
the constant is uh the time complexity
is also always yeah
oh n yes and and we we can also
use the um
use the
uh use the sum object so look we can
have a d
and then we can just do this return
yeah we want to sum this sum yeah
sum
v value yeah
uh for like a v uh
a v in
these dot items indeed
items look when you have additional
items it actually will be key and value
and value and if a
uh if a plus
a is the key a plus one in d
okay so let let's see um
yeah so do you see it look
this is a this is a very fancy syntax
okay so for a
v in d dot items and a is the number
yeah and now all the pr or k k is the
numbers
i wanted to check if k plus 1 is also in
d and i want to call that this v
counter v sum the v yeah this is
basically the same
as previously we we go we do this for
k v in d dot items yeah
and then look it's the same as if
k plus one in d when we do this
answer plus equals what plus
equals v why yeah answer equals zero
so look this bit is the same as this bit
okay yeah just a bit longer
yeah at least it's more fancier yeah you
want to some something
okay when you write more code you can
understand this a little bit but
it's not required at this moment the
most important thing is how how
you understand this okay so remember
so a bit challenging yeah okay so can
you write it
anything try it try your best
try your best try your best okay another
hype you come on
now try your best right you want to try
no
yeah you can do it look for all right
[Music]
numbers here for i in numbs
if if what
answer plus equals what
and return what okay okay can you feel
the blank
it's twice one
okay and
we want to check if next one sorry next
number
is in sorry norms
plus one right next number is
in the visionary in a sense in a
notebook
how do we do it
do you still remember
what's the opposite of out in
in what range in what in what which
variable is here
yeah okay so do you get to see now
do you see
you remember
okay if i plus one in
t answer plus equals one we're checking
the next number if it's in addition
array yeah
if it does okay come on i want you to
write it
come on yeah why don't you
even see you don't see it
come on try your best light one and then
we can finish it come on
right because we are checking the next
number if two the
three is in the next one in the
dictionary in in a set
we add a counter yeah okay see
[Music]
please please come on come
yeah that's perfect i that's i
small face okay i plus one right
yeah answer
plus equals one and you focus something
yeah okay so what's the time complexity
what's the thumbnail
what's the time complexity
please that's not funny
what's the time complexity oh n yeah
what's your space complexity
o n o n because we're using the thread
okay
come on bye bye see you tomorrow