go hello hello everybody hello
ryan how are you today good morning
okay so remember we talked about the
square root right squared
yeah right square root 25 what is the
answer
five right we're done okay so so today
we uh
and previously we talked about using the
binary search to
to compute the loop by at the root yeah
do you still remember yeah for example
like 25 so we
choose the left equals zero and right
equals 25 and then we calculate the
meter yeah
yeah and we compare the meter square
really
we compare the mean square to 25
to 25 and then depending on which side
it is we continue to search
in a half space right yes until we
we have this reasonably closed solution
right
do you get it yes
so today we talked about another another
solution is to
compute it because you only need to
compute it how can
it look so let's say we want to compute
the square root of n
right all right can you see that please
we want to compute this
square root of number n and then
if i said n is equals
a squared plus b where a is a square is
bigger
bigger than b right so for example like
i want to calculate 100
100 150 what's the square root of 150
so it equals to
which which number square itself is
less than 150 by the biggest
10 11 12 30 12 yes exactly
10 squared plus b right yeah so 12
squared plus 6
right okay yes yes
okay okay so remember a is 12
b is 6 okay so they get it a is try
something
yeah so we basically we try we we we
guess the big is the square number
that is less than the target right so
let's see a n equal let's do this n
equals a squared plus b
okay so what can we do is n minus
a n minus a square
equals equals b right yes
so do you still remember this formula
eric like
a plus b times a minus b
what does it equal
what does it equal a squared minus
b squared okay a plus b like
2 plus 1 times 2 minus 1
equals 2 square minus minus 1 squared
equals 3
right 3 times 1 is 3. correct yes
yes okay okay so
okay let me give you an another example
uh
5 plus 3 times
5 minus 3 equals 1.
16. yeah okay okay yeah
it's amazing yeah why are you while
you're missing the times
okay that's okay okay now look
so look what's this and this is
a square root of n plus a
times square minus n a right you get it
because look
this square
is n right yeah and then a square right
do you get it okay yeah
so this will be and uh a square right
okay
so look the lease is left
so what can we get all right look
what can we get so b if we move
move this thing uh move this thing
okay move these things to the right
it'll be
b divided by square root plus
n a right and then
that will be equals to this one right
look
and now what happens if i move the a to
left to the right hand side
so that will be plus
uh plus a right yeah all right
look look this is the thing we want to
compute yeah square root of m yeah and
this is the square root of n
we are going to compute so look let me
let me y again
square root of n equals p a plus b
a plus square root of n so what happened
look this is the magic yeah
what happens if i look
replace this bit with this bit
this is okay look at square root of m
equals a plus b divided by a plus square
root of n
okay what square root of n is this one
yeah so if i remove this
and then i replace this the whole thing
b divided by a plus
square root of n right
uh a a plus left a plus n so that would
be two a
yeah all right t times a
yeah yeah all right this will be the
same so you'll be
b a plus b divided by 2a plus b divided
by 2a plus
b divided by 2a plus b divided by 2a so
it continues that way
do you see the magic okay look
these originally is this okay
because look square root of n we want to
calculate the square root of n
right and then it has square root of n
in the right hand side right
yeah so if i remove this
and i take this whole thing what's n
what's 0 the n equals a plus square root
of n so that will be
b a
plus square root of n and plus
a right a plus that yeah and then look a
plus a that would be 2a
right so you can continue replacing this
square root of
n and then you come to this way so
square root of n equals
a plus b divided by 2a plus b divided by
2a plus b divided by 2a
this way continue right all right
so so so we can do this so
by a we know this and b we know this a
b the square root of n is just the
calculation of b
and a right all right all right are you
still with me
yeah okay a as b
by so look at that let me look so square
root of n
equals b a plus
b divided by 2 a plus b
divided by 2 a plus b
okay divide it continue
continue so it's like that yeah yeah
yeah
so look let's do this define let's call
it square root right square root
and we call it we want to calculate n
but we need to use the a
yeah and let's define
a small error small error so if you want
to compare two numbers if
they're the same you can if
two floating numbers like you want to
compute the two floating number if they
are the same
i mean they are very close you can use
the abs
do you still remember abs
a minus b if it's smaller or equal
a very small number like 0.0001
then we can say a and b are equal right
because in computer
you cannot because of a computer the way
how computers represent
the floating numbers the best way to
compare the equity
is to use the abs do you still remember
your abs
abs look in mathematics you can do this
abs
minus three equals one
it's the distance between the value and
zero
three a equals one
eight yeah so basically abs is
you can say abs is x if if
x is bigger or equal to zero or minus x
if if x is smaller than zero okay
yes this is called a function fbs
okay so we use the abs to compare these
two numbers if they are floating numbers
like 0.5
2.5 if there are difference yeah
if the distance between them is smaller
than a number
we can say it's equal right okay so now
we can call this ebs epa error here
we put an e comma okay yeah
whatever e we can do by default value we
can say
one e minus five what does it mean one e
minus five
scientific number this is the way in
computer we represent
one e minus five is like zero point zero
zero zero zero
one okay so uh five actually
one two three four another side so five
zeros
yeah okay so that's the small number is
the same and
one in minus two one e minus two is what
zero point zero one okay yes
okay so p what's p p equals y
we want to calculate p n equals a
squared plus b
so what's b equals
n minus a squared
a times a okay or a squared square you
can use
double star yeah
so we have n a we have a b
okay yeah so look now we want to
calculate
x x y so x x will be equals let's try x
x is the x is the the number we want to
calculate
right is best yeah x equals a
plus b divided by
let's do it divided by a okay yeah it's
2a but actually
i'll show you why it we should put a
here
so look why why abs
x times x yeah x times x
minus which number we are comparing
we want to find the distance between the
value of the target value
and n if it's bigger than e
right if the number if the x
if the target is not close enough right
yes yeah then what should we do
and you can imagine what should i return
here return what
i want to do something here but you tell
me what what's your life return
return there once you understand that
x return x yes
yeah because this x is the target okay
so now
so we need to
so we we need to replace this speed okay
so let's say
t will be equals x okay let's save this
value
and then another and then and when we
need to calculate these
um this new new value of the
of that of the t value yeah so what does
it equal
what is
plus b divided by
t x
and and t will be
will be one you guess so y plus b
divided by x now i actually realize the
problem with that is that
look this t is x so x
is that it it's actually one a
this is one a actually we want another
a plus t right so look because look
a this a will be a and then plus a right
so plus a a plus that and this thing
this thing is the new look a plus b
divided by a plus a plus b divided by 2a
i i
split it into a plus a right so what i'm
doing is
a plus b divided by a plus t so this
t thing is this new new iteration yeah
so it will be t and then i need to
substitute it with what
x well so look x so uh
t equals x look t the first iteration is
t
equals x right right because this is the
value
we guess but it's not close enough but
we we plug it
into these then will be
a the the first iteration will be a plus
a that'll be 2a right yes look
it's 2a right so is that enough
is not enough
yes i think so yes yes i think so so
so look this is the way we iterative to
computer
but a computer
compute the square root based on this
equation right yeah
okay okay so now
and in order to calculate the square
root of 150
you need to pass the value of a as well
right how do we pass
how do we calculate the evaluate
the integer bar i mean it's just in
a b square and if it's smaller than x
so if we just the integral integer part
of it
so this is actually this is the way to
show how you calculate it but
in practically it's not it's not fast
enough because if you want to get the
value of a you need to call this square
root function
and if you want to use this square root
function what why would you do this
because it's way slower right but um and
this is the way to calculate these uh
how do you call this kind of fraction
can conserve executive fraction right
yeah
consecutive fraction yeah do you
understand this constructive here
it's like let's try this okay a
is 12 b is six yeah
so square root of 150
equals what 12 squared
plus 6 divided by
24 plus 6 divided by
24 right yeah and you can keep doing
that
ok let's do this bit okay
let's do this pin so 12 plus 6 divided
by 24 plus
this is a quarter yeah
a quarter all right so what's this six
four ninety six plus one right
and six correct so if
i i i put it that way so that would be
97 24 plus
12 right yeah so what's this number
that's right uh let's do this okay
24 divided by 97 okay 24
divided by 97. what is what does equal
i guess look there's a zero yeah so
that's
yellow point
two right yeah it can't be three yeah
two four
one nine yeah six
four and then one
five no 4
38 4 2
and then 7
and more let's see so we have a
very close number is 12 12.24 okay
yeah uh
so let's let's square this number okay
let's use computer to spray let's see
what's what does it equal okay
okay so let's see
square they can't see it that's okay
squares
12.24 square too so it's
is 149.8 right
149.8 so look it's very close to 150
right
yeah so this is how we approach this if
we keep doing this
look if we keep doing this if we we say
square equals 12 plus 6 divided by 24
plus 6 divided by 24 plus 16 divided by
yeah if we keep doing this
yeah yeah yeah so do you get it yeah
yeah what do you call this continuous
fraction right
okay so um okay so
so can you tell me one cent what what's
one thing you learned from today
yeah okay so one is missing here can you
tell me what is that return x
return x okay what is that x yes
yes yeah okay so how about this i
divided it okay can you write it down
what's what's b b
[Music]
what's b what's b equals
n p equals one
minus a squared a squared a times
a yeah a times a a times a
a times a you can write this a times
times two yeah alright another way of
doing it
you can use the power function power a
two these three things the same a times
a
a times times two yeah or power a two
power function is a square okay okay so
today good job today
good job good job okay
you need to say thank you and see you
bye and see
you tomorrow okay bye