hello everyone hello ryan
hello hello are you all right yeah sit
down
please okay so today we're going to
talk about uh interesting problem which
is called
two summer
right so let's say given a number a
list okay so this problem is like that
given a list
like two four
six three one
okay seven okay seven one so given
a list of numbers and a target so this
is the
numbers okay let's call it lumps
lumps terrible writing anyway so then
there's a target
target and it's ten
no so yeah exactly so our target is to
check
if there are any two numbers any two
numbers
yeah in this given num
given list if they sum up to 10
yeah if it's if it is you just return
true otherwise it returns four okay
that's a simple version so any thoughts
any thoughts how do we do it that
i know so can you explain to me how
would you
do this how would you check if now look
this is a simple one because
we got this four and six plus to ten
right
so how do we how do we uh so what's your
general approach to solve this kind of
problem
ryan any thoughts
so how do you know it's uh that
how do you know given a list of numbers
and a target
how do you tell computer to return true
or false
eric eric how do you how do you do it
you just look for the numbers
yeah how
or you try different i mean you
search you enumerate all pairs
and then to see if we sum up to the
topic that's one approach
yes okay can we can we do this
like that okay can we do this sit down
otherwise
the audience will not see the whiteboard
please i can do this
and there was a lungs
and there's a turkey let's just call it
tea okay yeah
so we can look we can iterate all the
numbers right
yes we need to say t equals target
that's okay we just protect t so we all
can do it
let's say we first get a length equals
equal uh let's call it uh maybe
uh size equals land
lung okay
so now we just need to check for four
right
that's one solution for i in
range
what range s z
and then we we iterate here
and then we iterate another one it was j
in range but now we start from
start from zero to i j another variable
so so i'll
teach you about that later so now we got
it so
basically let me
where's the red pen okay let's try
so here we've got the i yes
i will be pointing to the first
second third fourth and fifth and j
we're pointing to the star and
until but not equal to i okay so now
what happened
is i got the numbers i and number three
so if
that's the interesting part
num i plus
num z equals
t what do we do so we found a pair
i and j right because if i is here then
j is here
i is is here and j
is here so numbers i plus num z
equals what the target right now
what's with return return
we are written true or false right
return true allies return first
do you get it ryan
do you get it ryan yes
sit down please right
okay so anyway
yeah yeah yeah look look this one okay
let's do this let's in let's go through
this example
look s z equals nine which is one two
three four
five so sc will be equals to five right
right
right listen yeah awake listen please
look sc will be five right
sc will be five because the length is
five
there are five elements so for i in
range sg so what will happen
so i will become the value of 0
1 2 3 and 4. i'm right
yeah for z equals range i will happen
when i is 0 then j will be nothing right
when i is one j will be what
the range range one then
left j will be what zero so
what does that mean means that the i
what okay so i this i pointer will point
to
this this list this list okay when i is
pointing to
6 then j we're pointing from 2
4 yeah so the left side of i right
when i is pointing seven j will be
pointing to two four
six and one i is pointing to one j will
be pointing
two four six seven do you get it yes
and then every time we have two two
pointers then we just check
if these two numbers added up to the
target if it is we return true right
immediately otherwise after these two
loop
if we can't find any number then we
return first
got it yeah so ho
so you see if this i is five
and uh if the number is there there are
five elements and how many times the
computer needs to check
five now when we look at this is one
time
this is two times and then
two so that would be that's okay that's
okay
so that will be around five
times five divided by two approximately
all right
right yes because one eye is pointing
here and then it needs to check one two
three four
yeah twenty times yes and it must be yes
12 yeah something like that so you can
imagine when this n
goes to very large it needs to be
approximately
a square n square divided by 2 right
because
it's when i is somewhere
it only goes to half of this eye okay so
it's not very efficient so how can we
improve it
how can we improve it this is one method
okay
so how about we use a
dictionary do you remember this
dictionary
okay yeah this
what do we call it curly brace yeah a
notebook oh remember the notebook
yeah yeah so
the uh the idea is we we go through once
alright look we go through these numbers
and then we put it in the notebook right
yeah yes and once we find it
if the target minus current number is in
the notebook so what happened
look i teach you i have a notebook right
i have no book
nope
yeah this is the notebook okay and
something like that maybe
maybe just just like that okay so look
the first number we're going
visiting the number first number is two
right
then the top is 10 right yes
so let's see if 10 minus 2 what what's
the
number eight hey if a is in the notebook
no okay so we continue but we put a two
here right in the notebook
we're gonna go to the sorry why because
we
we seen this number so we put it in the
notebook so we know it's there
yeah okay so now four is
is is 10 minus 4
6 is 6 in a notebook
no we haven't we haven't put it in the
notebook yet
we haven't put in notebook so now right
so what
i'll put as far there right we visit
okay we come to six
is ten minus six four in a notebook
yeah yes yeah yes we found the answer
look how easy is that with the
notebook thing yeah but it might be a
lot yeah but
but for this we just going through once
right
and this notebook is very fast when you
put it there
it's there when you read it when you
check it
it's it's very fast yeah yeah how do you
check the number is in number you open
the notebook and see oh it's there right
right yeah so how do we do this so this
is simple okay so look
how do we look we do we do it notebook
notebook
equals what curly brace
this represents the dictionary okay
adult book vision
dictionary is the what's dictionary
have you read the dictionary before yeah
we got one right now yeah so
look if you look at the table of
contents
right you will have this key and the
page right
you will have these keys yeah and the
so you can look it up so this notebook
is the same you have this key
and then you have this pair value right
right value key value pairs
so how do we do it
notebook oh in in fact you you can also
use
using the set remember we talked about
the set before
yes okay but it's quite similar okay so
notebook
goal is for i in
nums so what do we do look
if if
look if the target if target
minus minus
i is in the notebook right is a notebook
then we will have two right
ah then we need to do what we need to
put a notebook
we need to put i in the notebook how do
we do it notebook
i equals true right we just do it true
and then here we'll return first is it
simple
we're only using one four right i like
to
get it do you get it
are you sure okay so using the set is
quite
similar it's quite similar so we can
replace this with
with what we set we set
and then this is the same and these this
will be
we can do this notebook dot add
add one add one add what
set now add the number i yeah
okay and then this is return force right
you get it can we have a better solution
can we have a better solution
okay we can have another one look we can
i can teach you right
look this is another way yeah how about
how about how about look we saw this
number remember how do we sort it
so they make the numbers in order right
so in python we can use this
we can use lambs alright
when dot salt
okay that's it simple is that number
stop soft so leaf becomes
one two four six
seven all right eric
so when these two is sorting
then these numbers will become in order
yes
will become another when you do this all
right
right when you do this thought these
numbers will become in order
i would listen write a listener please
okay how about if i want to in the
reverse order
anyways why how we can do this we can
launch the sort and passing a key
called the reverse and
reverse equals true okay
reverse equals true and then it will be
in the reverse order okay
hey wait listen carefully please i'm
going to
test you later okay i just
looked down for like a second oh okay
and you haven't even thought anything
yeah so so
so look so now these numbers in order
that's a very interesting part and our
target is 10 right we are looking for
these 10
yeah these numbers in order so how do we
do it we have the left we point into the
to the smallest and we have a right we
point into the biggest
doesn't have to be involved yes that's
why i have i have sorted look the soft
yeah you don't need to be reverse then
will become the from largest to the
to the smallest so long story so
you would make the numbers array numbers
in order which is from the smallest to
the biggest
so now we left pointing to the smallest
number
right pointing to the biggest number
what's the
what's the sum of the numbers pointing
at
both eight we're done so if a smaller
than ten
yeah yes smaller than ten okay we're
looking for the
any two numbers adding up to ten so so
tell me
should i move the left to the right or
the right to the left
the left to the right why is that
why is that because we why is that
connected yeah
we need to move to the left to the right
why
because we need to make it bigger
[Music]
the right side only the left left
moving to the right will become bigger
right so yeah that's
great that's genius yes good good job
ryan do you get it yeah okay so now
we're moving to the
right so now what's the sum nine
nine is nine smaller than ten yeah so
what do we do
maybe move it again right so
fourth plus seven eleven eleven bigger
than ten so what do we do
[Music]
yeah because because you you can move to
the right because it moves to the right
then the sum will become bigger right we
want to reduce it
yeah so yeah and now four plus six
ten yeah we got it we found the answer
yeah so now return true
okay so how do we do it look i
actually look if you say if you look you
can write to
if i equal zero okay say equals
length lambda
minus 1 then you can write it in one
line yeah
i i j equals zero
length lungs okay numbs minus one
and what do we do why why they are no
meeting in the middle right
why the i and j no meeting in the middle
right
yes if glams
i plus num j
is is target then we return to right
yeah we found the target yeah am i
yes then okay so now i write it this way
choose more space here come come here
okay
then we need to check again if
nam
i plus num j if it's bigger than 10 what
do we do
what do we do here you will say right
[Music]
write me to the left so right minus
equals one right it means decrement yeah
and ask what should we do
no yes no yeah
well done wow that's amazing brilliant
okay and then at the end we return what
did he just say which one falls yes we
are the only thing first
so do you get it which way which one you
do you like the best
the shortest one the shortest one okay
how about you implement one approach
in your computer ryan eric i help you
okay
yes okay eric you say it's easy go i
i just introduced three methods yeah
okay one
last thing can you say bye bye to the
video please that's your happy time
ryan bye bye
bye okay
no no no no