hello hello what happened today hello
everybody hello ryan
how are you today yeah you seem not
quite
upbeat okay so remember we talk about
we talk about the happy numbers yeah can
you remind me what's happened numbers
uh you just square out the digits and
then until you get one
i need to go if it's okay one it's a
happy number yeah yeah
okay so today we're going to talk about
another number called ugly number
if a number has prime factors of two
three and five only they're actually for
example like
two three five four yeah yeah a
sixteen it has only two then it's
ugly 3
9 27 yeah i mean these are ugly
oh 5 25 125
but you also 6 is also ugly right
because 6
equals 2 times 3 and it's ugly
yeah only has 2 3 or 5 also so for
example like 30
30 equals 2 times 3 times 5
okay ugly yeah but if if
if that is like
so look if 210 is not big why
because 2 times 3 times 5 times 7
it has 7 which is
which is not included in the list right
so it's not ugly okay
so if a number is prime factors
it factors if you can express an integer
as 2 times a times 3 times b
times 5 times c yeah
if it is in this format it's an ugly
number a could be
bigger or zero equal to zero and b
also
yeah for example like um 20 is that the
other number
it's 2 to the power of 2 2 times 2
times 5 yes because it only has 2 and 5
right
okay let's see 36 is the
ugly number
look we can try with the smallest two
right two
times two times
three times three yeah it has only two
and three right
so it's ugly okay let's see another one
uh 49 uh
yes no because seven have seven
it's not right yeah yes
yes you do you have to decide is it just
using the same number yeah so if you're
finding the factors
you can actually any num any integer you
can express as these kind of
uh expressed as the prime these are
prime numbers yes
yeah any integer you can express as
prime numbers
uh you know 7d and the next prime number
is 11
e right yeah so it could be
this is multiplier it could be x any
integer could be expressed as
the prime numbers powers comes together
right
for example given a number like uh
you you say remember
what any number
why just pick a number come on
ryan um
109. 109. okay is that prime number
oh this number is too difficult right
pick another one
i don't know if it's a point number if
it's a point number then it's 109
to the power of one right obviously
right yes
okay ugly it's not
because because it's it doesn't have
two three five only if it's two three
five then it's an ugly number okay
it has one of those or mixed
you know it doesn't have anything else
right
okay so any number pick a smaller number
are you smaller number 25 25
5 times 5 okay so it's 5 to the power of
2 right look
this is the point number yeah oh any
number again
7 7 is a prime number yeah 7.
like another one 28 okay 28
28 is 2 to the power of 2 yeah this is a
good example times 7 to the power of 1
right this is point number this is my
number you see you can express as the
point numbers to the power terms
together
and this has factored two and seven so
this is not an argument because it has
seven
okay yes got it
so how can we check if the number is the
point number
uh what's the strategy what's the
statute
any strategies how we check if the
paranormal is wow
it has to be old
it has to be odd or
finally or the cell phone too
okay but and then what
wait uh no that's anything
and i don't know how to explain
okay that's fine so how about we we try
to divide the two three and five
right yeah as much as we can
until we can't and then if the remaining
integer
is one it's a algorithm right
if it's not one it's not arguable all
right
yes look for example 28
we divided by 2 14 divided by 2
7. can we divide by 3 now can we divide
by 5 no
and then the remaining is not a one then
it's not our
number how about 25 divide count divided
by two convergence
can i divide by five yes and connect
again divided by five yeah
and then it's one it's for every number
yeah
yeah you see this one sorry
so because we are checking if the number
has the only
two three five these three prime
factors so we can divide keep dividing
it
right yes because we are looking for
this
2 to the power of a times 3 to the power
of b
times c 5 to the power c yeah if it's a
point if it's a ugly number
it should be least yeah n equals that
so look look
and we can times something else
something like a
big a right so look
look because look if we divide keep
dividing by two
by dividing by three by dividing five
and if the remaining is one it's a prime
it's a ugly number if it's not right if
this is seven
or eleven it's not a
argument i'm right do you get it
oh yeah yeah yeah okay so
you tell me what to do okay if i agree
i'll go so look if
n is smaller or equal to zero would
return one
return false right because it's not uh
number yeah zero is not right my
negative is not
okay so look we can do this wire
n can be divided by 2 yeah 10
divided by 2 this is n can be divided by
2.
then we what do what do we do we keep
dividing by two right yeah
so and what are we
and dividing by two
equal one two okay and then wire
and three
[Music]
is
we can't divide it then we need to check
if n equals
to what length is rv number one
yeah return n equal equal one yeah
yeah so look this is the kind of
duplicate we can do this
in one a much simpler way so
four you have to say look looks p
in in what in two three five yeah
this is at least yes yes yes
yeah where's people
p will be two three five so this is the
iterative yeah
because this is a list for p in this
this it means the p
will be equal to two to this p will be
equal to three
do this p will be equal to five to this
yeah this is the loop okay
yeah n bigger than one
and n
can be divided by p yeah and then
can you tell me what should i do here
and what
if it can be divided by p and what
should i do
i divided by t and divide it equals
p yeah and then that's it and then
return and
equals one yeah got it okay so
that's it today will be just a simple
mess okay so
any questions before i erase any of them
and then
and then yeah okay so close your eyes
i'm going to eat where is
it okay
okay something yeah why or something
here come on
why okay
probably why yes okay
why why or what why we need to check if
why we can divide it by p y p will be
two
three and five p no
no why uh n will be equal to
bigger than one one bigger than one
because if it's one
if it's less than one we don't need to
continue to check
right n bigger than one
and
[Music]
and what we're checking if this number n
can be divided by p
right so how do we do if
n can be divided by p if
y no no no no if
and why n equals one and one
y n can be divided by p well how do you
check if it can be divided by p
how do you check the remainders
now this is to divide it but what we
want to check if we can
wonder modulus yes
yes we are done
it that's that's it that's it for today
so good job today
can you see say bye to people bye
good job