hey hello hello
how are you today everything ryan good
good
okay so today we talk about um
checking if two trees have similar
leaves so for example like these three
one
two three four
five and then these three
one four
two three
four uh
okay maybe i i will do this
another one seven
and then
four seven
uh okay so there's a four here okay so
these will be
yeah just get rid of it okay so now
look the leaves what what are the leaves
of this binary tree
one two three four leaves these
three four seven three four seven three
four seven
what what are the leaves of this binary
three four seven okay so we return
two if there are leaves in the left to
the from left to the right order is
three four seven okay so if i have
another one like a
then this will return first because the
eight is also the leaf
okay so these are not equal so do you
understand the problem
ryan do you understand the problem right
you understand the problem yeah so any
ideas
any sauce yes check the leaves
yeah well we're done what we chuck just
chicken leaves
and how do we check the leaves
how do we how do we first of all how do
we check if the nut is a leaf
it has no children well yes
exactly it has no children if a note has
no children it's a leaf
all right yeah just remember the tree is
upside down in computer yeah
this is the loot but in the real life
the root is down
and the leaves yeah growing upwards but
in computers
the leaf the tree is growing downwards
okay so that's the dude
that's the leaves that's the branch
that's the trunk yeah
trunk trunk yeah trunks
okay so look you mentioned something
very important is
how we checking the leaf is that we
check even now has no does it have an
uh uh and in children if it doesn't have
any children so leave now
but another thing to
see here is that we need to
we need to record the
leaf notes from the left to right so
do you remember which uh how how are we
traveling the trees
usually which kind of um
breakfast professors yes exactly this is
travel from
level to level yeah and another one
compared to
where down yeah definitely search okay
okay so which one do you think is better
suited in this case why is that
yes you are right definitely search so
you will go
left yeah as as deep as we want and
until we meet the leaf node now we know
we
win the develop right and then we go
back
we find four yeah go back up and seven
yeah
this is the travel yeah and then this is
some so we first of all we need a
function
to travel a tree from the root and then
we record the leaves
as we do the traveling therefore search
right
and at last we just need to compare if
the both
definitions produce the same sequence
all right
yes okay let's write it we're done we're
done
it's the default search okay so first of
all we need to check
uh let's say same leaf okay same leaf
leaves plural yeah send this and then
let's do this a and b yeah so there are
two notes
two trees a and b okay two new blues
so we again we can have another another
function inside
okay look we call it that first search
ah yeah and then let's call it a root
and then can you tell me what i'm
missing
how many columns one how many columns
one two okay so look
if root yeah you know this before yeah
it's long yeah then we should return
we want to return an empty bracket which
is empty list
i'll tell you what why is empty this
okay so if it's not
any link let's try it yes it doesn't
have any leaves
empty so basically this function will
return
a list of leaves in the order right
and if it's non it means there's no
leaves in the bucket
you can say it's a bucket yeah [ __ ]
at least yeah
okay then if loot
dot left is noun
and
dot right is num
so what does it mean here what does this
mean
if looter left if this boot blue dot
left
is num and no right it's not what does
it mean
it's a leaf no yeah we're done if we
don't need to know then we
can yeah remember if it's
leave no we need to return a bucket with
a leaf with current leave
yeah yeah so this bracket
but loot loo value
yeah does it make sense yeah yeah
okay then now now we recursively we just
need to return
therefore search blue dot
left plus
different search one let me guess
we are detaining the left and the right
so what was it
right or right yeah
so does it make sense if if it's not a
leaf now
if this if this is not leaf load yeah
so the final sequence will be the leaf
nuts in this bucket
in this tree plus the definite of on the
right tree
so put it together all right yeah let's
go to the first stage
and here if we want to compare if two
are the same so
return y can you can you guess
we have this function so therefore
search a or this is the
leaf order of the tree a
we want to compare it to the same as the
definition of loot
another tree so what is what should i
write here
something about b yes something about b
what what about b
that's a search b huh yeah and that's
what search b
so what should i put here equal
how many equals two yes well done wow be
confident come on you're right
yeah it's too too confident it doesn't
make sense
so look this function we define to
return
the to previously we have 1 3 4 yeah
yeah 134 so one maybe
uh three uh maybe here
three four yeah yeah yes so these return
one three four yeah
yeah and then another three different
different structure but
also return once before then we compare
if it's present
so at least look if a load isn't lung
return an empty bucket with no leaves
yeah because
if it's nothing it's air it's not a leaf
if no
left is numb and neutral rudolph is now
it means that the current leaf
cardinal is a different note then great
we just return a bucket with itself
otherwise this is not a leaf note right
and then we just need to recursively
travel on the left tree and the right
tree
because the left of tree and red we know
how to solve it we already
know it and then we after we get a
result we put it together
yeah so dfs root on left is one right
yeah and then dfs
do the right is three and four so plus
three and four so this is at least yeah
a bucket with the list one plus a
bucket with this three and four what
does it equal
a bucket with one three four yeah
got it yes whether what's the term
complexity
[Music]
guess if if there are n number of nodes
in the root a
and m number of nodes in the root b so
what's the term complexity
yeah we're done and what's the space
complexity let's say yeah
yeah so why is it oh n plus n because we
need to travel
the the all the end nodes in the in
one tree and the m nodes in another tree
yes
yes okay yes okay close your eyes
close your eyes hmm
i'm going to erase this
right come on return something yeah if
you come along is the leaf node what
will return if current this is the
the current is the leaf now and then
remember we want to return the bucket
with the current node
what does that mean return it just lay
it down return
okay return but yeah we're down if we
current note is the leaf node
yeah yeah i don't know is knee flow
right are you okay and bracket
bracket if we can't know it's the leaf
no like
one yeah and we want to return the leaf
node which is one
yeah so what do we want to put inside
the value of the node so what's the low
dot value yeah yeah
yeah you can do it look loose already
and then we're done yes that's what we
want okay
any any questions no okay so let's
say bye bye to people i see you tomorrow
blah blah blah
blah blah blah okay bye-bye see you
tomorrow