go hello hello hello mr
mr ryan how are you today good good
okay so today we uh talk about
the breakfast search yes remember the
breakfast
yeah you said you feel hungry by hearing
his name breakfast such breads with
bfs okay
breath versus so we're going to use the
breakfast search to
compute the left side of a binary tree
okay
left side so for example one two
three four five
on the left side so you're standing like
like
that's you okay that's you that's me
that's
that's you yes okay
what's your thing inside that okay
let's see looking from the left to the
right and then what you see is that
three hair
yeah that is one two and four yeah you
can't see
three and five yeah because that's
blocked okay so base
we can use the brush massager oh of
course we can also use the def
search dfs we which we will talk about
tomorrow okay
so you're standing on the left and
you're looking into
the right yeah then this is the
the first note you're going to see so
you we're going to use the preference
search okay
so how do we use the breakfast search
any idea
any idea so every time we expand the
notes in
the queue yeah yeah we use the queue to
store the nodes
in stolen notes
in in what in the final three yeah yeah
okay so remember look this is one
two how we do this okay
okay so look i have a q yeah i have a q
here first of all i put the one in yeah
yeah
okay okay let's see and then i i have
i have a i want to you know the dq
yeah dq the kill means
to take one element from the head of the
kill yeah
to take the element from the queue so
which is the head yeah
and the other the other operation is
called enqueue
which is the opposite so put push an
element to the
back of the queue yeah whether dq and
enqueue
so first of all we incur root and then
now
okay then let's go while loop why do i
yeah why the q
is not empty yeah y q is not empty this
is the
basic it's not empty
so what do we do we take we we dq we
take this one out yeah
yes we take this one now and
and we push its kids all all the kids
of it so which is
two and three okay yeah so
because we push uh we take a for one
hour and then we visit
now yeah when we visit the no we need to
check
if if it's the first time of this level
so when we
eq it when we decrease we take basically
take all elements of the queue
because they belong to the same level
which is level one okay and then i push
two and three
and now next time how many elements are
in the queue
two right yeah yeah no
two so these two elements belongs to the
same level yeah
i'm right yes so i take a two
i take the two and i put put a result
okay let's without one and
these are two okay but and i push like
in kill of its kids nothing right it
doesn't have any kids okay
yes yeah and i take the three
what's which
uh what kids does it have four and five
so i take it out
and push four inside there okay okay
okay then again now we look at this four
and five
belongs to some level you see yeah and i
i need to in this loop i need to
expand these two kids but it doesn't
have any look by the fall
the first time so i put it put it in the
ball
okay and that's it and take it for four
i'll take the fire out let's see
so there's one four one two four okay
what's the time complexity
leaflet and elements in the financing
what's the space complexity
uh we call it left left left view
and then loop and what's missing here
okay so look if first of all we need to
check if the root is empty or all right
if loot is numb we can walk
we can what if loot is now
what we're going to return return
a list of empty things yeah at least
empty this it means that a list
but has no elements in it okay
now remember we talked about
dq d-e-q-u-e what was that
q equals t e q u e what's this
p e q u e what's that
uh double k double ndq yeah
we can push and pop from the both sides
and now we need to push
we need to first of all initialize the
double ndq with only one anime in it
which is what
the first boot okay so but it takes the
parameter of this so put up
put a load in the list yeah basically
this parameter means that
this could should be enumerated
to be iterable so the loop is the should
be put
inside a list now how do we check if the
queue
has no has uh has any one at least one
element in it
wire why what
the lens how do we check the lens
lens yeah this is basically the same
segment
bigger than what
zero yeah okay
so now uh okay i forgot this i need to
put this answer here in the list
yeah and this is a list there okay so
now
now what now what i i say this
size yeah current element now the
current elements
s z equals length key here so this
basically this is the lens
so it means that they are s z
notes in the q right and they belong to
the same level do you get it
yeah so now i want to push the first one
in the in the
result so answer dot append
yeah open one
open one the first element wait
no no no the first first element in the
queue
which is q dot
q zero only bracket zero okay you can
use this index yeah so means the first
element okay so which is the left side
yeah
no less more note all right let me know
look i can do this one
two three okay okay four five
so look length skill now is one right
look
yeah and sz is one right
all right and answer put q0 which is one
right yes now i need to go through
this for i in
range actually
because we're not using the io we can
use underscore means that we don't care
yeah for we just want to iterate
as z times because they are s z
s z number of elements
in the in the queue and then we need to
pop it right pop it so look current
equals q
dot pop pop
left right pop left
and then we need to push it on top
easier if current got left
we push it to the qx a pen
and can you write the next one
what's next one b
yeah if this one
[Music]
what's missing here we need to return
what what's missing here
we're done wow yes we're done this is
the only thing
yeah so good a little bit wobbly yeah
because
you don't you know yeah it's just to
save time so this is the basic
structure of breakfast surgery
one step first step create a cure
with the root the first element and then
wire loop yeah you've seen this a lot of
times when we talk about breakfast
search
why why we check if there are elements
in the queue
yeah and then we can take this is the
number of
elements in the current queue right and
we visit we dequeue it
we will kill it which one is 2dq
to take element out of the queue which
one which which statement says that i
want to take our other one anime out of
the game
[Music]
which one this one this one this one
which one
take it take it out what is it what is
what is the operation of take it off
which one which one is to push into it
which operation here
pop left yes pop left look pop left i
want to take a q
take an element out of q and then which
one is to push it into the end
second and the third yeah because you
need to push you need to push the two
and three the left try and
right right any end of the key yeah so
when you push
the element you push in out at the end
of q when you take
element from the key you take it from
the beginning of the game
first thing what
first out yeah first thing like a queue
yeah
like like you right like you you are
look
this is uh this is the shop okay
this is a shop okay and then when the
people come
they join at the end of the queue yeah
but when these people get served
it serves from the beginning of q that
doesn't make sense yes
so first thing first off okay so this is
basically the data structure of that
so if i want to
to change it to right y view
so what should we do there's only one
thing you need to change look
if i want to change this agreement to
standing from the right hand side
and looking this way so you return 1 2 5
instead of 1 2 4.
so which one which one
you need to change make a guess
so how do you deal with this problem now
this this code this bit of code
a calculator of the left side area one
three one two four
now with a little bit change then
i will return right right view so
from the right hand side so looking this
way will be one three four
okay so which one which one deal with
appending the result into the answer
and instead of so any idea how to
yeah yeah well
which one deal with the answers so
instead of pushing two i want to push
three instead of pushing four i want to
push
where where is ansa come on where's
answer the answer is looking at you
wait we can answer which bit is dealing
with
appending the element into the answer
yes what are we looking for so instead
of pushing the first element i want to
push what
the second no no no no the last number
yeah because if there are
more elements there i want to push it a
lot yes yeah so
which q 0 is the first one and q what is
the last one
q q 1 minus what
one we're done yeah that's that's the
thing so you if you change this to minus
1 then you'll be right have
you yeah does it make sense yeah it
makes sense yes
we're done with them bye wait wait wait
no
no you need to say thank you and see you
tomorrow every time okay
thank you