hello mr
mr ryan how are you today good good okay
so
today we'll talk about some mathematics
no coding just mathematics okay so the
the combination and permutation so can
you tell me
which word you understand permutation
p e r permutation
and combination
i think combination is putting things
together
yeah yeah it has that meaning too but in
mathematics it means something different
combination
combining that's right a permutation
the different order of these
elements for example permutation if they
are one
two three so there are six permutations
no no no look permutation so different
orders
right right don't pull my thing okay
right look
one two three one three two
two one three two three one three one
two three two one you see so permutation
is the number of in the way in different
orders yeah
yeah so different all possibilities of
different orders of using these three
elements yes yeah and
combination is like there are three
numbers
how many ways to pick two
two of them the order does not match one
two is equals to one
so combination is that okay do you get
it
so how many ways if i want to pick two
out of these three elements how many
ways
one two one three three
two three we are done okay so this is a
combination
so so let's say let's define two symbols
okay
p for permutation c for combination
yeah p and m
and c and n so c and m
is like i if they are n items
n equals 3 i want to pick 2
m equals 2 so now how many ways it would
be c
3 2 okay yes this is the function we
defined yeah
yeah and the same if it's p3 to what
does it mean
it means that three elements i want to
pick two
and permutate it so it will be
1 2 1 3 2
3 3 2 and 1
and no 1 2 two one
one three three one you see yeah
so first of all pick two and then
permutate it
yeah got it so
so um this
okay so for permutation p and
m when m
is equals to one what does it mean there
are n
items i want to pick one animal how many
orders will there be
one p one m equals one last three apples
and i want to pick one apple and
communicate it how many ways
how many other places three yes we're
done so p
and n when m equals one it means that e
equals
n right yeah does it make sense guess
okay so when p and m
when m equals n what is what does it
equal
so there are in items i want to see the
order of everything
like three and the other will be six
yeah we talked about this before the for
the first position how many choice
do we have three okay for the second
choice how many two choice how fast
complaints how many choice do we have
two and for the third one one so what's
this
six yeah i know what's this and
factorial yes
yeah got it does it make sense three
yeah okay
okay so another case when p and
m when when
m bigger than one and smaller than n
what does it equal
okay so let's send if there are three
elements three apples and i want to pick
two and then permutate it for the first
position okay three
for the first position how many how many
do we have how many choice
three for the second one how many choice
okay that's it so what does it equal
six yeah i know it means that equals
n times n minus one times
n minus two times y and
minus m plus one okay so it doesn't make
sense because when when these end
one is m equals n then that will be one
right
yes and then that'll be n factorial do
you get it yeah
so so these these yeah is equals to
n factorial divided by n minus
n factorial okay okay
okay so this is p so what
what's the com what's this what's the
relation between p
and c remember the c does not have order
combination
but p has order yeah all right
so c combination c and m
equals what equals p and m divided by 1.
can you guess look this is i want
this is n is the order but i won't i
don't want the order so divided by 1.
there are m items this is with order
this is dozen with orders
say divided by
look there are items and then all the
how many orders how many computational
and
and sector yeah and this is with
different orders this is we now so
what you write divided by actually
yeah yeah got it yeah so because this
doesn't have order yeah
this this one two three
is and i'll pick 2 you'll be 1 2 right
right
2 and 1 2 is the same as 2 1 in the c
in a combination but in a p this is
different order yeah
yeah then you have to divide by two
factorial yeah
yeah sorry least so c c
n m equals least divided by n factorial
so it's
n factorial divided by n factorial and
n minus l factorial all right yes
okay does it make sense yeah okay so
interesting so so this is the cmp and
today we're going to talk about
more importantly this is the c
combination because this is very
important right
they are um
they are four epochs
and i want to pick how many ways of
picking two
so you see yeah combination put two
apples the order does not match is c
for two yeah seven yeah yeah so what
does this equal
so how do we check so look this is
n yeah this is m yeah yeah so n
factorial divided by
n factorial and n minus n factorial
n bacteria is four factorial two
factorial
and four minus two two factorial so that
was like 4 times 3
times 2 times 1 divided by 2 times 1
divided times 2 times 1 right so 2 2
1 1 2 2 6.
yeah got it so there are six ways
yeah doesn't make sense yeah okay so
so look c and
m okay so c
n one equals one
how many ways is like an apples i want
to pick one at first how many ways are
there
n yeah it's the same as permutation
because there's only one right
yeah yeah and how about c and n
there are unapples i want to pick n
apples how many ways one
yeah obviously yeah okay so how about
c and m and
and c n n minus n
i think at least two what what which one
is bigger or they are equal
are they equal look
i show you there are six apples yeah
there are six apples
oh it doesn't look like a phone okay i
want to pick two it looks
like yeah i want to take two yeah yeah
yeah
i want to pick two so it's c six two
right
yeah every time i pick two is there a
solution for c4
yeah because two plus four equals 6 do
you get it
so every time i want to pick 2 i also
have a solution for
4 right does it make sense
so c and m and c n minus m what is it
which two are they equal yeah yeah it's
equal yeah
does that make sense yes
okay yes because look c and c64
i pick these two like it's the same
thing as i pick these four right
yes all right yeah every time you you
divide
into two and four you got the four
solution which is the same as the two
right
yeah solutions yeah doesn't make sense
okay so
this is one this is condition and
another another condition is
c and m so they are n items
they are an item yeah okay there are an
item look this is very interesting
there are an item there's seven items
yeah yeah they're in items
and does it mean that i want to
if i for the last item just look at the
last liner
and how many possibilities of last last
item i can pick or not pick
right yeah so when i pick it
so what's it what does it go when i take
it when i pick this item
yeah so i have n minus one items to pick
yeah from
oh i have n minus items pick two from
n minus item right yeah so i pick these
i pick this item and
how many items i need to pick and minus
one yeah
and minus one all right yes and
that's what by the way c and n c
and n you can write it as c and m okay
so n in a lower and then p
p and n is the same thing as p and
m okay so you place the first parameter
and then lower
at the corner right yeah it's the
notation cmn
so i pick this one so i have
i have n minus i one item right yes
and then i need to pick my my minus one
right yeah
okay so and how about if i don't pick
this one
if i don't pick this one
yeah so what does it go
so look
so it's equals to what
so look if if i don't pick at least one
i
i have n minus one items right but i
need to pick
m m items because i haven't picked
anything but i decided not to pick the
last one right
it doesn't make sense yeah um
right look this is very interesting this
is the equation
i want to pick an item from the i want
to pick m
items from n right and look at the last
item
if i decide to pick the last item how
many ways
how many solutions do i have i have n
minus
one item here and i have n minus one
because i already pick one here right
and if i decide not to pick this one i
have
n minus one item but i have to pick m
item because i haven't picked anything
yeah because i decide to skip this one
right
yeah so the total solution is c m m
equals c
n minus one uh c m minus one m minus one
and c
minus one and i'm right let's make sense
okay so what is it what does
look like i show you remember this one
yeah this one what does
this what's this
triangle well done
okay so look this item equals
this plus this yeah so f is it
equals the sum sum of the shooters yeah
yeah so look if this is n
rho is n and column is m c
and m here right yeah
equals c n minus 1 and minus 1 is this
item yeah
yeah plus c n
minus 1 m is this item
so do you get it this is pascal triangle
please okay so combination look
another one five what's this
ten ten i want it
by one yeah okay so this number
equals four plus six right so look
this is c n minus this is
n right and minus one
it's it's not this row yeah yeah right
and m m m
this item six yeah and minus one this
item
yeah got it okay so this is pascal
triangle so
yeah is it amazing yeah this is the way
how we calculate cnn
right okay and we can do it if we we
know this
we can do it recursively okay it will be
very easy yeah
look define c
and m column yeah yeah
let's say if m equal
one what is the return
an item i want to pick one how many ways
and yeah we know already yeah
if m equals n return one
[Music]
how many ways one one yeah got it
okay then if
okay so look because look c
and m equals c and n minus m yeah we
talk about laser when m is zero
what does it mean c n zero equals c and
n right so it's one right yes
yeah so look if m y n equals one
m equals n we can say o
or what m equals zero okay
column yeah written one yeah otherwise
return c
n minus one and minus one
plus c n minus 1 what
what and okay so that's it
that's the way to do it but look look
because these will be
expanded and there are lots of
calculations we can just do a magic
just every time we we can use a notebook
yeah remember we can use a notebook here
yeah and we can check if and m in
notebook when we return the value
and before we can already write it to
the notebook but
there's a better way you can do this at
lru cash this is a caching
and then let's say next size equals
none and in this way the computer will
catch the
values and then this is the perfect
solution to get it
you see look once we have this
formulation yeah we can translate into
python code easily right it doesn't make
sense yeah
yeah you see because look we just found
out that c n m equals c
n minus one what can you tell me
okay so can you tell me what's these
okay
these two can you feel it
and then look once we have this then we
can translate it
right this is the terminal condition
right terminal condition
once we have communication we can do it
calculate this
recursively right this is all the
cushion yeah because look the cushion
doesn't make sense yeah got it
okay so that's it for today
is it interesting why is it interesting
bye bye okay let's see that's it for
today
for today we talk about a combination of
communication and see you tomorrow okay
bye bye