hello hello hello mr eric mr ryan how
are you today good
good okay so today we'll talk about
finding the max product so what's
product
of three numbers in an array so product
is times together multiply
so next product
of three numbers
in array okay so for example like
and the numbers could be negative for
example like minus one
two three five so
the next three numbers will be four
numbers
yeah i know but you choose three numbers
and then times it together
i want you to compute the max product
it is 30. yeah we're done 2.35 yes
okay so and remember it could be
negative so for example it will be
minus 200 minus
a hundred so what's the arizona
so you pick minus 200 minus 100
double negative makes positive so 200
times 100 times 5 that's the max product
got it yes any questions
what can you use the same number twice
that's a good question no
we can't we you only pick one numbers
once okay so any thoughts and this
number these arrays
are not necessarily sorted you know
for now i just give it from from the
smallest to the
largest yeah so it's it's not necessary
sorry i will give you an
assorted list for example like 2
1 minus ten
three ten so what's the
next product
uh
[Music]
fifty fifty how do you come up with
fifty
ten times three times two then that's
fifty that's sixty isn't it
oh yeah yeah
okay okay so any idea how we start
solving this problem
ryan any sauce so let's sort them out
we're done so first of all we saw this
array okay
we saw for example this is salted
alright so first of all
okay so that look define max
product okay
okay so first of all we saw this number
so how do we solve it
[Music]
okay so when you do this it's sorting
from the smallest to the
largest is ascending order okay so
if you want to sort it in the reverse
order for example it would be
five three two minus one minus and minus
two hundred you have to
put a thing here called reverse
reverse yeah us equals true
so if you put that thing in here then
you start it from the largest to the
smallest okay
so after salting in another salting we
talked about a quick saw the merch saw
yeah
you still remember yeah quick so almost
so yeah
what's the time complexity of this
sorting
okay yeah we're done
okay so once we sorted how do we find
out the next three products
we go from the last
and then then go
back yeah twice okay so
you first of all you check these three
yeah yeah again
that's it how about you for this
negative look because it could be
negative yeah if they're too
negative yeah so basically you check
two yeah and you you check these two
plus
times this all right yeah so there are
only two possibilities yeah
could could it be choosing three numbers
here no
right because if you if you choose two
from the list
yeah the best case is these two are
negative
and then this is positive right but if
you could choose a positive why not
choose
these big largest positive
do you see the problem yes only so these
the maximum of these three numbers and
these two numbers and these is the
answer
yeah you could choose how about if i
choose one
what numbers here if i choose one number
this could be negative right
yes if it's negative then the result is
negative
obviously that's not not let's not do it
by a minute
okay okay okay so now let's find um
so how do we do this look let's
return yeah you just tell me return max
max what numbs
what's this minus one yeah yeah tons
what's this
[Music]
what was this i'm going to compare with
space so
[Music]
yellow yeah times what's this
noun is what
minus one okay so so look
do you understand what's the complexity
yeah we're done because this is constant
yeah this is constant and
it's this whole thing is dominated by
this uh
sorting aggregate so one more time okay
so the maximum three products could be
only
if it is negative because we're sorting
the array
then that you'll be from the negative
possibly to the largest after the
positive so the
the next three product could be the
biggest three numbers yeah or the
smallest two numbers because
they may carry the negative sign and
when it comes together the negative
will become positive yeah but uh because
there's three numbers so we need one
more number so what
if these two numbers make positive and i
need one more number i
i could better choose the largest one
yeah which is this side
all right yeah because i choose this
list obviously not optimal i can choose
this
yes got it okay so that's it bye
bye bye bye
bye