ready steady go hello
okay hello mr eric mr ryan how are you
today
good okay so today we talk about
confusing number yeah you're right
confusing number
so what's confusing uh misunderstanding
yeah mr understanding okay so so what
are the confusing first of all
look look these numbers 1 0
6 9 8
what's the comment what are the comments
of these numbers
but not 2 3 4
5 7 yeah
so what's the difference between this
group of number and this school for now
no i mean these numbers belongs to
something and these numbers are on
other you know different group can you
make can you find the difference
uh that's the same thing similar thing
same police and
same police think about it
it has to be something to do with if you
can't you can turn the numbers
around
okay and in this group these two these
three are belongs to the same
but not these two
make a guess that's weird
whatever yeah if you look numbers
upside down what happened
if you look at the numbers upside down
so what
what which one still be the same eight
very one we're down but six nine will
become 96 yes
but how about you look the numbers
upside down
it doesn't make sense right this number
doesn't matter okay so that
that's the difference so for all those
five numbers
you can look it upside down it will
become a different number
but at least confusing digit i would say
please are invalid numbers so a number
is if it's a confusing number if
it's if you look it upside down
it's a valid number right like 89 if you
look it upside down you become
86 68 68 yes
what look you're looking this way 60
yeah yeah
you have to it's like these are 10
around 180 degrees right
so look if you turn around it's still a
very number
and it's not the same as origin number
it's a confusion number
so look if it's one i'm not confusing
i'm an understanding number look if you
want
turn around what will happen it is tier
one right
and then this is not confusing okay and
how about this
23 23
when you make turn around it comes like
five no no no it's invalid because
one three and two turn around it doesn't
make sense it's not red number so this
is not confusing
also to sum up a confusing number is
when you look it up right now it's still
a ready number but it's different than
the original number like we call it
confusing okay
confusing yeah does it make sense
yes yes so how are we doing this
default definitely so first of all we
need the functions to tell if the number
can be looked
up strong upside down right and if we
can
now we can turn it if not we can turn
back to something like minus one right
all right okay i'm not a confused
maybe maybe just just make it just say
10 okay
10 x
all right okay y if you should be
confusing number
wait this is the hyper function we're
going to make okay if
if x equals 1 or
x equals 0 or x
equals a what should we return what
if x equals 1 or x equals 0 or x equals
a because
x yeah we're done because when you look
upside down it's the same yeah
yeah okay so if x equals
six what will be ten
nine we're done and if x equals nine
six
we return a minus one to say it's in
value yeah if it's all
other numbers like two three five seven
yeah and what what uh what whatever four
two three four five seven then three
here is
two three four five
seven yeah these five numbers will
determine minus one because it's invalid
i'm right
yes okay so now now we got this turn
okay
make sure we we we remember that and
then
define love so let's say if
uh confusing let's confusion we return
true or false okay
let's say n okay
okay so what we need this is the number
we need to take we need to
convert it into string to be able to
extract hcg
we can divide by 10 and get a remainder
yeah
yeah okay so let's do this let's do the
n
equal str
and so now we turn this number into a
string yeah start me streaming
man yeah okay now
now let's go let's confirm uh conver
stories these into uh
the new new com let's
uh store the upside down value in a
string into this okay
answer and then let's say four
i in n okay so now we are getting each
digit for example one
a nine okay one eight nine yeah yeah
i'll be
six okay one now let's say x
equals ten yeah yeah we're turning this
yeah
but this is this is uh accepting this
number so we need to convert it back
integer i
i so now look
if x equal equals minus one what should
we do
[Music]
pretend
this one a9 is bigger and yeah when we
do this strn
it becomes this smaller lowercase and
you become a string yeah
and then we're going to do this for i in
n then we get each
each digit will be 1 a
9 yeah and then we pass it into these
because then we need to convert this
string to numbers
yeah using this in function yeah in the
function
and then if it returns minus one then we
can make it
yeah nan alternatively
yeah alternating to you if we as we
changing this to
accepting string then we can do this
look we need to put this chord yeah
all right look if we place okay and then
it will be
become easier right yeah because
everything is in string yeah
okay yes and then now
we don't need to convert it to an
integer we just pass this i because it's
already integer
and if we add into minus one we put a
curve left because this is
string type return false otherwise
answer
equals x plus answer yeah so we put this
new number before
in the front so you will be opposite
yeah
and then after that return
answer equal or not equal
n what's your what's your input here
equal or not equal
if it's a valid number uh if it's a
confusing number it's
true equal or not equal
not equal yeah because it's confusing
yeah not equal
so does that make sense yes
yes what's the term complexity if there
are n numbers and digits in the
n something oh and yeah if if
n is the number of digits in there in a
string
number yeah okay so
uh what what's the time context
you always know i just told you well
yeah space complexity do we are we using
any space complex
space here
this could be a space yes we convert
into
string
we are using that yeah yeah okay so
um why
any questions yes or close your eyes i'm
going to
i'm going to i'm going to close your
eyes please
please
okay so stupid x
here and then here
yeah so what should we do here that's
definitely
a bracket yeah so what what were you
[Music]
i
bracket
you don't need an inner because i
already changed here okay x equals 10
x 10 i yeah
10 i that's it and then here what's this
what's this
what is what we are doing here we need
to answer
yeah yeah what we need to put them
we need to please x this is upside down
yeah when we upside down
we need to put it in the front right
yeah
so what do we do answer equals what
what are we doing here
this x thing if it's counting yeah
x squared x y minus
where's y equals equals we need to put
it a pen so what's the append
a pen
does it make sense you know you don't
understand it fully otherwise okay one
more time i'm going to erase some more
okay
but not here okay okay close your eyes
close this
that one or that one i'm not going to
tell you
okay so this [ __ ]
there are two lands come on we turn both
here
no i it wastes too long why you look
white in the last one yeah and then why
what happened x equals
minus one is upside down what the why
are we retaining force here what
happened
if x equals
equals minus one column i think
return false yeah okay not just look
look
if we do if you just put the return
first what happened
and then you just return first without
any further right
because this is very important right
yeah it only be ten fourths if
got it does it make sense yeah okay so
bye
bye bye bye bye
[Music]
bye we need to say see you tomorrow