[Applause]
okay so
first of all remind me what kind of
numbers have you learned
so far ugly number happy number sad
and confusing okay so happy number
what's happy number
uh if you just whatever did you until
you get one
yeah and what's the confusing number uh
it's when you turn it
upside down yeah it's still a number but
it's different
okay what's the and what was there
another one you talked about
number it only has the factors the
two three and five right yeah uh devices
okay so this perfect number is something
to do with the divisor as well so
for example 28 yeah is 28 a perfect
number
yes why is that because 2j is a divisor
1 2 4
7 14 okay but not 28 not including
excluding is there okay so what's the
divisor added together
what's this 3 7
10 28 yeah
it is
is it so this is the perfect number do
you get it it's divisor look at this
this what's divisor so this number
can be divided 28 divided by 1
28 28 2
yes so any
thoughts how we doing this any idea
how are we doing this say
we just why what are the numbers
so we iterate divided by 28.
then they must equal 28. so we check
yeah so first of all we need to go
through these numbers
yeah and to find out if it can be
devised
if it's a divisor if it's a divisor then
we add a number
yeah and then we finally check if this
number is
the itself is same yeah
is definitely not perfect sorry
apply number definitely not perfect
well done yeah because it cannot be
equal to yourself yeah
that's number cannot be a perfect number
of course it's it's not uh
it's one one is the perfect number yeah
two
no no uh no okay so one is a very
special case so
this one the perfect number maybe
it might be yes yes okay so zero is not
a perfect number right
yeah negative numbers not perfect number
yeah
okay so let's try this define
perfect perfect what's perfect
good very good yeah what's the opposite
of perfect
i don't know okay and yeah
okay if and smaller equals zero
return
okay so now we we sum this digit in
some number in s okay s first one zero
okay
so for i in
range range one start from one right
yeah the number is done from one number
so do we need to go above half
like if there is no no because 28
listen it's impossible to find a divisor
that is bigger than half of it right am
i right
any number like a hundred cannot be
divided by
some number more than 50 right yeah you
got it
so 60 this this n
divided by two by plus one yeah because
up to
this okay sorry what's missing here
you're not even looking how do you know
it's missing columns i
know i know every time okay so now
if if what if num
divided by i what's your apple here
if it can be divided so what what what
how do you
represent if we can be divided you put
it
in something evil and
what's this percentage what does that
mean
i think it's something like i didn't
know how to explain
modulus yeah and yeah
okay so now what should i do here what
should i do here
what should i do here we can something
s yeah s s one plus plus one
okay so we plus all the divisors yeah
yeah
we pass already and we turn
even though this number goes through
just half of it but it's still always
it's nino yeah
can we make it better can we make it
better do you notice something
do you notice something look look every
eric look
look this is 28 yeah 28
1 2
4 7 14 okay and possibly 28
here so what do you notice what do you
notice
two and fourteen four and seven
one and twenty eight so what does it
mean they all
times out together yes so if if i follow
a two
factor direction two yeah there must be
another factor which is 24
uh 28 divided by two all right yeah
if i find the four what does it mean i
also find 28
divided by four all right because look
if i find a divisor d you also find
something
n divided by d and you
yeah so what does it mean i don't need
to go through to half i only think i
only
need to go through my face i only need
to go through
the numbers when i
times i square is smaller than y
equals n right okay so look i
square smaller or equals m so what does
it mean
what does it mean it means i smaller
than square n
all right it's the same thing yeah yes
okay so look so it will be faster okay
so
let me write the code okay look
yeah this is the same okay so now
i still have s equals zero okay here
right right
to enter the uh to to solve the number
of the to store the sum
of the direct divisors devices
so now i will be equal to 1
first okay so now y
i times i
is smaller or equals n right yes
because now we're already we are
checking if i smaller right then what
should we do if
n divided by i can we divide it yeah
so now what should we do s plus equals i
now i found the divisor i yeah
so what's the other part what's the
other divisor i
i divided by that and divided by
i
look there's a very special case
like 16 yeah 16.
i found a four what's the other half
four yeah it's the same yeah yeah but
obviously you can only add one right
yeah do you get it because one when
the other n divided by i is also the
same you can only
add one right so here if
i times i not equals
not equals n right yeah all right
then i can edit x plus equals
n divided by i right yes
okay what you doing
and look and then i need to increment i
plus equals one
okay so hey
so now what should i return here because
i
have i and i also have n look because i
at the i
and i also added n so what does it mean
look wait we turn something look look
look we turn
x look look i equals 1 n is 24 a
yeah all right look i equals 1.
look look listen to me if n
28 modulus i equals 0 i 81 right and if
i
if 1 times 1 not equals 28 right it's
not equal right
so i also added 28 divided by 1 is 28 so
do you see
i also added one more n right
so i should i should check return
s minus s1
s minus n equals n right or s
equals n plus n is the same thing do you
see what why
this is i need to subtract subtract n
from s
do you get it why
i just told you why uh
why because what because
because what when i equals one
and i added one more here and
you see look at it
can you repeat uh i equals one
and then s as equals and divided by
i yeah so but then let's wear this n is
wrong and i need to substitute
n not if it's the if it's the sum equals
to n i need a perfect number to get it
yeah does it make sense do you see lace
coat
which part you don't understand
which part what's the time complexity
oh and
why because least i times i smaller than
n
so what does this mean i
square smaller equals n right
yeah so if i
square root of both sides array
so what does this become i square
i square square root is i right
yeah so i smaller than square root of n
right
yeah so if i is a hundred i only need to
iterate how many times
yeah square root of 100 is 10. so
previously i need to iterate how many
times
50. yeah so which is better 10.
obviously 10 times is better yes the
computer
needs 10 times compared to these
50 times if if this n is bigger like
if n is a thousand
no no no maybe 10 000. ten thousand yeah
if it's ten thousand
ten thousand okay so pretty much
the first method how many times
five thousand times yeah and
and this this this agreement how many
times
uh 100 100 you see
now it's almost 50 times
difference do you get it yeah so one n
gets bigger
this this equivalent is faster a lot
faster than that
when any smaller maybe no difference for
example like
150 compared to 10
yeah this is five times and now this
five thousand compared to a hundred this
is
50 times you see you see the difference
yes yes okay so now let me
let me you want to take another look
before i erase some of it eric and ryan
ryan you want to help right
okay eric you want to take a look uh
i don't know i don't know i don't know
just take a final look and let me erase
some of that okay
close your eyes on which one i think
it's gonna be the
bottom half right
okay okay now close
i think if i times i is
not equals to n what happens we need to
add it
as
what are we doing there we are
come home
yeah look we are adding right here we if
we find the four
and we are adding we need to add a seven
right yeah yeah you got it
okay okay that's it okay see you
tomorrow
bye bye bye bye