hello hello mr erwin hello
uh how are you today good okay so today
we're going to talk about a final
research tree again by what spine
research tree can you remind me
with someone else and finally search
tree with the nose so what what is the
tree about i mean
what kind of binary tree is a binary
surgery
a binding binary third tree on the left
side is
smaller than the adult and
the right side is bigger than
yellow then parents not at all yeah yeah
yeah you can say this is
the kids okay good job uh okay so like
like
that okay so so the left
is strictly smaller than the parents and
the right is
strictly larger than the parents okay
yes
okay so now this is one parent between
the street and another tree like
five one
yeah seven and eight
and then that'll be six okay so i give
you two primary search three
and then how about if i give i give you
a target like
nine or maybe maybe five okay let's say
five
so five talking is five so
can you tell me whether there are notes
in
i picked one note from each tree okay
pay attention it's one note from each
tree you can pick two from both three
okay one either tree you pick one from
either tree
and then you make some up to five four
one yeah we're done four one yeah
so do you get it yeah and if i tell you
a hundred t equals 100 you tell me four
okay yeah because you can't find any
number
any two numbers from people's trees
let's sum up to a hundred okay so
can we what's your thoughts about this
problem
how can we manage it
how can we do it for example like uh
five okay five yeah yeah so look
if i'm here i have two trees yeah point
here
so what's the sum of these two nine okay
and then i'm looking for five
am right so what does it mean
one of them go to the right
one let's go to the left here so these
could go to the left or this could go to
the left yeah
yeah all right so you you can search
these three underneath three these three
yeah
yeah another three for example i know
okay so zero yeah so basically
i i want they only put two possibilities
either
it's in these three and then this
structure the same problem yep
yeah or it will be in this tree
and then this three yeah so you either
pick one
root to go to the left yeah because we
want to
we want a smaller sum which is five all
right
but now we have what we have got is nine
all right
yeah so we want the smaller one so how
do we make a smaller one we pick
one of them there are two choices okay
pick one of them go to the left yeah
okay and if we are looking for
uh let's say eleven eight and three
four and seven okay yeah so look
so look four and five is smaller than
eleven so we have to move one of them to
the right because
it will be bigger right so it will be
seven
and these three these two will be set
and all
will be these three and then this
substrate do you get it
yeah yeah okay so now let's write this
code
we can use this uh recursion
strategy okay define
sum of bsts
let's do it a and b okay i want some
missing here
column okay okay and and
of course we have we need to have a
target t okay
if a is now
or b is now what does it mean
if one or three is empty you so we can't
pick two notes
right little force whether yes
okay now if a top value
plus dot value equals t
we found it
okay now we need to compare if a value
plus speed of value if it's smaller okay
if it's smaller than target yeah
if it's smaller than target we go to the
right
smaller than the target so we need to go
there two cases
so then we can say return yeah return
okay let's let's let's make this simple
okay without writing too much let's do
it let's make it f
f function right the function name f
function now we can do this f
move to the right so a top
right yeah and then b
t or f
a b dot right all right
do you understand this t yeah
does this make sense so you could be
only into
these two cases right yeah we don't need
to search for the left tree
because it will be smaller got it
yeah yeah yeah yeah and as
there is no b1 that will be a
top value plus speed of value is one
larger than t
right all right it's larger than c so
what's this what's here
return f
if it's larger then we want the smaller
ones
now what should i put here
well the smaller one left left
and then one b
dot do we need the o
no b b t because
because we either go uh
navigate to one of the sub trees that's
true we don't need to
navigate too right or there's another
cases or
f a
right no no no we go
look b a come on b
right b left yeah and t so
does it make sense yeah look look
again again
okay so if something is smaller it's
something smaller
it then we can call this function to go
to the left so
it will be this one and this one oh
oh what all this one
and this one together
doesn't make sense yeah
so because look because these two are
bigger so we want smaller so how can we
move smaller we move
this one to the left yeah
or all this one to the left but not both
all right maybe both but
but recursively we only deal with one at
a time
okay what's the term complexity
because in the worst case in the worst
case we need to find
exactly how you know how what's the
worst case what's the worst case i tell
you okay
for example it's false no you'll be like
that
will be a little bit like that
okay okay so oh like if this is
if this is one zero minus one
minus two one zero minus one minus two
if i tell you that i want uh a value
which
is sum up to minus four
okay so now one plus one smaller
yeah so i got this one yeah
one still soon
two is bigger than we need to go to the
left yeah say
that's smaller again
smaller smaller yeah and this doesn't
work out right or and then this one
zero yellow smaller smaller
looks smaller so so
oh minus three minus two
yeah minus two minus okay so wait
could in the worst case could be o a
times b
i was thinking because how many times
you're iterating
look one
one one it doesn't find it you only need
the smaller
one zero yeah
[Music]
still smaller still smaller still
smaller yeah
yeah oh there'll be one and this one
okay so it's smaller
it's smaller than smaller smaller
yeah smaller smaller smaller smaller
so actually it's r a times b in the
worst case
time b yes yeah
this makes sense in the worst case it's
a times o a times b
uh what's the space complexity
[Music]
or you you don't need the air so you
just return it just normally a little
bit
here it's the same because when you
return you can't go further
do you get it in a function when you
return for example in return
and the curl doesn't get executed
anymore if we fall into this branch
okay any questions
no any questions
no no questions okay