[Music]
[Applause]
so
today we are going to talk about
the concept of concept of dynamic
programming
i already know dynamics are you sure
yeah
it's one piano from instruments
it's about how loud
dynamic programming so what's dynamic
what's the dynamic what's the opposite
of dynamic
uh what's dynamic what does it mean
something like sound so
dynamic means you know and the opposite
will be static
static yeah static dynamic yeah dynamic
programming so it's very
it's not easy to understand what it
means from there from the
phone just look uh reading these two
words so if i give you one example yeah
so it's like the way we store the
intermediate result there's nothing
there so don't look at it so for example
if i give you
uh five apples yeah you have five
percent
no no and then i later like five seconds
later i give you one more so how many of
them all together six
let's anime programming because you
don't count from the start
yeah you know already know what you got
is five
and you you're given one more so you
just reuse the result the fight
you you're not counting it from start
one two three four five
does it make sense
so you tell me what it is okay f n
equals
f n minus one plus f n minus two
what does it mean this item
is the sum of the previous two items
1 1 2 3 5
8 13 what's this
[Music]
say retirement x
let's make it zero one one two okay so
let's return n yeah
and then return
f n plus s m minus one
plus fn minus two am i minus ten
okay yes oh so this is recursion yeah
but do you see the problem of this
eric do you see the problem
the problem of this girl do you see it
i see the whole thing yeah look i if
look i showed you this before right
remember if i want to calculate f4
so f4 i need to calculate
i need to know s3 yes and
f2 right yes all right and in order to
calculate f3 what's your handle
and i'm maybe not
remember what i need to calculate one
f1 and f0 yeah yeah and f1 and 0 we
already know right
yeah look do you see this problem f2
i need to calculate f1 and f0
so do you see the problem eric
do you see the problem from this if i
want to calculate f1 ryan
i need to calculate f3 and f2 and in
order to catch the f3
i need to calculate f2 and f1 in order
to calculate f2 i need to
kill f1 and f0 in order to calculate f2
i need to go to
f1 and 0 do you see the problem
do you see the problem ryan come on
so it's it's right there what's the
problem release
it's like a bunny between yeah it's the
battery but look
i want to calculate f4 by using this
code right the question
i i need to calculate f3 and f2 yeah
there are two function chords
in order to character s3 i need to kick
the f2 and f1
in order to calculate f2 i need to get
do you see the problem do you see the
problem it's right there
what's the problem what's the problem of
this this is not
symmetrical no what
i give you a hint it's something that
has been
calculated more than once
once which one one and zero
and two two two yeah you see because
look f2
i want to calculate f2 and then here i
order again
and can you imagine there are lots of
things coming up yeah
if f5 and then you'll find f3 somewhere
you calculate again and again and this
this grows exponential
do you get it do you see it
yeah this is the problem yeah because i
want to calculate f3 and then i need to
click the f2
but somehow f2 is being calculated here
and i also i have
no matter how complex is f2 i need to do
it again
yeah so it's like i give you five apples
i give you one more
you can you calculate it you count it
again one upper two or four three before
i put five four
and then you know you now know six zero
and now you have six airport i give you
one
more point get one two three four five
six seven you're not doing that right
right
you could just go next number big by b4
yeah
that's right so what's the technology
here so you're not counting it from this
beginning because it takes time and it's
you are already you calculated the thing
you already know right
it's it's like you already know there
are five of us and then you're counting
it again
yeah because you're not remembering okay
so how to remembering i'll give you a
hint
it's a it's a it's a word i i talk about
that a lot
what what kind of data structure are we
using to remember
remember yes that is facebook notebook
facebook okay
so look the problem of this is that we
are we are not remembering
the results
right if if we're remembering this
if we calculate the first time we
calculate f2 yeah
we save this we save this into a
notebook and then
when we come here f2 now we know already
f2
right so we no need to calculate again
right we can just get a value from
the notebook all right so let's
dynamic programming to get it
so let's recursion but with the notebook
actually it's not notebook but notebook
is for your understanding
in in in computer science it's called
this
me mo my zation
what does it mean memorization
yeah recursion with the minimalization
so how do we do this
what does this move
what does this mean look
we can do this put a notebook yeah
equals
uh we can just
f n minus 1 plus f minus 2 okay
so now i want to put it look it here so
look
and in notebook
return notebook
end and now i need to say
value equals and then what should i do i
should put it in the notebook right
yeah so notebook and
equals y equals
[Music]
what are we calculating yeah ryan any
f what's f f is a function name come on
value value
look this is the value we put it in the
notebook do you get it underneath
this bit is to check if this n is in the
notebook
if it's in the notebook it means we have
calculated it before right
so we don't calculate we just return the
value
okay yeah okay so this whole thing
we don't need to do that that's one
magic
erase this it raise this
it raise this just go back to the
beginning okay return yeah
yeah return this yeah this is a
recursion yeah
all we have to do is
add something here at lru
this recently you need cash
and now we can specify a size max size
equals nut so
so this is just to to ask computer to
cache this function impossible
so the computer when we recursively call
is f2 for example f2 yeah
then if we check if it's already
calculated before
you won't continue you will just return
the value
right so i can't remember that
that's okay that's okay that's okay but
you can remember the notebook thing yeah
it's the same
thing air are you cash cash you know
what's cash
cash money no cash not cash
this is cash cash cash
what cash it's it's like what
it's like uh uh
it's it's like something you want to use
frequently and then you don't need to go
and do it again you can just
just put it on the someplace that you
can fetch it
quickly cache okay a storage
a storage a storage that stores the
intermediate
in the frequently used value like like
notebook yeah
a storage okay so look five airports
yeah then you know in your memory you
know there's a place called
you'll now have five apples and the next
time
you're given one airport you'll ask
yourself how many of us do i have right
now
i have fireballs and then i can just say
okay i get these five apples
and then plus one so i will have six
reports
and then you update in the cache and
then it will become
six and next time you're given one apple
and you you go and
ask ask the cash how many apples do i
have now six
yeah and then six plus one you were
seven and then you go back to update the
cash
if you don't have this cash what
happened you need to do this heavy work
you need to count apple from one two
three four five seven
imagine you you are given a million
apples
like you take time right but if you have
a cache a place
memory to tell you how many apples do
you need to go there
no right yeah i need and this will be
very fast yeah
yeah a fast a fast storage a fast
retrieve storage
cash so we could look this is the
question recursion with
with cash minimization yeah minimization
the thing i talked about
what are we talking about today the
words the two
two words
something very good dynamic programming
or vp
dynamic programming this is very
advanced technology okay
lungs aggregate dynamic programming
got it yeah all right
so can you write the fibonacci number
okay so one more time okay i already one
more
tell me what what look zero
what's d oh look dynamic programming
you can write it look this way yeah
define
f and yeah okay let's
write the notebook notebook version okay
okay if n smaller
equals one return
and what u and then if
and in notebook what should we return
[Music]
minus one plus
and then i need to go go top down f n
minus one and
f n minus two and then these will be f
and minus two
f minus three yeah look top
down yeah so this is dynamic programming
we
again we we call it top down because
look the way you
you are calculating this from top to
down yeah actually top down yeah
top down dynamic programming and you is
usually
implemented using recursion with a
notebook with the memorization it's
called
recursion with the minimization it's
very this is very important if you don't
memorize the results not the values
it's not the core dynamic programming
yeah the beauty of dynamic programming
is that you don't calculate those
intermediate values over and over again
so let's speeds up right
if you're calculating these f4 f2
again and again again it's going to take
forever it's going to take
exponential time but with this moment
memorization
for fn how many times you just have to
calculate it
uh what n because
for each for each value let's say
f10 so i just need to calculate f9
fa f7 tier x1 f0
all these numbers only calculate once
right yes
why is that because if it's calculated i
can put it in the notebook
and next time you want it i just get it
right
yes so look recursion with the
memorization
dynamic programming the complexity for
the fibonacci number is
r1
oh and it goes back in time but we love
the minimization
without repeat i won it's what
it's over and square
not quite close it's look on them
no look look each one you spawn two
possibilities each one is going to
possibility
and keep it two to the power n
exponential got it yeah
because at each one you have two spawn
two each one you have two
do to get it so it's exponential look
o 2 n and o 1 which is better
yeah of course because look o n is this
o 2 n is what
yeah so when n is 10 2
n is 1024 but 10
oh n is just 10. yeah you got it
yeah this this 2n graph is a lot higher
right
this is the iron okay
yes okay so this top down
dynamic programming we also can
calculate from bottom up by dynamic
programming
look if we calculate from this direction
yeah we can calculate f0 first f1 and
then we can tell you f2
f3 f4 f5 until f10 got it
so dc symbology number f10 top down we
can't we also calculate f10
now we calculate f a and f9 and in order
to calculate f9
i need to cancel f a and f7 let's top
down right
it's called it's implemented by
recursion with the minimization you got
it this far
i want to calculate f10 but let's take
the f zero f1 first
f0 f1 and then i can kill the f2 yeah
f1 and f2 i can kick the f3 got it
yeah so how do we do it look
we can just do this yeah
f let's just call the first one f0 and
f1
okay equals zero one okay yeah
then for i in range
i okay then n and f
zero f one equals
equals one look f0 will become f1 right
yes yeah look
one one two three okay so this is f0
this is f1
so the next direction next iteration
will be f zero f1 yeah
so f0 will become the f1 and f1 will
become f01 plus s1 right
yes so that will be f0 plus f1
okay yes so after
n direction so look if f3 f3 is
that's if you want to calculate f3 so
this is three times
so one two three
so we just return within this number
which is
return f1 right correct
so typically if i want to capture f10
fcr f1 and i will i can calculate f
look f10 5 a 13
21 okay so look this is f01 yeah
and the next one is i move here i can
categorize yeah
i move here move here
each one f0 equals f1 f1 will be f zero
plus one look
f0 f1 f0 is the f1 will become the new
f0
and then the new s1 will become the old
f 0 and f1 right
got it okay so this is called the bottom
up it's also dynamic programming
this is also dynamic programming why is
that because we use the values
intermediate value yeah you see you see
for f2 you only calculate one
right it doesn't calculate again and
again right
so the complexity is also one
okay so do you get it so how many kind
of dynamic programmings we have
uh three two three
two what are those uh the
dino
one within
it's called the top down right yeah and
this one is what
bottle up right why are we using the
dynamic programming to
what what's the what's the ability
[Music]
memorization yeah to avoid to avoid
to calculate the same value again and
again
okay so this is to we use the thing
to do to avoid calculating intermediate
results over and over again because we
we calculate once we remember it we
don't come back and calculate it again
this is the advantage okay okay
that's it for today thank you bye
bye bye bye bye
bye