go hello hello hello mr eric mr ryan
how are you today good have a nice
weekend yeah it's friday okay
so remember what we have talked about
yesterday
we talked about
dynamics programming yes well
dynamic programming okay so basic
dynamic programming is an
optimization technique yeah to
speed up your algorithm right it's kind
of like a
you ask computer to remember the things
it has calculated so it doesn't we
calculate those
things right again again okay so
it will save us time so today we're
going to talk about
an interesting problem using this
dynamic programming and
possibly the permutation and combination
yeah you still remember combination yeah
how many apples how many how many apples
you can pick
i mean how many ways of picking three
apples out of five
so what's this number is c five three
yeah picking three numbers out of five
yeah
we love orders yeah so what does it
equal remember
equals 5 times 4 times
3 divided by 3 times 2 times 1 okay
yeah okay
so it's 10 weights okay so c and m
equals n factorial divided by
m factorial divided by n minus m
factorial
okay okay yes and c
5 3 is equal to c phi 2 okay
it's the same because if you there are
five airplanes and if you pick the three
apples
you also have a solution for picking two
apples all right
yeah okay so now how about if i give you
a
a grid a grade a grid
like three
and then four maybe
so eric you are here yeah are we where
am i
ever getting ryan is here right
at the top left corner uh
possibly that's not not not the corner
okay
let's let's put it in here okay you can
walk in the square
what so yeah here and then why anything
why are we naked
i know okay everyone here yeah you can
okay what's this direction that's east
yeah yeah
let's let's uh stop yes yes
so look you're at the top left corner
and then
every time you can walk one step
to the east or to the south but you
cannot you cannot go to the north and
the
west why i say so
okay okay because
yeah because i say so doesn't
make it more detailed
not about detail okay so that's supposed
to you can only walk eastern
you need to go you want to go here come
here
how many how many ways how can you do it
lots
lots yeah so i want you to compute the
number of ways you can do it
look you can do this do this do this
again or you can do it
or you can do this here lots of ways
this is too
too uh a bit complicated how about these
just two squares you and you're here
and you want to go through here how many
ways
two yeah yeah there's three there's one
three
all four okay okay three four one
right so look at how what why you
wouldn't say this is true this is easy
right
yeah because
because
yeah so how many ways i you want to go
to the
right top uh right bottom corner
three one two
three yes three it just
so how can we uh
so it's that way we can count it huh
so let's suppose they are n
they are n squared if that's not you
just divided by
2 or something no not even because look
there are
n squares vertically
and m squares horizontally
so let's change blue pin yeah
so look how many ways i need to
e1 how many way how many steps from the
left top right top left corner to the uh
bottom right corner how many steps
how many steps so in order to work one
two three four five
five step yeah yes one two three four
one two three so seven
no one two three four five five steps
also they can be like this uh
different steps no no you cannot go up
so look one
two three four five one two three four
five
one two three four five do you still
still get it oh yeah
so home the the the total steps is fixed
so it equals m plus m minus one right
because the first step doesn't count
yeah you need to minus it right
yeah yeah okay yes
so look at this one how many steps
how many
yeah one two three and
one two three okay one
two three so look
so how many steps going going
to the south
how many steps do you need to go to to
the south here
if two which is m
minus one yeah minus one so you're going
to solve n
minus one okay are you going to know
north you need how many one
three which is that's east
which is which is
m minus one one two three
okay so uh one two three yeah okay
y is minus n plus n minus one
one one two three so n minus one
okay yeah so look they are n
minus one to the south and minus one to
the east
so all together is m plus n minus two
okay so actually it's a minus center
three plus
four three plus four seven minus two
okay yeah this is five right one two
three four five it's right it's
minus two okay yeah
so of all these steps this is total step
and i want to pick number
the the number of south
does it make sense yeah
so for example this one they are
one step to the north and then there are
one two two steps to the to the south to
the east so how many way how many steps
three steps yeah yes so let's
follow those three steps i want to pick
one step to the north
then that's the number of waves am i
right
so let the how many waves of this is c
two plus one and mark one all right
yeah does it make sense look look
so this is the total of steps
and among that i can pick i need to pick
the steps n minus one steps to the south
or
a minus one step to the east so the
number of
ways is c n plus
m minus two n minus one or
because this is two equal right c m plus
m minus two n minus one okay so these
these two are equal right remember
because these two added together would
be the least
we still still remember c n m equals c
n n minus n remember
yeah this is remember this yeah
no one will just talk about it picking
three apples after five is the same as
speaking to apples
out of five am i yes
n is bigger this is the total number of
apples this is five plus
five plus i only pick three it's the
same as five
i want to pick five minus three two
apples here
got it yeah so look the total number of
apples is n plus and minus
two right i want to pick a minus and one
apple to decide to go to the south so
this is the number of ways
to get it yeah do you get it
so how many ways is this five
no no no no look n is
one two three m is seven so c five
two what's c by two
five times four divided by two
is ten way they're all there ten ways
let's let's verify it okay
ten ways one two three four five
here one two three four five yeah
yeah two three
okay four
five six
seven eight nine
ten correct so that's him yeah
so as long as we know the n and m
we know the mathematics ways to
calculate it the number of ways
got it does it make sense
okay so look this is the
mathematic way of doing this okay so
how can we calculate it remember look
look eric
define this is right here
define f
and then m yeah
look at previously with n so the number
of voice is what
we want to know this cm plus m
uh minus one minus two
and minus one yeah we want to take the
least number yeah
yes yeah okay so
actually actually
look this is mathematic but
again let's let's see this
if i'm at this point i'm here
yeah where can i uh
where could the possible letter come
from which place which two
i'm at this is the beginning so if
someone
somehow i'm at this point so
where where was where i where was i in
the previous step
where where where could i come from
it's cleanest top left corner yeah this
is the starting point and you can only
go to the south and to the east and go
to the south so
i'm here where could i possibly go
only here yeah so here and here right
you could the previous section could
only be here and here right
okay so suppose there are only one way
come here
one way come here yeah and there's only
one way come here
so how many ways can i come here two
yeah because here and here
got it so look
this is original f zero f zero okay f
zero
zero equals one okay and then here
here suppose this is f n m right
so what does the equal f and m
equals 1 here
f n n minus 1
plus here what's here f
in order to calculate this i need to
catch at least and this because
if i know they are baby 20 ways
to come here and then there are 30 ways
to come here so how many ways i can come
here
if there are 20 ways i can reach this
point and 30 ways i can reach
this one how many ways i can come here
please from this
place on this right
why is it 25 i just sent eddie together
what do you think
why would you thinking yes 50.
look so the target is i then i can
calculate this point yeah because
because i can kick a previous two and
then previously so
remember what is this similar to
fibonacci number
yeah the fibonacci number look f n
equals
f n minus 1 plus f minus 2 right
yeah it depends on previous steps and
remember how many dynamic programming
can we
can we use how many ways of dynamic
programming
i give you i think top down and
top down and what what's the other way
and what no butter
up come on you forgot remember
remember yesterday we talked about top
down f n calculate from f
n and then i want to calculate f minus
one
and then again again calculate f 10 f
0 and f and bottom up is calculated
starting from f0
and f1 f2 got it the same thing here
top down top down is that
i want to calculate a way to get the
number of ways of
getting this the right button turner
yeah then i need to calculate these two
right yeah in order to do like that i
need to calculate these two
all right this is called top bottom top
down
then i can i can i know the the number
of ways i can
get here and get here and from this
point i can get here
why because this each number is the sum
of
previous of these and then this yeah
does it remind you of the pasta triangle
yeah
each number is the sum of the is it's
sugar
1 1 1 1 2 1
1 3 3 1 each number is the sum of
its above and the left got it
okay at least it can also be calculated
from top down
or butter up okay top down is i want to
calculate
i want to calculate this and i go go
actually is the opposite i go take a
list with the three and then i need to
kick at least two and if i on the table
at least i need to kick at least this
a button up is that i calculate from the
first first row
and then keep going keep going until i
reach the number i want okay
so here again
all right pay attention come on it's
very important here
look define f and
m okay so if n
equals zero okay the first one
all the oh column yeah and it was zero
return what how many ways can you do it
how many if i'm here how many ways i can
come from here
one how many ways i can come here
one yeah because the first row and first
column is always one all right
yeah yeah because you can only go to the
south and uh and the east
and there's only one possibility you go
straight yeah
the the sum of these two points yeah n
minus one
and plus f and
n minus one right yes top down
remember we need to use the notebook
yeah remember yesterday in the notebook
yes so how do we use the notebook
yeah no book
no book e
okay a tuper yeah n m
yeah look if this entry is already
in notebook return
notebook and m
right otherwise the value
equals f n minus one
m plus f and n
minus one and put it on the notebook
you just copy this yeah yeah
equals value return
please
return what
what are we calculating here return
value obviously remember yesterday it's
the same remember
this is the same exactly the same except
this bit
yeah remember yesterday minus one plus f
of minus two yeah
all right we know that it's only one
parameter now i have two parameters
so this is called top down top down
diameter programming okay top down
got
okay so how about butter up
oh remember yesterday we talked about if
we want to if we don't want to use
implement a notebook we can put
something at the beginning this will
remember
at a r u cash
num okay omega equals num so when you
please it means that the compiler the
computer will say
okay i want to cache this function
as much as i can so meaning that if i
see this parameter
n and m if you give me f 2 2
and i have already calculated f 2 2
then i will immediately return it
without calculating it right
without invoking the recursion again and
again okay
yeah okay so this is the magic keyword
okay
to save you from implementing the
notebook
okay so from the
from the button up button
define f and m column
so look we need to put it in the array
right
so look dt equals
we will create a two dimensional array
yeah
zero for we at least
specify the for i
in range m
and then actually it's here
it's been 21 minutes okay for j
in j range m okay
and m so this is n this is m okay so now
we have this tp which is two dimensional
way to tell me
and then i can i need to specify the for
i
for row in branch
this is a bit complicated when you end
okay so n runs
and then i can say dp
the first one is is one right the first
first column
is one and the same as for c in
range m
and dp
uh actually zero c equals one okay so
let's first color first row
is one right i put a one here and i put
a one here
and then for other values in the in in
the metric four are in
range one and
four c in range
one c one m okay and then i can do this
look at it
b p r c equals one
p rc equals one dp
r minus one c plus
plus dp r c minus one okay
yeah yeah so look we're using the four
and this is
complexities oh
m yeah because i need to fill in this
metric
this magic two-dimensional matrix array
okay and then the last value i want to
return is return
return what pp minus one the last row
and the minus one the last column so
which is the right
the bottom right column okay button
right here this is called bottom
complexity okay so now one more thing
okay so this is as usual and one more
thing okay so this is a bit tricky but
but i think you you you must be clever
to think about it
yeah look so look again
this is a map okay suppose i already
give you the answer of f
f what is that and
m is the number
if they are n square okay so
suppose suppose if there are
n squares n squares this side
and n square this side and then you can
use this function to tell me
to say okay the number of ways for early
on ryan to go from the
top left corner top left corner to the
right bottom
corner is f and n okay supposing
yeah yeah suppose you already know
suppose you can give me this okay yes
now finish yeah finish line
that's square doesn't matter so this is
okay
all right okay in this square
in this square the last square okay so
now
s and m okay so look at n is what
one two three four five so you and one
two three four
five six so it's 5 f 5
6 is the number of ways for everything
ryan to come from the top left corner
to the bottom right corner okay yes
okay okay how about i said okay so eric
and ryan must
visit tesco somehow the tesco is is here
today we just went to tesco yeah let's
go here
so now the same rule you must go to the
south and the east but you must go here
first and how many ways somewhere
[Music]
in three three
how many ways from here and here
you don't need to give me the exact
numbers but i want to know how you think
about it
how you calculate how what how do you
know it's six
i mean i guess you wanna guess so how
what do you do
so in order for everything ryan to go
here
these can be divided into how many steps
how many ways of can you do it it takes
you think about it think
you think so i'll give you a thing how
many
so you need to come from
the top left corner to to which place
first
how many ways let's go yes how many ways
of doing that
it takes you three steps f
and in order to come here to hear how
many steps f
no you don't you don't need to give me
the answer i just need to know how many
f3 two right
yes three columns three rows and two
columns all right
i have three two okay yes yeah so that's
how many you we can calculate that yeah
and how many ways
and then what's next how many ways of
calculating
from tesco to this place and how many
ways there
one two three and then i said one two
three four
five yeah so if the waste of tesco is
s35 okay so now this problem can be
divided into two
in order for you to go to this target
i need to go you need to go to the tesco
first and then go to from
tesco go to this yeah your home okay
that's home
okay so i have two numbers the number of
ways from these to this testicle
is s32 okay the number from tesco to
home is f35 so
what should i do how many ways from here
to here
what should i do with these two number
is should we
add it or times it you pick one
should we add it or 5 times it
really
everybody any thoughts
there are there are eight ways to come
to tesco
and there are big ways to from to from
tesco to home
so a b should i
edit or transit
add times add times
both i think it's probably
why is that time times
it's times if our of course is terms how
how how is that
nearly been half an hour okay so i why
is it terms
okay yes look if there are two ways of
coming there and then three ways are
coming next
so how many ways
five why is five for each one
i can pick three one
two three and for this one i can pick
three one
two three you get it so it's two times
three it's not two and three got it
yeah yeah it's the multiple it's not
this is very important okay
got it why don't you get it there are
two ways coming here
unless we always going home how many
ways to do go home
five six six it's not five look one
two three
and then here five
all right well uh four five six do you
get it
because if you said it sorry
okay so how many ways how can you do it
if there are
two and then four here how many ways
because there's six in the way
here yeah every right look
eight ways anyways yeah because two
times four
right three yeah yeah so the same thing
is
here this is the ways to go here tesco
and this is the ways of going
home from tesco so you need to prance it
again
so do you get it do you see this problem
yeah
yeah do you get it yeah i'm gonna ask
you tomorrow morning okay i'll give you
a little passion
because this no yeah no this is called
the dynamic programming okay being half
an hour
dynamic program okay say bye bye to
people