Hello Mr Eric, Mr Ryan
Are you all right?
okay so
binary tree, right, binary search tree
do you still remember?
yeah
but we are in your office
okay so this is the binary tree
also Binary Search Tree
because the left nodes are smaller than the root
than the parents
the right nodes are strictly bigger than the parent
okay this is a valid binary search tree
let's look at this as well
that one is gonna be invalid
1.5
yeah that node you're gonna write is gonna be imblanced
no no I'm not going to
that's a -1
that's invalid
why is it invalid
because it's on the right
still on the right side
no because it's bigger than 1
yeah this one is less than 1
yeah but even this node is smaller than 2
but it's bigger than 1 which is not right okay
it's less than 1
but it's less than
it's less than 1 so this is invalid
so what's the
most important thing about this binary search tree
is that
is that we can put it In-order and it will be in order
that's right if we perform an in order traversal
so basically we visit the left tree first
and the current node and the right tree
that will give us an
in order okay
there we can see your shadow
that's fine okay
so let's look at a simple binary search tree
which is
0 1 2 3,  4 nodes
so is this a binary search tree?
is this a binary search tree? yes?
yeah 1 2 3
yeah it's a linked list, it's also a binary search tree
but what's different what's so special about it
it is one line
one line, so
is it a good is is it a good binary search tree
it's imbalance
it's imbalance yes what I'm talking about is imbalance
what's balance
balance is, a balance tree
a balance binary tree
is that the difference of any
different
the difference of the left tree and the right tree
for any node should be no more than 1
okay for but for this one
is imbalance because look at this node
the left tree the distance
the depth is zero the right is 1, 2, 3
three minus zero is more than 1
this is imbalance
but in the meantime if we put the one here
zero
uh two three
this is balance
okay this is balance because look this is one
this is 2,  Two Minus One
no more than one
right the difference no more than one is one
okay makes sense? this is the balance also
what can we do? two
0, 3, right
this is also a balance binary tree
binary search tree
all 1 2 3 all these three are binary search trees
this is not balanced
this is balanced
right here what if the one has a number
what do you mean with it
with the one here
uh you mean what do you put here I'm
no no okay are you in 1.5
yeah yeah yeah is is it a
yes it's a binary search tree, for any
any node, look the difference left one is
uh the same yeah I'm saying
is that, you're talking about the 2-1
any questions so far for the, isn't that 3
isn't that 3 um
you were talking about with 2 - 1 thing
the difference the absolute difference left
| left-right | is more
what's the difference in that one?
this one yeah
okay let's look at this node the
the left tree
the depth is 1 2, the right tree is 1
oh yeah so for any node
for any node every node sorry for every node
okay but for this one look
the difference, the left is 0 the right is 1 2 3
3-0 is bigger than 1
that is what I am saying..
the depths of the the left tree and the right tree
for every node
for every node okay
every node, why do we prefer
do you know we prefer the balance over imbalance
why?
because imbalance is usually the worst case
is why why in worst case in what
in some problems
some problem, what kind of problem?
what do we need a binary search tree for?
um, to find the solution
putting things in order to find a solution
to find a
yeah to find for example if I want to find a 2 here
so there's only one way I can go right
yeah? find 2 or 3
find two or three, in the worst case I need to travel N steps
Am I right? there's only one way
so basically it's linear search
we are not making use of the binary search property
but for this one if I want to look for number two
right, balance, I don't
yeah I don't need to look for anything here right
then there could be a
very big number of nodes on the left tree
so at each
at each step I can abandon almost half of it (binary search)
but what if there's nothing on the left side
then this, look
yeah that's what I'm saying
this is imbalance for imbalance tree
if we perform a
search it will be degraded into a linear search
because we are not making use of
the property that the left trees are smaller
and the right are bigger trees - basically one line
that's right yes okay so
okay so we've given a
binary search tree we want to make it a balance
you can, I mean obviously look there are many
there are more than one
balance versions of the same binary search tree, right?
so you can return any of it
okay so for example we given any
binary search tree, we want to make it balanced
okay?
so any idea?
so if we've given these any binary search tree okay
we've given any binary search tree
given we're given a BST, we want to balance it
we want to make a balanced version of it
and because they are more than one
they are more than one
usually and they could be more than one
they could be more than one balanced version of this
same BST we can just return any of them
what I mean by
the same version is that if we perform an in order
we get the same sorted list right?
if we perform an in order we get the sorted list
okay
that's a hint
so how can we do it? any idea?
so, it's a
left node right
yes what what's this?
the left node right what are we doing there?
uh it's in order
okay so we can make an In-order
of the BST then we got the sorted list
am I right? that's the first step right
so for example like this one we have a sorted list
1 2 3 4 5 6 7
so how do we make a balance
binary search tree out of it
so which node should be in the
root node if we want to make a balance
so which node should be the root
um... 4
4, yes, we choose the middle right, for example like
yeah we can get this sorted list, right
by performing the in order of any binary search tree
we get the sorted list and then we
we pick the middle as the root right, so okay four
so what nodes are on the left? what nodes are on the right?
what nodes are on the left? what nodes are on the right?
1 2 3 is on the left and 5 6 7 is on the right
that's right yes so 1 2 3 is here right
that's 1 2 3 here
5 6 7 is here right
yes, so...
okay and then
4 to 6 and then 6
it is 5 and 7
yeah okay
okay so now look
what's this? look we pick the root node
and then these nodes are on the left
these nodes are on right
so we can
continue working out on this sub-problem right
so for 1 2 3 this is sorted list
what node should be in the middle?
so four should be connected to two
yes so 2 should be in the middle right
okay so what's that
uh
1, what's that? 3
oh what's right okay three
okay and this one as well, so we pick six 6
and 5 and 7 okay so
this is the recursive problem - recursion
recursion right, every time we pick in the middle
the left is the left tree
the right is the right tree
and we continue dividing this sub problem
until we get only one node
if it's one node
we don't need to divide anymore, am I right?
yeah
if it is one node, we just return it, ok, so
the in order thing that
let's do the in order thing first and then we do this
then the next step is to build it using the recursion
okay
so we talk about this In-order thing many many times
we can do it many ways
the recursion is the way to go
and we can use the Iterator right
define
depth first search
the root
if not root
then return
ok then, yield from, right, we talked about that in
in previous lesson
yield from dfs(root.left)
I will visit the left tree first
then yield, remember this yield keyword?
I promise you
to give you £5 every month, I promise you to give you £5
that at the end of every month, yield root.val, ok?
and then
what's next? we visit the left tree, we visit the
we visit the current node, what's next?
look this is the root
we visit the root.left here, yield from root.left
because there could be a many so we yield from here
yield from okay we yield from
this place yield this value and what's next?
root.right
yield from root.right
so yield from
dfs(root.right), ok
we can do it by
inserting so if we have this array here
we can inserting instead of yield from we can say
array.append uh
we can Depth First Search root.left and then
and then array.append(root.val)
dfs(root.right), ok, this is
this is much cleaner syntax
syntax sugar
okay then with this DFS and then we can array
equals, that we converted the
because it's a iterator we converted
converted to a list
dfs
now we have a sorted list
we have a sorted list
now we want to
build/construct the binary search tree
balance binary search tree using this approach
recursion using this approach
okay so how do we do it
using recursion
define let's say f
def f
we say build tree, ok, build, build tree
build binary search tree BST
so we want to build it here
we need to give a left or right pointer right
left or right pointer
if the left is
bigger than right
and we just return because there's no point right
left or right pointer
we use the left or right point right
the left at the beginning we put it here
right here
if L == R
if there's only one node, then we just return right
return TreeNode
what's what if that is an even number
array
arr[L].val
okay what do you mean?
what if it is an even number?
for example if it's 8 and then there's no center
okay so that's a very good point
okay so if there's 8 nodes, there's no center
you can pick four or five
it doesn't matter as long as it's balance
right we can prove that by choosing the middle one
either is this one or that one
it gives us the optimal
right because the balance
tree is that the difference is no more than 1
okay now if if there's only 1 node
then we just return of it, right
otherwise root equals TreeNode
TreeNode
we want to get the middle right
the middle one is what
the middle one is left plus right divided by 2 right
or shifts one position to the right e.g. >>1
Am I right? the middle one
how do you get the middle
(L+R)/2
Am I Right? Yes
okay the middle one
TreeNode, root, Array
array[middle one].val
now we want to build the left tree, right? root
root.left = buildTree
now the left bit
okay look this is middle right?
yeah
this is middle
now this middle is root
now the left tree is
root on left equals build tree, recursion right?
the left to be L
middle minus 1 right yeah
look root.right equals what?
root.right = build tree
what's the, what's the index I should give it
this one is M plus 1
middle plus one
up to R okay and then, return root
okay you see, using the recursion, 2 recursions
the left recursion is to perform
an in order on the binary search tree
and we get a
array, sorted array
the right recursion
we are building a binary search tree
balance binary search tree
by following the strategy always pick the middle
as the root, once we pick the middle we know the left
the numbers on the left
we know the numbers on the right
and we recursively build it
yeah if there's only one root, then we return
just return
the leaf node, this is the leaf node
otherwise we get the middle
and the left part we're using the recursion to build it
the right part we're using the recursion to build it
and we return the root, ok
okay any questions so far? no
okay so what have you learned today?
Ummm, we learned about...
Can you just
present this solution here just like Daddy, come on
quickly bonus 5 minutes (watching TV time)
you can, two, you two can come on
come on come on come on
demonstrate on the whiteboard, come on
yeah 5 minutes
me
yeah yeah both
you two can work as a team
we have a binary search tree
imbalance, ... should I
I mean, you can, there are two
you can both present one okay?
so okay so we have a
a binary search tree, and
and we
so first of all in
we wanna make it a balance not imbalance
that's right
imbalance is when the depths
the depths of the left, and of the right trees, is, Uhm
more over one
difference, the depths
yeah that's what I just said
okay
and then okay so
so we give you those like numbers
uh yeah here we do 2 pointer and then we
and then we close the gap, until it's
until they are the same, Uhm
um until they meet like
in the center or if it is even
and then you just
you can choose the left
uh left or right if there is no center
yeah you have get
get a chunk to the left side
and get a chunk to the right side
yeah and and yeah hmm
what you were drawing that was interesting, can you
can you say it, a tiny binary search tree
tiny.. okay so can you say in one or two sentence
two or three sentences what are we doing today
we have a BST, and we want to make it balanced
wow that's very concise
yes that's what we're doing here
what kind of strategy are we using to build the balanced
balanced binary search tree
we
just use computer
okay so Ryan
yeah so the solution is that we
because it's the binary search tree
we perform in order we get the sorted list, right？
do you understand this part？ yes
now with the sorted list
then
every time we pick the one in the middle as the root
so root 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
we pick the 4
as the root and the 1 2 3 should be on the left side
5 6 7 should be on the right side, right?
and for the left tree and right tree
1 2 3, for 1 2 3
the 2 should be in the middle right?
so 2 should be in the middle
1 should be in the
left and 3 should be the right
so we can recursively divide this problem into the
sub problem, do you get it?
and this way we can build the balanced binary search tree
okay, good job, that is it for today, Bye Bye!
bye bye bye