yeah so let's say t equals table
[Music]
C equals okay
and
T equals
[Music]
so obviously there is two the same
tables right yeah let's do some table so
this is turtle
[Music]
this is the
this is the table table so table is X
here
and this is the
cat okay
so what can we get from here
170 plus
170 plus t
X
classy all right yeah 170 plus T is it
this big right is it equals to X plus C
and now let's take a look at this one
here this is no cap right same thing cat
plus 130 equals
please speak
X Plus what's the speed this what's this
X Plus t
what do we get we have these two we want
to find out
x x equals 170
plus T minus C and then here x equals
130 plus C minus t
add it together what do we have ADD it
together 2x 2x equal here is T minus t
here is C is minus C cancel out
equals 300 what's X
okay we're looking at this this equation
what's the size of the table okay I'm
working 24
this table
make sense
they have no idea why because it's hard
to to do less mess in your head but when
I put it down I can hear the value T C
cat X table so look Tata plus 170 is it
equal this high right this is the same
as X
cable plus cap yeah that's no cat that's
a human okay the first equation and how
about this one
X Plus Theta is equals cat plus 130
right look the right one has a
yeah
what happened
we are interested in this x variable
right how about if we move these things
from the right hand side from one side
of the equation to the other side what
happened to the side we make it the
opposite right look when you put move
the C to the left side you need to minus
C right it makes sense yeah
yeah it's like a hundred equals 60 plus
40. so when you move the 40 to the left
hand side what happened
minus 40 is the same thing look
we want to know that X we move the T to
the left hand side so it needs to be
minority and then look x equals this x
equals this we add it together
the left hand side is 2 times x the
right hand side look here is T here's
minus t comes out here is C here's minus
C because R so only constant of seventy
170 plus 130 300 so 2x equals 300 x
equals 150 but to the other hand this
this value of T and C matter can we
solve all the T and C here can we
look two equations two two equations
three unknowns yes we are known as
we can't we can't solve it right
why can we solve solve the X here
because we cancel out
the two T and C but T and C can be
anything right
exactly we don't know the value of TNT
but that's that's okay we can still find
out the x value okay that's it
foreign