I just noticed if you have a numbers
sorted the answer is the smallest number
how can you prove I don't know but it
looks like it right it looks like it
because look because you because you
because you always end
anything like
and the and the first number the
smallest number is at the beginning and
and that's where the minimum is going
minimum Max minimum Max and it starts at
the minimum so the most minimum goes
down that little bit most minimum
because it's always at the start so and
it always starts at minimum so it's
always obviously gonna pass and then
eventually eventually it's going to go
to minimum and then good job good job
excellent that's a weird Discovery yes
yes you're right