why this endless thing is useful okay
just imagine you know that there are
unlimited number of prime numbers right
all right how to improve these are
unlimited look if the first number prime
number is P1 second prime number is P2
and prime number needs to be P3 if they
are limited number of prime numbers
let's say piano
up to pm
and how about if we times least together
that's limited I know I know I'm proving
that it's unlimited so let's assume the
opposite it's a limited and there are n
prime numbers P one p two P three up to
PN and that time Z together plus one
obviously this number is not divisible
by any of these right
am I right so this is also a prime
number we just assume there are n prime
numbers but now we found another one
so what does it mean the assumption is
wrong the Assumption what's the
Assumption there are n prime numbers
this assumption is wrong
okay so what does it mean it means we
have unlimited number of prime numbers
okay
okay so but you're saying B1 p2p3 but
you only have n two times together and
plus one that's right and this number is
the prime number yeah you only have an N
to multiply by
yes and that's limited because you only
have Ben yes and my assumption is that
okay let's assume that and prime numbers
yeah and then let us know this number
plus one comes together plus one is also
a prime number yeah that's only one more
one more okay so there's only one more
so it contracted it conflicts with the
assumption that only end actually n plus
one and I can keep doing this keep
adding this keep adding it so that means
that keeps adding okay I'm assuming
there are n prime numbers but now I
found another one which is not part of
this end
okay so I have one more number here
which is the prime number yeah but how
do you add another one
this is another one this is another one
yeah so you times that another one where
the other end yes so this this number
this number is a new prime number but
when you
in our first cry number times
number what about 21 free look look two
times three it equals six plus one
equals seven you missed a five
that's okay okay so let's assume that
only two point numbers right let's
assume okay we want to prove there are
only two that they are Limited Brand
number which is two and three now I'm
telling you two times three plus one
this is obviously a prime number
seven and then two times three times
seven okay so we found another prime
number which is seven
so the original assumption is wrong they
are not just two prime number because
seven is another prime number
my origin assumptions they are only n
prime numbers now I found another one
number which is point number so it's
contracted the original assumption
so the origin assumption is wrong
the opposite is correct which is there
are unlimited number of prime numbers